<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108180</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108180</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086372</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Judged by Your Peers": Fighting Discrimination in Texas Court Rooms</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"geurteilt durch Ihre Gleichen": Kämpfende 
Unterscheidung in den Texas Gericht-Räumen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"jugé par vos pairs" : Discrimination de 
combat dans des salles de cour du Texas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"julgado por seus pares": Discriminação de
combate em quartos da corte de Texas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"giudicato dai vostri pari": Distinzione di 
combattimento nelle stanze della corte del Texas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κριθείς από τους λόρδους σασ": Διάκριση πάλης 
στα δικαστήρια του Τέξας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"juzgado por sus pares": Discriminación que
lucha en cuartos de la corte de Tejas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With the annexation of Texas in 1848 at the end of the Mexican-American War, Tejanos--Texans of Mexican descent--lost property rights and political power in a society dominated by Anglos. Through discriminatory practices and violent force, Tejanos were kept at the bottom of the new political and socio-cultural order. From 1900-1930, as an influx of immigrants from Mexico came north to meet a growing demand for cheap labor in the developing commercial agriculture industries, Tejanos experienced continued discrimination in employment, housing, public facilities, the judicial system, and educational institutions. In addition, many were disenfranchised, due to poll tax requirements and all-white primaries, and excluded from jury duty. The struggle of Mexican Americans to end such discriminatory practices accelerated following World War II. In the early 1950s, attorneys for two Mexican-American civil rights groups, the League of United Latin American Citizens (LULAC) and the American G.I. Forum, argued before the U.S. Supreme Court in  Hern_ndez  v.  Texas  that exclusion from jury duty based on class constituted discrimination. The state of Texas acknowledged that in the previous 25 years no person with a Spanish surname had served on any juries. The Warren Court ruled unanimously that persons of Mexican American ancestry did constitute a class within the community in which the original trial was held, and that exclusion of Mexican Americans from juries resulted in a denial of the equal protection guarantee of the 14th Amendment for Mexican American defendants. In the following interview, Pete Tijerina, a member of LULAC and the first executive director of the Mexican American Legal Defense and Educational Fund (MALDEF), discussed all-Anglo juries and other discriminatory conditions in Texas society in the 1950s and 1960s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mit der Annexion von Texas 1848 am Ende des 
Mexikanisch-Amerikanischen Krieges, des Tejanos -- des Texans des 
mexikanischen Abfalls -- verlorene Eigentumsrechte und politische 
Energie in einer Gesellschaft beherrscht von Anglos. Durch 
diskriminierende Praxis und heftige Kraft wurden Tejanos an der 
Unterseite der neuen politischen und soziologisch-kulturellen Ordnung 
gehalten. Von 1900-1930 während ein Zufluß der Immigranten von
Mexiko nördlich kam, eine steigende Nachfrage nach preiswerter Arbeit
in den sich entwickelnden kommerziellen Landwirtschaft Industrien zu 
treffen, erfuhr Tejanos anhaltende Unterscheidung in der 
Beschäftigung, im Gehäuse, in den allgemeinen Teildiensten, im 
Gerichtssystem und in den pädagogischen Anstalten. Zusätzlich 
wurden viele entrechtet, wegen der Gemeindeabgabeanforderungen und der
all-weißen Primärstromkreise und ausgeschlossen von der jury 
Aufgabe. Der Kampf der mexikanischen Amerikaner, zum solcher 
diskriminierender Praxis zu beenden beschleunigte folgenden Weltkrieg 
II. In den frühen fünfziger Jahren setzten Rechtsanwälte für
zwei Mexikanisch-Amerikanische Zivilrechtgruppen, die Liga der 
vereinigten lateinamerikanischen Bürger (LULAC) und amerikanische 
G.I. Forum, argumentiert vor dem VEREINIGTE STAATEN Höchsten Gericht 
in Hern_ndez V. Texas, das Ausschluß von der jury Aufgabe auf 
Kategorie gründete, Unterscheidung fest. Der Zustand von Texas 
bestätigte den in den vorhergehenden 25 Jahren, die keine Person mit 
einem spanischen Familiennameen auf allen möglichen Jurys gedient 
hatte. Das Warren Gericht ordnete einmütig an, daß Personen 
des mexikanischen amerikanischen Geschlechtes eine Kategorie innerhalb
der Gemeinschaft festsetzten, in der der ursprüngliche Versuch 
angehalten wurde, und daß Ausschluß der mexikanischen Amerikaner von
den Jurys eine Ablehnung der gleichen Schutzgarantie der 14. Änderung
für mexikanische amerikanische Beklagte ergab. Im folgenden 
Interview, Peter Tijerina, ein Bauteil von LULAC und der erste 
Executivdirektor der mexikanischen amerikanischen zugelassenen 
Verteidigung und der pädagogischen Kapitals (MALDEF), behandelte 
all-Anglojurys und andere diskriminierende Bedingungen in der Texas 
Gesellschaft in den fünfziger Jahren und in den sechziger Jahren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec l'annexation du Texas en 1848 à la fin de la
guerre, du Tejanos Mexicain-Américains -- Texan de descente 
mexicaine -- droites de propriété perdues et puissance politique 
dans une société dominée par Anglos. Par les pratiques 
discriminatoires et la force violente, Tejanos ont été maintenus au 
bas de la nouvelle commande politique et socio-culturelle. De 
1900-1930, pendant qu'un afflux des immigrés du Mexique venait au 
nord pour satisfaire une demande croissante en main d'oeuvre à prix 
réduit dans les industries commerciales se développantes 
d'agriculture, Tejanos a éprouvé la discrimination continue dans 
l'emploi, le logement, les équipements publics, le système 
juridique, et les établissements éducatifs. En outre, beaucoup
ont été privés des droits civiques, en raison des conditions 
d'impôt local et des primaires tout-blanches, et exclus du devoir de 
fortune. La lutte des Américains mexicains pour terminer de 
telles pratiques discriminatoires a accéléré la deuxième guerre 
mondiale suivante. Au début des années 50, les mandataires 
pour deux groupes Mexicain-Américains de droits civiques, la ligue 
des citoyens latino-américains unis (LULAC) et le G.I. Forum 
américain, discuté devant la cour suprême des ETATS-UNIS dans 
Hern_ndez v. le Texas que l'exclusion du devoir de fortune a basé sur
la classe ont constitué la discrimination. L'état du Texas a 
reconnu cela en 25 années précédentes qu'aucune personne avec un 
nom de famille espagnol n'avait servies sur aucun jury. La cour 
de Warren a régné unanimement que les personnes de l'ascendance 
américaine mexicaine ont constitué une classe au sein de la 
communauté dans laquelle l'épreuve initiale a été tenue, et que 
l'exclusion des Américains mexicains des jurys a eu comme 
conséquence un démenti de la garantie égale de protection du 14ème
amendement pour les défendeurs américains mexicains. Dans 
l'entrevue suivante, Peter Tijerina, un membre de LULAC et le premier 
directeur exécutif de la défense légale américaine mexicaine et 
les fonds éducatifs (MALDEF), jurys tout-Anglo discutés et d'autres 
conditions discriminatoires dans la société du Texas dans les 
années 50 et les années 60.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com o annexation de Texas em 1848 no fim da 
guerra, do Tejanos -- o Texans Mexicano-Americanos da descida mexicana
-- direitas de propriedade perdidas e potência política em uma 
sociedade dominada por Anglos. Através das práticas 
discriminatory e da força violenta, Tejanos foi mantido no fundo da 
ordem política e socio-socio-cultural nova. De 1900-1930, 
enquanto um influx dos immigrants de México veio para o norte se 
encontrar com uma demanda de crescimento para o trabalho barato nas 
indústrias comerciais se tornando da agricultura, Tejanos 
experimentou a discriminação continuada no emprego, na carcaça, em 
facilidades públicas, no sistema judicial, e em instituições 
educacionais. Além, muitos disenfranchised,  devido às 
exigências do imposto de votação e aos primaries todo-brancos, e 
foram excluídos do dever jury. O esforço dos americanos 
mexicanos para terminar tais práticas discriminatory acelerou 
seguinte segunda guerra mundial. Nos 1950s adiantados, os 
advogados para dois grupos Mexicano-Americanos das direitas civis, a 
liga dos cidadãos americanos latin unidos (LULAC) e o G.I. americano 
Forum, discutido antes da corte suprema de ESTADOS UNIDOS em Hern_ndez
v. Texas que a exclusão do dever jury baseou na classe constituíram 
a discriminação. O estado de Texas reconheceu aquele nos 25 
anos onde precedentes nenhuma pessoa com um sobrenome espanhol tinha 
servido em todos os júris. A corte de Warren governou 
unânimemente que as pessoas do ancestry americano mexicano 
constituíram uma classe dentro da comunidade em que a 
experimentação original foi prendida, e que a exclusão de 
americanos mexicanos dos júris resultou em uma negação da garantia 
igual da proteção da 1â emenda para réus americanos mexicanos. 
Na seguinte entrevista, Pete Tijerina, um membro de LULAC e o 
primeiro diretor executivo da defesa legal americana mexicana e o 
fundo educacional (MALDEF), júris todo-all-Anglo discutidos e outras 
condições discriminatory na sociedade de Texas nos 1950s e nos 
1960s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con il annexation del Texas in 1848 alla 
conclusione della guerra di messicano-american, del Tejanos -- il 
Texans della discesa messicana -- diritti di proprietà persi e 
potenza politica in una società dominata da Anglos. Attraverso 
le pratiche discriminatorie e la forza violenta, Tejanos è stato 
mantenuto alla parte inferiore di nuovo ordine politico e 
socio-culturale. Da 1900-1930, mentre un afflusso degli 
immigranti dal Messico è venuto a nord venire a contatto di una 
domanda crescente del lavoro poco costoso nelle industrie 
commerciali di sviluppo di agricoltura, Tejanos ha avvertito la 
distinzione continuata nell'occupazione, in alloggiamento, nelle 
attrezzature pubbliche, nel sistema giudiziario e negli istituti 
scolastici. In più, molti disenfranchised, dovuto i requisiti 
di imposta di scrutinio e le cose principali tutto-bianche e sono 
stati esclusi dal dovere jury. La lotta degli Americani 
messicani per concludere tali pratiche discriminatorie ha accelerato
la seguente seconda guerra mondiale. Nell'inizio degli anni 
cinquanta, gli avvocati per due gruppi di diritti civili di 
messicano-american, la lega dei cittadini dell'America latina uniti 
(LULAC) ed il G.I. Forum americano, discussa prima della Corte suprema
degli STATI UNITI in Hern_ndez v. il Texas che l'esclusione dal dovere
jury ha basato su codice categoria hanno costituito la distinzione. 
Il dichiarare del Texas ha riconosciuto quello durante i 25 
anni che precedenti nessuno con un cognome spagnolo aveva servito su 
tutte le giurie. La corte di Warren ha regolato all'unanimità 
che le persone dell'ascendenza americana messicana hanno costituito 
un codice categoria all'interno della Comunità in cui la prova 
originale è stata tenuta e che l'esclusione degli Americani 
messicani dalle giurie ha provocato una smentita della garanzia 
uguale di protezione della quattordicesima correzione per i difensori 
americani messicani. Nella seguente intervista, Pete Tijerina,
un membro di LULAC ed il primo direttore esecutivo della difesa legale
americana messicana ed il fondo monetario educativo (MALDEF), giurie
tutto-all-Anglo discusse ed altri termini discriminatori nella 
società del Texas negli anni 50 e negli anni 60.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με την προσάρτηση του Τέξας το 1848 στο τέλος του 
Μεξικανοαμερικάνύ πολέμου, Tejanos -- Texans της μεξικάνικης
καταγωγής -- έχασαν τα δικαιώματα ιδιοκτησιών και την πολιτική 
δύναμη σε μια κοινωνία που εξουσιάστηκε από Anglos. Μέσω
των μεροληπτικών πρακτικών και της βίαιας δύναμης, Tejanos 
κρατήθηκε στο κατώτατο σημείο της νέας πολιτικής και 
κοινωνικοπολιτιστικής κατάταξης. Από το 1900-1930, καθώς 
μια εισροή των μεταναστών από το Μεξικό ήρθε βόρεια να 
ικανοποιήσει μια αυξανόμενη ζήτηση για τη φτηνή εργασία στις 
αναπτυσσόμενες εμπορικές βιομηχανίες γεωργίας, Tejanos 
δοκίμασε τη συνεχή διάκριση στην απασχόληση, την κατοικία, τις 
δημόσιες εγκαταστάσεις, το δικαστικό σύστημα, και τα εκπαιδευτικά
όργανα. Επιπλέον, πολλοί ήταν, λόγω στις 
απαιτήσεις κεφαλικού φόρου και τα όλος-άσπρα κωπαία πτερά, και 
απέκλεισαν από το καθήκον κριτικών επιτροπών. Η προσπάθεια
μεξικάνικων Αμερικανών να τελειώσουν τέτοιες μεροληπτικές 
πρακτικές επιτάχυνε μετά από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ. Στις
αρχές της δεκαετίας του '50, οι πληρεξούσιοι για δύο 
Μεξικανοαμερικάές ομάδες αστικών δικαιωμάτων, η ένωση των 
ενωμένων λατινοαμερικανικών πολιτών (LULAC) και το αμερικανικό 
G.I. φόρουμ, υποστήριξαν ενώπιον του ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΎ ανώτατου 
δικαστηρίου σε Hern_ndez V. το Τέξας ότι ο αποκλεισμός από 
το καθήκον κριτικών επιτροπών βασισμένο στην κλάση αποτέλεσε τη 
διάκριση. Η κατάσταση του Τέξας αναγνώρισε ότι στα 
προηγούμενα 25 έτη κανένα πρόσωπο με ένα ισπανικό επώνυμο 
δεν είχε εξυπηρετήσει σε οποιεσδήποτε κριτικές επιτροπές. 
Το δικαστήριο κυκεώνων διέταξε ομόφωνα ότι τα πρόσωπα της 
μεξικάνικης αμερικανικής καταγωγής αποτέλεσαν μια κλάση εντός 
της κοινότητας στην οποία η αρχική δίκη πραγματοποιήθηκε, και 
ότι ο αποκλεισμός μεξικάνικων Αμερικανών από τις κριτικές 
επιτροπές οδήγησε σε μια άρνηση της ίσης εγγύησης προστασίας της
14$ης τροποποίησης για τους μεξικάνικους αμερικανικούς 
κατηγορουμένους. Στην ακόλουθη συνέντευξη, pete 
Tijerina, ένα μέλος LULAC και ο πρώτος εκτελεστικός 
σκηνοθέτης της μεξικάνικης αμερικανικής νομικής υπεράσπισης και 
του εκπαιδευτικού Ταμείου (MALDEF), συζήτησαν τις κριτικές 
επιτροπές όλος- anglo και άλλους μεροληπτικούς όρους στην 
κοινωνία του Τέξας στη δεκαετία του '50 και τη δεκαετία του '60.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con la anexión de Tejas en 1848 en el final de la
guerra, del Tejanos -- el Texans Mexicano-Americanos de la pendiente 
mexicana -- las derechas de característica perdidas y potencia 
política en una sociedad dominada por Anglos. A través de 
prácticas discriminatorias y de fuerza violenta, Tejanos fue guardado
en el fondo de la nueva orden política y socio-cultural. A 
partir de 1900-1930, como una afluencia de inmigrantes de México vino
al norte resolver una demanda creciente para el trabajo barato en las 
industrias comerciales de la agricultura que se convertían, Tejanos 
experimentó la discriminación continuada en el empleo, la cubierta, 
los recursos públicos, el sistema judicial, e instituciones 
educativas. Además, muchos disenfranchised,  debido a los 
requisitos del impuesto de encuesta y a las primarias todo-blancas, y 
fueron excluidos de deber del jurado. La lucha de los americanos
mexicanos para terminar tales prácticas discriminatorias aceleró la 
Segunda Guerra Mundial siguiente. En los comienzos de los años 
50, los abogados para dos grupos Mexicano-Americanos de las derechas 
civiles, la liga de los ciudadanos americanos latinos unidos (LULAC) y
el G.I. americano Forum, discutido antes del Tribunal Supremo de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS en Hern_ndez v. Tejas que la exclusión del deber del 
jurado basó en clase constituyeron la discriminación. El 
estado de Tejas reconoció eso en los 25 años anteriores que ninguna 
persona con un apellido español había desempen'ado servicios en 
cualquier jurado. La corte de Warren gobernó unánimemente que 
las personas de la ascendencia americana mexicana constituyeron una 
clase dentro de la comunidad en quien el ensayo original fue llevado a
cabo, y que la exclusión de americanos mexicanos de los jurados dio 
lugar a una negación de la garantía igual de la protección de la 
14ta enmienda para los demandados americanos mexicanos. En la 
entrevista siguiente, Pete Tijerina, un miembro de LULAC y el primer 
director ejecutivo de la defensa legal americana mexicana y el fondo 
educativo (MALDEF), jurados todo-all-Anglo discutidos y otras 
condiciones discriminatorias en la sociedad de Tejas en los años 50 y
los años 60.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086372</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108180</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/judged-by-your-peers-fighting-discrimination-in-texas-court-rooms</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
