<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107960</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107960</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086894</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Baby Was Made 'Delegate No. 800'": Frances Willard Meets Elizabeth Rodgers in the 1880s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Das Baby Wurde ' Delegierten Nr. 800 '" Gebildet:
Frances Willard trifft Elizabeth Rodgers im 1880s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Le Bébé A été fait Au 'Numéro 800 De 
Délégué '" : Frances Willard rencontre Elizabeth Rodgers 
dans le 1880s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O Bebê Foi feito ' Ao Delegado No. 800 '": 
Frances Willard encontra-se com Elizabeth Rodgers no 1880s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Bambino È stato reso 'A Delegato Il No. 800 
'": Frances Willard viene a contatto di Elizabeth Rodgers nel 
1880s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το μωρό έγινε" τον εκπρόσωπο αριθ. 800 "": 
Θ*Φρανθες Willard Meets Elizabeth Rodgers στο 
1880s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Hicieron El Bebé El ' Delegado No. 800 '": 
Frances Willard resuelve Elizabeth Rodgers en el 1880s</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The commitment of the Knights of Labor to equality for women was more than rhetorical, as seen in the career of Elizabeth Rodgers, the Master Workman, or head, of the organization's giant Chicago District No. 24. This 1889 portrait of Rodgers, offered by leading national anti-liquor activist Frances Willard, underscored the desire on the part of many Knights, both men and women, to connect the struggle for labor reform with a broader vision that included vehement opposition to liquor. It also showed the complex ways in which the Knights managed to simultaneously advocate equal rights for women at the same time they upheld the Victorian ideal of domesticity for women. Thus, although Rodgers presided over a Local Assembly with 50,000 male and female members, she was still listed as a "housewife" when she attended the 1886 Richmond convention.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Verpflichtung der Ritter der Arbeit zur 
Gleichheit für Frauen war mehr als rhetorisch, wie in die Karriere 
von Elizabeth Rodgers, der Vorlagenarbeiter oder Kopf gesehen, des 
riesigen Bezirkes Nr. 24 Chicago der Organisation. Dieses 
Portrait 1889 von Rodgers, angeboten, indem es nationalen Anti-Alkohol
Aktivisten Frances Willard führte, unterstrich den Wunsch von seiten 
vieler Ritter, Männer und Frauen, den Kampf für Arbeitsverbesserung 
mit einem ausgedehnteren Anblick anzuschließen, der vehemente 
Opposition zum Alkohol einschloß. Es stellte auch dar, daß die
komplizierten Methoden, in denen die Ritter handhatten, gleiche Rechte
für Frauen gleichzeitig gleichzeitig zu befürworten, sie das 
viktorianisch ideale von Domesticity für Frauen unterstützten. So
obgleich Rodgers einer lokalen Versammlung mit 50.000 männlich und 
weiblichen Bauteilen vorsaß, wurde sie noch als "Hausfrau" 
ausgedruckt, als sie die Richmond Versammlung 1886 bediente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'engagement des chevaliers du travail à 
l'égalité pour des femmes était davantage que rhétorique, comme vu
dans la carrière d'Elizabeth Rodgers, l'ouvrier principal, ou chef,
du numéro géant 24 de zone de Chicago de l'organisation. Cette
verticale 1889 de Rodgers, offerte en menant l'activiste national 
Frances Willard d'anti-boisson alcoolisée, a souligné le désir de 
la part de beaucoup de chevaliers, des hommes et des femmes, de relier
la lutte pour la réforme de travail à une plus large vision qui a 
inclus l'opposition véhémente à la boisson alcoolisée. Elle 
a également montré que les voies complexes dont les chevaliers sont 
parvenus à préconiser simultanément l'égalité des droits pour des
femmes en même temps elles ont confirmé l'idéal victorien de la 
domesticité pour des femmes. Ainsi, bien que Rodgers ait 
présidé au-dessus d'une Assemblée locale avec 50.000 mâles et des 
membres féminins, elle était encore énumérée en tant que "femme 
au foyer" quand elle a servi la convention 1886 de Richmond.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O compromisso dos knights do trabalho à igualdade
para mulheres era mais do que rhetorical, como visto na carreira de 
Elizabeth Rodgers, trabalhador mestre, ou cabeça, do distrito gigante
no. 24 de Chicago da organização. Este retrato 1889 de 
Rodgers, oferecido conduzindo à activista nacional Frances Willard do
anti-licor, underscored o desejo na parte de muitos knights,  homens e
mulheres, conectar o esforço para a reforma labor com uma visão mais
larga que incluísse a oposição vehement ao licor. Mostrou 
também que as maneiras complexas em que os knights controlaram 
advogar simultaneamente ao mesmo tempo direitas iguais para mulheres 
elas upheld o Victorian ideal da domesticidade para mulheres. 
Assim, embora Rodgers presided sobre um conjunto local com os 
50.000 masculinos e membros fêmeas, foi alistada ainda como um 
"housewife" quando atendeu à convenção 1886 de Richmond.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'impegno dei cavalieri del Lavoro ad 
uguaglianza per le donne era più di retorico, come visto nella 
carriera di Elizabeth Rodgers, l'operaio matrice, o testa, del 
distretto gigante il no. 24 del Chicago dell'organizzazione. 
Questo ritratto 1889 di Rodgers, offerto conducendo 
l'attivista nazionale Frances Willard del anti-liquore, ha 
sottolineato il desiderio da parte di molti cavalieri, sia uomini che 
donne, collegare la lotta per la riforma di lavoro con una più vasta
visione che ha incluso l'opposizione veemente a liquore. 
Egualmente ha mostrato che i modi complessi in cui i cavalieri 
sono riuscito a sostenere simultaneamente i diritti uguali per le 
donne allo stesso tempo hanno sostenuto il Victorian ideale di 
domesticity per le donne. Quindi, anche se Rodgers ha presieduto
un'Assemblea locale con 50.000 maschii ed i membri femminili, ancora 
è stata elencata come "casalinga" quando ha assistito alla 
convenzione 1886 de Richmond.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η υποχρέωση των ιπποτών της εργασίας στην ισότητα για 
τις γυναίκες ήταν περισσότερο από ρητορική, όπως βλέπει
στη σταδιοδρομία Elizabeth Rodgers, ο κύριος εργάτης, ή το 
κεφάλι, της γιγαντιαίας περιοχής αριθ. 24 του Σικάγου της 
οργάνωσης. Αυτό το πορτρέτο 1889 Rodgers, που 
προσφέρθηκε από το κορυφαίο εθνικό ενεργό στέλεχος Frances 
Willard αντι-ποτού, υπογράμμισε την επιθυμία στο μέρος πολλών 
ιπποτών, και άνδρες και γυναίκες, για να συνδέσει την προσπάθεια 
για τη μεταρρύθμιση εργασίας με μια ευρύτερη οπτική που περιέλαβε
την vehement αντίθεση στο ποτό. Εμφάνισε επίσης ότι οι 
σύνθετοι τρόποι με τους οποίους οι ιππότες κατόρθωσαν να 
υποστηρίξουν ταυτόχρονα τα ίσα δικαιώματα για τις γυναίκες 
συγχρόνως αυτοί υποστήριξαν το βικτοριανό ιδανικό της 
νοικοκυροσύνης για τις γυναίκες. Κατά συνέπεια, αν και 
Rodgers προήδρευσε πέρα από μια τοπική συμβολική γλώσσα με 
50.000 άνδρες και γυναίκες μέλη, εμφανίστηκε λίστα ακόμα ως 
"νοικοκυρά" όταν παρευρέθηκε στη σύμβαση 1886 Ρίτσμοντ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La consolidación de los caballeros del trabajo a 
la igualdad para las mujeres era más que retórica, según lo 
considerado en la carrera de Elizabeth Rodgers, el trabajador 
principal, o pista, del districto gigante No. 24 de Chicago de la 
organización. Este retrato 1889 de Rodgers, ofrecido 
conduciendo a activista nacional Frances Willard del contra-licor, 
subrayó el deseo de parte de muchos caballeros, los hombres y las 
mujeres, de conectar la lucha para la reforma de trabajo con una 
visión más amplia que incluyó la oposición vehemente al licor. 
También mostró las maneras complejas de las cuales los 
caballeros manejaron abogar simultáneamente las derechas iguales para
las mujeres en el mismo tiempo que mantuvieron el Victorian ideal de 
la domesticidad para las mujeres. Así, aunque Rodgers presidió
una asamblea local con 50.000 masculinos y miembros femeninos, la 
todavía enumeraron como "ama de casa" cuando ella atendió a la 
convención 1886 de Richmond.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086894</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107960</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-baby-was-made-delegate-no-800-frances-willard-meets-elizabeth-rodgers-in-the-1880s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
