<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105868</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105868</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086339</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Iroquois Creation Myth, 1816</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Irokese-Kreation Mythus, 1816</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mythe de Création de Iroquois, 1816</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mito Da Criação Do Iroquois, 1816</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mito Della Creazione Del Iroquois, 1816</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Iroquois μύθος δημιουργιών, 1816</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mito De la Creación Del Iroquois, 1816</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many Indian peoples had and still have stories of creation that explain how they came to be and to live in their homelands. These narratives offer a glimpse into the belief systems present before Europeans entered North America. Many northeastern Indian peoples share a legend of how the world was created on the back of a giant sea turtle (some still refer to North America as a "turtle island"). While there are many versions of the tradition, the following selection is from the Iroquois Indians of New York State. Anthropologists collected and transcribed most versions of the Iroquois creation myth in the late-nineteenth and early-twentieth centuries. However, John Norton, son of Scottish and Cherokee parents and adopted by the Mohawks, recorded this version, one of the earliest, in 1816. Norton traveled widely in the eastern woodlands, playing an important role in the life of the Mohawks in the early-nineteenth century.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele indische Völker hatten und haben noch 
Geschichten der Kreation, die erklären, wie sie, in ihren Heimaten zu
sein kamen und zu leben. Diese Darstellungen bieten einen Blick 
in die Glaubenssysteme an, die vor Europäer betretenem Nordamerika 
vorhanden sind. Viele nordöstliche indische Völker teilen eine
Legende von, wie die Welt auf der Rückseite einer riesigen 
Seeschildkröte hergestellt wurde (einige sprechen noch Nordamerika 
als "Schildkröteinsel" an). Während es viele Versionen der 
Tradition gibt, ist die folgende Auswahl von den Irokese-Indern des 
Staates New-York. Die gesammelten Anthropologen und übertrugen 
die meisten Versionen des Irokesekreation Mythus in den spät-19. und 
früh-zwanzigsten Jahrhunderten. Jedoch speicherte John Norton, 
der Sohn der schottischen und Cherokee Eltern und bei den Mohikanern 
angenommen, diese Version, eine von den frühesten, 1816. Norton
reiste weit in das östliche Waldland und spielte eine wichtige Rolle 
im Leben der Mohikaner im früh-19.jahrhundert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Beaucoup de peuples indiens ont eu et ont toujours
les histoires de la création qui expliquent comment elles sont venues
pour être et vivre dans leurs patries. Ces récits offrent un 
aperçu dans les systèmes de croyance actuels avant l'Amérique 
du nord entrée par Européens. Beaucoup de peuples indiens
du nord-est partagent une légende de la façon dont le monde a été 
créé sur le dos d'une tortue géante de mer (certains mentionnent 
toujours l'Amérique du nord comme "île de tortue"). 
Tandis qu'il y a beaucoup de versions de la tradition, la 
sélection suivante est des Indiens de Iroquois de l'état de 
New-York. Les anthropologues rassemblés et ont transcrit la 
plupart des versions du mythe de création de Iroquois aux 
tard-dix-neuvième et tôt-vingtième siècles. Cependant, John 
Norton, fils des parents écossais et cherokee et adopté par les 
Mohawk, a enregistré cette version, une des plus tôt, en 1816. 
Norton a voyagé largement dans les régfions boisées 
orientales, jouant un rôle important dans la vie des Mohawk au 
tôt-dix-neuvième siècle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muitos povos indian tiveram e têm ainda as 
histórias da criação que explicam como vieram estar e viver em seus
homelands. Estas narrativas oferecem um glimpse nos sistemas da 
opinião atuais antes de America do Norte entrada Europeus. 
Muitos povos indian do nordeste compartilham de uma legenda de 
como o mundo foi criado na parte traseira de uma tartaruga gigante do 
mar (alguns consultam ainda a America do Norte como da "um console 
tartaruga"). Quando houver muitas versões da tradição, a 
seguinte seleção é dos indians do iroquois do estado de New York. 
Os antropólogos coletados e transcreveram a maioria de versões
do mito da criação do iroquois nos tarde-décimos nonos e 
cedo-vigésimos séculos. Entretanto, John Norton, filho de pais
scottish e cherokee e adotado pelos mohawks, gravou esta versão, um 
do mais adiantada, em 1816. Norton viajou extensamente nas 
florestas orientais, jogando um papel importante na vida dos mohawks 
no cedo-décimo nono século.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molta gente indiana ha avuta ed ancora ha storia 
della creazione che spiegano come sono venuto essere e vivere nelle 
loro patrie. Queste descrizioni offrono un glimpse nei 
sistemi di credenza presenti prima dell'America del Nord inserita 
Europei. Molta gente indiana di nordest ripartisce una leggenda 
di come il mondo è stato creato sulla parte posteriore di una 
tartaruga gigante del mare (alcuni ancora si riferiscono all'America 
del Nord come "isola della tartaruga"). Mentre ci sono molte 
versioni della tradizione, la seguente selezione proviene dal iroquois
che gli indiani di New York Dichiarano. Gli antropologi 
hanno raccolto e trascritto la maggior parte delle versioni del mito 
della creazione del iroquois nei in ritardo-diciannovesimi e 
presto-ventesimi secoli. Tuttavia, John Norton, figlio dei 
genitori scozzesi e cherokee ed adottato dai mohawks, ha registrato 
questa versione, una dei più in anticipo, in 1816. Norton ha 
viaggiato ampiamente nei terreni boscosi orientali, svolgenti un ruolo
importante nella vita dei mohawks nel presto-diciannovesimo secolo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλοί ινδικοί λαοί είχαν και έχουν ακόμα τις 
ιστορίες της δημιουργίας που εξηγούν πώς ήρθαν να είναι και να 
ζήσουν στις πατρίδες τους. Αυτά τα αφηγήματα προσφέρουν μια
αναλαμπή στα συστήματα πεποίθησης παρόντα προτού να πάνε οι 
Ευρωπαίοι στη Βόρεια Αμερική. Πολλοί βορειοανατολικοί 
ινδικοί λαοί μοιράζονται έναν μύθο για το πώς ο κόσμος 
δημιουργήθηκε στην πλάτη μιας γιγαντιαίας χελώνας θάλασσας 
(μερικοί αναφέρονται ακόμα στη Βόρεια Αμερική ως "νησί 
χελωνών"). Ενώ υπάρχουν πολλές εκδόσεις της παράδοσης, η 
ακόλουθη επιλογή είναι από iroquois Ινδοί του κράτους της 
Νέας Υόρκης. Οι ανθρωπολόγοι συνέλεξαν και μετέγραψαν τις 
περισσότερες εκδόσεις του iroquois μύθου δημιουργιών στους 
πρόσφατος-δέκατους έννατους και πρόωρος-εικοστούς αιώνες. 
Εντούτοις, John Norton, γιος των σκωτσέζικων και 
τσερόκι γονέων και υιοθετημένος από το Mohawks, κατέγραψε 
αυτήν την έκδοση, ένας από τον πιό πρόωρο, σε 1816, Norton
που ταξίδεψαν ευρέως στις ανατολικές δασώδεις περιοχές, 
διαδραματίζοντας έναν σημαντικό ρόλο στη ζωή του Mohawks στον 
πρόωρος-δέκατο έννατο αιώνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mucha gente india tenía y todavía tiene 
historias de la creación que explican cómo vinieron estar y vivir en
sus patrias. Estas narrativas ofrecen una ojeada en los sistemas
de la creencia presentes antes de Norteamérica entrada europeos. 
Mucha gente india del noreste comparte una leyenda de cómo el 
mundo fue creado en la parte posteriora de una tortuga gigante del mar
(algo todavía refiere a Norteamérica como "isla de la tortuga"). 
Mientras que hay muchas versiones de la tradición, la 
selección siguiente es de los indios del iroquois del estado de Nueva
York. Los antropólogos recogidos y transcribieron la mayoría 
de las versiones del mito de la creación del iroquois en los 
tarde-diecinueveavo y temprano-vige'simos siglos. Sin embargo, 
Juan Norton, hijo de padres escoceses y cherokee y adoptado por los 
mohawks, registró esta versión, una del más temprana, de 1816. 
Norton viajó extensamente en los arbolados del este, 
desempeñando un papel importante en la vida de los mohawks en el 
temprano-diecinueveavo siglo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086339</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105868</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/iroquois-creation-myth-1816</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
