<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107697</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107697</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206942</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Independence Day: Today in History</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unabhängigkeit-Tag: Heute in der 
Geschichte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jour d'Indépendance : Aujourd'hui dans 
l'histoire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dia De Independência: Hoje no history</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giorno Di Indipendenza: Oggi nella storia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ημέρα ανεξαρτησίας: Σήμερα στην ιστορία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Día De Independencia: Hoy en historia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site tells how we've celebrated July 4 since that day in 1776, when the Second Continental Congress unanimously adopted the Declaration of Independence. Independence Day celebrations became commonplace after the War of 1812, when events like the ground-breaking ceremony for the Erie Canal were scheduled to coincide with July 4 festivities. By the 1870s, the Fourth of July was the most important secular holiday on the calendar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site erklärt, wie wir Juli 4 seit dem 
gefeiert haben, der Tag 1776, als der zweite kontinentale Kongreß 
einmütig die Unabhängigkeitserklärung annahm. 
Unabhängigkeit-Tagesfeiern wurden nach dem Krieg von 1812 
alltäglich, als Fälle wie die Boden-brechende Zeremonie für den 
Erie Kanal eingeplant wurden, um mit Juli 4 Festlichkeiten 
übereinzustimmen. Durch das 1870s war das Viertel von Juli der 
wichtigste weltliche Feiertag auf dem Kalender.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site indique que nous avons célébré juillet 
4 depuis qui jour en 1776, quand le deuxième congrès continental a 
adopté à l'unanimité la déclaration de l'indépendance. Les 
célébrations de jour d'indépendance sont devenues banales après la
guerre de 1812, quand des événements comme la cérémonie 
d'inauguration pour le canal d'Erie ont été programmés pour 
coïncider avec des festivités juillet de 4. Par le 1870s, le 
quart de juillet était les vacances séculaires les plus importantes 
sur le calendrier.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local diz como nós temos comemorado julho 4 
desde que dia em 1776, quando o segundo congress continental adotou 
unânimemente a declaração de independência. Os celebrations 
do dia de independência tornaram-se commonplace após a guerra de 
1812, quando os eventos como o ceremony terra-quebrando para o canal 
de erie foram programados para coincidir com os festivities julho de 
4. Pelo 1870s, o fourth de julho era o feriado secular o mais 
importante no calendário.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo dice a come abbiamo celebrato da 
allora il 4 luglio che giorno in 1776, quando il secondo congresso 
continentale ha adottato all'unanimità la dichiarazione di 
indipendenza. Le celebrazioni di giorno di indipendenza sono 
diventato ordinarie dopo la guerra di 1812, quando gli eventi come la 
cerimonia approfondita per il canale di Erie sono stati previsti per 
coincidere con del 4 i festeggiamenti luglio. Dal 1870s, il 
Quarto di luglio era la festa secolare più importante sul 
calendario.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή λέει πώς έχουμε γιορτάσει τις 4 
Ιουλίου από εκείνη την ημέρα το 1776, όταν υιοθέτησε ομόφωνα
το δεύτερο ηπειρωτικό συνέδριο τη Διακήρυξη της ανεξαρτησίας. 
Οι εορτασμοί ημέρας ανεξαρτησίας έγιναν κοινοί μετά από 
τον πόλεμο 1812, όταν σχεδιάστηκαν τα γεγονότα όπως την 
έδαφος-σπάζοντας τελετή για το κανάλι του Erie για να 
συμπέσουν με τις 4 Ιουλίου εορτασμοί. Μέχρι 1870s, το 
τέταρτο του Ιουλίου ήταν οι σημαντικότερες κοσμικές διακοπές στο
ημερολόγιο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio dice cómo hemos celebrado de julio el 
4 desde entonces que día en 1776, cuando el segundo congreso 
continental adoptó unánimemente el declaración de la independencia.
Las celebraciones del día de independencia llegaron a ser 
corrientes después de la guerra de 1812, cuando los acontecimientos
como la ceremonia tierra-que se rompi'a para el canal de Erie 
programar para coincidir con las festividades de julio del 4. Por
el 1870s, el cuarto de julio era el día de fiesta secular más 
importante en el calendario.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206942</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107697</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/independence-day-today-in-history</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
