<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105515</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105515</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200416</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">An Activity to Introduce the Geoscience Perspective</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Aktivität, zum der Geoscience Perspektive 
vorzustellen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une activité pour présenter la perspective de 
Geoscience</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma atividade para introduzir o perspective de 
Geoscience</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un'attività per introdurre la prospettiva di 
Geoscience</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια δραστηριότητα για να εισαγάγει την προοπτική 
Geoscience</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una actividad para introducir la perspectiva de 
Geoscience</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This exercise is intended to connect students to geology and to remind them of the diverse ways in which people, including geoscientists, relate to rocks. Groups of students are asked to examine rock samples from specific perspectives such as sculptors, landowners or geologists, and then present relevant observations and questions. Next, individuals write one-minute papers summarizing what they have learned and evaluating the activity. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Übung soll Kursteilnehmer an Geologie 
anschließen und sie an die verschiedenen Methoden erinnern, in denen 
Leute, einschließlich geoscientists, auf Felsen in Verbindung stehen.
Gruppen Kursteilnehmer werden gebeten, Felsenproben von den 
spezifischen Perspektiven wie Sculptors, Grundbesitzer oder Geologen 
und dann anwesende relevante Beobachtungen und Fragen zu überprüfen.
Zunächst schreiben Einzelpersonen die Einminute 
Papierzusammenstellung, was sie erlernt haben und die Aktivität 
auswertend. Auf dieser Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer auf 
Informationen über die erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für 
Gebrauch-, die Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, 
Lehrmittel, Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet exercice est destiné pour relier des 
étudiants à la géologie et pour les rappeler les voies diverses 
desquelles les gens, y compris des geoscientists, rapportent aux 
roches. Des groupes d'étudiants sont invités à examiner des 
échantillons de roche provenant des perspectives spécifiques telles 
que des sculpteurs, des propriétaires fonciers ou des géologues, et 
puis des observations et des questions appropriées. Ensuite, 
les individus écrivent la récapitulation de papiers d'un-minute ce 
qu'ils ont appris et évaluant l'activité. À cette page de 
point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux informations 
sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les extrémités 
d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel didactique, 
les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este exercício é pretendido conectar estudantes 
à geologia e lembrá-los das maneiras diversas em que os povos, 
including geoscientists, se relacionam às rochas. Os grupos dos
estudantes são pedidos para examinar amostras da rocha dos 
perspectives específicos tais como sculptors, latifundiários ou 
geólogos, e então as observações e as perguntas relevantes atuais.
Em seguida, os indivíduos escrevem sumariar dos papéis de 
um-minuto o que aprenderam e avaliando a atividade. Nesta 
página do ponto começar, os usuários podem alcançar a informação
sobre os objetivos de aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as 
pontas do uso, ensinar as notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias 
da avaliação, as referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa esercitazione è intesa per collegare gli 
allievi alla geologia e per ricordare loro dei modi vari in cui la 
gente, compreso i geoscientists, riferisce alle roccie. I gruppi
degli allievi sono chiesti di esaminare i campioni della roccia dalle 
prospettive specifiche quali gli scultori, latifondisti o geologi ed 
allora osservazioni e domande relative attuali. Dopo, gli 
individui scrivono la ricapitolazione delle carte da un-minuto che 
cosa hanno imparato e valutando l'attività. A questa pagina del
punto di partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle informazioni sugli
obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto per le punte di 
istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le idee di 
valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η άσκηση προορίζεται να συνδέσει τους σπουδαστές
με τη γεωλογία και να υπενθυμίσει σε τους τους διαφορετικούς 
τρόπους με τους οποίους οι άνθρωποι, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των 
geoscientists, αφορούν τους βράχους. Οι ομάδες σπουδαστών
καλούνται να εξετάσουν τα δείγματα βράχου από τις συγκεκριμένες 
προοπτικές όπως οι γλύπτες, τα landowners ή οι γεωλόγοι, και 
έπειτα οι παρούσες σχετικές παρατηρήσεις και οι ερωτήσεις. 
Έπειτα, τα άτομα γράφουν τα ένας-μικρά έγγραφα που 
συνοψίζουν τι έχουν μάθει και αξιολογώντας τη δραστηριότητα. 
Σε αυτήν την σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν
πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης,
πλαίσιο για τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, 
τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este ejercicio se piensa para conectar a 
estudiantes con la geología y para recordarlos las maneras diversas 
de las cuales la gente, incluyendo geoscientists, se relaciona con las
rocas. Piden los grupos de estudiantes examinar muestras de la 
roca de perspectivas específicas tales como escultores, los 
terratenientes o los geólogos, y entonces las actuales observaciones 
y preguntas relevantes. Después, los individuos escriben 
resumir de los papeles del uno-minuto qué han aprendido y evaluando 
la actividad. En esta paginación del punto de partida, los 
utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la información sobre las metas que
aprenden del ejercicio, contexto para las extremidades del uso, de la 
enseñanza las notas y, los materiales didácticos, las ideas del 
gravamen, las referencias y los asuntos cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KAREN HAVHOLM
FN:KAREN HAVHOLM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200416</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105515</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/an-activity-to-introduce-the-geoscience-perspective</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
