<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107743</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107743</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205891</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Weir Farm: Home of an American Impressionist</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wehr-Bauernhof: Haus eines amerikanischen 
Impressionisten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ferme de Déversoir : Maison d'un 
impressionniste américain</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fazenda Do Weir: HOME de um impressionist 
americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Podere Della Diga: Sede di un impressionist 
americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Weir αγρόκτημα: "Οικία" ενός αμερικανικού 
ιμπρεσσιονιστή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Granja Del Vertedero: Hogar de un 
impresionista americano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines the farm acquired by painter Alden Weir (1852-1919), where he summered for nearly 40 years (northeast of New City). At a time railroads were expanding, populations were increasing, and America's agrarian system was being replaced by industry, Weir was an artist who found inspiration in the quiet everyday settings of New England, and, in many ways, defined our vision of the American landscape.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft den Bauernhof, der durch Maler Alden 
Wehr (1852-1919) erworben wird, wo er für fast 40 Jahre summered 
(Nordosten der neuen Stadt). Hintereinander erweiterten 
Eisenbahnen, erhöhten sich Bevölkerungen, und Amerikas 
landwirtschaftliches System wurde durch Industrie ersetzt, war Wehr 
ein Künstler, der Inspiration in den ruhigen täglichen Einstellungen
von Neu-England und, in vielen Methoden fand, definierte unseren 
Anblick der amerikanischen Landschaft.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine la ferme saisie par le déversoir d'Alden 
de peintre (1852-1919), où il summered pendant presque 40 années 
(nord-est de nouvelle ville). À la fois les chemins de fer 
augmentaient, les populations augmentaient, et le système agraire de 
l'Amérique était remplacé par industrie, le déversoir était un 
artiste qui a trouvé l'inspiration dans les configurations 
journalières tranquilles de la Nouvelle Angleterre, et, de beaucoup
de voies, a défini notre vision de l'horizontal américain.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina a fazenda adquirida pelo weir de Alden do 
pintor (1852-1919), onde summered por quase 40 anos (nordeste da 
cidade nova). Em um momento as estradas de ferro estavam 
expandindo, as populações estavam aumentando, e o sistema agrarian 
de América era substituído pela indústria, o weir era um artista 
que encontrasse a inspiração nos ajustes diários quietos de Nova 
Inglaterra, e, em muitas maneiras, definiu nossa visão da paisagem 
americana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina il podere acquistato dalla diga dell'Alden
del pittore (1852-1919), dove summered per quasi 40 anni (nordest di 
nuova città). Alla volta le ferrovie stavano espandendosi, le 
popolazioni stavano aumentando ed il sistema agrario dell'America 
stava sostituendo da industria, la diga era un artista che ha trovato 
l'ispirazione nelle regolazioni giornalieri calme della Nuova 
Inghilterra e, in molti modi, ha definito la nostra visione del 
paesaggio americano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει το αγρόκτημα που αποκτιέται από alden 
ζωγράφων weir (1852-1919), όπου για σχεδόν 40 έτη 
(βορειοανατολικά της νέας πόλης). Σε μια εποχή οι 
σιδηρόδρομοι επεκτείνονταν, οι πληθυσμοί αυξάνονταν, και το 
αγροτικό σύστημα της Αμερικής αντικαθίστατο από τη βιομηχανία, 
weir ήταν καλλιτέχνης που βρήκε την έμπνευση στις ήρεμες 
καθημερινές τιμές των παραμέτρων της Νέας Αγγλίας, και, από 
πολλές απόψεις, καθόρισε το όραμά μας του αμερικανικού τοπίου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina la granja adquirida por el vertedero de 
Alden del pintor (1852-1919), donde él summered por casi 40 años 
(noreste de la ciudad nueva). Al mismo tiempo los ferrocarriles 
se ampliaban, las poblaciones aumentaban, y el sistema agrario de 
América era substituido por la industria, el vertedero era un artista
que encontró la inspiración en las configuraciones diarias 
reservadas de Nueva Inglaterra, y, de muchas maneras, definió nuestra
visión del paisaje americano.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205891</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107743</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/weir-farm-home-of-an-american-impressionist</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
