<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108398</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108398</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085255</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Japanese American Internment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Japanische Amerikanische Internierung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Internement Américain Japonais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Internamento Americano Japonês</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Internamento Americano Giapponese</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιαπωνικός αμερικανικός περιορισμός</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Internación Americana Japonesa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">After the bombing of Pearl Harbor, President Franklin D. Roosevelt signed Executive Order 9066, which established 10 internment camps for "national security" purposes. Although most internment camps were along the West Coast, others could be found in Wyoming and Colorado, and as far east as Arkansas. One photo shows Japanese American boys in San Francisco shortly before the evacuation order; another shows a woman waiting for the evacuation bus in Hayward; approximately 660 people being evacuated by bus from San Francisco on the first day of the program; and an aerial image of people sitting on their belongings, waiting to be taken to Manzanar. The government-sponsored War Relocation Authority (WRA) hired Dorothea Lange and other photographers to take pictures of the relocation and internment of Japanese Americans. Lange?s photographs, some of which were suppressed by the WRA and only released later, often capture the irony inherent in the situation. Although internees were allowed to take only what they could carry with them to the camps, one Lange photo juxtaposes a bus poster "Such a load off my mind ? Bekins stored my things" next to a pile of internees' belongings. Another striking Lange image shows a Japanese American-owned corner store with a large "I am an American" banner hanging beneath a "Sold" sign. Another photograph of an engine's distributor, removed from a car owned by an internee, showed that people were truly prisoners at the camp, unable to drive their own cars away. Several paintings by interned Japanese American artists Henry Sugimoto and Hisako Hibi reflect their emotional experiences and give viewers a sense of what life was like for them. The paintings express the pain, suffering, and anger of those subjected to internment. Over 100,000 Japanese American men, women, and children were relocated and detained at these camps. Photographs here show people of all ages, including a grandfather and grandchild, and young children. This internment is now recognized as a violation of their human and civil rights. In 1980, the US government officially apologized and reparations were paid to survivors.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nach der Bombardierung von Pearl Harbor, 
unterzeichnete Präsident Franklin D. Roosevelt Ausführungsverordnung
9066, die 10 Internierunglager "Staatssicherheit" zu den Zwecken 
herstellte. Obgleich die meisten Internierunglager entlang der 
Westküste waren, konnten andere in Wyoming und in Kolorado und als 
Ferner Osten als Arkansas gefunden werden. Ein Foto zeigt 
japanische amerikanische Jungen in San Francisco kurz vor der 
Evakuierungordnung; eine anderen Erscheinen eine Frau, die den 
Evakuierungbus in Hayward wartet; ungefähr 660 Leute, die durch
Bus von San Francisco am ersten Tag des Programms evakuiert werden; 
und ein Luftbild der Leute, die auf ihrem Eigentum, wartend, 
genommen zu werden Manzanar sitzen. Die staatlich geförderte 
Krieg-Verschiebung Berechtigung (WRA) stellte Dorothea Lange und 
andere Photographen an, um Photos der Verschiebung und der 
Internierung der japanischen Amerikaner zu machen. Lange?s 
Fotographien, von denen einige durch das WRA unterdrückt wurden und 
nur später freigegeben, erfassen häufig die Ironie, die in der 
Situation zugehörig ist. Obgleich Internees erlaubt wurden, nur
zu nehmen, was sie mit ihnen zu den Lagern tragen konnten, hält ein 
Lange Foto ein Busplakat "solch eine Eingabe weg von meinem Verstand 
gegeneinander? Bekins speicherte meine Sachen "nahe bei einem 
Stapel des Eigentums der Internees'. Ein anderes auffallendes 
Lange Bild stellt dar, daß ein japanischer Amerikanisch-besessener 
Eckspeicher mit einem großem "ich eine amerikanische" Fahne sind, die
unter einem "verkauften" Zeichen hängt. Eine andere Fotographie
des Verteilers einer Maschine, gelöscht von einem Auto, das von einem
Internee besessen wurde, zeigte, daß Leute wirklich Gefangene am 
Lager waren, nicht imstande, ihre eigenen Autos weg anzutreiben. 
Einige Anstriche durch internierten japanischen amerikanischen 
Künstler Henry Sugimoto und Hisako Hibi reflektieren ihre emotionalen
Erfahrungen und geben Projektoren eine Richtung, welcher Lebensdauer 
wie für sie war. Die Anstriche drücken die Schmerz, den 
Suffering und den Zorn von denen aus, die Internierung unterworfen 
werden. Über 100.000 japanischen amerikanischen Männern wurden
Frauen und Kinder an diesen Lagern verlagert und zurückgehalten. 
Fotographien hier zeigen Leute alles Alters, einschließlich 
einen Großvater und ein Enkelkind und junge Kinder. Diese 
Internierung wird jetzt als Verletzung ihrer menschlichen und 
Zivilrechte erkannt. 1980 US entschuldigte sich Regierungsbeamt 
und den Überlebenden Reparationen wurden gezahlt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après le bombardement du port de perle, le 
Président Franklin D. Roosevelt a signé la commande exécutive 9066,
qui a établi 10 camps d'internement pour la sécurité "nationale". 
Bien que la plupart des camps d'internement aient été le long 
de la côte occidentale, d'autres pourraient être trouvés au Wyoming
et le Colorado, et comme l'Extrême-Orient comme l'Arkansas. Une
photo montre aux garçons américains japonais dans San Francisco peu
avant la commande d'évacuation ; des autres expositions une 
femme attendant le bus d'évacuation dans Hayward ; 
approximativement 660 personnes évacué en le bus de San 
Francisco le premier jour du programme ; et une image aérienne
des personnes s'asseyant sur leurs affaires, attendant pour être pris
à Manzanar. L'autorité commanditée par le gouvernement de 
réadressage de guerre (WRA) a loué Dorothea Lange et d'autres 
photographes pour prendre des photos du réadressage et de 
l'internement des Américains japonais. Les photographies de 
Lange?s, dont certaines ont été supprimées par le WRA et plus tard 
seulement libérées, capturent souvent l'ironie inhérente à la 
situation. Bien que des internés aient été permis de prendre 
seulement ce qu'ils pourraient porter avec eux aux camps, une photo de
Lange juxtapose-t-elle une affiche de bus un "tel chargement outre de 
mon esprit ? Bekins a enregistré mes choses "à côté d'une 
pile des affaires des internés. Une autre image saisissante de 
Lange montre que une mémoire faisante le coin Américain-possédée 
japonaise avec un grand "je suis" un drapeau américain s'arrêtant 
sous un signe "vendu". Une autre photographie du distributeur 
d'un moteur, retirée d'une voiture possédée par un interné, a 
prouvé que les gens étaient vraiment des prisonniers au camp, 
incapable de conduire leurs propres voitures loin. Plusieurs 
peintures par Henry américain japonais interné Sugimoto et Hisako 
Hibi d'artistes reflètent leurs expériences émotives et donnent à 
des visualisateurs un sens de quelle vie était comme pour elles. 
Les peintures expriment la douleur, la douleur, et la colère de
ceux soumis à l'internement. Plus de 100.000 hommes américains
japonais, les femmes, et les enfants ont été replacés et détenus 
à ces camps. Les photographies ici montrent des personnes de 
tous les âges, y compris un grand-père et un petit-enfant, et des 
enfants en bas âge. Cet internement est maintenant identifié 
comme violation de leurs droits humains et civiques. En 1980, le
gouvernement des USA a officiellement fait des excuses et des 
réparations ont été payées aux survivants.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Após o bombardeio do porto de pérola, o 
presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt assinou a ordem executiva 9066, que 
estabeleceu 10 acampamentos do internamento para "finalidades da 
segurança nacional". Embora a maioria de acampamentos do 
internamento fossem ao longo da costa ocidental, outros poderiam ser 
encontrados em Wyoming e em Colorado, e como o leste distante como 
Arkansas. Uma foto mostra meninos americanos japoneses em San 
Francisco logo antes da ordem da evacuação; umas outras 
mostras uma mulher que espera a barra-ônibus da evacuação em 
Hayward; aproximadamente 660 povos que estão sendo evacuados 
pela barra-ônibus de San Francisco no primeiro dia do programa; 
e uma imagem aérea dos povos que sentam-se em seus pertences, 
esperando para ser feito exame a Manzanar. A autoridade 
government-sponsored do relocation da guerra (WRA) empregou Dorothea 
Lange e outros fotógrafos para fazer exame de retratos do relocation 
e do internamento de americanos japoneses. As fotografias de 
Lange?s, algumas de que foram suprimidas pelo WRA e liberadas somente 
mais tarde, capturam frequentemente o irony inerente na situação. 
Embora sejam permitidos aos internees fazer exame somente o que 
poderiam carregar com eles aos acampamentos, uma foto de Lange 
juxtaposes um poster da barra-ônibus "tal carga fora de minha mente? 
Bekins armazenou minhas coisas "ao lado de uma pilha de 
pertences dos internees'. Uma outra imagem impressionante de 
Lange mostra que uma loja de canto Americano-possuída japonesa com um
grande "mim é" uma bandeira americana que pendura abaixo de um sinal 
"vendido". Uma outra fotografia do distribuidor de um motor, 
removida de um carro possuído por um internee, mostrou que os povos 
eram verdadeiramente prisioneiros no acampamento, incapaz de dirigir 
afastado seus próprios carros. Diversas pinturas pelo Henry 
americano japonês internado Sugimoto e Hisako Hibi dos artistas 
refletem suas experiências emocionais e dão a visores um sentido de 
que vida era como para elas. As pinturas expressam a dor, o 
sofrimento, e a raiva daqueles sujeitados ao internamento. Sobre
100.000 homens americanos japoneses, as mulheres, e as crianças 
relocated e foram detidas nestes acampamentos. As fotografias 
aqui mostram povos de todas as idades, including um avô e um 
grandchild, e crianças novas. Este internamento é reconhecido 
agora como uma violação de suas direitas humanas e civis. Em 
1980, o governo dos E. U. desculpou-se oficialmente e os reparations 
foram pagados aos sobreviventes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dopo il bombardamento del porto di perla, il 
presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt ha firmato l'ordine esecutivo 9066, 
che ha stabilito 10 accampamenti di internamento per "gli scopi di 
sicurezza nazionale". Anche se la maggior parte dei accampamenti
di internamento erano lungo il litorale ad ovest, altri potrebbero 
essere trovati nel Wyoming e Colorado e come Estremo-Oriente come 
Arkansas. Una foto mostra a ragazzi americani giapponesi a San 
Francisco poco prima l'ordine dell'evacuamento; lle altre 
esposizioni una donna che aspetta il bus dell'evacuamento in Hayward; 
circa 660 genti che sono evacuate in bus da San Francisco il 
primo giorno del programma; e un'immagine aerea della gente che 
si siede sui loro effetti personali, attendente per essere preso a 
Manzanar. L'autorità government-sponsored di rilocazione di 
guerra (WRA) ha assunto Dorothea Lange ed altri photographers per 
prendere le immagini della rilocazione e dell'internamento degli 
Americani giapponesi. Le fotografie di Lange?s, alcuni di cui 
sono stati soppressi dal WRA e soltanto sono stati liberati più 
successivamente, bloccano spesso l'ironia inerente alla situazione. 
Anche se ai internees sono stati permessi prendere soltanto che 
cosa potrebbero trasportare con loro agli accampamenti, una foto di 
Lange juxtaposes un manifesto del bus "un tal carico fuori della mia 
mente? Bekins ha memorizzato le mie cose "vicino ad un mucchio 
degli effetti personali dei internees. Un'altra immagine 
notevole di Lange mostra che un deposito d'angolo Americano-posseduto 
giapponese con un grande "io sono" una bandiera americana che appende 
sotto un segno "venduto". Un'altra fotografia del distributore 
del motore, rimossa da un automobile posseduto da un internee, ha 
indicato che la gente era allineare prigionieri all'accampamento, 
incapace condurre i loro propri automobili via. Parecchie 
pitture dal henry americano giapponese internato Sugimoto e Hisako 
Hibi degli artisti riflettono le loro esperienze impressionabili e 
danno a visori un senso di che vita era come per loro. Le 
pitture esprimono il dolore, il suffering e la rabbia di quelli 
sottoposti all'internamento. Oltre 100.000 uomini americani 
giapponesi, le donne ed i bambini sono stati riassegnati e ritenuto 
stati a questi accampamenti. Le fotografie qui mostrano la gente
di tutte le età, compreso un nonno e un grandchild ed i bambini in 
giovane età. Questo internamento ora è riconosciuto come 
violazione dei loro diritti umani e civili. In 1980, il governo 
degli Stati Uniti ha chiesto scusa ufficialmente ed i reparations sono
stati pagati ai superstiti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από το βομβαρδισμό του λιμανιού μαργαριταριών, ο
Πρόεδρος Franklin D. Roosevelt υπέγραψε την εκτελεστική 
κατάταξη 9066, η οποία καθιέρωσε 10 στρατόπεδα περιορισμού για
λόγους "εθνικής ασφάλειασ". Αν και τα περισσότερα 
στρατόπεδα περιορισμού ήταν κατά μήκος της δυτικής ακτής, άλλα
θα μπορούσαν να βρεθούν στο Wyoming και το Κολοράντο, και ως 
Απω Ανατολή ως Αρκάνσας. Μια φωτογραφία εμφανίζει ιαπωνικά
αμερικανικά αγόρια στο Σαν Φρανσίσκο λίγο πριν που η εκκένωση 
διατάζει  άλλος εμφανίζει μια γυναίκα που περιμένει το 
διάδρομο εκκένωσης σε Hayward  περίπου 660 άνθρωποι 
που εκκενώνονται με το διάδρομο από το Σαν Φρανσίσκο την πρώτη 
ημέρα του προγράμματος  και μια εναέρια εικόνα των ανθρώπων
που κάθονται στις περιουσίες τους, που περιμένει να ληφθεί σε 
Manzanar. Η χρηματοδοτούμενη από την κυβέρνηση αρχή 
πολεμικής επαναμετάθεσης (WRA) μίσθωσε Dorothea Lange και 
άλλους φωτογράφους για να πάρει τις εικόνες της επαναμετάθεσης 
και του περιορισμού ιαπωνικών Αμερικανών. Οι φωτογραφίες 
Lange?s, μερικές από τις οποίες καταστάλθηκαν από το WRA 
και εκδόθηκαν μόνο αργότερα, συλλαμβάνουν συχνά την ειρωνεία 
έμφυτη στην κατάσταση. Αν και τα internees επιτράπηκαν για
να πάρουν μόνο τι μπόρεσαν να φέρουν με τους στα στρατόπεδα, μια 
φωτογραφία Lange αντιπαραβαεται μια αφίσα διαδρόμων "ένα 
τέτοιο φορτίο από το μυαλό μου; Το Bekins καταχώρησε τα 
πράγματά μου "δίπλα σε έναν σωρό των περιουσιών των 
internees. Μια άλλη εντυπωσιακή εικόνα Lange εμφανίζει
ότι ένα ιαπωνικό αμερικανικός-κύριο κατάστημα γωνιών με έναν 
μεγάλο "είμαι μια αμερικανική" ένωση εμβλημάτων κάτω από ένα 
"πωλημένο" σημάδι. Μια άλλη φωτογραφία του διανομέα μιας 
μηχανής, που αφαιρέθηκε από ένα αυτοκίνητο που ήταν κύριο από 
ένα internee, έδειξε ότι οι άνθρωποι ήταν αληθινά 
φυλακισμένοι στο στρατόπεδο, ανίκανο να οδηγήσει τα αυτοκίνητά 
τους μακριά. Διάφορα έργα ζωγραφικής από τους θεμένους 
υπό περιορισμό ιαπωνικούς αμερικανικούς καλλιτέχνες Henry 
Sugimoto και Hisako Hibi απεικονίζουν τη συναισθηματική 
εμπειρία τους και δίνουν στις εμφανίσεις μια αίσθηση ποιας ζωής 
ήταν όπως για τα. Τα έργα ζωγραφικής εκφράζουν τον πόνο, 
το βάσανο, και το θυμό εκείνοι που υποβάλλονται στον περιορισμό. 
Οι πάνω από 100.000 ιαπωνικοί αμερικανικοί άνδρες, 
γυναίκες, και παιδιά επανεντοπίστηκαν και τέθηκαν υπό κράτηση σε
αυτά τα στρατόπεδα. Οι φωτογραφίες εμφανίζουν εδώ τους 
ανθρώπους όλων των ηλικιών, συμπεριλαμβανομένου ενός παππού και 
ενός εγγονιού, και μικρά παιδιά. Αυτός ο περιορισμός 
αναγνωρίζεται τώρα ως παραβίαση των ανθρώπινων και αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων τους. Το 1980, η αμερικανική κυβέρνηση ζήτησε 
συγγνώμη επίσημα και οι επιδιορθώσεις πληρώθηκαν στους επιζόντες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después del bombardeo del puerto de perla, 
presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt firmó la orden ejecutiva 9066, que 
estableció 10 campos de la internación para los propósitos de la 
"seguridad nacional". Aunque la mayoría de los campos de la 
internación estaban a lo largo de la costa del oeste, otros se 
podrían encontrar en Wyoming y Colorado, y como este lejano como 
Arkansas. Una foto muestra a muchachos americanos japoneses en 
San Francisco poco antes la orden de la evacuación; otras 
demostraciones una mujer que espera el megabus de la evacuación en 
Hayward; aproximadamente 660 personas que son evacuadas por el 
megabus de San Francisco en el primer día del programa; y una 
imagen aérea de la gente que se sienta en sus pertenencia, esperando 
para ser llevado Manzanar. La autoridad government-sponsored de 
la realocación de la guerra (WRA) empleó Dorothea Lange y otros 
fotógrafos para tomar los cuadros de la realocación y de la 
internación de americanos japoneses. Las fotografías de 
Lange?s, algunas de las cuales fueron suprimidas por el WRA y 
release/versión solamente más adelante, capturan a menudo la ironía
inherente en la situación. ¿Aunque se permitió a los 
internados tomar solamente qué podrían llevar con ellos a los 
campos, una foto de Lange juxtaposes un cartel del megabus "tal carga 
de mi mente? Bekins salvó mis cosas "al lado de una pila de las
pertenencia de los internados. Otra imagen llamativa de Lange 
muestra que un almacén de la esquina Americano-posei'do japonés con 
un grande "yo es" una bandera americana que cuelga debajo de una 
muestra "vendida". Otra fotografía de la distribuidor de un 
motor, quitada de un coche poseído por un internado, mostró que la 
gente era verdad presos en el campo, incapaz conducir sus propios 
coches lejos. Varias pinturas por el Henrio americano japonés 
internado Sugimoto e Hisako Hibi de los artistas reflejan sus 
experiencias emocionales y dan a espectadores un sentido de qué vida 
era como para ellas. Las pinturas expresan el dolor, el 
sufrimiento, y la cólera de ésos sujetados a la internación. 
Sobre 100.000 hombres americanos japoneses, volvieron a poner y 
fueron detenidos a las mujeres, y a los niños en estos campos. 
Las fotografías aquí muestran a la gente de todas las edades, 
incluyendo un abuelo y un nieto, y a niños jóvenes. Esta 
internación ahora se reconoce como violación de las sus derechas 
humanas y civiles. En el an o 80, el gobierno de los E.E.U.U. se
disculpó oficial y las reparaciones fueron pagadas a los 
sobrevivientes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085255</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108398</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/japanese-american-internment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
