<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105709</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105709</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087246</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Won't they be edified!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"werden nicht sie erbaut!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"elles ne seront pas édifiées!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"não edified!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"non edified!"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είναϊ"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no edified!"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">World War I introduced the world to killing and destruction on a scale never seen before. During the battle of the Somme, 19,000 men died on the first day alone. By the end of the campaign the British had gained only 125 miles of territory at a terrible cost: casualties on both sides exceeded one million. For many, the senseless slaughter represented the worst expression of European imperialism, militarism, and nationalism. A 1914 cartoon published in the  Chicago Daily News  uses racial chauvinism to condemn the European war for undermining the moral supremacy of Western Civilization.""</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Erste Weltkrieg führte die Welt zur Tötung und zur 
Zerstörung auf einer Skala ein, die nie vorher gesehen wurde. 
Während der Schlacht des Somme, starben 19.000 Männer am 
ersten Tag alleine. Ende der Kampagne hatten die Briten nur 125 
Meilen der Gegend an schrecklichen Kosten gewonnen: Unfall auf 
beiden Seiten überstiegen eine Million. Für viele stellte das 
senseless Gemetzel den falschsten Ausdruck des europäischen 
Imperialismuses, des Militarismus und des Nationalismus dar. 
Eine Karikatur 1914 veröffentlichte im rassischen 
Chauvinismus Chicago des täglichen Nachrichten Gebrauches, um den 
europäischen Krieg für das Untergraben der moralischen 
Vorherrschaft der westlichen Zivilisation zu verurteilen.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Première Guerre Mondiale a présenté le monde au 
massacre et à la destruction sur une échelle jamais non avant vue. 
Pendant la bataille du Somme, 19.000 hommes sont morts le 
premier seul jour. Vers la fin de la campagne les Anglais 
avaient gagné seulement 125 milles de territoire à un coût terrible
: les accidents des deux côtés ont excédé un million. 
Pour beaucoup, l'abattage insensé a représenté la plus 
mauvaise expression de l'impérialisme, du militarisme, et du 
nationalisme européens. Un dessin animé 1914 a édité dans le
chauvinisme racial d'utilisations quotidiennes de nouvelles de Chicago
pour condamner la guerre européenne pour miner la suprématie morale 
de la civilisation occidentale.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O world.war.i introduziu o mundo à matança e à 
destruição em uma escala nunca vista antes. Durante a batalha 
do Somme, 19.000 homens morreram no primeiro dia sozinho. Para o
fim da campanha os Ingleses tinham ganhado somente 125 milhas do 
território em um custo terrível: as víctimas em ambos os 
lados excederam um milhão. Para muitos, o slaughter senseless 
representou a expressão a mais má do imperialism, do militarism, e 
do nationalism europeus. Um cartoon 1914 publicou dos usos 
diários da notícia de Chicago no chauvinism racial para condemn a 
guerra européia para undermining o supremacy moral da civilização 
ocidental.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il world.war.i ha introdotto il mondo all'uccisione ed 
alla distruzione su una scala non vista mai prima. Durante la 
battaglia del Somme, 19.000 uomini sono morto il primo giorno da solo.
Per la fine della campagna i Britannici avevano guadagnato 
soltanto 125 miglia del territorio ad un costo terribile: gli 
incidenti da entrambi i lati hanno ecceduto un milione di. Per 
molti, il macello senseless ha rappresentato l'espressione più 
difettosa dell'imperialismo, del militarism e del nazionalismo 
europei. Un fumetto 1914 ha pubblicato nel chauvinism razziale 
di usi quotidiani di notizie del Chicago per condannare la guerra 
europea per insidiare il supremacy morale di civilizzazione 
occidentale.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παγκόσμιος πόλεμος εισήγαγα τον κόσμο στη δολοφονία 
και την καταστροφή σε μια κλίμακα που εβλέίδε ποτέ πριν. 
Κατά τη διάρκεια της μάχης somme, 19.000 άτομα 
πέθαναν την πρώτη ημέρα μόνο. Μέχρι το τέλος της 
εκστρατείας οι Βρετανοί είχαν κερδίσει μόνο 125 μίλια του 
εδάφους με φοβερό κόστος: τα θύματα και στις δύο πλευρές 
υπερέβησαν ένα εκατομμύριο. Για πολλούς, η ανόητη σφαγή 
αντιπροσώπευσε τη χειρότερη έκφραση του ευρωπαϊκών 
ιμπεριαλισμού, του μιλιταρισμού, και του εθνικισμού. 
Κινούμενα σχέδια του 1914 που δημοσιεύονται στις 
καθημερινές ειδήσεις του Σικάγου χρησιμοποιούν το φυλετικό 
σοβινισμό για να καταδικάσουν τον ευρωπαϊκό πόλεμο για την 
υπονόμευση της ηθικής υπεροχής του δυτικού πολιτισμού.""</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Primera Guerra Mundial introdujo el mundo a la matanza 
y a la destrucción en una escala nunca considerada antes. 
Durante la batalla del Somme, 19.000 hombres murieron en el 
primer día solamente. Para el final de la campaña los 
Británicos habían ganado solamente 125 millas del territorio en un 
coste terrible: las muertes en ambas caras excedieron de un 
millón. Para muchos, la matanza senseless representó la 
expresión peor del imperialismo, del militarismo, y del nacionalismo 
europeos. Una historieta 1914 publicó en el chauvinismo racial 
de las aplicaciones diarias de las noticias de Chicago para condenar 
la guerra europea para minar la supremacía moral de la civilización 
occidental.""</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087246</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105709</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/wont-they-be-edified</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
