<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107469</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107469</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202696</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Rhythm, Patterns, Color, and Texture in Art and Poetry</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rhythmus, Muster, Farbe und Beschaffenheit in der 
kunst und in der Poesie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Rythme, configurations, couleur, et texture dans 
l'art et la poésie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ritmo, testes padrões, cor, e textura na arte e 
na poesia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ritmo, modelli, colore e struttura nell'arte e 
nella poesia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ρυθμός, πρότυπα, χρώμα, και σύσταση στην τέχνη και 
την ποίηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ritmo, modelos, color, y textura en arte y 
poesía</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this lesson, students will discover the meaning of "rhythm," "patterns," "color," and "texture" through the performance and modeled analysis of a class "symphony." Students will also evaluate the impact of each element on the whole work and note personal reactions and connections to this art form. Students will then work in small groups to apply the same elements and personal evaluation and connections to a historical work of visual art. At the end of the lesson, students will reflect on ways these two experiences are similar.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Lektion entdecken Kursteilnehmer die 
Bedeutung "des Rhythmus," "Muster," "Farbe," und "Beschaffenheit" 
durch die Leistung und die geformte Analyse einer Kategorie 
"Symphonie." Kursteilnehmer auch werten die Auswirkung jedes 
Elements auf die Ganzarbeit aus und beachten persönliche Reaktionen 
und Anschlüsse zu dieser Kunstform. Kursteilnehmer arbeiten 
dann in den kleinen Gruppen, um die gleichen Elemente und persönliche
Auswertung und Anschlüsse zu einer historischen Arbeit der Sichtkunst
anzuwenden. Am Ende der Lektion, reflektieren sich 
Kursteilnehmer auf Methoden, die diese zwei Erfahrungen ähnlich sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette leçon, les étudiants découvriront la
signification du "rythme," des "configurations," "couleur," et 
"texture" par l'exécution et l'analyse modelée d'une classe 
"symphonie." Les étudiants également évalueront l'impact de 
chaque élément dans l'ensemble le travail et noteront des réactions
et des connexions personnelles à cette forme d'art. Les 
étudiants travailleront alors dans de petits groupes pour appliquer 
les mêmes éléments et évaluation et connexions personnelles à un 
travail historique d'art visuel. À la fin de la leçon, les 
étudiants réfléchiront sur des voies que ces deux expériences sont
semblables.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta lição, os estudantes descobrirão o 
meaning do "ritmo," "testes padrões," "cor," e "textura" com o 
desempenho e a análise modelada de uma classe "symphony." Os 
estudantes também avaliarão o impacto de cada elemento no trabalho 
do todo e anotarão reações e conexões pessoais a este formulário 
de arte. Os estudantes trabalharão então em grupos pequenos 
para aplicar os mesmos elementos e avaliação e conexões pessoais a 
um trabalho histórico da arte visual. No fim da lição, os 
estudantes refletirão em maneiras que estas duas experiências são 
similares.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa lezione, gli allievi scopriranno il 
significato "del ritmo," "modelli," "colore," e "struttura" con le 
prestazioni e l'analisi modellistica di un codice categoria 
"symphony." Gli allievi egualmente valuteranno l'effetto di ogni
elemento nel complesso il lavoro e noteranno le reazioni ed i 
collegamenti personali a questa forma di arte. Gli allievi 
allora lavoreranno nei piccoli gruppi per applicare gli stessi 
elementi e valutazione e collegamenti personali ad un lavoro storico 
dell'arte visiva. Alla conclusione della lezione, gli allievi 
rifletteranno sui modi che queste due esperienze sono simili.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το μάθημα, οι σπουδαστές θα ανακαλύψουν την 
έννοια "του ρυθμού," "πρότυπα," "χρώμα," και "σύσταση" μέσω της 
απόδοσης και της διαμορφωμένης ανάλυσης μιας κλάσης "συμφωνία." 
Οι σπουδαστές θα αξιολογήσουν επίσης τον αντίκτυπο κάθε 
στοιχείου απασχολούνται γενικά και σημειώνουν στις προσωπικές 
αντιδράσεις και τις συνδέσεις σε αυτήν την μορφή τέχνης. Οι
σπουδαστές θα εργαστούν έπειτα στις μικρές ομάδες για να 
εφαρμόσουν τα ίδια στοιχεία και την προσωπικές αξιολόγηση και τις
συνδέσεις σε μια ιστορική εργασία της εικαστηκής τέχνης. 
Στο τέλος του μαθήματος, οι σπουδαστές θα εξετάσουν τους 
τρόπους που αυτή η δύο εμπειρία είναι παρόμοια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta lección, los estudiantes descubrirán el 
significado del "ritmo," los "modelos," "color," y "textura" con el 
funcionamiento y el análisis modelado de una clase "sinfonía." 
Los estudiantes también evaluarán el impacto de cada elemento 
en el trabajo del conjunto y observarán reacciones y conexiones 
personales a esta forma de arte. Los estudiantes entonces 
trabajarán en grupos pequeños para aplicar los mismos elementos y 
evaluación y conexiones personales a un trabajo histórico del arte 
visual. En el final de la lección, los estudiantes reflejarán 
en maneras que estas dos experiencias son similares.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CAROL HORNE
FN:CAROL HORNE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202696</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107469</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/rhythm-patterns-color-and-texture-in-art-and-poetry</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
