<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103128</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103128</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200322</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Aboard Alvin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An Bord Alvin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À bord d'Alvin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A bordo De Alvin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">A bordo Di Alvin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε Alvin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A bordo De Alvin</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Gulf of Maine educational website takes students aboard the submersible Alvin. It includes informational pages such as a project overview, as well as pages about Alvin, hydrothermal vents, and the researchers involved in the project. Classroom activities explore nautical and mythical names, such as the Titanic, instruct students how to make a model of the ocean floor in a shoebox, and introduce topics such as deep sea vents and plate tectonics. A photo gallery highlights research aboard the Alvin and links are provided to recent dispatches describing research experiences on the Alvin.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Golf Maine der pädagogischen Web site 
nimmt Kursteilnehmer an Bord des versenkbaren Alvin. Er enthält
informatorische Seiten wie ein Projektüberblick, sowie Seiten über 
Alvin, hydrothermale Entlüftungsöffnungen und die Forscher, die mit 
dem Projekt beschäftigt ge$$$WESEN werden. 
Klassenzimmeraktivitäten erforschen See und mythische Namen, 
wie das Titanic, zeigen Kursteilnehmern, wie man ein Modell vom 
Ozeanfußboden in einem shoebox bildet und stellen Themen wie tiefe 
Seeentlüftungsöffnungen und Plattentektonik vor. Höhepunkte 
einer Fotogalerie erforschen an Bord des Alvin und Links werden zu den
neuen Abfertigungen zur Verfügung gestellt, die Forschung Erfahrungen
auf dem Alvin beschreiben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce Golfe de site Web éducatif du Maine prend des 
étudiants à bord de l'Alvin submersible. Il inclut les pages 
informationnelles telles qu'une vue d'ensemble de projet, aussi bien 
que des pages au sujet d'Alvin, les évents hydrothermiques, et les 
chercheurs impliqués dans le projet. Les activités de salle de
classe explorent nautique et les noms mythiques, tels que Titanic,
instruisent des étudiants comment faire un modèle du fond océanique
dans un shoebox, et présentent des sujets tels que les évents de mer
et la tectonique de plat profonds. Les points culminants d'une 
galerie de photo recherchent à bord de l'Alvin et des liens sont 
fournis aux expéditions récentes décrivant des expériences de 
recherches sur l'Alvin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este golfo do Web site educacional de Maine faz 
exame de estudantes a bordo do Alvin submergível. Inclui 
páginas informativas tais como uma vista geral do projeto, as.well.as
páginas sobre Alvin, respiradouros hydrothermal, e os investigadores 
envolvidos no projeto. As atividades da sala de aula exploram 
náutico e os nomes mythical, tais como o Titanic, instruem estudantes
como fazer um modelo do assoalho de oceano em um shoebox, e introduzem
tópicos tais como respiradouros do mar e o tectonics de placa 
profundos. Os destaques de uma galeria da foto pesquisam a bordo
do Alvin e as ligações são fornecidas às expedições recentes que
descrevem experiências da pesquisa no Alvin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo golfo del Web site educativo della Maine 
prende gli allievi a bordo del Alvin sommergibile. Include le 
pagine informative quali una descrizione di progetto, così come le 
pagine circa Alvin, gli sfiati idrotermali ed i ricercatori addetti al
progetto. Le attività dell'aula esplorano nautico ed i nomi 
mythical, quale il Titanic, insegnano agli allievi come fare un 
modello del pavimento di oceano in uno shoebox ed introducono i 
soggetti quali gli sfiati del mare e la tettonica di piastra profondi.
I punti culminanti della galleria della foto ricercano a bordo 
del Alvin ed i collegamenti sono forniti alle spedizioni recenti che 
descrivono le esperienze di ricerca sul Alvin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο κόλπος του εκπαιδευτικού ιστοχώρου του 
Maine παίρνει τους σπουδαστές στο υποβρύχιο Alvin. 
Περιλαμβάνει τις ενημερωτικές σελίδες όπως μια επισκόπηση 
προγράμματος, καθώς επίσης και τις σελίδες για Alvin, τις 
υδροθερμικές διεξόδους, και τους ερευνητές σχετικούς στο 
πρόγραμμα. Οι δραστηριότητες τάξεων ερευνούν τα ναυτικά και
μυθικά ονόματα, όπως ο τιτανικός, καθοδηγούν τους σπουδαστές 
πώς να κάνουν ένα μοντέλο του ωκεάνιου πατώματος σε ένα 
shoebox, και εισάγουν τα θέματα όπως η τεκτονική διεξόδων και 
πιάτων μεγάλων θαλασσίων βαθών. Μια στοά φωτογραφιών 
δίνει έμφαση στην έρευνα στο Alvin και οι συνδέσεις παρέχονται
στις πρόσφατες αποστολές περιγράφοντας την ερευνητική εμπειρία 
στο Alvin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este golfo del Web site educativo de Maine toma a 
estudiantes a bordo del Alvin sumergible. Incluye las 
paginaciones informativas tales como una descripción del proyecto, 
así como las paginaciones sobre Alvin, respiraderos hidrotérmicos, y
los investigadores implicados en el proyecto. Las actividades de
la sala de clase exploran náutico y los nombres míticos, tales como 
el Titanic, mandan a estudiantes cómo hacer un modelo del suelo 
marino en un shoebox, e introducen asuntos tales como respiraderos del
mar y tectónica de placa profundos. Los toques de luz de una 
galería de la foto investigan a bordo del Alvin y las conexiones se 
proporcionan a los envíos recientes que describen experiencias de la 
investigación en el Alvin.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GULF OF MAINE AQUARIUM
FN:GULF OF MAINE AQUARIUM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200322</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103128</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/aboard-alvin</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
