<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108106</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108106</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205896</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Reporting America at War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Berichten über Amerika am Krieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enregistrement de l'Amérique à la guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Relatando América na guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Segnalazione dell'America alla guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποβολή εκθέσεων της Αμερικής στον πόλεμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Señalar América en la guerra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores the role of journalists in covering America's wars. The website, companion to a PBS documentary, offers a teachers guide with lessons on press censorship, message control, the power of pictures, finding the right words, and works by Ernie Pyle and Edward R. Murrow. The documentary examines the challenges of reporting from the front lines and the role of the correspondent in shaping how wars have been understood and remembered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht die Rolle der Journalisten in den 
Kriegen Bedeckung Amerikas. Die Web site, Begleiter zu einem PBS
Dokumentarfilm, bietet Lehrer Anleitung mit Lektionen auf 
Pressezensur, Meldung Steuerung, die Energie der Abbildungen an und 
findet die rechten Wörter und die Arbeiten durch Ernie Pyle und 
Edward R. Murrow. Der Dokumentarfilm überprüft die 
Herausforderungen des Berichtes von den vorderen Zeilen und die Rolle 
des Korrespondenten, wenn er formt, wie an Kriege verstanden worden 
und erinnert worden sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore le rôle des journalistes dans les guerres
de l'Amérique de bâche. Le site Web, compagnon à un 
documentaire de PBS, offre des professeurs guide avec des leçons sur 
la censure de presse, la commande de message, la puissance des images,
trouvant les bons mots, et des travaux par Ernie Pyle et Edouard 
R. Murrow. Le documentaire examine les défis de 
l'enregistrement des lignes de front et le rôle du correspondant en 
formant comment des guerres ont été comprises et retrouvées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora o papel dos journalists em guerras de 
América do covering. O Web site, companheiro a um documentary 
de PBS, oferece professores guia com lições na censura da imprensa, 
controle da mensagem, a potência dos retratos, encontrando as 
palavras direitas, e trabalhos por Ernie Pyle e por Edward R. Murrow. 
O documentary examina os desafios do relatório das linhas 
dianteiras e o papel do correspondente em dar forma a como as guerras 
foram compreendidas e recordadas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora il ruolo dei giornalisti nelle guerre 
dell'America del covering. Il Web site, compagno ad un 
documentary di PBS, offre gli insegnanti guida con le lezioni su 
censura della pressa, il controllo del messaggio, l'potenza delle 
immagini, trovando le giuste parole e gli impianti da Ernie Pyle e da 
Edward R. Murrow. Il documentary esamina le sfide di 
segnalazione dalle righe anteriori ed il ruolo del corrispondente 
nella modellatura come le guerre sono state capite e si ricordate di.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ερευνά το ρόλο των δημοσιογράφων στην κάλυψη των 
πολέμων της Αμερικής. Ο ιστοχώρος, σύντροφος σε ένα 
ντοκιμαντέρ PBS, προσφέρει έναν οδηγό δασκάλων με τα μαθήματα
στη λογοκρισία Τύπου, έλεγχος μηνυμάτων, η δύναμη των εικόνων, 
που βρίσκει τις σωστές λέξεις, και τις εργασίες από Ernie 
Pyle και τον Edward R. Murrow. Το ντοκιμαντέρ 
εξετάζει τις προκλήσεις της υποβολής έκθεσης από τις πρώτες 
γραμμές και το ρόλο του ανταποκριτή στη διαμόρφωση πώς οι 
πόλεμοι έχουν γίνει κατανοητοί και έχουν αναφερθεί.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora el papel de periodistas en las guerras de 
América de la cubierta. El Web site, compañero a un 
documentary de PBS, ofrece a profesores guía con lecciones en la 
censura de la prensa, control del mensaje, la potencia de cuadros, 
encontrando las palabras derechas, y los trabajos por Ernie Pyle y 
Edward R. Murrow. El documentary examina los desafíos de 
señalar de las líneas delanteras y el papel del correspondiente en 
formar cómo se han entendido y se han recordado las guerras.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205896</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108106</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/reporting-america-at-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
