<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104077</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104077</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207085</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Emerging and Re-emerging Infectious Diseases</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auftauchende und Re-emerging ansteckende 
Krankheiten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les maladies infectieuses naissantes et de 
réapparitions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Doenças infectious emergentes e reemirjindo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Malattie contagiose d'emersione e di 
riapparizione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αναδυόμενες και επανεμφανιμένος μολυσματικές ασθένειες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Enfermedades infecciosas que emergen y que 
reaparecen</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores factors associated with disease emergence and re-emergence and considers the human activities that can increase or decrease the likelihood of outbreaks of infectious diseases. Students play the role of epidemiologists looking for clues to solve the case of a mystery disease, watch simulations of herd immunity and the impact of vaccination programs, and assign limited funds to three proposals submitted to address a major infectious disease.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht die Faktoren, die mit Krankheit 
Hervortreten und Re-Hervortreten verbunden sind und betrachtet die 
menschlichen Aktivitäten, die sich erhöhen können oder die 
Wahrscheinlichkeit von Ausbrüchen der ansteckenden Krankheiten 
verringern. Kursteilnehmer spielen die Rolle der Kenner der 
epidemischen Krankheiten, die nach Anhaltspunkten suchen, um den Fall 
von einer Geheimniskrankheit zu lösen, Simulationen der 
Herdeimmunität und der Auswirkung der Schutzimpfungprogramme zu 
überwachen, und begrenzte Kapital drei Angeboten zuzuweisen, die 
eingereicht werden, um eine ansteckende hauptsächlichkrankheit zu 
adressieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore des facteurs liés à l'apparition et à 
la re-apparition de la maladie et considère les activités humaines 
qui peuvent augmenter ou diminuent la probabilité des manifestations 
des maladies infectieuses. Les étudiants jouent le rôle des 
épidémiologues recherchant des indices pour résoudre le cas d'une 
maladie de mystère, pour observer des simulations d'immunité de 
troupeau et de l'impact des programmes de vaccination, et pour 
assigner les fonds limités à trois propositions soumises pour 
adresser une maladie infectieuse importante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora os fatores associados com o emergence e o 
re-re-emergence da doença e considera as atividades humanas que podem
aumentar ou diminuem a probabilidade dos outbreaks de doenças 
infectious. Os estudantes jogam o papel dos epidemiólogos que 
procuram indícios para resolver o exemplo de uma doença do 
mistério, para prestar atenção a simulações do immunity do 
rebanho e do impacto de programas do vaccination, e para atribuir 
fundos limitados a três propostas submetidas para dirigir-se a uma 
doença infectious principal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora i fattori connessi con l'emersione e 
l're-emersione di malattia e considera le attività umane che possono 
aumentare o fanno diminuire la probabilità degli scoppi di malattie 
contagiose. Gli allievi svolgono il ruolo degli epidemiologi che
cercano gli indizii per risolvere il caso di una malattia di mistero, 
per guardare le simulazioni di immunità del gregge e dell'effetto dei
programmi di vaccinazione e per assegnare i fondi monetari limitati a 
tre proposte presentate per richiamare una malattia contagiosa 
importante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ερευνά τους παράγοντες που συνδέονται με την εμφάνιση 
και την επανεμφάνιση ασθενειών και εξετάζει τις ανθρώπινες 
δραστηριότητες που μπορούν να αυξήσουν ή να μειώσουν την 
πιθανότητα των ξεσπασμάτων των μολυσματικών ασθενειών. Οι 
σπουδαστές διαδραματίζουν το ρόλο των επιδημιολόγων που ψάχνουν 
τις ενδείξεις για να λύσουν την περίπτωση μιας ασθένειας 
μυστηρίου, προσέχουν τις προσομοιώσεις της ασυλίας κοπαδιών και 
του αντίκτυπου των προγραμμάτων εμβολιασμού, και αναθέτουν τα 
περιορισμένα κεφάλαια σε τρεις προτάσεις που υποβάλλονται για να 
εξετάσουν μια σημαντική μολυσματική ασθένεια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora los factores asociados a la aparición y a
la re-aparicio'n de la enfermedad y considera las actividades humanas 
que pueden aumentar o disminuyen la probabilidad de brotes de 
enfermedades infecciosas. Los estudiantes desempeñan el papel 
de los epidemiólogos que buscan pistas para solucionar el caso de una
enfermedad del misterio, para mirar simulaciones de la inmunidad de la
manada y del impacto de los programas de la vacunación, y para 
asignar fondos limitados a tres ofertas sometidas para tratar una 
enfermedad infecciosa importante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207085</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104077</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/emerging-and-re-emerging-infectious-diseases</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
