<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108714</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108714</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086906</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Bottom of the Economic Totem Pole": African American Women in the Workplace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Unterseite des ökonomischen Totem Pole": 
Afrikanische amerikanische Frauen an dem Arbeitsplatz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"le bas du Totem économique Polonais" : 
Femmes américaines africaines dans le lieu de travail</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o fundo do Totem econômico Pólo": 
Mulheres americanas africanas no workplace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la parte inferiore del Totem economico Palo": 
Donne americane africane nel posto di lavoro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το κατώτατο σημείο του οικονομικού τοτέμ Πολωνόσ": 
Αφρικανικές αμερικανικές γυναίκες στον εργασιακό χώρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el fondo del Totem económico poste": 
Mujeres americanas africanas en el lugar de trabajo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During World War II, a number of states passed legislation to combat salary inequities suffered by female workers. Many unions also adopted standards to insure that female employees received the same salaries as males who performed similar jobs. The Equal Pay Act of 1963, the first Federal legislation guaranteeing equal pay for equal work, prohibited firms engaged in interstate commerce from paying workers according to wage rates determined by sex. It did not, however, prevent companies from hiring only men for higher paying jobs. Despite the fact that Title VII of the landmark Civil Rights Act of 1964 further prevented sex discrimination in employment, African-American women as a class remained "at the bottom of the economic totem pole" because of "their dual victimization by race and sex-based discrimination," in the words of Dr. Pauli Murray, whose testimony to Congress appears below. Dr. Murray, an African-American professor of American studies specializing in law and social change expressed concern that despite previous antidiscrimination legislation, "we are holding on very definitely to the patriarchal aspect of white America." Murray advocated the position that all antidiscrimination legislation should explicitly prohibit sex descrimination.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des Zweiten Weltkrieges führte eine 
Anzahl von Zuständen Gesetzgebung zu den Kampfgehalt 
Ungerechtigkeiten, die durch weibliche Arbeiter erlitten wurden. 
Viele Anschlüße nahmen auch Standards an, um zu versichern, 
daß weibliche Angestellte die gleichen Gehälter wie Männer 
empfingen, die ähnliche Jobs durchführten. Die gleiche 
Bezahlung Tat von 1963, die erste Bundesgesetzgebung, die gleicher 
Bezahlung für gleiche Arbeit, verbotene Unternehmen garantiert, 
engagierte sich im landesweiten Handel vom Zahlen der Arbeiter 
entsprechend den Lohnkinetik, die durch Geschlecht festgestellt 
wurden. Sie nicht verhinderte jedoch Firmen an der Einstellung 
der nur Männer für höhere zahlende Jobs. Obwohl Titel VII der
Grenzstein Zivilrecht-Tat der weiteren verhinderten Unterscheidung 
unter des Geschlechtes 1964 in der Beschäftigung, 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Frauen, wie eine Kategorie "an der 
Unterseite des ökonomischen totem Pfostens" wegen "ihrer 
DoppelSchuldzuschreibung durch Rennen blieb und Geschlecht-gründete 
Unterscheidung," in den Wörtern von Dr. Pauli Murray, dem Zeugnis zum
Kongreß erscheint. Dr. Murray, ein Afrikanisch-Amerikanischer 
Professor der Amerikanerstudien spezialisierend auf Gesetz und 
Sozialänderung drückte Interesse aus, das trotz der vorhergehenden 
antidiscrimination Gesetzgebung, "wir anhalten an sehr definitiv zum 
patriarchalischen Aspekt von weißem Amerika." Murray 
befürwortete die Position, daß alle antidiscrimination Gesetzgebung 
Geschlecht descrimination ausdrücklich verbieten sollte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale, un certain 
nombre d'états ont passé la législation aux injustices de salaire 
de combat souffertes par les ouvriers féminins. Beaucoup de 
syndicats ont également adopté des normes pour assurer que les 
employés féminins ont reçu les mêmes salaires que les mâles qui 
ont exécuté les travaux semblables. La Loi d'égalité de 
salaires de 1963, la première législation fédérale garantissant la
salaire égal, les sociétés interdites s'est engagée dans le 
commerce entre Etats de payer des ouvriers selon des salaires horaires
déterminés par le sexe. Elle, cependant, n'a pas empêché des
compagnies de louer seulement des hommes pour les travaux de paiement 
plus élevés. Malgré le fait que titre VII de l'acte de droits
civiques de borne limite de la discrimination de sexe 1964 empêchée 
encore dans l'emploi, femmes afro-américaines comme une classe est 
demeurée "au bas du poteau économique de totem" en raison de 
"leur victimisation duelle par la course et sexe-a basé la 
discrimination," dans les mots de Dr. Pauli Murray, au-dessous du dont
le témoignage au congrès apparaît. Dr. Murray, un professeur 
afro-américain des études d'Américain se spécialisant légalement et 
le changement social a exprimé les inquiétudes qui en dépit de la 
législation précédente d'antidiscrimination, "nous se tiennent en 
fonction très certainement sur l'aspect patriarcal de l'Amérique 
blanche." Murray a préconisé la position que toute la 
législation d'antidiscrimination devrait explicitement interdire le 
descrimination de sexe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante a segunda guerra mundial, um número de 
estados passaram a legislação aos inequities do salário do combate 
sofridos por trabalhadores fêmeas. Muitas uniões adotaram 
também padrões para segurar que os empregados fêmeas receberam os 
mesmos salários que os machos que executaram trabalhos similares. 
O ato de 1963, a primeira legislação federal do pagamento 
igual que garante o pagamento igual para o trabalho igual, firmas 
proibidas acoplou no comércio interstate de pagar trabalhadores de 
acordo com as taxas de salário determinadas pelo sexo. , 
entretanto, não impediu que as companhias empreguem somente homens 
para uns trabalhos pagando mais elevados. Apesar do fato que 
título VII do ato das direitas civis do marco da discriminação de 
sexo 1964 impedida mais adicional no emprego, mulheres 
Africano-Americanas como uma classe remanesceu "no fundo do pólo 
econômico do totem" por causa de "seu victimization duplo pela raça 
e sexo-baseou a discriminação," nas palavras do Dr. Pauli Murray, do
cujo o testimony ao congress aparece abaixo. O Dr. Murray, um 
professor Africano-Americano de estudos do americano que 
especializa-se na lei e na mudança social expressou o interesse que 
apesar da legislação precedente do antidiscrimination, "nós está 
prendendo sobre muito definitivamente ao aspecto patriarchal de 
América branca." Murray advogou a posição que toda a 
legislação do antidiscrimination deve explicitamente proibir o 
descrimination do sexo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante la seconda guerra mondiale, un certo 
numero dichiara la legislazione passata alle ingiustizie di 
stipendio di combattimento sofferte dagli operai femminili. 
Molti sindacati egualmente hanno adottato gli standard per 
assicurare che gli impiegati femminili hanno ricevuto gli stessi 
stipendi dei maschi che hanno effettuato i lavori simili. La 
Legge di 1963, la prima legislazione federale di parità salariale che
garantisce la parità salariale per lavoro uguale, ditte proibite si 
è agganciata nel commercio da uno stato all'altro dal pagamento degli
operai secondo i tassi di stipendio determinati dal sesso. , 
tuttavia, non ha impedito alle aziende di assumere soltanto gli uomini
per gli più alti lavori di pagamento. Malgrado il fatto che 
titolo VII della Legge di diritti civili del limite di ulteriore 
discriminazione in base al sesso evitata 1964 nell'occupazione, donne 
Africano-Americane come un codice categoria è rimasto "alla parte 
inferiore del palo economico del totem" a causa "della loro 
vittimizzazione doppia tramite la corsa e sesso-ha basato la 
distinzione," nelle parole del Dott. Pauli Murray, di cui la 
testimonianza al congresso compare sotto. Il Dott. Murray, un 
professore Africano-Americano degli studi dell'americano che si 
specializza nella legge e nel cambiamento sociale ha espresso la 
preoccupazione che malgrado legislazione precedente di 
antidiscrimination, "noi è tenuta sopra molto definitivamente 
alla funzione patriarchal dell'America bianca." Murray ha 
sostenuto la posizione che tutta la legislazione di antidiscrimination
dovrebbe proibire esplicitamente il descrimination del sesso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ, διάφορα 
κράτη πέρασαν τη νομοθεσία στις αδικίες μισθών αγώνα που 
υποφέρονται από τη γυναίκα εργαζόμενοι. Πολλές ενώσεις 
υιοθέτησαν επίσης τα πρότυπα για να ασφαλίσουν ότι η γυναίκα 
υπάλληλοι έλαβε τους ίδιους μισθούς με τα αρσενικά που εκτέλεσαν
τις παρόμοιες εργασίες. Ο νόμος ίσης αμοιβής του 1963, η
πρώτη ομοσπονδιακή νομοθεσία που εγγυάται την ίση αμοιβή για την
όμοια εργασία, απαγόρευσε τις εταιρίες που συμμετέχθηκαν στο 
διακρατικό εμπόριο από την πληρωμή των εργαζομένων σύμφωνα με τα
ποσοστά αμοιβών που καθορίστηκαν από το φύλο. , Εντούτοις,
δεν απέτρεψε τις επιχειρήσεις από τη μίσθωση μόνο των ατόμων για
τις υψηλότερες εργασίες πληρωμής. Παρά το γεγονός ότι ο 
τίτλος VII του νόμου αστικών δικαιωμάτων ορόσημων των 
περαιτέρω διακρίσεων λόγω φύλου του 1964 στην απασχόληση, 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικές γυναίκες ως κλάση παρέμεινε "στο 
κατώτατο σημείο του οικονομικού πόλου τοτέμ" λόγω της "διπλής 
δίωξής τους από τη φυλή και την φύλο-βασισμένη στον διάκριση," 
στις λέξεις του Δρ Pauli Murray, η ο οποίος κατάθεση στο 
συνέδριο εμφανίζεται κατωτέρω. Ο Δρ Murray, ένας 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικός καθηγητής των αμερικανικών μελετών που 
ειδικεύονται στην εκφρασμένη ανησυχία νόμου και κοινωνικής 
αλλαγής αυτός παρά την προηγούμενη νομοθεσία 
antidiscrimination, "κρατάμε επάνω πολύ σίγουρα στην 
πατριαρχική πτυχή της λευκιάς Αμερικής." Το Murray 
υποστήριξε τη θέση ότι όλη η νομοθεσία antidiscrimination 
πρέπει ρητά να απαγορεύσει το descrimination φύλων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial, un número de 
estados aprobaron la legislación a las injusticias del sueldo del 
combate sufridas por los trabajadores femeninos. Muchas uniones 
también adoptaron estándares para asegurar que los empleados 
femeninos recibieron los mismos sueldos que los varones que realizaron
trabajos similares. El acto de 1963, la primera legislación 
federal de la igualdad de salario que garantizaba la igualdad de 
salario para el trabajo igual, las firmas prohibidas enganchó a 
comercio de un estado a otro de pagar a trabajadores según las 
tarifas de salario determinadas por el sexo. , sin embargo, no 
evitó que las compañías emplearan solamente a hombres para trabajos
que pagaban más altos. A pesar de el hecho de que título VII 
del acto de las derechas civiles de la señal de la discriminación de
sexo prevenida adicional 1964 en el empleo, mujeres 
Africano-Americanas como seguía habiendo "en el fondo del poste 
económico del totem" debido a "su persecución dual por la raza y 
sexo-baso' una clase la discriminación," en las palabras del Dr. 
Pauli Murray, debajo de quienes testimonio al congreso aparece. 
El Dr. Murray, profesor Africano-Americano de los estudios del 
americano que se especializaba en ley y cambio social expresó la 
preocupación que a pesar de la legislación anterior del 
antidiscrimination, "nosotros está sosteniendo encendido muy 
definitivamente al aspecto patriarchal de América blanca." 
Murray abogó la posición que toda la legislación del 
antidiscrimination debe prohibir explícitamente el descrimination del
sexo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086906</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108714</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-bottom-of-the-economic-totem-pole-african-american-women-in-the-workplace</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
