<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103522</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103522</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211247</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Center for Science Education</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationale Mitte für Wissenschaft Ausbildung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Centre national pour l'éducation de la Science</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Centro nacional para a instrução da ciência</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Centro nazionale per formazione di scienza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνικό κέντρο για την εκπαίδευση επιστήμης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Centro nacional para la educación de la ciencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The National Center for Science Education (NCSE) is a nonprofit organization working to defend the teaching of evolution against sectarian attack. The group is committed to defending the teaching of evolution in public schools. They hope to prevent the teaching of "scientific creationism" in classrooms. The site contains detailed descriptions of past and ongoing court cases, education outreach projects, and ongoing debate over the validity of evolution, plus numerous essays on the controversy. This is a useful site for instructors looking for information to support the teaching of evolution in public schools.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die nationale Mitte für Wissenschaft Ausbildung 
(NCSE) ist eine Organisationfunktion, zum des Unterrichts der 
Entwicklung gegen sectarian Angriff zu verteidigen. Die Gruppe 
wird am Verteidigen des Unterrichts der Entwicklung in den allgemeinen
Schulen festgelegt. Sie hoffen, den Unterricht "des 
wissenschaftlichen Kreationismus" in den Klassenzimmern zu verhindern.
Die Site enthält ausführliche Beschreibungen von letztem und 
fortwährende Gerichtfälle, Ausbildung übertreffen Projekte und 
fortwährende Debatte über der Gültigkeit der Entwicklung, plus 
zahlreiche Versuche auf der Kontroverse. Dieses ist eine 
nützliche Site für die Ausbilder, die nach Informationen suchen, um 
den Unterricht der Entwicklung in den allgemeinen Schulen zu 
unterstützen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le centre national pour l'éducation de la Science
(NCSE) est un fonctionnement d'organisation à but non lucratif pour 
défendre l'enseignement de l'évolution contre l'attaque 
sectaire. Le groupe est investi dans défendre 
l'enseignement de l'évolution dans des écoles d'Etat. Elles 
espèrent empêcher l'enseignement "du créationisme scientifique" 
dans les salles de classe. Le site contient des descriptions 
détaillées de passé et les affaires en jugement continues, 
éducation dépassent des projets, et la discussion continue au-dessus
de la validité de l'évolution, plus de nombreux essais sur la 
polémique. C'est un site utile pour des instructeurs 
recherchant l'information pour supporter l'enseignement de 
l'évolution dans des écoles d'Etat.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O centro nacional para a instrução da ciência 
(NCSE) é um funcionamento da organização nonprofit para defender o 
ensino da evolução de encontro ao ataque sectarian. O grupo é
cometido a defender o ensino da evolução em escolas públicas. 
Esperam impedir o ensino "do creationism científico" nas salas 
de aula. O local contem descrições detalhadas de passado e os 
casos de corte ongoing, instrução excedem projetos, e debate ongoing
sobre a validez da evolução, mais essays numerosos na controvérsia.
Este é um local útil para os instrutores que procuram a 
informação para suportar o ensino da evolução em escolas 
públicas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il centro nazionale per formazione di scienza 
(NCSE) è un funzionamento di organizzazione senza scopo di lucro per 
difendere l'insegnamento dello sviluppo contro l'attacco sectarian. 
Il gruppo è stanziato a difendere l'insegnamento dello sviluppo
in "public school". Sperano di impedire l'insegnamento "del 
creationism scientifico" in aule. Il luogo contiene le 
descrizioni dettagliate di passato ed i casi di corte continui, 
formazione superano i progetti ed il dibattito continuo sopra la 
validità di sviluppo, più i saggi numerosi sulla polemica. 
Ciò è un luogo utile per gli istruttori che cercano le 
informazioni per sostenere l'insegnamento dello sviluppo in "public 
school".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το εθνικό κέντρο για την εκπαίδευση επιστήμης 
(NCSE) είναι μια μη κερδοσκοπική οργάνωση που εργάζεται για να 
υπερασπίσει τη διδασκαλία της εξέλιξης ενάντια στην αιρετικοη 
επίθεση. Η ομάδα είναι δεσμευμένη στην υπεράσπιση της 
διδασκαλίας της εξέλιξης στα δημόσια σχολεία. Ελπίζουν να 
αποτρέψουν τη διδασκαλία του "επιστημονικού creationism" στις 
τάξεις. Η περιοχή περιέχει τις λεπτομερείς περιγραφές των 
προηγούμενων και τρεχουσών δικαστικών υποθέσεων, η εκπαίδευση 
ξεπερνά τα προγράμματα, και την τρέχουσα συζήτηση πέρα από την 
ισχύ της εξέλιξης, συν τα πολυάριθμα δοκίμια σχετικά με τη 
διαμάχη. Αυτό είναι μια χρήσιμη περιοχή για τους 
εκπαιδευτικούς που ψάχνουν τις πληροφορίες για να υποστηρίξει τη 
διδασκαλία της εξέλιξης στα δημόσια σχολεία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El centro nacional para la educación de la 
ciencia (NCSE) es un funcionamiento de la organización no lucrativa 
para defender la enseñanza de la evolución contra ataque sectarian. 
El grupo está confiado a defender la enseñanza de la 
evolución en escuelas públicas. Esperan prevenir la enseñanza
del "creationism científico" en salas de clase. El sitio 
contiene descripciones detalladas de último y los procesos legales en
curso, educación exceden proyectos, y el discusión en curso sobre la
validez de la evolución, más ensayos numerosos en la controversia. 
Esto es un sitio útil para los instructores que buscan la 
información para utilizar la enseñanza de la evolución en escuelas 
públicas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211247</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103522</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-center-for-science-education</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
