<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107012</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107012</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086931</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Eruption of Tulsa": An NAACP Official Investigates the Tulsa Race Riot of 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Eruption von Tulsa": Ein NAACP Beamter 
forscht den Tulsa Rennen-Aufstand von 1921 nach</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"l'éruption de Tulsa" : Un fonctionnaire de
NAACP étudie l'émeute de course de Tulsa de 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o eruption de Tulsa": Um oficial de NAACP 
investiga o motim da raça de Tulsa de 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il eruption di Tulsa": Un funzionario di 
NAACP studia il tumulto della corsa de Tulsa di 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η έκρηξη Tulsa": Ένας ανώτερος υπάλληλος 
NAACP ερευνά τη φυλετική ταραχή Tulsa του 1921</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la erupción de Tulsa": Un funcionario de 
NAACP investiga el alboroto de la raza de Tulsa de 1921</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The years following World War I in the United States saw devastating race riots around the nation: in small cities like Elaine, Arkansas, and Knoxville, Tennessee as well as in larger ones such as Chicago, where a four-day riot in 1919 left two dozen African Americans dead and more than 300 injured. But the Tulsa race riot was perhaps the worst. In fact, white Tulsans' 24-hour rampage was one of the most vicious and intense race riots in American history before or since, resulting in the death of anywhere from 75 to 250 people and the burning of more than 1,000 black homes and businesses. Walter White, an official of the NAACP, traveled to Tulsa in disguise to survey the damage caused by the 1921 race riot. His report, one of many articles on the riot, was published in the  Nation  in the summer of 1921.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Jahre dem Ersten Weltkrieg in den Vereinigten 
Staaten folgend sahen verheerende Rennenaufstände um die Nation: 
in den kleinen Städte mögen Sie Elaine, Arkansas und 
Knoxville, Tennessee sowie in den größeren wie Chicago, in denen ein
viertätiger Aufstand in 1919 zwei Dutzend afrikanische Amerikaner tot
und mehr als 300 verletzt ließ. Aber der Tulsa Rennenaufstand 
war möglicherweise das falschste. Tatsächlich randalieren 
weißen Tulsans', das 24stündig ist, war einer der schändlichsten 
und intensivsten Rennenaufstände in der amerikanischen Geschichte vor
oder, da, und das überall resultiert im Tod von von 75 bis 250 Leuten
und das Brennen von mehr als 1.000 schwarzen Häusern und von 
Geschäften. Walter Weiß, ein Beamter des NAACP, gereist nach 
Tulsa in der Verkleidung, um die Beschädigung zu überblicken 
verursacht durch den Aufstand mit 1921 Rennen. Sein Report, 
einer vieler Artikel auf dem Aufstand, wurde in der Nation am Sommer 
von 1921 veröffentlicht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les années suivant la Première Guerre Mondiale 
aux Etats-Unis ont vu des émeutes dévastatrices de course dans la 
nation : dans de petites villes aimez Elaine, l'Arkansas, et 
Knoxville, Tennessee aussi bien qu'à le plus grand tel que Chicago, 
où une émeute de quatre jours dans 1919 a laissé deux douzaine 
Américains africains morts et plus de 300 blessés. Mais 
l'émeute de course de Tulsa était peut-être la plus mauvaise. 
En fait, le saccage de 2$4$ heures de Tulsans blanc était l'une
des émeutes de course les plus méchantes et les plus intenses dans 
l'histoire américaine avant ou puisque, ayant pour résultat la mort 
n'importe où de de 75 à 250 personnes et la brûlure de plus de 
1.000 maisons et entreprises noires. Blanc de Walter, un 
fonctionnaire du NAACP, parcouru à Tulsa dans le déguisement pour 
examiner les dommages provoqués par l'émeute de 1921 courses. 
Son état, un de beaucoup d'articles sur l'émeute, a été 
édité dans la nation en été de 1921.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os anos que seguem o world.war.i nos estados 
unidos viram motins devastating da raça em torno da nação: em
cidades pequenas goste de Elaine, de Arkansas, e de Knoxville, 
Tennessee as.well.as em os maiores tais como Chicago, onde um motim 
four-day em 1919 deixou dois dúzia americanos africanos inoperantes e
mais de 300 feridos. Mas o motim da raça de Tulsa era talvez o 
mais mau. No fato, o rampage de 24 horas de Tulsans' branco era 
um dos motins os mais vicious e os mais intensos da raça no history 
americano antes ou desde que, tendo por resultado a morte em qualquer 
lugar  de 75 a 250 povos e da queimadura de mais de 1.000 HOME e 
negócios pretos. Branco de Walter, um oficial do NAACP, viajado
a Tulsa no disfarce para examinar os danos causados pelo motim de 1921
raças. Seu relatório, um de muitos artigos no motim, foi 
publicado na nação no verão de 1921.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli anni che seguono il world.war.i in unito 
Dichiara i tumulti devastating della corsa della sega intorno 
alla nazione: in piccole città gradisca Elaine, l'Arkansas e 
Knoxville, Tennessee così come in quei più grandi quale Chicago, in 
cui un tumulto di quattro giorni in 1919 ha lasciato due dozzina 
Americani africani guasti e più di 300 danneggiati. Ma il 
tumulto della corsa de Tulsa era forse il più difettoso. 
Infatti, il rampage di 24 ore del Tulsans bianco era uno dei 
tumulti della corsa più viziosi e più intensi nella storia americana
prima o poiché, con conseguente morte dovunque di 75 - 250 genti e 
bruciarsi di più di 1.000 sedi e commercio neri. Bianco di 
Walter, un funzionario del NAACP, viaggiato a Tulsa nella 
travestimento per esaminare danni causati dal tumulto della 1921 
corsa. Il suo rapporto, uno di molti articoli sul tumulto, è 
stato pubblicato nella nazione di estate di 1921.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα έτη μετά από παγκόσμιος πόλεμος Ι στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες εβλέίδαν τις καταστρεπτικές φυλετικές ταραχές 
γύρω από το έθνος: στις μικρές πόλεις συμπαθήστε την 
Elaine, το Αρκάνσας, και Knoxville, Tennessee τόσο καλά 
όσο μεγαλύτερα τέτοιοι ως Σικάγο, όπου μια τεσσάρων ημερών 
ταραχή το 1919 άφησε δύο δωδεκάδυς αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς 
νεκρούς και περισσότερων 300 που τραυματίστηκαν από. 
Αλλά η φυλετική ταραχή Tulsa ήταν ίσως η χειρότερη. 
Στην πραγματικότητα, η εικοσιτετράωρη έξαλλη συμπεριφορά 
άσπρου Tulsans ήταν μια από τις πιό κακοήθεις και έντονες 
φυλετικές ταραχές στην αμερικανική ιστορία πριν από ή από 
τότε, με συνέπεια το θάνατο οπουδήποτε από 75 έως 250 
ανθρώπους και το κάψιμο περισσότερων από 1.000 μαύρων σπιτιών
και επιχειρήσεων. Walter White, ένας ανώτερος 
υπάλληλος του NAACP, ταξίδεψε σε Tulsa στη μεταμφίεση για να 
ερευνήσει τη ζημία που προκλήθηκε από τη φυλετική ταραχή του 
1921. Η έκθεσή του, ένα από πολλά άρθρα σχετικά με την
ταραχή, δημοσιεύθηκε στο έθνος το καλοκαίρι του 1921.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los años que seguían Primera Guerra Mundial en 
los Estados Unidos consideraron alborotos devastadores de la raza 
alrededor de la nación: en ciudades pequeñas tenga gusto de 
Elaine, de Arkansas, y de Knoxville, Tennessee así como en los más 
grandes tales como Chicago, en donde un alboroto de cuatro días en 
1919 dejó dos docena americanos africanos muertos y más de 300 
dañados. Pero el alboroto de la raza de Tulsa era quizás el 
peor. En hecho, el alboroto de 24 horas de Tulsans blanco era 
uno de los alborotos más viciosos y más intensos de la raza de la 
historia americana antes o puesto que, dando por resultado la muerte 
dondequiera a partir de 75 a 250 personas y quemarse de más de 1.000 
hogares y negocios negros. Blanco de Walter, funcionario del 
NAACP, viajado a Tulsa en disfraz para examinar el daño causado por 
el alboroto de 1921 razas. Su informe, uno de muchos artículos 
sobre el alboroto, fue publicado en la nación en el verano de 1921.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086931</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107012</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-eruption-of-tulsa-an-naacp-official-investigates-the-tulsa-race-riot-of-1921</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
