<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106220</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106220</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206228</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Water Resources Education Resources</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wasser-Betriebsmittel-Ausbildung Betriebsmittel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ressources D'Éducation de Ressources d'Eau</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Recursos Da Instrução Dos Recursos De Água</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Risorse Di Formazione Delle Risorse idriche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς εκπαίδευσης των υδάτινων πόρων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recursos De la Educación De los Recursos De Agua</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a collection of classroom activities that teach students about the properties of water. There is an interactive center where students can give opinions and test their water knowledge, FrogWeb, which focuses on amphibian declines and deformities, free education posters on wetlands and water use, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Ansammlung Klassenzimmeraktivitäten, die
Kursteilnehmer über die Eigenschaften des Wassers unterrichten. 
Es gibt eine interaktive Mitte, in der Kursteilnehmer Urteile 
abgeben und ihr Wasserwissen prüfen können, FrogWeb, das Foki auf 
amphibisch Abnahmen und Mißbildungen, freie Ausbildung Plakate auf 
Sumpfgebieten und Wassergebrauch und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une collection d'activités de salle de classe
qui enseignent des étudiants au sujet des propriétés de l'eau. 
Il y a un centre interactif où les étudiants peuvent donner 
des avis et tester leur connaissance de l'eau, FrogWeb, qui des foyers
sur des déclins et des défauts de forme amphibies, des affiches 
libres d'éducation sur des marécages et l'utilisation de l'eau, et
plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma coleção das atividades da sala de aula 
que ensinam estudantes sobre as propriedades da água. Há um 
centro interativo onde os estudantes possam dar opiniões e testar seu
conhecimento da água, FrogWeb, que focos em declínios e em 
deformities amphibian, posteres livres da instrução em wetlands e em
uso da água, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una collezione di attività dell'aula che 
insegnano gli allievi circa le proprietà di acqua. Ci è un 
centro interattivo in cui gli allievi possono esprimere i pareri e 
verificare la loro conoscenza dell'acqua, FrogWeb, che fuochi sui 
declini e sulle deformità amfibi, manifesti liberi di formazione sui 
wetlands e sull'uso dell'acqua e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια συλλογή των δραστηριοτήτων τάξεων που 
διδάσκουν τους σπουδαστές για τις ιδιότητες του ύδατος. 
Υπάρχει ένα διαλογικό κέντρο όπου οι σπουδαστές μπορούν 
να εκφέρουν τις γνώμεις και να εξετάσουν τη γνώση ύδατός τους, 
FrogWeb, το οποίο εστιάζει στις αμφίβιες πτώσεις και τις 
παραμορφώσεις, ελεύθερες αφίσες εκπαίδευσης στους υγρότοπους και 
τη χρήση ύδατος, και περισσότερο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una colección de las actividades de la sala de
clase que enseñan a estudiantes sobre las características del agua. 
Hay un centro interactivo donde los estudiantes pueden dar 
opiniones y probar su conocimiento del agua, FrogWeb, que los focos en
declinaciones y deformidades anfibias, los carteles libres de la 
educación en wetlands y uso del agua, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206228</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106220</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/water-resources-education-resources</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
