<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104758</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104758</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206974</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Travelers in the Middle East Archive</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reisende im Mittlere Osten-Archiv</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Voyageurs dans des archives de le Moyen-Orient</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Viajantes no arquivo de o Oriente Médio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Viaggiatori nell'archivio di Medio Oriente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ταξιδιώτες στο αρχείο της Μέσης Ανατολής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hojas de ruta (traveler) en el archivo de el 
Oriente Medio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">focuses on Western interactions with the Middle East, particularly travels to Egypt during the 19th and early 20th centuries. It features texts (such as travel narratives), photos and images of Egypt, and maps of Egypt and Cyprus. More than 40 educational modules (many about Egypt) put materials in context and help students see how historical research is done.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Foki auf westlichen Interaktionen mit dem 
Mittlere Osten, besonders Spielräume nach Ägypten während des 19. 
und früh 20. Jahrhunderte. Es kennzeichnet Texte (wie 
Spielraumdarstellungen), Fotos und Bilder von Ägypten und Karten von 
Ägypten und von Zypern. Mehr als 40 pädagogische gesetzte 
Materialien der Module (viele über Ägypten) in den Kontext- und 
Hilfenkursteilnehmern sehen, wie historische Forschung erfolgt ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">foyers sur des interactions occidentales avec le 
Moyen-Orient, en particulier voyages en Egypte pendant la 19ème et 
début du 20ème siècles. Elle comporte des textes (tels que 
des récits de voyage), des photos et des images de l'Egypte, et des 
cartes de l'Egypte et de la Chypre. Plus de 40 matériaux mis 
éducatifs des modules (beaucoup au sujet de l'Egypte) dans des 
étudiants de contexte et d'aide voient comment la recherche 
historique est faite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">focos em interações ocidentais com o Oriente 
Médio, particularmente cursos a Egipto durante o 1ø e cedo 20os 
séculos. Caracteriza textos (tais como narrativas do curso), 
fotos e imagens de Egipto, e mapas de Egipto e de Chipre. Mais 
de 40 materiais postos educacionais dos módulos (muitos sobre Egipto)
em estudantes do contexto e da ajuda vêem como a pesquisa histórica 
é feita.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fuochi sulle interazioni occidentali con 
Medio Oriente, specialmente corse nell'Egitto durante il diciannovesimo 
ed inizio del 20esimo secoli. Caratterizza i testi (quali le 
descrizioni di corsa), foto ed immagini dell'Egitto e programmi 
dell'Egitto e della Cipro. Più di 40 materiali messi educativi 
dei moduli (molti circa l'Egitto) negli allievi di aiuto e di contesto
vedono come la ricerca storica è fatta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εστίαση στις δυτικές αλληλεπιδράσεις με τη Μέση 
Ανατολή, ιδιαίτερα ταξίδια στην Αίγυπτο κατά τη διάρκεια του 
19$ου και 20οί νωρίς αιώνες. Χαρακτηρίζει τα κείμενα (όπως
τα αφηγήματα ταξιδιού), τις φωτογραφίες και τις εικόνες της 
Αιγύπτου, και τους χάρτες της Αιγύπτου και της Κύπρου. 
Περισσότερες από 40 εκπαιδευτικές ενότητες (πολλές για 
την Αίγυπτο) βάζουν τα υλικά στο πλαίσιο και οι σπουδαστές 
οδηγιών βλέπουνε πώς η ιστορική έρευνα γίνεται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">focos en interacciones occidentales con el Oriente
Medio, determinado recorridos a Egipto durante el diecinueveavo y 
temprano vigésimos siglos. Ofrece los textos (tales como 
narrativas del recorrido), las fotos y las imágenes de Egipto, y las 
correspondencias de Egipto y de Chipre. Más de 40 materiales 
puestos educativos de los módulos (muchos sobre Egipto) en 
estudiantes del contexto y de la ayuda consideran cómo se hace la 
investigación histórica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206974</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104758</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/travelers-in-the-middle-east-archive</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
