<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105471</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105471</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086296</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Stumbled on the Place by Sheer Accident": Oscar Ameringer Discovers the Cincinnati Public Library in 1888</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich stolperte auf den Platz durch Sheer 
Accident": Oscar Ameringer entdeckt die Cincinnati allgemeine 
Bibliothek 1888</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"j'ai trébuché sur l'endroit par Sheer Accident"
: L'oscar Ameringer découvre la bibliothèque publique de
Cincinnati en 1888</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu tropecei no lugar por Sheer Acidente": 
Oscar Ameringer descobre a biblioteca pública de Cincinnati em 
1888</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ho inciampato sul posto da Sheer Accident": 
Oscar Ameringer scopre la biblioteca pubblica de Cincinnati in 
1888</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"σκόνταψα στη θέση από το καθαρό ατύχημα": 
Θ*Οσθαρ Ameringer Discovers η δημόσια βιβλιοθήκη του 
Κινκινάτι το 1888</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"tropecé en el lugar de Sheer Accident": 
Oscar Ameringer descubre la biblioteca pública de Cincinnati en
1888</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Libraries in the late 19th century were seen by their founders as instruments of social and cultural uplift, meant to raise the working class out their ignorance and teach them how to be middle class. But men like Oscar Ameringer, who immigrated to the United States from Germany when he was 15 and later became a socialist organizer, humorist, and editor, took away different lessons. In this selection from his 1940 autobiography, Ameringer described his discovery of American history books, translated into German, at the local public library.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bibliotheken im des späten 19. jahrhunderts 
Jahrhundert wurden von ihren Gründern als Instrumente von Sozial 
gesehen und kulturelle Erhebung, bedeutete, die Funktion Kategorie aus
ihrer Unwissenheit anzuheben und ihnen zu unterrichten, wie man 
mittlere Kategorie ist. Aber Männer mögen Oscar Ameringer, das
in die Vereinigten Staaten aus Deutschland einwanderte, als er 15 war 
und ein sozialistischer Organisator, ein Humorist und ein Herausgeber 
später wurden, wegnahmen unterschiedliche Lektionen. In dieser 
Auswahl von seiner Autobiographie 1940, beschrieb Ameringer seine 
Entdeckung der amerikanischen Geschichte Bücher, übersetzt in 
Deutschen, an der lokalen allgemeinen Bibliothek.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des bibliothèques vers la fin du 19ème siècle 
ont été vues par leurs fondateurs comme instruments de social et le 
soulèvement culturel, a signifié pour soulever la classe ouvrière 
hors de leur ignorance et pour leur enseigner comment être la 
bourgeoisie. Mais les hommes aiment l'Oscar Ameringer, qui
a immigré aux Etats-Unis d'Allemagne quand il avait 15 ans et plus en
retard sont devenus un organisateur, un humoriste, et un éditeur 
socialistes, ont emporté différentes leçons. Dans cette 
sélection à partir de sa autobiographie 1940, Ameringer a décrit sa
découverte des livres américains d'histoire, traduite en Allemand, 
à la bibliothèque publique locale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As bibliotecas no 1ø século atrasado foram 
vistas por seus founders como instrumentos de social e o uplift 
cultural, significou levantar a classe de funcionamento para fora de 
seu ignorance e ensinar-lhe como ser classe média. Mas os 
homens gostam de Oscar Ameringer, que immigrated aos estados unidos de
Germany quando era 15 e mais atrasado se tornaram um organizer, um 
humorist, e um editor socialist, fizeram exame de lições diferentes 
ausentes. Nesta seleção de seu autobiography 1940, Ameringer 
descreveu sua descoberta de livros americanos do history, traduzida no
alemão, na biblioteca pública local.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le librerie verso la fine del diciannovesimo 
secolo sono state viste dai loro fondatori come strumenti di sociale 
ed il uplift culturale, ha significato sollevare il codice categoria 
di funzionamento verso l'esterno la loro ignoranza ed insegnare loro 
come essere codice categoria centrale. Ma gli uomini gradiscono 
Oscar Ameringer, che immigrated al unito Dichiara dalla 
Germania quando era 15 e più in ritardo sono diventato un 
organizzatore, un humorist e un editore socialisti, ha tolto le 
lezioni differenti. In questa selezione dal suo autobiography 
1940, Ameringer ha descritto la sua scoperta dei libri americani di 
storia, tradotta in tedesco, alla biblioteca pubblica locale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι βιβλιοθήκες προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα 
εβλέίδαν από τους ιδρυτές τους όπως τα όργανα της 
κοινωνικής και πολιτιστικής ανόδου, σήμαναν να αυξήσουν την 
εργατική τάξη έξω η άγνοιά τους και να τις διδάξουν πώς να 
είναι μέση κλάση. Αλλά τα άτομα συμπαθούν τον Oscar 
Ameringer, ο οποίος μετανάστευσε στα ενωμένα κράτη από τη 
Γερμανία όταν ήταν 15 και έγινε αργότερα σοσιαλιστικός 
διοργανωτής, ευθυμογράφος, και ο επεξεργαστής, πήρε μακριά τα 
διαφορετικά μαθήματα. Σε αυτήν την επιλογή από την 
αυτοβιογραφία του 1940 του, Ameringer περιέγραψε την 
ανακάλυψή του αμερικανικών βιβλίων ιστορίας, που μεταφράστηκε 
στα γερμανικά, στην τοπική δημόσια βιβλιοθήκη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las bibliotecas en la a fines del siglo XIX fueron
vistas por sus fundadores como instrumentos de social y el 
levantamiento cultural, significó levantar la clase obrera fuera de 
su ignorancia y enseñarle cómo ser clase media. Pero los 
hombres tienen gusto de Oscar Ameringer, que immigrated a los Estados 
Unidos de Alemania cuando él era 15 y más adelante hicieron un 
organizador, un humorista, y editor socialistas, quitaron diversas 
lecciones. En esta selección de su autobiografía 1940, 
Ameringer describió su descubrimiento de los libros americanos de la 
historia, traducido a alemán, en la biblioteca pública local.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086296</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105471</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-stumbled-on-the-place-by-sheer-accident-oscar-ameringer-discovers-the-cincinnati-public-library-in-1888</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
