<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102902</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102902</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087018</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The People Versus the Private Army</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Leute gegen die private Armee</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les personnes contre l'armée privée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os povos contra o exército confidencial</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La gente contro l'esercito riservato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι άνθρωποι εναντίον του ιδιωτικού στρατού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La gente contra el ejército privado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Labor conflicts in Pennsylvania's coal mines and steel mills during the nineteenth and early-twentieth centuries were usually violent. In order to insure that they had the upper hand and to avoid relying on local police (who were sometimes sympathetic to strikers), mine and mill operators set up their own "Coal and Iron Police" as early as the 1870s. Public reaction against these private armies led the Pennsylvania legislature to create a Department of State Police as an ostensibly more neutral and highly-trained law enforcement body. But the cure turned out to be worse than the disease. In the 1910 strike at Bethlehem Steel, the state police proved to be as pro-management as the Coal and Iron Police and even more brutal. The following testimony from workers and labor leaders appearing before the U.S. Commission on Industrial Relations in 1915 underscored the anger and discontent of common laborers with the military mindset of the newly formed Pennsylvania State Police.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Arbeit $überschneidungen in den Kohlengruben 
Pennsylvanias und in den Stahltausendsteln während der 19. und 
früh-zwanzigsten Jahrhunderte waren normalerweise heftig. Um zu
versichern daß sie die obere Hand hatten und auf lokale Polizei (wer 
zu bauen vermeiden zu den Schlaggeräten manchmal sympatisch waren), 
führten Grube und die Tausendstelbediener, die herauf ihre Selbst 
"Kohle-und Eisen-Polizei" schon in der allgemeinen Reaktion 1870s. 
gegen diese privaten Armeen eingestellt wurden die Pennsylvania 
Gesetzgebung ein Außenministerium Polizei als anscheinend Null- und 
hoch-ausgebildeter Gesetzdurchführungkörper zu erstellen. Aber
die Heilung fiel aus, als die Krankheit falscher zu sein. Im 
Schlag 1910 am Bethlehem Stahl, prüfte die Zustandpolizei, als 
Pro-Management als die Kohle-und Eisen-Polizei und sogar brutaleres zu
sein. Das folgende Zeugnis von den Arbeitern und von 
Gewerkschaftsführern, die vor der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Kommission auf 
industriellen Beziehungen zwischen den Sozialpartnern in 1915 
erscheinen, unterstrich den Zorn und die Unzufriedenheit der gemeinen 
Arbeiter mit der militärischen Denkrichtung der eben gebildeten 
Pennsylvania Zustand-Polizei.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les conflits de travail dans les mines de houille 
de la Pennsylvanie et les aciéries pendant les dix-neuvième et 
tôt-vingtième siècles étaient habituellement violents. Afin 
d'assurer qu'elles ont eu le dessus et pour éviter de compter sur la 
police locale (qui étaient parfois sympathiques aux butées), la mine
et les opérateurs de moulin ont installé leurs propres "charbon et 
la police de fer" dès la réaction 1870s. publique contre ces armées
privées a mené la législature de la Pennsylvanie à créer un 
service de police d'état comme corps en apparence plus neutre et 
haut-qualifié d'application de loi. Mais le traitement s'est 
avéré être plus mauvais que la maladie. Dans la grève 1910 
à l'acier de Bethlehem, la police d'état s'est avérée être comme 
pro-gestion en tant que la police de charbon et de fer et bien plus 
brutal. Le témoignage suivant des ouvriers et des dirigeants 
syndicaux apparaissant devant la Commission des ETATS-UNIS sur des 
relations industrielles dans 1915 a souligné la colère et le 
mécontentement des travailleurs communs avec la mentalité militaire
de la police nouvellement formée d'état de la Pennsylvanie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os conflitos do trabalho em minas de carvão de 
Pensilvânia e nos moinhos de aço durante os décimos nonos e 
cedo-vigésimos séculos eram geralmente violentos. A fim 
segurar que teve a mão superior e para evitar de confiar em polícias
locais (quem eram às vezes sympathetic aos grevistas), a mina e os 
operadores do moinho ajustados acima do seus próprios de "polícias 
carvão e de ferro" assim que a reação 1870s. pública de encontro a
estes exércitos confidenciais conduziram à legislatura de 
Pensilvânia criar um departamento de polícias do estado como um 
corpo ostensibly mais neutro e elevado-treinado do enforcement de lei.
Mas a cura girou para fora para ser mais má do que a doença. 
Na batida 1910 no aço de Bethlehem, as polícias do estado 
provaram ser como a pro-gerência como as polícias de carvão e de 
ferro e mesmo mais brutal. O seguinte testimony dos 
trabalhadores e dos líderes labor que aparecem antes do commission de
ESTADOS UNIDOS em relações industriais em 1915 underscored a raiva e
o discontent de laborers comuns com o mindset militar das polícias 
recentemente dadas forma do estado de Pensilvânia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I conflitti di lavoro nelle miniere di 
carbone della Pensilvania ed in acciaierie durante i diciannovesimi e 
presto-ventesimi secoli erano solitamente violenti. Per 
assicurare che hanno avute la mano superiore ed evitare di contare 
sulla polizia locale (chi erano a volte simpatici ai percussori), la 
miniera e gli operatori del laminatoio installano il loro propri 
"carbone e la polizia del ferro" fin dal 1870s. che la reazione del 
pubblico contro questi eserciti riservati ha condotto la legislatura 
della Pensilvania creare un reparto di Dichiara la polizia 
come corpo apparentemente più neutro ed alto-addestrato di 
applicazione di legge. Ma la cura è risultato essere più 
difettosa della malattia. Nel colpo 1910 all'acciaio de 
Bethlehem, la polizia di dichiarare è risultato essere come 
pro-gestione come la polizia del ferro e del carbone ed ancor più 
brutale. La seguente testimonianza dagli operai e dai 
capi di lavoro che compaiono prima della Commissione 
degli STATI UNITI sulle relazione industriali in 1915 ha sottolineato 
la rabbia ed il discontent dei lavoratori comuni con il mindset 
militare della Pensilvania recentemente formata Dichiara la 
polizia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι συγκρούσεις εργασίας στα ορυχεία άνθρακα της 
Πενσυλβανίας και τους μύλους χάλυβα κατά τη διάρκεια των δέκατων
έννατων και πρόωρος-εικοστών αιώνων ήταν συνήθως βίαιες. 
Προκειμένου να ασφαλιστεί ότι είχαν το ανώτερο χέρι και 
για να αποφύγει στην τοπική αστυνομία (που ήταν μερικές φορές 
συμπονετική στους απεργούς), το ορυχείο και οι χειριστές μύλων 
ίδρυσαν το "άνθρακά τους και η αστυνομία σιδήρου" από τη 
1870s. δημόσια αντίδραση ενάντια σε αυτούς τους ιδιωτικούς 
στρατούς οδήγησε το νομοθετικό σώμα της Πενσυλβανίας για να 
δημιουργήσει ένα τμήμα κρατικής αστυνομίας ως φαινομενικά πιό 
ουδέτερο και ιδιαίτερα-εκπαιδευμένο σώμα επιβολής νόμου. 
Αλλά η θεραπεία αποδείχθηκε χειρότερη από την ασθένεια. 
Στην απεργία του 1910 στο χάλυβα της Βηθλεέμ, η κρατική 
αστυνομία αποδείχθηκε ως υπέρ-διαχείριση ως αστυνομία άνθρακα 
και σιδήρου και ακόμα πιό βάναυσος. Η ακόλουθη κατάθεση 
από τους εργαζομένους και τους ηγέτες εργασίας που εμφανίζονται 
ενώπιον της ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Επιτροπής στις εργασιακές σχέσεις το 
1915 υπογράμμισε το θυμό και τη δυσαρέσκεια των κοινών 
laborers με τη στρατιωτική νοοτροπία της πρόσφατα διαμορφωμένης
κρατικής αστυνομίας της Πενσυλβανίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los conflictos del trabajo en las minas de carbón
de Pennsylvania y los molinos de acero durante los diecinueveavo y 
temprano-vige'simos siglos eran generalmente violentos. Para 
asegurar que tenían la mano superior y evitar de confiar en el 
policía local (quiénes eran a veces comprensivos a los huelguistas),
la mina y los operadores del molino fijados encima sus los propios 
"policía del carbón y del hierro" desde la reacción pública 1870s.
contra estos ejércitos privados condujeron a legislatura de 
Pennsylvania a crear un departamento del policía del estado como 
cuerpo aparentemente de más neutral y de alto-entrenado de la 
aplicación de ley. Pero la curación resultó ser peor que la 
enfermedad. En la huelga 1910 en el acero de Bethlehem, el 
policía del estado demostró estar como favorable-gerencia como el 
policía del carbón y del hierro y aún más brutal. El 
testimonio siguiente de los trabajadores y de los arranques de cinta 
de trabajo que aparecían ante la Comisión de ESTADOS UNIDOS en 
relaciones laborales en 1915 subrayó la cólera y el descontento de 
trabajadores comunes con el mindset militar del policía nuevamente 
formado del estado de Pennsylvania.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087018</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102902</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-people-versus-the-private-army</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
