<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105604</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105604</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211995</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Rwanda: You Go, Girls!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ruanda: Sie Gehen, Mädchen!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Rwanda : Vous Allez, Des Filles !</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Rwanda: Você Vai, Meninas!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Ruanda: Andate, Ragazze!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ρουάντα: Πηγαίνετε, κορίτσια!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Rwanda: ¡Usted Va, Las Muchachas!</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The PBS WIDE ANGLE documentary series analyzes a number of significant and current global issues. In 'Ladies First' (2004), WIDE ANGLE delivers a riveting report on the political and socio-economic success of the Rwandan women after the genocide of 1994 that divided the country's major ethnic groups, the Tutsi and the Hutu. The purpose of this lesson is to use 'Ladies First' to show not only that women working together can and did create a dialogue and a basis for trust among ethnic groups, but also to show how these same women are challenging their traditional role in Rwandan society and assuming unprecedented leadership. Although the basis of the lesson is the success of women in Rwanda post-genocide, the lesson begins with a clip from the movie HOTEL RWANDA, which establishes the devastating brutality of 1994 that left the country in utter ruin. As a Culminating Activity, students will use various Web sites to hone skills needed for the Global Studies Regents Exam, including: analyzing statistical, economic, and demographic information; a map exercise; and the interpretation of a primary document. </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die PBS dokumentarische Weitwinkelserie analysiert eine 
Anzahl von bedeutenden und aktuellen globalen Ausgaben. ' in den
Damen zuerst ' (2004), Weitwinkel liefert einen befestigenden Bericht 
über den politischen und sozioökonomischen Erfolg der Rwandan Frauen
nach dem Genozid von 1994, der die ethnischen 
hauptsächlichgruppen des Landes, den Tutsi und den Hutu teilte. 
Der Zweck dieser Lektion ist, ' Damen zuerst zu verwenden ', um 
zu zeigen nicht nur daß die Frauen, die zusammen arbeiten können und
einen Dialog und eine Grundlage für Vertrauen unter ethnischen 
Gruppen erstellten, aber auch zu zeigen, wie diese gleichen Frauen 
ihre traditionelle Rolle in der Rwandan Gesellschaft und in 
anmaßender beispielloser Führung schwierig sind. Obgleich die 
Grundlage der Lektion der Erfolg der Frauen in Ruanda post-Genozid 
ist, fängt die Lektion mit einem Clip vom Film HOTEL RUANDA an, das 
die verheerenden Brutalitäten von 1994 herstellt, denen nach links 
das Land innen Ruine äußern. Als kulminierende 
Aktivität benutzen Kursteilnehmer verschiedene Web-Sites, um die 
Fähigkeiten abzuziehen, die für die globale Studien Regents Prüfung
benötigt werden und schließen ein: statistische, ökonomische 
und demographische Informationen Analysierens; eine Karte 
Übung; und die Deutung eines Primärdokumentes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La série documentaire GRANDE-ANGULAIRE de PBS analyse un 
certain nombre de questions globales significatives et actuelles. 
Dans les 'dames en premier '(2004), GRAND-ANGULAIRE fournit un 
état de rivetage sur le succès politique et socio-économique des 
femmes rwandaises après le génocide de 1994 qui a divisé les 
groupes ethniques principaux du pays, le Tutsi et le 
Hutu. Le but de cette leçon est d'utiliser les 'dames en
premier 'pour prouver non seulement que les femmes travaillant 
ensemble peuvent et ont créé un dialogue et une base pour la 
confiance parmi les groupes ethniques, mais pour montrer également 
comment ces mêmes femmes sont provocantes leur rôle traditionnel 
dans la société rwandaise et la conduite sans précédent 
arrogante. Bien que la base de la leçon soit le succès des 
femmes au Rwanda post-génocide, la leçon commence par un clip de 
l'HÔTEL RWANDA de film, qui établit la brutalité dévastatrice de 
1994 qui à gauche le pays dans la ruine totale. Comme activité
culminante, les étudiants emploieront de divers sites de Web 
pour rectifier des qualifications requises pour les Régents 
globaux examen d'études, incluant : l'information statistique, 
économique, et démographique d'analyse ; un exercice de carte 
; et la traduction d'un document primaire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A série documentary do ÂNGULO LARGO de PBS analisa um 
número de edições globais significativas e atuais. ' em 
senhoras primeiramente ' (2004), o ÂNGULO LARGO entrega um relatório
rebitando no sucesso político e socio-economic das mulheres rwandan 
após o genocide de 1994 que dividiu os grupos étnicos principais do 
país, o tutsi e o hutu. A finalidade desta lição é usar 
primeiramente ' senhoras ' mostrar para mostrar não somente que as 
mulheres que trabalham junto podem e criaram um diálogo e uma base 
para a confiança entre grupos étnicos, mas também como estas mesmas
mulheres são challenging seu papel tradicional na sociedade rwandan e
em liderança unprecedented presumida. Embora a base da lição 
seja o sucesso das mulheres no borne-genocide de Rwanda, a lição 
começa com um grampo do HOTEL RWANDA do filme, que estabelece o 
brutality devastating de 1994 que à esquerda o país na ruína 
totala. Como uma atividade culminando, os estudantes usarão 
vários locais do Web afiar as habilidades necessitadas para o exam 
global de Regents dos estudos, incluindo: informação 
estatística, econômica, e demográfica da análise; um 
exercício do mapa; e a interpretação de um original 
preliminar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La serie documentaria GRANDANGOLARE di PBS analizza un 
certo numero di questioni globali significative ed attuali. 'in 
signore in primo luogo '(2004), GRANDANGOLARE trasporta un rapporto di
rivettamento sul successo politico e socio-economico delle donne 
rwandan dopo il genocide di 1994 che ha diviso i gruppi etnici 
principali del paese, il tutsi ed il hutu. Lo scopo di questa 
lezione è usare 'le signore in primo luogo 'per indicare non soltanto
che le donne che lavorano insieme possono ed hanno creato un dialogo e
una base per fiducia fra i gruppi etnici, ma anche mostrare come 
queste stesse donne sono challenging il loro ruolo tradizionale nella 
società rwandan e nella direzione senza precedente assuming. 
Anche se la base della lezione è il successo delle donne in 
alberino-genocide della Ruanda, la lezione comincia con una clip 
dall'HOTEL RUANDA di film, che stabilisce il brutality 
devastating di 1994 che a sinistra il paese in rovina assoluta. 
Come attività di culminazione, gli allievi useranno i vari 
luoghi di Web per smerigliatrice le abilità state necessarie per il 
exam globale di Regents di studi, includendo: le informazioni 
statistiche, economiche e demografiche analizzare; 
un'esercitazione del programma; ed interpretazione di un 
documento primario.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αποδεικτική σειρά PBS WIDE.ANGLE αναλύει 
διάφορα σημαντικά και παρόντα παγκόσμια ζητήματα. "Στις 
κυρίες πρώτα" (2004), WIDE.ANGLE παραδίδει μια έκθεση 
καρφώματος σχετικά με την πολιτική και κοινωνικοοικονομική 
επιτυχία των της Ρουάντα γυναικών μετά από τη γενοκτονία του 
1994 που διαίρεσε τις σημαντικές εθνικές ομάδες της χώρας, 
τους Tutsi και τους Hutu. Ο σκοπός αυτού του μαθήματος 
είναι να χρησιμοποιηθούν "οι κυρίες πρώτα" για να επιδείξει όχι 
μόνο ότι οι γυναίκες που εργάζονται μαζί μπορούν και 
δημιούργησαν ένα διαλογικό παράθυρο και μια βάση για την 
εμπιστοσύνη μεταξύ των εθνικών ομάδων, αλλά και για να επιδείξει
πώς αυτές οι ίδιες γυναίκες προκαλούν τον παραδοσιακό ρόλο τους
στην της Ρουάντα κοινωνία και υποθέτουν την πρωτοφανή ηγεσία. 
Αν και η βάση του μαθήματος είναι η επιτυχία των γυναικών 
στην μετα-γενοκτονία της Ρουάντα, το μάθημα αρχίζει με έναν 
συνδετήρα από το ΞΕΝΟΔΟΧΕΙΟ ΡΟΥΑΝΤΑ κινηματογράφων, το οποίο 
καθιερώνει την καταστρεπτική βιαιότητα του 1994 που άφησε τη 
χώρα στην παντελή καταστροφή. Σαν καταλήγοντας 
δραστηριότητα, οι σπουδαστές θα χρησιμοποιήσουν τους διάφορους 
ιστοχώρους για να ακονίσουν τις δεξιότητες που απαιτούνται για το 
σφαιρικό διαγωνισμό αντιβασιλέων μελετών, που περιλαμβάνει: 
ανάλυση των στατιστικών, οικονομικών, και δημογραφικών 
πληροφοριών  μια άσκηση χαρτών  και η ερμηνεία ενός 
αρχικού εγγράφου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La serie documental GRANANGULAR de PBS analiza un número 
de ediciones globales significativas y actuales. En ' señoras 
primero ' (2004), GRANANGULAR entrega un informe que clava sobre el 
éxito político y socioeconómico de las mujeres rwandan después del
genocidio de 1994 que dividió a los grupos étnicos principales del 
país, al tutsi y a hutu. El propósito de esta lección es 
utilizar a ' señoras primero ' para mostrar no solamente que las 
mujeres que trabajan juntas pueden y crearon un diálogo y una base 
para la confianza entre grupos étnicos, pero también mostrar cómo 
estas mismas mujeres son desafiadoras su papel tradicional en sociedad
rwandan y la dirección sin precedente asumida. Aunque la base 
de la lección es el éxito de mujeres en Rwanda post-genocidio, la 
lección comienza con un clip del HOTEL RWANDA de la película, que 
establece la brutalidad devastadora de 1994 que a la izquierda el 
país en ruina completa. Como actividad que culmina, los 
estudiantes utilizarán varios sitios del Web para afilar con 
piedra las habilidades necesitadas para los Regentes globales 
examen de los estudios, incluyendo: información estadística, 
económica, y demográfica el analizar; un ejercicio de la 
correspondencia; y la interpretación de un documento primario.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MARGARET FAY
FN:MARGARET FAY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211995</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105604</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/rwanda-you-go-girls</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
