<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105209</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105209</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201273</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Digging Up the Dirt on Soil Microbes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Graben herauf den Schmutz auf Boden-Mikroben</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Creuser vers le haut de la saleté sur des 
microbes de sol</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Escavar acima da sujeira em micróbios do solo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scavando sulla sporcizia sui microbi del terreno</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Να σκάψει επάνω το ρύπο στα εδαφολογικά μικρόβια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El cavar encima de la suciedad en microbios del 
suelo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This hands-on exercise introduces students, grades K-8, to the idea of soil as a habitat for many different organisms, links between the biological adaptation of an organism and the physical demands of its habitat, and identification of soil and aquatic organisms. The activity includes objectives, standards addressed, materials needed, teaching tips, procedure, questions with potential answers, summary of learned material, and additional resources. The exercise was a product of the Soil and Environmental Camp June 2003. PDF document.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Blindeinschub Übung stellt Kursteilnehmer, 
Grade K-8, zur Idee des Bodens als Lebensraum für viele 
unterschiedliche organismen, Links zwischen der biologischen Anpassung
eines Organismus und den körperlichen Nachfragen seines Lebensraums 
und Kennzeichen des Bodens und der Wasserorganismen vor. Die 
Aktivität schließt Lernziele, die Standards, die adressiert werden, 
die benötigten Materialien, die unterrichtenden Spitzen, Prozedur, 
Fragen mit möglichen Antworten, Zusammenfassung des gelehrten 
Materials und zusätzliche Betriebsmittel ein. Die Übung war 
ein Produkt des Bodens und des Klimalagers Juni 2003. Pdf 
Dokument.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet exercice à commande manuelle présente des 
étudiants, les catégories K-8, à l'idée du sol comme habitat pour 
beaucoup de différentes organizations, liens entre l'adaptation 
biologique d'une organization et les demandes physiques de son 
habitat, et identification de sol et d'organizations aquatiques. 
L'activité inclut des objectifs, des normes adressées, des 
matériaux requis, des extrémités d'enseignement, le procédé, des 
questions avec des réponses potentielles, le sommaire du matériel 
instruit, et des ressources supplémentaires. L'exercice était 
un produit du sol et du camp environnemental juin 2003. Document
de pdf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este exercício hands-on introduz estudantes, 
classes K-8, à idéia do solo como um habitat para muitos organismos 
diferentes, ligações entre a adaptação biológica de um organismo 
e as demandas físicas de seu habitat, e identificação do solo e de 
organismos aquáticos. A atividade inclui objetivos, padrões 
dirigidos, materiais necessitados, pontas ensinando, procedimento, 
perguntas com respostas potenciais, sumário de material instruído, e
recursos adicionais. O exercício era um produto do solo e do 
acampamento ambiental junho 2003. Original do pdf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa esercitazione hands-on introduce gli 
allievi, i gradi K-8, all'idea di terreno come habitat per molti 
organismi differenti, i collegamenti fra l'adattamento biologico di un
organismo e le richieste fisiche del relativo habitat e 
l'identificazione di terreno e degli organismi acquatici. 
L'attività include gli obiettivi, gli standard indirizzati, i 
materiali stati necessari, le punte d'istruzione, la procedura, le 
domande con le risposte potenziali, il sommario di materiale istruito 
e le risorse supplementari. L'esercitazione era un prodotto del 
terreno e dell'accampamento ambientale giugno del 2003. 
Documento del pdf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η εμπράγματη άσκηση εισάγει τους σπουδαστές, 
βαθμολογεί Κ-8, στην ιδέα του χώματος ως βιότοπο για πολλούς 
διαφορετικούς οργανισμούς, συνδέσεις μεταξύ της βιολογικής 
προσαρμογής ενός οργανισμού και των φυσικών απαιτήσεων του 
βιότοπού της, και του προσδιορισμού του χώματος και των υδρόβιων 
οργανισμών. Η δραστηριότητα περιλαμβάνει τους στόχους, τα 
πρότυπα που εξετάζονται, τα υλικά που απαιτούνται, τις άκρες 
διδασκαλίας, τη διαδικασία, τις ερωτήσεις με τις πιθανές 
απαντήσεις, την περίληψη του μαθημένου υλικού, και τα πρόσθετα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς. Η άσκηση ήταν ένα προϊόν του 
χώματος και του περιβαλλοντικού στρατόπεδου 2003, Ιουνίου 
έγγραφο PDF.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este ejercicio con manos introduce a estudiantes, 
grados K-8, a la idea del suelo como habitat para muchos diversos 
organismos, las conexiones entre la adaptación biológica de un 
organismo y las demandas físicas de su habitat, y la identificación 
del suelo y de los organismos acuáticos. La actividad incluye 
objetivos, los estándares tratados, los materiales necesitados, las 
extremidades de enseñanza, procedimiento, preguntas con respuestas 
potenciales, el resumen del material docto, y recursos adicionales. 
El ejercicio era un producto del suelo y del campo ambiental 
junio de de 2003. Documento del pdf.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KURT WILLIAMSON
FN:KURT WILLIAMSON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:INSTITUTE OF SOIL AND ENVIRONMENTAL ECOLOGY, UNIVERSITY OF DELAWARE
FN:INSTITUTE OF SOIL AND ENVIRONMENTAL ECOLOGY, UNIVERSITY OF DELAWARE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201273</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105209</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/digging-up-the-dirt-on-soil-microbes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
