<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104655</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104655</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205811</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Jazz in America: National Jazz Curriculum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jazz in Amerika: Nationaler Jazz-Lehrplan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jazz en Amérique : Programme d'études 
National de Jazz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jazz em América: Curriculum Nacional Do 
Jazz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Jazz in America: Programma di studi 
Nazionale Di Jazz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τζαζ στην Αμερική: Εθνικό πρόγραμμα σπουδών τζαζ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Jazz en América: Plan de estudios Nacional 
Del Jazz</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The school offers lessons for teaching about jazz in American history or music class for Grades 5, 8, and 11. Learn about the evolution of jazz, different jazz styles, improvisation, basic musical elements, and how jazz influenced (and was influenced by) American culture. 	The mission of The Thelonious Monk Institute of Jazzis to offer public school-based jazz education programs for young people around the world, helping students develop imaginative thinking, creativity, curiosity, a positive self image, and a respect for their own and others' cultural heritage.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Schule bietet Lektionen für das Unterrichten 
über Jazz in der amerikanischen Geschichte oder Musikkategorie für 
Grade 5, 8 und 11 an. Erlernen Sie über die Entwicklung von 
Jazz, unterschiedliche Jazzarten, Improvisation, grundlegende 
musikalische Elemente und wie Jazz (und wurde vorbei beeinflußt), 
amerikanische Kultur beeinflußte. Die Mission des Thelonious 
Mönch-Instituts von Jazzis, zum der allgemeinen school-based 
Jazzausbildung Programme für junge Leute um die Welt anzubieten, 
helfende Kursteilnehmer entwickeln das phantasiereiche Denken, 
Kreativität, Neugier, ein positives Selbstbild und einen Respekt für
ihre Selbst- und andere kulturelles Erbe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'école offre des leçons pour enseigner au sujet
du jazz dans la classe américaine d'histoire ou de musique pour les 
catégories 5, 8, et 11. Renseignez-vous sur l'évolution du 
jazz, différents modèles de jazz, improvisation, les éléments 
musicaux de base, et comment le jazz a influencé (et a été 
influencé près) la culture américaine. La mission de 
l'institut de moine de Thelonious de Jazzis pour offrir des programmes
scolaires publics d'éducation de jazz pour les jeunes autour du 
monde, les étudiants aidants développent la pensée imaginative, la 
créativité, la curiosité, une image positive d'art de l'auto-portrait, et un 
respect pour leurs propres et d'autres acquis culturel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A escola oferece lições para ensinar sobre o 
jazz na classe americana do history ou da música para as classes 5, 
8, e 11. Aprenda sobre a evolução do jazz, estilos diferentes 
do jazz, improvisation, elementos musicais básicos, e como o jazz 
influenciou (e foi influenciado perto) a cultura americana. A 
missão do instituto do monk de Thelonious de Jazzis para oferecer 
programas school-based públicos da instrução do jazz para povos 
novos em torno do mundo, estudantes de ajuda desenvolve pensar 
imaginative, creatividade, curiosidade, uma imagem positiva do self, e
um respeito para seus próprios e outros heritage cultural.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La scuola offre le lezioni per l'istruzione circa 
il jazz nel codice categoria americano di musica o di storia per i 
gradi 5, 8 e 11. Impari circa lo sviluppo di jazz, stili 
differenti di jazz, improvvisazione, elementi musicali di base e come 
il jazz ha influenzato (ed è stato influenzato vicino) la coltura 
americana. La missione dell'istituto del monk di Thelonious di 
Jazzis per offrire i programmi school-based pubblici di formazione di 
jazz per i giovani intorno al mondo, allievi d'assistenza sviluppa 
pensare immaginativo, la creatività, la curiosità, un'immagine 
positiva di auto e un rispetto per il loro propri ed altri eredità 
culturale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το σχολείο προσφέρει τα μαθήματα για τη διδασκαλία για
την τζαζ στην αμερικανική κλάση ιστορίας ή μουσικής για τους 
βαθμούς 5 ..8, και 11, μαθαίνουν για την εξέλιξη της τζαζ, 
διαφορετικές μορφές τζαζ, αυτοσχεδιασμός, βασικά μουσικά 
στοιχεία, και πώς η τζαζ επηρέασε (και επηρεάστηκε κοντά) τον 
αμερικανικό πολιτισμό. Η αποστολή του ιδρύματος μοναχών 
Thelonious Jazzis για να προσφέρει τα δημόσια σχολικά 
προγράμματα εκπαίδευσης τζαζ για τους νέους σε όλο τον κόσμο, που
βοηθά τους σπουδαστές να αναπτύξουν την επινοητική σκέψη, τη 
δημιουργικότητα, την περιέργεια, μια θετική μόνη εικόνα, και 
έναν σεβασμό της και άλλοι πολιτιστικής κληρονομιάς τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La escuela ofrece las lecciones para enseñar 
sobre jazz en la clase americana de la historia o de la música para 
los grados 5, 8, y 11. Aprenda sobre la evolución del jazz, 
diversos estilos del jazz, improvisación, los elementos musicales 
básicos, y cómo el jazz influenció (y fue influenciado cerca) la 
cultura americana. La misión del instituto del monk de 
Thelonious de Jazzis para ofrecer los programas school-based públicos
de la educación del jazz para la gente joven alrededor del mundo, los
estudiantes que ayudan desarrolla el pensamiento imaginativo, la 
creatividad, la curiosidad, una imagen positiva del uno mismo, y un 
respecto por sus el propios y otros patrimonio cultural.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205811</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104655</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/jazz-in-america-national-jazz-curriculum</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
