<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105193</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105193</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206556</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Federal Judicial Center</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bundesgerichtsmitte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Centre Juridique Fédéral</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Centro Judicial Federal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Centro Giudiziario Federale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ομοσπονδιακό δικαστικό κέντρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Centro Judicial Federal</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is the education and research agency for the federal courts. Learn about the federal court system - how the various courts work, are organized, and fit into the U.S. system of government. See histories of the Supreme Court, courts of appeals, district courts, circuit courts, and other courts. Find units for teaching about notable federal trials -- the Sedition Act trials, the Aaron Burr treason trial, Amistad, Chinese exclusion and the federal courts, and others.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist die Ausbildung und Forschung Agentur für die
Bundesgerichtshöfe. Erlernen Sie über das 
Bundesgerichtshofsystem - wie die verschiedenen Gerichte arbeiten, 
werden organisiert und passen in die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Staatsform. 
Sehen Sie Geschichten des Höchsten Gerichts, Gerichte von 
Anklänge, Amtsgerichte, Schwurgerichte und andere Gerichte. 
Finden Sie Maßeinheiten für das Unterrichten über 
bemerkenswerte Bundesversuche -- die Sedition-Tat Versuche, der Aaron 
GratVerratversuch, das Amistad, chinesischer Ausschluß und die 
Bundesgerichtshöfe und andere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est l'agence d'éducation et de recherches pour 
les cours fédérales. Renseignez-vous sur le système de cour 
fédérale - comment les diverses cours fonctionnent, sont organisés,
et s'adaptent dans le système des ETATS-UNIS du gouvernement. 
Voir des histoires de la cour suprême, des cours des appels, 
des cours de zone, des cours de circuit, et d'autres cours. 
Trouvez les unités pour enseigner au sujet des épreuves 
fédérales notables -- les épreuves de Loi de sedition, l'épreuve 
de trahison de bavures d'Aaron, l'Amistad, exclusion chinoise et 
les cours fédérales, et d'autres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é a agência da instrução e da pesquisa para 
as cortes federais. Aprenda sobre o sistema de corte federal - 
como as várias cortes trabalham, são organizados, e cabidos no 
sistema de ESTADOS UNIDOS de governo. Veja histories da corte 
suprema, cortes de apelações, cortes de distrito, cortes de 
circuito, e outras cortes. Encontre unidades para ensinar sobre 
experimentações federais notáveis -- as experimentações do ato do
sedition, a experimentação do treason da rebarba de Aaron, o 
Amistad, exclusão chinesa e as cortes federais, e outras.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è l'agenzia di ricerca e di formazione per le 
corti federali. Impari circa il sistema di corte federale - come
le varie corti funzionano, sono organizzati ed inseriscono nel sistema
degli STATI UNITI del governo. Veda i dati storici della Corte 
suprema, le Corti d'Appello, le corti di distretto, le corti di 
circuito ed altre corti. Trovi le unità per l'istruzione circa 
le prove federali notevoli -- le prove di Legge di sedition, la prova 
del treason della bava di Aaron, il Amistad, esclusione cinese e 
le corti federali ed altre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι η αντιπροσωπεία εκπαίδευσης και έρευνας για τα 
ομοσπονδιακά δικαστήρια. Μάθετε για το ομοσπονδιακό σύστημα
δικαστηρίων - πώς η διάφορη εργασία δικαστηρίων, οργανώνεται, 
και εναρμόνιση στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ σύστημα της κυβέρνησης. 
Δείτε τις ιστορίες του ανώτατου δικαστηρίου, των 
Εφετείων, των περιφερειακών δικαστηρίων, των δικαστηρίων 
κυκλωμάτων, και άλλων δικαστηρίων. Βρείτε τις μονάδες για 
τη διδασκαλία για τις ξεχωριστές ομοσπονδιακές δίκες -- οι δίκες 
νόμων στασιασμού, η δίκη προδοσίας σαλιασμάτων του Aaron, το 
Amistad, ο κινεζικός αποκλεισμός και τα ομοσπονδιακά 
δικαστήρια, και άλλα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es la agencia de la educación y de la 
investigación para las cortes federales. Aprenda sobre el 
sistema judicial federal - cómo las varias cortes trabajan, se 
ordenan, y caben en el sistema de ESTADOS UNIDOS del gobierno. 
Vea las historias del Tribunal Supremo, los tribunales de 
apelación, las cortes de districto, las cortes de circuito, y otras 
cortes. Encuentre las unidades para enseñar sobre los ensayos 
federales notables -- los ensayos del acto de la sedición, el ensayo 
de la traición de las rebabas de Aaron, el Amistad, exclusión china
y las cortes federales, y otras.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206556</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105193</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/federal-judicial-center</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
