<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108069</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108069</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209767</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Learning about Camera Lenses</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lernen über Kameraobjektive</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Se renseigner sur des objectifs d'appareil-photo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aprendizagem sobre lentes de câmera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Imparando circa gli obiettivi di macchina 
fotografica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκμάθηση για τους φακούς φωτογραφικών μηχανών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El aprender sobre las lentes de cámara 
fotográfica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this lesson, you will learn that: A wide angle lens creates a mood which is cold and distant. A telephoto lens creates a mood which is very warm, comfortable and close. A neutral lens (half way between a telephoto and a wide angle) creates a neutral, almost boring scene. When you create the 3D storyboards for Seduced by the Dark Side!, the camera must help you create many moods. Therefore we need to learn what moods are possible with lenses.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Lektion erlernen Sie das: Ein 
Weitwinkelobjektiv erstellt eine Stimmung, die kalt und entfernt ist. 
Ein Telephotoobjektiv erstellt eine Stimmung, die sehr warm ist,
bequem und schließt. Ein Nullobjektiv (halbe Methode zwischen 
einem Telephoto und einem Weitwinkel) erstellt ein Neutrales, fast 
langweilige Szene. Wenn Sie die storyboards 3D für Seduced 
durch die dunkle Seite! erstellen, die Kamera muß Ihnen helfen,
viele Stimmungen zu erstellen. Folglich müssen wir erlernen, 
welche Stimmungen mit Objektiven möglich sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette leçon, vous apprendrez cela : Un
objectif grand-angulaire crée une humeur qui est froide et 
éloignée. Un objectif de téléobjectif crée une humeur qui 
est très chaude, confortable et se ferme. Un objectif neutre 
(demi de voie entre un téléobjectif et un grand-angulaire) crée un 
point mort, scène presque ennuyeuse. Quand vous créez les 
storyboards 3D pour séduit par le côté en noir !, 
l'appareil-photo doit vous aider à créer beaucoup de modes. 
Par conséquent nous devons apprendre quels modes sont possibles
avec des objectifs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta lição, você aprenderá aquele: Uma 
lente larga do ângulo cría um modo que seja frio e distante. 
Uma lente do telephoto cría um modo que esteja muito morno, 
confortável e fecha-se. Uma lente neutra (meia maneira entre um
telephoto e um ângulo largo) cría um ponto morto, cena quase 
aborrecida. Quando você criar os storyboards 3D para seduzido 
pelo lado escuro!, a câmera deve ajudar-lhe criar muitos modos.
Conseqüentemente nós necessitamos aprender que modos são 
possíveis com lentes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa lezione, imparerete quello: Un 
obiettivo grandangolare crea un umore che è freddo e distante. 
Un obiettivo del telephoto crea un umore che è molto caldo, 
comodo e si chiude. Un obiettivo neutro (modo mezzo fra un 
telephoto e un grandangolare) crea un neutrale, scena quasi noiosa. 
Quando create gli storyboards 3D per sedotto dal lato scuro!, 
la macchina fotografica deve aiutarla a creare molti 
atteggiamenti. Di conseguenza dobbiamo imparare che 
atteggiamenti sono possibili con gli obiettivi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το μάθημα, θα μάθετε ότι: Ένας φακός 
wide.angle δημιουργεί μια διάθεση που είναι κρύα και απόμακρη.
Ένας φακός telephoto δημιουργεί μια διάθεση που είναι 
πολύ θερμή, άνετη και στενή. Ένας ουδέτερος φακός (μισός
μεταξύ ενός telephoto και ενός wide.angle) δημιουργεί μια 
ουδέτερη, τρυπώντας σχεδόν σκηνή. Όταν δημιουργείτε τα 
τρισδιάστατα storyboards για παραπλανημένος από τη σκοτεινή 
πλευρά!, η φωτογραφική μηχανή πρέπει να σας βοηθήσει να 
δημιουργήσετε πολλές διαθέσεις. Επομένως πρέπει να μάθουμε
ποιες διαθέσεις είναι δυνατές με τους φακούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta lección, usted aprenderá eso: Una 
lente granangular crea un humor que sea frío y distante. Una 
lente del telephoto crea un humor que sea muy caliente, cómodo y se 
cierra. Una lente neutral (media manera entre un telephoto y un 
granangular) crea a hilo neutro, escena casi aburrida. Cuando 
usted crea los storyboards 3D para seducido por la cara oscura!, 
la cámara fotográfica debe ayudarle a crear muchos humores. 
Por lo tanto necesitamos aprender qué humores son posibles con 
las lentes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209767</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">GNU Free Documentation License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108069</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/learning-about-camera-lenses</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
