<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103211</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103211</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207039</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Civil War Soldier in the Wildcat Regiment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Bürgerkrieg-Soldat im wilden Regiment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un soldat de guerre civile dans le régiment 
sauvage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um soldado da guerra civil no regiment 
desorganizado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un soldato di guerra civile nel regiment 
selvaggio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας στρατιώτης εμφύλιου πολέμου στο παράτολμο 
σύνταγμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un soldado de la guerra civil en el regimiento 
salvaje</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A Civil War Soldier in the Wild Cat Regiment: Selections from the Tilton C. Reynolds Papers documents the Civil War experience of Captain Tilton C. Reynolds, a member of the 105th Regiment of Pennsylvania Volunteers. Comprising 164 library items, or 359 digital images, this online presentation includes correspondence, photographs, and other materials dating between 1861 and 1865. The letters feature details of the regiment's movements, accounts of military engagements, and descriptions of the daily life of soldiers and their views of the war. Forty-six of the letters are also made available in transcription.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Bürgerkrieg-Soldat im wilden Katze-Regiment: 
Anwählungen vom Tilton C. Reynolds Papers dokumentiert die 
Bürgerkriegerfahrung des Kapitäns Tilton C. Reynolds, ein Bauteil 
des 105. Regiments der Pennsylvania Freiwilliger. 164 
Bibliothekeinzelteile oder 359 digitalisierte Bilder enthalten, 
schließt diese Onlinedarstellung Korrespondenz, Fotographien und 
andere Materialien, die zwischen 1861 und 1865 datieren ein. Die
Zeichen kennzeichnen Details der Bewegungen des Regiments, Konten der 
militärischen Verpflichtungen und Beschreibungen des täglichen 
Lebens der Soldaten und ihrer Ansichten des Krieges. Forty-six 
der Zeichen werden auch in der Übertragung zur Verfügung gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un soldat de guerre civile dans le régiment 
sauvage de chat : Les sélections à partir du Tilton C. 
Reynolds Papers documente l'expérience de guerre civile de capitaine 
Tilton C. Reynolds, un membre du 105th régiment des volontaires de la
Pennsylvanie. Comportant 164 éléments de bibliothèque, ou 359
images digitales, cette présentation en ligne inclut la 
correspondance, les photographies, et d'autres matériaux datant entre
1861 et 1865. Les lettres comportent des détails des mouvements
du régiment, des comptes des engagements militaires, et des 
descriptions de la vie quotidienne des soldats et de leurs vues de la 
guerre. Forty-six des lettres sont également rendus disponible 
dans la transcription.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um soldado da guerra civil no regiment selvagem do
gato: As seleções do Tilton C. Reynolds Papel documentam a 
experiência da guerra civil do capitão Tilton C. Reynolds, um membro
do 105th regiment de voluntários de Pensilvânia. Compreendendo
164 artigos da biblioteca, ou 359 imagens digitais, esta 
apresentação em linha inclui a correspondência, as fotografias, e 
os outros materiais que datam entre 1861 e 1865. As letras 
caracterizam detalhes dos movimentos do regiment, clientes de 
acoplamentos militares, e descrições da vida diária dos soldados e 
de suas vistas da guerra. Forty-six das letras é feito também 
disponível na transcrição.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un soldato di guerra civile nel regiment selvaggio
del gatto: Le selezioni dal Tilton C. Reynolds Papers documenta 
l'esperienza di guerra civile nel capitano Tilton C. Reynolds, un 
membro del 105th regiment dei volontari della Pensilvania. 
Contenendo 164 articoli delle biblioteche, o 359 immagini 
digitali, questa presentazione in linea include la corrispondenza, le 
fotografie ed altri materiali che datano fra 1861 e 1865. Le 
lettere caratterizzano i particolari dei movimenti del regiment, i 
clienti degli impegni militari e le descrizioni della vita quotidiana 
dei soldati e dei loro punti di vista della guerra. Forty-six 
delle lettere egualmente è reso disponibile nella trascrizione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας στρατιώτης εμφύλιου πολέμου στο άγριο σύνταγμα 
γατών: Οι επιλογές από Tilton Γ. Ρέυνολντς έγγραφα 
τεκμηριώνουν την εμπειρία εμφύλιου πολέμου του καπετάνιου 
Tilton C. Reynolds, ένα μέλος του 105th συντάγματος των
εθελοντών της Πενσυλβανίας. Περιλαμβάνοντας 164 
αντικείμενα βιβλιοθηκών, ή 359 ψηφιακές εικόνες, αυτή η σε 
απευθείας σύνδεση παρουσίαση περιλαμβάνει την αλληλογραφία, τις 
φωτογραφίες, και άλλα υλικά που χρονολογούν μεταξύ 1861 και 
1865. Οι επιστολές χαρακτηρίζουν τις λεπτομέρειες των 
μετακινήσεων, των απολογισμών των στρατιωτικών δεσμεύσεων, και των
περιγραφών του συντάγματος της καθημερινής ζωής των στρατιωτών 
και των όψεών τους του πολέμου. Σαράντα έξι από τις 
επιστολές παρέχονται επίσης στη μεταγραφή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un soldado de la guerra civil en el regimiento 
salvaje del gato: Las selecciones del Tilton C. Reynolds Papers 
documentan la experiencia de la guerra civil de capitán Tilton C. 
Reynolds, miembro del 10ö regimiento de los voluntarios de 
Pennsylvania. Abarcando 164 items de la biblioteca, o 359 
imágenes digitales, esta presentación en línea incluye 
correspondencia, las fotografías, y otros materiales que fechan entre
1861 y 1865. Las cartas ofrecen los detalles de los movimientos 
del regimiento, las cuentas de contratos militares, y las 
descripciones de la vida de cada día de soldados y de sus opiniones 
de la guerra. Forty-six de las cartas también se hace 
disponible en la transcripción.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207039</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103211</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/a-civil-war-soldier-in-the-wildcat-regiment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
