<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102920</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102920</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207228</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Constitution: Counter Revolution or National Salvation?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Beschaffenheit: Gegenumdrehung oder 
nationale Rettung?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Constitution : Contre- révolution ou 
salut national ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Constitution: Volta contrária ou 
salvation nacional?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Costituzione: Contro giro o Salvezza 
nazionale?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το σύνταγμα: Αντίθετη επανάσταση ή εθνική 
σωτηρία;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Constitución: ¿Revolución contraria o 
salvación nacional?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">casts students in the role of politically active citizens in 1787, when the Federal Convention in Philadelphia presented the nation with a new model of government. Students, using primary documents from American Memory, produce a broadside in which they argue for or against replacing the Articles of Confederation with the new model?the Constitution.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">wirft Kursteilnehmer in der Rolle der politisch aktiven 
Bürger 1787, als die Bundesversammlung in Philadelphia die Nation mit
einem neuen Modell der Regierung darstellte. Kursteilnehmer mit 
Primärdokumenten vom amerikanischen Speicher, produzieren eine 
Breitseite, in der sie für oder gegen das Ersetzen der Artikel des 
Bündnisses mit der neuen model?the Beschaffenheit argumentieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">moule des étudiants dans le rôle des citoyens 
politiquement actifs en 1787, quand la convention fédérale à 
Philadelphie a présenté la nation avec un nouveau modèle de 
gouvernement. Les étudiants, en utilisant les documents 
primaires de la mémoire américaine, produisent un flanc dans 
pour lequel ils discutent ou contre substituer les articles de la 
confédération avec la nouvelle constitution de model?the.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">molda estudantes no papel de cidadãos polìtica ativos em
1787, quando a convenção federal em Filadélfia apresentou a nação
com um modelo novo do governo. Os estudantes, usando originais 
preliminares da memória americana, produzem um broadside em que 
discutem para ou de encontro a substituir os artigos do confederation 
com o constitution novo do model?the.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">lancia gli allievi nel ruolo dei cittadini politicamente 
attivi in 1787, quando la convenzione federale a Filadelfia ha 
presentato la nazione con un nuovo modello del governo. Gli 
allievi, usando i documenti primari dalla memoria americana, producono
un attacco in cui parlano per o contro la sostituzione degli 
articoli di confederazione con la nuova costituzione del model?the.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">πετά τους σπουδαστές στο ρόλο των πολιτικά ενεργών 
πολιτών το 1787, όταν παρουσίασε η ομοσπονδιακή Συνθήκη στη 
Φιλαδέλφεια στο έθνος με ένα νέο μοντέλο της κυβέρνησης. 
Οι σπουδαστές, που χρησιμοποιούν τα αρχικά έγγραφα από την 
αμερικανική μνήμη, παράγουν broadside στο οποίο μιλούν ή 
ενάντια στην αντικατάσταση των άρθρων της συνομοσπονδίας με το 
νέο σύνταγμα model?the.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">echa a estudiantes en el papel de ciudadanos político 
activos en 1787, cuando la convención federal en Philadelphia 
presentó la nación con un nuevo modelo del gobierno. Los 
estudiantes, usando documentos primarios de la memoria americana, 
producen un costado en para el cual discutan o contra substituir 
los artículos de la confederación por la nueva constitución del 
model?the.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207228</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102920</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-constitution-counter-revolution-or-national-salvation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
