<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103080</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103080</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087480</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Chicago under the mob."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Chicago unter dem Pöbel."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Chicago sous la foule."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Chicago sob o mob."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Chicago sotto il mob."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Σικάγο κάτω από τον όχλο."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Chicago bajo la multitud."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1894, a strike at the Pullman Palace Car Company spread across the nation as the American Railway Union organized a national boycott and strike against all trains hauling Pullman cars. Strikers were met with the full force of company and government might. Thirty-four people were killed in two weeks of clashes between troops and workers across the nation. An ardent admirer of the military, artist-reporter Frederic Remington displayed no sympathy for the Pullman strikers in his reports for  Harper's Weekly . Endorsing suppression, Remington described the strikers as a "malodorous crowd of foreign trash" talking "Hungarian or Polack, or whatever the stuff is."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1894 bildet ein Schlag an der Pullman Palace Car Company 
Verbreitung über der Nation, da der amerikanische Bahnanschluß 
organisierte, ein nationaler Boykott und Schlag gegen alle das 
Schleppen der Pullmanautos aus. Schlaggeräte wurden die volle 
Kraft der Firma getroffen und Regierung konnte. Thirty-four 
Leute wurden in zwei Wochen Zusammentreffen zwischen Truppen und 
Arbeitern über der Nation beendet. Ein leidenschaftlicher 
Bewunderer des Militärs, Künstler-Reporter Frederic Remington zeigte
keine Sympathie für die Pullmanschlaggeräte in seinen Reports für 
Wochenzeitung Harpers an. Ausgleich indossierend, beschrieb 
Remington die Schlaggeräte als "malodorous Masse des fremden Abfalls"
sprechen"Ungar oder Polack, oder was auch immer das Material ist."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1894, une grève à la diffusion de Pullman Palace Car 
Company à travers la nation car l'union ferroviaire américaine a 
organisé un boycott national et la grève contre toutes forme 
transporter des voitures de pullman. Des butées ont été 
rencontrées la pleine force de la compagnie et le gouvernement 
pourrait. Des personnes de Thirty-four ont été détruites en 
deux semaines de désaccords entre les troupes et les ouvriers à 
travers la nation. Un admirateur ardent des militaires, 
artiste-journaliste Frederic Remington n'a affiché aucune sympathie 
pour les butées de pullman dans ses états pour l'hebdomadaire de 
Harper. Approuvant la suppression, Remington a décrit les 
butées comme "foule malodorante Hongrois" parlant "ou Polack de 
détritus étranger, ou celui qui la substance est."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1894, uma batida na propagação de Pullman Palácio 
Carro Companhia através da nação porque a união railway americana 
organizou um boycott nacional e a batida de encontro a todas treinam 
transportar carros do Pullman. Os grevistas foram encontrados 
com com a força cheia da companhia e o governo pôde. Os povos 
de Thirty-four foram matados em duas semanas dos clashes entre tropas 
e trabalhadores através da nação. Um admirador ardent das 
forças armadas, artista-repórter Frederic Remington não indicou 
nenhum sympathy para os grevistas do Pullman em seus relatórios para 
o semanário de Harper. Endossando a supressão, Remington 
descreveu os grevistas como "multidão malodorous hungarian" falando 
um "ou um Polack do lixo extrangeiro, ou o que quer que o material 
é."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1894, un colpo alla diffusione del Pullman Palace Car 
Company attraverso la nazione poichè l'unione ferroviaria americana 
ha organizzato un boicottaggio nazionale ed il colpo contro tutto 
addestra il trasporto degli automobili del pullman. I percussori
sono stati incontrati la forza completa dell'azienda ed il governo 
potrebbe. La gente di Thirty-four è stata uccisa in due 
settimane dei disaccordi fra le truppe e gli operai attraverso la 
nazione. Un ammiratore ardent dei militari, artist-reporter 
Frederic Remington non ha visualizzato compassione per i percussori 
del pullman nei suoi rapporti per il settimanale del Harper. 
Firmando la soppressione, Remington ha descritto i percussori 
come "folla malodorous un ungherese" di comunicazione "o Polack dei 
rifiuti stranieri, o qualunque il roba è."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1894, μια απεργία στο Pullman Palace Car 
Company διέδωσε σε ολόκληρο το έθνος δεδομένου ότι η 
αμερικανική ένωση σιδηροδρόμων οργάνωσε ένα εθνικές 
μποϊκοτάρισμα και μια απεργία ενάντια σε όλα τα τραίνα που 
μεταφέρουν τα αυτοκίνητα Pullman. Οι απεργοί συναντήθηκαν
με την πλήρη δύναμη της επιχείρησης και η κυβέρνηση. 
Τριάντα τέσσερις άνθρωποι σκοτώθηκαν σε δύο εβδομάδες των 
διαφωνιών μεταξύ των στρατευμάτων και των εργαζομένων σε ολόκληρο
το έθνος. Ένας διακαής θαυμαστής του στρατιωτικού, 
καλλιτέχνης-δημοσιογράφος Frederic Remington δεν παρουσίασε 
καμία συμπόνοια για τους απεργούς Pullman στις εκθέσεις του για
την εβδομαδιαία έκδοση Harper. Επικυρώνοντας την 
καταστολή, Remington περιέγραψε τους απεργούς ως "δυσώδες 
πλήθος των ξένων απορριμμάτων" τα ομιλούν "ουγγρικά ή Polack,
ή οποιοσδήποτε η ουσία είναι."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1894, una huelga en la extensión de Pullman Palace Car
Company a través de la nación como la unión ferroviaria americana 
ordenó un boicoteo nacional y la huelga contra toda entrena a 
acarrear los coches del pullman. Los huelguistas fueron 
resueltos con la fuerza completa de la compañía y el gobierno pudo. 
Mataron a la gente de Thirty-four en dos semanas de choques 
entre las tropas y los trabajadores a través de la nación. Un 
admirador ardiente de los militares, artista-reportero Frederic 
Remington no visualizó ninguna condolencia para los huelguistas del 
pullman en sus informes para el semanario de Harper. Endosando 
la supresión, Remington describió los huelguistas como "muchedumbre 
maloliente un húngaro" que hablaba "o Polack de la basura no nativa, 
o lo que la materia es."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087480</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103080</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/chicago-under-the-mob</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
