<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104524</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104524</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206129</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Smithsonian: Science and Technology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Smithsonian: Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Smithsonien : La Science et technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Smithsonian: Ciência e tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Smithsonian: Scienza e tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σμιθσονιτικός: Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Smithsonian: Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores the Apollo 11 mission to the moon, Arctic wildlife, migratory birds, stars and black holes, sky watching, the Galapagos Islands, invasive species, living fossils of the Bahamian sea floor, views of earth, milestones of flight, shade grown coffee, species of Indian River Lagoon, the Chandra X-ray Observatory, polio, and portraits of famous scientists, inventors, and engineers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht die Apollo 11 Mission zum Mond, die 
arktische Wildnis, die wandernden Vögel, die Sterne und die schwarzen
Bohrungen, der Himmel, die, überwachen, die Galapagos-Inseln, 
Angriffssorte, lebende Fossilien des Bahamian Meeresgrundes, Ansichten
von Masse, Meilensteine des Fluges, Farbton angebauter Kaffee, Sorte 
der indischen Fluss-Lagune, die Chandra Röntgenstrahl-Sternwarte, 
Poliomyelitis und Portraits der berühmten Wissenschaftler, der 
Erfinder und der Ingenieure.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore la mission d'Apollo 11 à la lune, faune 
arctique, oiseaux migrateurs, tient le premier rôle et les trous noirs, le 
ciel observant, les îles de Galapagos, des espèces 
invahissantes, des fossiles vivants du fond sous-marin bahamien, 
des vues de la terre, des étapes importantes de vol, café cultivé 
par ombre, des espèces de lagune indienne de fleuve, 
l'observatoire de rayon X de Chandra, poliomyélite, et verticales des
scientifiques, des inventeurs, et des ingénieurs célèbres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora a missão de Apollo 11 à lua, os animais 
selvagens árticos, os pássaros migratory, as estrelas e os furos 
pretos, o céu prestando atenção, os consoles de Galápagos, 
espécie invasive, fossils vivos do assoalho de mar de Bahamian, 
vistas da terra, marcos miliários do vôo, café crescido máscara, 
espécie da lagoa indian do rio, o obervatório do raio X de Chandra, 
poliomielite, e retratos de cientistas, de inventores, e de 
coordenadores famosos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora la missione dell'Apollo 11 alla luna, la 
fauna selvatica artica, gli uccelli migratori, le stelle ed i fori 
neri, il cielo guardanti, le isole di galapagos, specie invasive, 
fossili viventi del pavimento di mare di Bahamian, viste di terra, 
pietre del volo, caffè coltivato schermo, specie di laguna indiana 
del fiume, l'osservatorio dei raggi X di Chandra, poliomelite e 
ritratti degli scienziati, degli inventori e degli assistenti 
tecnici famosi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξερευνά τον απόλλωνα 11 αποστολή στο φεγγάρι, την 
αρκτική άγρια φύση, τα μεταναστευτικά πουλιά, τα αστέρια και τις
μαύρες τρύπες, την προσοχή ουρανού, τα galapagos νησιά, της 
εισβολής είδη, απολιθώματα διαβίωσης του των Μπαχάμας πυθμένα 
θάλασσας, όψεις της γης, κύρια σημεία της πτήσης, αυξημένος 
σκιά καφές, είδη ινδικής λιμνοθάλασσας ποταμών, το των ακτίνων 
X παρατηρητήριο Chandra, η πολιομυελίτιδα, και τα πορτρέτα 
των διάσημων επιστημόνων, των εφευρετών, και των μηχανικών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora la misión de Apolo 11 a la luna, la fauna
ártica, los pájaros migratorios, las estrellas y los calabozos, el 
cielo mirando, las islas de las Islas Galápagos, especie invasora, 
los fósiles vivos del suelo de mar de Bahamian, las vistas de la 
tierra, los jalones del vuelo, café producido cortina, especie de la 
laguna india del río, el observatorio de la radiografía de Chandra, 
poliomielitis, y los retratos de científicos, de inventores, y de 
ingenieros famosos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206129</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104524</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/smithsonian-science-and-technology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
