<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107397</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107397</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206649</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Hoover Museum -- Just For Kids</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Staubsauger-Museum -- Gerade Für Zicklein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Musée d'Aspirateur -- Juste Pour des Gosses</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Museu Do Hoover -- Apenas Para Miúdos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Museo Del Hoover -- Appena Per I Capretti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το μουσείο Hoover -- ακριβώς για τα κατσίκια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Museo De la Aspiradora -- Apenas Para Los 
Cabritos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">portrays the life of President Hoover using resources from the Hoover Presidential Library such as a chronology, a biography of his wife, Lou Henry, excerpts from speeches, political cartoons, and texts by researchers. Also available is information on Laura Ingalls Wilder and her family and writings.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">schildert das Leben des Präsidenten Hoover mit 
Betriebsmitteln von der Staubsauger-Präsidentenbibliothek wie einem 
Chronologie, einer Biographie seiner Frau, Lou Henry, Excerpts von den
Reden, politischen Karikaturen und Texten durch Forscher. Auch 
sind Informationen über Laura wilderes Ingalls und ihre Familie und 
Schreiben vorhanden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dépeint la vie du Président Hoover en utilisant 
des ressources de la bibliothèque présidentielle d'aspirateur telle 
qu'une chronologie, une biographie de son épouse, Henry de Lou, des 
extraits des discours, des dessins animés politiques, et des textes 
par des chercheurs. En outre disponible est l'information sur 
Laura Ingalls plus sauvage et sa famille et écritures.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">portrays a vida do presidente Hoover usando 
recursos da biblioteca presidencial do hoover tal como um chronology, 
uma biografia de sua esposa, o Henry de Lou, os excerpts dos 
discursos, cartoons políticos, e textos por investigadores. 
Também disponível está a informação em Laura Ingalls mais 
selvagem e suas família e escritas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ritrae la vita del presidente Hoover usando le 
risorse dalla libreria presidenziale del hoover quali una cronologia, 
una biografia della sua moglie, il henry di Lou, i brani dai discorsi,
i fumetti politici ed i testi dai ricercatori. Egualmente 
disponibili sono le informazioni su Laura Ingalls più selvaggio e la 
sue famiglia e scritture.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">απεικονίζει τη ζωή του Προέδρου Hoover 
χρησιμοποιώντας τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς από τη Hoover 
προεδρική βιβλιοθήκη όπως μια χρονολογία, μια βιογραφία της 
συζύγου του, Lou Henry, αποσπάσματα από τις ομιλίες, τα 
πολιτικά κινούμενα σχέδια, και τα κείμενα από τους ερευνητές. 
Επίσης διαθέσιμες είναι οι πληροφορίες για τη Laura 
Ingalls Wilder και την οικογένεια και τις γραφές της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">retrata la vida de presidente Hoover usando 
recursos de la biblioteca presidencial de la aspiradora tal como una 
cronología, una biografía de su esposa, Henrio de Lou, extractos de 
discursos, historietas políticas, y textos de los investigadores. 
También disponible está la información sobre Laura Ingalls 
más salvaje y su familia y escrituras.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206649</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107397</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-hoover-museum-just-for-kids</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
