<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107963</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107963</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212182</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Solid Waste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Feststoff</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Déchets Solides</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Desperdício Contínuo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rifiuti solidi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στερεά απόβλητα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Basura Sólida</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This EPA clearinghouse provides comprehensive information related to solid waste prevention and disposal. Topics include industrial waste, pollution prevention, treatment and control, waste programs, cleanup, recycling, and EPA partnership programs. Each topic includes links to general information, fact sheets, regulations and publications. The information is presented in a clear and easy-to-understand format.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese EPA Verrechnungszentrale liefert die 
kompletten Informationen, die auf Feststoffverhinderung und 
-beseitigung in Verbindung gestanden werden. Themen schließen 
Industrieabfälle, Verunreinigung Verhinderung, Behandlung und 
Steuerung, überschüssige Programme, Reinigung, Wiederverwertung und 
EPA Teilhaberschaft Programme ein. Jedes Thema schließt Links 
zu den allgemeinen Informationen, zu den Tatsache Blättern, zu den 
Regelungen und zu den Publikationen ein. Die Informationen 
werden in einem freien Raum dargestellt und Format 
einfach-zu-verstehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette chambre de compensation d'EPA fournit des 
informations complètes liées à l'empêchement et à la disposition 
de déchets solides. Les sujets incluent la perte industrielle, 
l'empêchement de pollution, le traitement et la commande, les 
programmes de rebut, le nettoyage, réutilisation, et des programmes 
de l'association d'EPA. Chaque sujet inclut des liens aux 
informations générales, aux fiches documentaires , aux règlements 
et aux publications. L'information est présentée dans un 
espace libre et facile-à-comprend le format.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este clearinghouse de EPA fornece a informação 
detalhada relacionada à prevenção waste contínua e à 
eliminação. Os tópicos incluem o desperdício industrial, a 
prevenção da poluição, o tratamento e o controle, os programas 
waste, o cleanup, recycling, e da parceria de EPA programas. 
Cada tópico inclui as ligações à informação geral, às 
folhas do fato, aos regulamentos e às publicações. A 
informação é apresentada em um espaço livre e fácil-à-compreende
o formato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa stanza di compensazione di EPA fornisce le 
informazioni complete relative alla prevenzione ed all'eliminazione 
dei rifiuti solidi. I soggetti includono lo spreco industriale, 
prevenzione di inquinamento, trattamento e controllo, programmi 
residui, pulizia, riciclare e programmi di associazione di EPA. 
Ogni soggetto include i collegamenti a generalità, ai fogli di 
fatto, alle regolazioni ed alle pubblicazioni. Le informazioni 
sono presentate in una radura e facile-$$$-CAPISCONO il formato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το γραφείο συμψηφισμού EPA παρέχει τις 
εκτενείς πληροφορίες σχετικές με την πρόληψη και τη διάθεση 
στερεών αποβλήτων. Τα θέματα περιλαμβάνουν τα βιομηχανικά 
απόβλητα, την πρόληψη ρύπανσης, τη θεραπεία και τον έλεγχο, τα 
προγράμματα αποβλήτων, τον καθαρισμό, την ανακύκλωση, και τα 
προγράμματα συνεργασίας EPA. Κάθε θέμα περιλαμβάνει τις 
συνδέσεις με τις γενικές πληροφορίες, τα ενημερωτικά δελτία, τους
κανονισμούς και τις δημοσιεύσεις. Οι πληροφορίες 
παρουσιάζονται σε έναν σαφή και εύκολος-$$$-ΚΑΤΑΛΑΒΑΊΝΟΥΝ τη 
μορφή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta cámara de compensación de EPA proporciona a
la información comprensiva relacionada con la prevención inútil 
sólida y la disposición. Los asuntos incluyen la basura 
industrial, prevención de la contaminación, tratamiento y control, 
los programas inútiles, limpieza, reciclaje, y los programas de la 
sociedad de EPA. Cada asunto incluye conexiones a la 
información de carácter general, a las hojas del hecho, a las 
regulaciones y a las publicaciones. La información se presenta 
en un claro y fa'cil-a-entiende formato.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212182</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107963</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/solid-waste</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
