<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105881</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105881</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206202</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Practical Uses of Mathematics and Statistics and Science and Technology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Praktische Gebräuche von Mathematik und 
Statistiken und Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Utilisations pratiques des mathématiques et les 
statistiques et la Science et la technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Usos práticos da matemática e os statistics e a 
ciência e a tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Usi pratici di matematica e statistiche e scienza 
e tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρακτικές χρήσεις των μαθηματικών και των στατιστικών 
και επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aplicaciones prácticas de las matemáticas y 
estadística y ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers more than 60 one-page examples of how science and math can be used in interesting settings and everyday life. Topics include clouds (why they float), social security benefits (algebra), Pythagoras theorem (cabinet corners), ice sheets and sea level, logarithms, matching birthdays (statistics), natural selection and a scavenger hunt, photons, traffic signals (probability), seasons (causes), volcanic clouds, wind chill (algebra), and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet mehr als 60 Einseite Beispiele von an, wie 
Wissenschaft und Mathe in interessanten Einstellungen und in der 
täglichen Lebensdauer verwendet werden können. Themen 
enthalten Wolken (warum sie schwimmen), Sozialversicherungserträge 
(Algebra), Pythagoras Theorem (Schrankecken), Eisblätter und 
Meeresspiegel, die Logarithmen und bringen Geburtstage (Statistiken), 
natürliche Auswahl und eine Reinigerjagd, Photonen, Verkehrszeichen 
(Wahrscheinlichkeit), Jahreszeiten (Ursachen), vulkanische Wolken, ein
Windschauer (Algebra) und mehr zusammen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre plus de 60 exemples d'un-page de la façon 
dont la science et des maths peuvent être utilisées dans les 
configurations intéressantes et la vie quotidienne. Les sujets 
incluent des nuages (pourquoi ils flottent), des prestations de la 
sécurité sociale (algèbre), théorème de Pythagore (coins de 
module), des feuilles de glace et niveau de la mer, logarithmes, 
appariant des anniversaires (statistiques), sélection normale et une 
chasse à Scavenger, des photons, des feux de signalisation 
(probabilité), des saisons (causes), des nuages volcaniques, un froid
de vent (algèbre), et un plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece mais de 60 exemplos da um-página de como 
a ciência e o math podem ser usados em ajustes interessantes e na 
vida diária. Os tópicos incluem nuvens (porque flutuam), 
benefícios de segurança social (álgebra), theorem de Pythagoras 
(cantos do armário), folhas do gelo e nível de mar, logarítmos, 
combinando aniversários (statistics), seleção natural e uma caça 
do SCAVENGER, uns photons, uns sinais de tráfego (probabilidade), 
umas estações (causas), umas nuvens vulcânicas, um frio do vento 
(álgebra), e um mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre più di 60 esempi della un-pagina di come la
scienza ed il per la matematica possono essere usati nelle regolazioni
interessanti e nella vita di tutti i giorni. I soggetti 
includono le nubi (perchè galleggiano), indennità della previdenza 
sociale (algebra), teorema del Pythagoras (angoli) dell'armadietto, 
fogli del ghiaccio ed il livello del mare, logaritmi, abbinanti i 
compleanni (statistiche), la selezione naturale e un pulitore 
cerca, fotoni, segnali stradali (probabilità), stagioni 
(cause), nubi vulcaniche, freddo del vento (algebra) e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει περισσότερα από 60 μονοσέλιδα 
παραδείγματα για το πώς η επιστήμη και math μπορεί να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί στις ενδιαφέρουσες τιμές των παραμέτρων και την 
καθημερινή ζωή. Τα θέματα περιλαμβάνουν τα σύννεφα (γιατί 
επιπλέουν), τα οφέλη κοινωνικής ασφάλισης (άλγεβρα), το θεώρημα 
Πυθαγόρα (γωνίες γραφείων), τα φύλλα πάγου και τη στάθμη 
θάλασσας, λογάριθμοι, ταιριάζοντας με τα γενέθλια (στατιστικές), 
τη φυσική επιλογή και ένα κυνήγι οδοκαθαριστών, φωτόνια, τα 
σήματα κυκλοφορίας (πιθανότητα), τις εποχές (αιτίες), τα 
ηφαιστειακά σύννεφα, την ψύχρα αέρα (άλγεβρα), και 
περισσότερους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece más de 60 ejemplos de la uno-paginacio'n 
de cómo la ciencia y la matemáticas se pueden utilizar en 
configuraciones interesantes y vida diaria. Los asuntos incluyen
las nubes (porqué flotan), las ventajas de Seguridad Social 
(álgebra), teorema de Pythagoras (esquinas de la cabina), las hojas y
nivel del mar, logaritmos del hielo, correspondiendo con los 
cumpleaños (estadística), selección natural y una caza del 
limpiador, fotones, señales de tráfico (probabilidad), estaciones 
(causas), nubes volcánicas, una frialdad del viento (álgebra), y 
más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206202</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105881</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/practical-uses-of-mathematics-and-statistics-and-science-and-technology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
