<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107231</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107231</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086203</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"God Knows More about Time Than President Wilson": Letters against Daylight Saving</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Gott weiß mehr über Zeit als Präsident 
Wilson": Zeichen gegen Tageslicht-Einsparung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Dieu sait plus au sujet du temps que le 
Président Wilson" : Lettres contre l'économie de jour</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">o "deus sabe mais sobre o tempo do que o 
presidente Wilson": Letras de encontro ao saving da luz do dia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il dio conosce più circa tempo che il presidente
Wilson": Lettere contro il saving di luce del giorno</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο Θεός ξέρει περισσότερων για το χρόνο από τον 
Πρόεδρο Wilson": Επιστολές ενάντια στην αποταμίευση 
φωτός της ημέρας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el "dios sabe más sobre tiempo que presidente 
Wilson": Cartas contra el ahorro de la hora solar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The quest for efficiency touched nearly every aspect of American life during World War I, including the nation's clocks. Daylight saving first appeared during the war years as an experiment to save fuel. Theoretically, people would use less artificial light in the evenings thanks to the extra hour of daylight. Urban dwellers generally delighted in the "extra hour," but protests by farmers and other rural citizens brought the experiment to an end after only one year. Farmers, rural Americans, and those whose jobs forced them to work very early hours disliked the measure intensely. They bombarded Congress with petitions, letters, and angry telegrams demanding the return to "God's time." According to farmers, city dwellers who wanted more leisure in the afternoon could just show up for work an hour earlier and leave an hour earlier.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Suche nach Leistungsfähigkeit berührte fast 
jeden Aspekt der amerikanischen Lebensdauer während des Ersten 
Weltkrieges, einschließlich die Taktgeber der Nation. 
Tageslichteinsparung schien zuerst während der Kriegsjahre wie 
ein Experiment, Kraftstoff zu sichern. Theoretisch würden Leute
weniger künstliches Licht in den Abenddank die Überstunde des 
Tageslichts benutzen. Städtische Bewohner erfreuten im 
Allgemeinen sich in der "Überstunde,", aber Proteste durch Landwirte 
und andere landwirtschaftliche Bürger holten das Experiment zu einem 
Ende nach nur einem Jahr. Landwirte, landwirtschaftliche 
Amerikaner und die deren Jobs sie erzwangen, sehr frühe Stunden zu 
bearbeiten, lehnten das Maß intensiv ab. Sie bombardierten 
Kongreß mit Petitionen, Zeichen und den verärgerten Telegrammen, 
welche verlangen die Rückkehr "zur Zeit des Gottes." Nach 
Ansicht der Landwirte konnten Stadtbewohner, die wünschten, mehr 
Freizeit am Nachmittag für Arbeit ein die Stunde früher gerade oben 
darstellen und lassen eine Stunde früher.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La recherche pour l'efficacité a touché presque 
chaque aspect de vie américaine pendant la Première Guerre Mondiale,
y compris les horloges de la nation. L'économie de jour a 
semblé la première fois pendant les années de guerre comme une 
expérience sauvegarder le carburant. Théoriquement, les gens 
utiliseraient moins de lumière artificielle dans grâce de soirées 
à l'heure supplémentaire du jour. Les habitants urbains ont 
généralement enchanté dans "l'heure supplémentaire," mais les 
protestations par des fermiers et d'autres citoyens ruraux ont 
apporté l'expérience à une extrémité après seulement un an. 
Les fermiers, les Américains ruraux, et ceux dont les travaux 
les ont forcés à travailler des heures très tôt ont détesté la 
mesure intensément. Ils ont bombardé le congrès avec des 
pétitions, des lettres, et des télégrammes fâchés exigeant le 
retour au "temps de Dieu." Selon des fermiers, les habitants de 
ville qui ont voulu plus de loisirs l'après-midi pourraient juste 
révéler pour le travail par heure plus tôt et laissent une heure 
plus tôt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O quest para a eficiência tocou em quase cada 
aspecto da vida americana durante o world.war.i, including os pulsos 
de disparo da nação. O saving da luz do dia pareceu 
primeiramente durante os anos de guerra como uma experiência 
conservar o combustível. Teòrica, os povos usariam menos luz 
artificial nos agradecimentos das noites à hora extra da luz do dia. 
Os moradores urbanos deleitaram-se geralmente "na hora extra," 
mas os protestos por fazendeiros e por outros cidadãos rurais 
trouxeram a experiência a uma extremidade após somente um ano. 
Os fazendeiros, os americanos rurais, e aqueles cujos os 
trabalhos os forçaram a trabalhar horas muito adiantadas não 
gostaram da medida intensa. Bombardearam o congress com 
petições, letras, e os telegramas irritados que exigem o retorno do 
"ao tempo deus." De acordo com fazendeiros, os moradores da 
cidade que quiseram mais lazer na tarde poderiam apenas mostrar acima 
para o trabalho um a hora mais adiantada e deixam uma hora mais 
adiantada.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La ricerca per risparmio di temi ha toccato quasi 
ogni funzione di vita americana durante il world.war.i, compreso gli 
orologi della nazione. Il saving di luce del giorno in primo 
luogo è sembrato durante gli anni di guerra come un esperimento 
salvare il combustibile. Teoricamente, la gente userebbe meno 
luce artificiale in grazie di sere all'ora supplementare di luce del 
giorno. Gli abitanti urbani si dilettavano generalmente 
"nell'ora supplementare," ma le proteste dai coltivatori e da altri 
cittadini rurali hanno portato l'esperimento ad un'estremità dopo 
soltanto un anno. I coltivatori, gli Americani rurali e quelli 
di cui i lavori li hanno forzati lavorare le ore molto in anticipo 
hanno avuto antipatia per la misura intensamente. Hanno 
bombardato il congresso con le petizioni, le lettere ed i telegrammi 
arrabbiati che richiedono il ritorno "a tempo del dio." Secondo 
i coltivatori, gli abitanti della città che hanno desiderato più 
svago nel pomeriggio potrebbero rivelare appena per lavoro un l'ora 
più in anticipo e lasciano un'ora più in anticipo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αναζήτηση για την αποδοτικότητα άγγιξε σχεδόν κάθε 
πτυχή της αμερικανικής ζωής κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου 
πολέμου Ι, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των ρολογιών του έθνους. Η 
αποταμίευση φωτός της ημέρας εμφανίστηκε αρχικά κατά τη 
διάρκεια των πολεμικών ετών σαν ένα πείραμα να σώζει τα 
καύσιμα. Θεωρητικά, οι άνθρωποι θα χρησιμοποιούσαν το 
λιγότερο τεχνητό φως τα βράδια χάρι στην πρόσθετη ώρα του φωτός
της ημέρας. Οι αστικοί κάτοικοι ευχαρίστησαν γενικά στη 
"πρόσθετη ώρα," αλλά οι διαμαρτυρίες από τους αγρότες και 
άλλους αγροτικούς πολίτες έθεσαν τέλος στο πείραμα μετά από 
μόνο ένα έτος. Οι αγρότες, αγροτικοί Αμερικανοί, και 
εκείνοι οι των οποίων εργασίες τους ανάγκασαν για να 
λειτουργήσουν των πολύ στις αρχές ωρών αντιπάθησαν το μέτρο 
έντονα. Βομβάρδισαν το συνέδριο με τις αιτήσεις, τις 
επιστολές, καια τα τηλεγραφήματα που απαιτεί την επιστροφή στο 
"χρόνο του Θεού." Σύμφωνα με τους αγρότες, οι κάτοικοι 
πόλεων που θέλησαν περισσότερο ελεύθερο χρόνο το απόγευμα θα 
μπορούσαν ακριβώς να παρουσιάσουν για την εργασία μια ώρα 
νωρίτερα και να αφήσουν μιας ώρας πιό στις αρχές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La búsqueda para la eficacia tocó casi cada 
aspecto de la vida americana durante Primera Guerra Mundial, 
incluyendo los relojes de la nación. El ahorro de la hora solar
primero aparecía durante los años de guerra como un experimento 
salvar el combustible. Teóricamente, la gente utilizaría menos
luz artificial en los gracias de las tardes a la hora adicional de la 
hora solar. Los habitantes urbanos encantaron generalmente la 
"hora adicional," pero las protestas de los granjeros y de otros 
ciudadanos rurales trajeron el experimento a un extremo después de 
solamente un año. Los granjeros, los americanos rurales, y los 
que trabajos los forzaron trabajar horas muy tempranas tuvieron 
aversión la medida intenso. Bombardearon a congreso con 
peticiones, cartas, y telegramas enojados que exigían la vuelta al 
"tiempo del dios." Según granjeros, los habitantes de la ciudad
que desearon más ocio por la tarde podrían apenas mostrar para 
arriba para el trabajo a la hora anterior y dejan una hora anterior.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086203</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107231</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/god-knows-more-about-time-than-president-wilson-letters-against-daylight-saving</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
