<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105569</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105569</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206118</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Tsunamis and Earthquakes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tsunamis und Erdbeben</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tsunamis et tremblements de terre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tsunamis e terremotos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tsunamis e terremoti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Tsunamis και σεισμοί</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tsunamis y terremotos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">uses animation and virtual reality to show how tsumanis are generated by earthquakes. Learn about tsunami research and mitigation efforts -- how sediments are transported by a tsunami, how researchers decipher the geologic record of prehistoric tsunamis, and the seismograph network of the west coast tsunami warning system.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gebrauchanimation und virtuelle Wirklichkeit, zum 
zu zeigen, wie tsumanis durch Erdbeben festgelegt werden. 
Erlernen Sie über tsunami Forschung und Mitigationbemühungen 
-- wie Sedimente durch ein tsunami transportiert werden, wie Forscher 
den geologischen Satz der prähistorischen tsunamis dechiffrieren und 
das Seismographnetz der Westküste tsunami Warnanlage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">animation d'utilisations et réalité virtuelle 
pour montrer comment des tsumanis sont produits par des tremblements 
de terre. Renseignez-vous sur la recherche de tsunami et des 
efforts de réduction -- comment des sédiments sont transportés par 
un tsunami, comment les chercheurs déchiffrent l'enregistrement 
géologique des tsunamis préhistoriques, et le réseau de sismographe
du système d'avertissement de tsunami occidental de côte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">animation dos usos e realidade virtual para 
mostrar como os tsumanis são gerados por terremotos. Aprenda 
sobre a pesquisa do tsunami e esforços do mitigation -- como os 
sedimentos são transportados por um tsunami, como os investigadores 
decifram o registro geologic de tsunamis pré-históricos, e a rede do
seismograph do sistema de advertência do tsunami ocidental da costa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">animazione di usi e realtà virtuale per mostrare 
come i tsumanis sono generati dai terremoti. Impari circa 
ricerca di tsunami e sforzi di mitigation -- come i sedimenti sono 
trasportati da un tsunami, come i ricercatori decifrano il record 
geologico dei tsunamis prehistoric e la rete del sismografo del 
sistema d'avvertimento di tsunami ad ovest del litorale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χρησιμοποιεί τη ζωτικότητα και την εικονική 
πραγματικότητα για να επιδείξει πώς τα tsumanis παράγονται από
τους σεισμούς. Μάθετε για τις προσπάθειες έρευνας και 
μετριασμού tsunami -- πώς τα ιζήματα μεταφέρονται από ένα 
tsunami, πώς οι ερευνητές αποκρυπτογραφούν το γεωλογικό αρχείο
των προϊστορικών tsunamis, και το seismograph δίκτυο του 
συστήματος προειδοποίησης tsunami δυτικών ακτών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">animación de las aplicaciones y realidad virtual 
para mostrar cómo los tsumanis son generados por terremotos. 
Aprenda sobre la investigación del tsunami y los esfuerzos de 
la mitigación -- cómo los sedimentos son transportados por un 
tsunami, cómo los investigadores descifraron el expediente geológico
de tsunamis prehistóricos, y la red del sismógrafo del sistema 
amonestador del tsunami del oeste de la costa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206118</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105569</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/tsunamis-and-earthquakes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
