<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106049</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106049</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974073</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Circle of Stories</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kreis von Geschichten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cercle des histoires</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Círculo das histórias</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cerchio delle storia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κύκλος των ιστοριών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Círculo de historias</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Welcome to the CIRCLE OF STORIES lesson plans. These lessons will allow students to examine the complex and rich oral tradition of Native American storytelling, create their own stories to share, explore indigenous and Native American cultures and the issues which face them today, and research and explore their own cultural heritage by recording their unique family stories and heritage. These lessons are directed toward grades 6 through 12, for use in the following subject areas: language arts, theater, history, social studies, multicultural studies, technology, and life science.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Willkommen zum KREIS der GESCHICHTE-Lektion plant.
Diese Lektionen erlauben Kursteilnehmern, die komplizierte und 
reiche Mundtradition des gebürtigen amerikanischen Storytellings zu 
überprüfen, ihre eigenen Geschichten zu erstellen, um zu teilen, die
eingeborenen und gebürtigen amerikanischen Kulturen und die Ausgaben,
die sie heute gegenüberstellen, und Forschung zu erforschen und 
erforschen ihr eigenes kulturelles Erbe, indem sie ihre eindeutigen 
Familie Geschichten und Erbe speichern. Diese Lektionen werden 
in Richtung zu Graden 6 bis 12, für Gebrauch in den folgenden 
Bereichen verwiesen: Sprachenkünste, Theater, Geschichte, 
Sozialstudien, multikulturelle Studien, Technologie und 
Lebenwissenschaft.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La bienvenue au CERCLE de la leçon d'HISTOIRES 
projette. Ces leçons permettront à des étudiants d'examiner 
la tradition orale complexe et riche de storytelling américain 
indigène, de créer leurs propres histoires pour partager, d'explorer
les cultures américaines indigènes et indigènes et les issues qui 
leur font face aujourd'hui, et la recherche et explorent leur propre 
acquis culturel en enregistrant leurs seuls histoires et héritage de 
famille. Ces leçons sont orientées sur les catégories 6 à 
12, pour l'usage dans les domaines suivants : arts de langage, 
théâtre, histoire, études sociales, études multiculturelles, 
technologie, et science de vie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A boa vinda ao CÍRCULO da lição das HISTÓRIAS 
planeia. Estas lições permitirão que os estudantes examinem a
tradição oral complexa e rica de storytelling americano nativo, 
críem suas próprias histórias para compartilhar, explorem as 
culturas americanas indígenas e nativas e as edições que os 
enfrentam hoje, e a pesquisa e exploram seu próprio heritage cultural
gravando seus histórias e heritage originais da família. Estas
lições são dirigidas para as classes 6 a 12, para o uso nas 
seguintes áreas sujeitas: artes da língua, teatro, history, 
estudos sociais, estudos multicultural, tecnologia, e ciência de 
vida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il benvenuto al CERCHIO della lezione di STORIA 
progetta. Queste lezioni permetteranno che gli allievi esaminino
la tradizione orale complessa e ricca di storytelling americano 
natale, creino le loro proprie storia per ripartirsi, esplorino le 
colture americane indigene e natali e le edizioni che le affrontano 
oggi e la ricerca e che esplorano la loro propria eredità culturale 
registrando le loro storia ed eredità uniche della famiglia. 
Queste lezioni sono orientate verso i gradi da 6 a 12, per uso 
nei seguenti settori: arti di linguaggio, teatro, storia, studi 
sociali, studi multicultural, tecnologia e scienze biologiche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποδοχή στον ΚΥΚΛΟ των σχεδίων μαθήματος ΙΣΤΟΡΙΩΝ. 
Αυτά τα μαθήματα θα επιτρέψουν στους σπουδαστές για να 
εξετάσουν τη σύνθετη και πλούσια προφορική παράδοση εγγενή 
αμερικανικά, να δημιουργήσουν τις ιστορίες τους για να μοιραστούν,
να ερευνήσουν τους γηγενείς και εγγενείς αμερικανικούς 
πολιτισμούς και τα ζητήματα που τους αντιμετωπίζουν σήμερα, και 
την έρευνα και ερευνούν την πολιτιστική κληρονομιά τους με την 
καταγραφή των μοναδικών οικογενειακών ιστοριών και της 
κληρονομιάς τους. Αυτά τα μαθήματα κατευθύνονται προς τους 
βαθμούς 6 μέχρι 12, για τη χρήση στις ακόλουθες θεματικές 
περιοχές: γλωσσικές τέχνες, θέατρο, ιστορία, κοινωνικές 
μελέτες, πολυπολιτισμικές μελέτες, τεχνολογία, και βιολογική 
επιστήμη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La recepción al CÍRCULO de la lección de las 
HISTORIAS planea. Estas lecciones permitirán que los 
estudiantes examinen la tradición oral compleja y rica de 
storytelling americano nativo, que creen sus propias historias para 
compartir, que exploren las culturas americanas indígenas y nativas y
las ediciones que les hacen frente hoy, y la investigación y exploran
su propio patrimonio cultural registrando sus historias y herencia 
únicas de la familia. Estas lecciones se dirigen hacia los 
grados 6 a 12, para el uso en los temas siguientes: artes del 
lenguaje, teatro, historia, estudios sociales, estudios multicultural,
tecnología, y ciencia de vida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BETSY NORRIS
FN:BETSY NORRIS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974073</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106049</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/circle-of-stories</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
