<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104965</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104965</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087143</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"True towel tales . . . as told to us by a soldier."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"zutreffende Tuchgeschichten. . . 
wie von einem Soldaten erklärt uns."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"véritables contes de serviette. . . 
comme dit à nous par un soldat."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"tales verdadeiros de toalha. . . 
como dito a nós por um soldado."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"veri racconti del tovagliolo. . . 
come detto a noi da un soldato."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αληθινές ιστορίες πετσετών. .. όπως μας 
λέεται σε από έναν στρατιώτη."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"cuentos verdaderos de la toalla. . . 
según lo dicho a nosotros por un soldado."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Life in the armed services had a long-lasting impact on America's homosexual population. Far from home, many gay men and lesbian women felt less social pressure to conform to heterosexual social norms, and the need for manpower made the military somewhat more tolerant of homosexual men and women in its ranks (although it still purged many gay and lesbian soldiers). Many who first expressed their sexual orientation during the war later became pioneers in the gay and lesbian rights movement. This towel advertisement was one of a series published during 1943-44 that framed its sales-pitch in homoerotic imagery inspired by purported testimony from G.I.s overseas. The ads, which are sexually ambiguous, suggest how the same-sex environment in the military afforded young men, both gay and straight, with opportunities for sexual self-discovery.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Leben in den bewaffneten Dienstleistungen hatte eine 
langlebige Auswirkung auf Amerikas homosexuelle Bevölkerung. 
Weit von Haus glaubten viele homosexuelle Männer und lesbische 
Frauen weniger Sozialdruck, sich an heterosexual Sozialnormen 
anzupassen, und die Notwendigkeit an der menschlichen Arbeitskraft 
bildete das Militär ein wenig toleranter gegen homosexuelle Männer 
und Frauen in seinen Rank (obgleich sie noch viele homosexuelle und 
lesbische Soldaten löschte). Viele, die zuerst ihre sexuelle 
Lagebestimmung während des Krieges später ausdrückten, wurden 
Pioniere in der homosexuellen und Lesbierrechtbewegung. Diese 
Tuchreklameanzeige war eine einer Serie, die während 1943-44 
veröffentlicht wurde, das sein Verkauf-werfen in die homoerotic 
Bilder gestaltete, die übersee durch behauptetes Zeugnis von G.I.s 
angespornt wurden. Das ADS, die sexuell vieldeutig sind, 
schlagen wie die Gleichgeschlecht Umgebung in den militärischen 
geleisteten jungen Männern vor, homosexuell und gerade, mit 
Gelegenheiten für sexuelle Selbst-Entdeckung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La vie dans les forces armées a eu un impact durable sur 
la population homosexuelle de l'Amérique. Loin de la maison, 
beaucoup d'hommes et femmes lesbiennes gais ont senti moins de 
pression sociale de se conformer aux normes sociales 
hétérosexuelles, et le besoin de main d'oeuvre a rendu les 
militaires en quelque sorte plus tolérants des hommes et des femmes 
homosexuels dans ses rangs (bien qu'il purgeait toujours beaucoup de 
soldats gais et lesbiens). Beaucoup qui ont exprimé la 
première fois leur orientation sexuelle pendant la guerre plus tard 
sont devenus des pionniers dans le mouvement gai et de lesbienne de 
droits. Cette publicité de serviette était une d'une série 
éditée pendant 1943-44 qui a encadré le son vente-lancent dans le 
langage figuré homoerotic inspiré par témoignage prétendu de G.I.s
outre-mer. L'ADS, qui sont sexuellement ambigus, suggèrent 
comment l'environnement de même-sexe chez les jeunes hommes eus les 
moyens militaires, gais et droits, avec des occasions pour 
art de l'auto-portrait-discovery sexuel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A vida nos forças armadas teve um impacto long-lasting na
população homosexual de América. Longe da HOME, muitos homens
e mulheres lesbian gay sentiram menos pressão social conformar-se às
normas sociais heterosexual, e a necessidade para o manpower fêz as 
forças armadas um tanto mais tolerantes de homens e de mulheres 
homosexual em seus Rank (embora removeu ainda muitos soldados gay e 
lesbian). Muitos que expressaram primeiramente sua orientação 
sexual durante a guerra mais tarde transformaram-se pioneiros no 
movimento gay e do lesbian das direitas. Esta propaganda de 
toalha era uma de uma série publicada durante 1943-44 que moldou o 
seu venda-lança no imagery homoerotic inspirado pelo testimony 
purported de G.I.s no ultramar. O ads, que são sexually 
ambiguous, sugere como o ambiente do mesmo-sexo nos homens novos tidos
recursos para militares,  gay e retos, com oportunidades para a 
self-descoberta sexual.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La vita nelle forze armate ha avuta un effetto duraturo 
sulla popolazione omosessuale dell'America. Lontano dalla sede, 
molti uomini di gay e donne lesbiche hanno ritenuto meno 
pressione sociale essere conforme alle norme sociali eterosessuali ed 
il fabbisogno di manodopera ha reso i militari piuttosto più 
tolleranti degli uomini e delle donne omosessuali nella relativa 
truppa (anche se ancora ha eliminato l'inceppo molto i soldati 
della lesbica e di gay). Molti che in primo luogo 
esprimessero più successivamente il loro orientamento sessuale 
durante la guerra sono diventato pionieri nel movimento di diritti 
della lesbica e di gay. Questa pubblicità del 
tovagliolo era una di una serie pubblicata durante il 1943-44 che ha 
incorniciato il relativo vendita-lancia nel linguaggio figurato 
homoerotic ispirato dalla testimonianza pretesa da G.I.s oltremare. 
Il ads, che sono sessualmente ambigui, suggerisce come 
l'ambiente del stesso-sesso nei giovani permessi militari, sia 
gay che diritto, con le occasioni per la auto-scoperta 
sessuale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ζωή στις Ένοπλες Δυνάμεις άσκησε μακράς διαρκείας 
επίδραση στον ομοφυλοφιλικό πληθυσμό της Αμερικής. Μακριά 
από το σπίτι, πολλοί ομοφυλόφιλοι άνδρες και λεσβιακές γυναίκες
αισθάνθηκαν τη λιγότερη κοινωνική πίεση να προσαρμοστούν στους 
κοινωνικούς κανόνες ετεροφυλόφιλων, και η ανάγκη για το εργατικό 
δυναμικό έκανε στρατιωτικό κάπως τον πιό ανεκτικό των 
ομοφυλοφιλικών ανδρών και των γυναικών στις τάξεις της (αν και 
εξάγνισε ακόμα πολλούς ομοφυλόφιλους και λεσβιακούς στρατιώτες).
Πολλοί που εξέφρασαν αρχικά το σεξουαλικό προσανατολισμό 
τους κατά τη διάρκεια του πολέμου έγιναν αργότερα πρωτοπόροι στο
ομοφυλοφιλικό και λεσβιακό κίνημα δικαιωμάτων. Αυτή η 
διαφήμιση πετσετών ήταν μια από μια σειρά που δημοσιεύθηκε κατά
τη διάρκεια του 1943-44 που πλαισίωσε την πώληση-πίσσα της στα 
homoerotic καλολογικά στοιχεία που εμπνεύστηκαν από την 
ισχυρισμένη κατάθεση από G.I.s στο εξωτερικό. Οι 
αγγελίες, που είναι σεξουαλικά διφορούμενες, προτείνουν πώς το 
περιβάλλον ίδιος-φύλων στους στρατιωτικούς διατεθειμένους 
νεαρούς άνδρες, και εύθυμους και ευθείς, με τις ευκαιρίες για τη 
σεξουαλική μόνος-ανακάλυψη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La vida en las fuerzas armadas tenía un impacto duradero 
en la población homosexual de América. Lejos de hogar, muchos 
hombres y mujeres lesbianas gays sentían menos presión 
social de conformarse con las normas sociales heterosexuales, y la 
necesidad de la mano de obra hizo a militares algo más tolerantes de 
hombres y de mujeres homosexuales en sus filas (aunque todavía purgó
a muchos soldados gays y lesbianos). Muchos que primero 
expresaron su orientación sexual durante la guerra más adelante 
hicieron pioneros en el movimiento de las derechas del gay y de
la lesbiana. Este anuncio de la toalla era uno de una serie 
publicada durante 1943-44 que enmarcó su venta-echa en las imágenes 
homoerotic inspiradas por testimonio pretendido de G.I.s en ultramar. 
El ads, que son sexual ambiguos, sugiere cómo el ambiente del 
mismo-sexo en los hombres jóvenes producidos militares, gays 
y rectos, con las oportunidades para el uno mismo-descubrimiento 
sexual.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087143</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104965</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/true-towel-tales-as-told-to-us-by-a-soldier</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
