<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105491</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105491</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087217</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We're Looking for Zoot-Suits to Burn": Mexican Americans and the Zoot Suit Riots</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir suchen nach Zoot-Klagen, um zu brennen": 
Mexikanische Amerikaner und das Zoot entsprechen Aufständen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous recherchons des Zoot-Costumes pour brûler" 
: Les Américains mexicains et le Zoot conviennent à des 
émeutes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós estamos procurando Zoot-Ternos para 
queimar-se": Os americanos mexicanos e o Zoot servem motins</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"stiamo cercando i Zoot-Vestiti per bruciarsi": 
Gli Americani messicani e lo Zoot soddisfano i tumulti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ψάχνουμε τα ζοοτ-κοστούμια που καίνε": 
Μεξικάνικοι Αμερικανοί και οι ταραχές κοστουμιών Zoot</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"estamos buscando Zoot-Juegos para quemarnos": 
Los americanos mexicanos y el Zoot satisfacen alborotos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">While the exact origin of the loose-fitting "zoot suit," worn by Mexican-American and African-American youths in the 1940s, is obscure, its most important roots were among Mexican-American youths, or  pachucos . In the context of World War II, this defiant gesture of group identity put the Mexican-American zoot suiters into direct conflict with another youth group--white servicemen stationed on the West Coast. Wartime rationing regulations effectively banned zoot suits because they ostensibly wasted fabric, so a combination of patriotism and racism impelled white soldiers to denounce Mexican-American wearers of the zoot suit as slackers and hoodlums. In June 1943, apparently provoked by stories that Mexican Americans had beaten up a group of Anglo sailors, servicemen on leave began to attack Mexican-American neighborhoods in Los Angeles. These anti-Mexican riots often featured the ritualistic stripping of the zoot suiters. Despite the brutality of these incidents, most press coverage was sympathetic to the servicemen. One exception was this description by Al Waxman, editor of the  Eastside Journal , an East Los Angeles community newspaper.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während der genaue Ursprung der Losbefestigung 
"zoot Klage," getragen durch Mexikanisch-Mexican-American und 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Jugend in den vierziger Jahren, 
unverständlich ist, gehörten seine wichtigsten Wurzeln zu 
Mexikanisch-Amerikanischer Jugend oder Pachucos. Im Kontext des 
Zweiten Weltkrieges, setzte diese defiant Geste der Gruppe Identität 
die Mexikanisch-Amerikanischen zoot suiters in direkte 
$überschneidung mit einer anderen Jugendgruppe -- die weißen 
Soldaten, die auf die Westküste stationiert wurden. Der 
Krieg, der Regelungen verbot rationiert effektiv, zoot Klagen, weil 
sie anscheinend Gewebe vergeudeten, also denunzieren eine Kombination 
von Patriotismus und Rassismus genötigte weiße Soldaten 
Mexikanisch-Amerikanische Träger der zoot Klage als slackers und 
Strolche. Im Juni 1943, anscheinend erregt durch Geschichten, 
die mexikanische Amerikaner herauf eine Gruppe Angloseeleute 
geschlagen hatten, Soldaten auf Urlaub fing an, 
Mexikanisch-Amerikanische Nachbarschaften in Los Angeles in Angriff zu
nehmen. Diese Anti-Mexikanischen Aufstände kennzeichneten 
häufig das ritualistic Entfernen der zoot suiters. Trotz der 
Brutalitäten dieser Ereignisse, war die meiste Pressedichte zu den 
Soldaten sympatisch. Eine Ausnahme war diese Beschreibung 
durch Al Waxman, Herausgeber des Eastside Journals, eine Ostlos 
Angeles Gemeinschaftszeitung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tandis que l'origine exacte du lâche-ajustage de 
précision "costume de zoot," porté par des jeunesses de 
Mexicain-Mexican-American et d'Afro-Américain dans les années 40, est 
obscure, ses racines plus importantes étaient parmi les jeunesses 
Mexicain-Américaines, ou les pachucos. Dans le contexte de la 
deuxième guerre mondiale, ce geste provoquant d'identité de groupe a
mis les suiters Mexicain-Américains de zoot dans le conflit direct 
avec un autre groupe de la jeunesse -- soldats blancs postés sur la 
côte occidentale. Le temps de guerre rationnant des règlements
a pertinemment interdit des costumes de zoot parce qu'ils ont en 
apparence gaspillé le tissu, ainsi une combinaison de patriotisme et 
les soldats blancs poussés par racisme dénoncent les porteurs 
Mexicain-Américains du costume de zoot comme slackers et truands. 
En juin 1943, apparemment provoqué par les histoires que les 
Américains mexicains avaient battues vers le haut d'un groupe de 
marins anglo, soldats sur le congé a commencé à attaquer les 
voisinages Mexicain-Américains à Los Angeles. Ces émeutes 
anti-Mexicaines ont souvent comporté éliminer ritualiste des suiters
de zoot. En dépit de la brutalité de ces incidents, la plupart
d'assurance de presse était sympathique aux soldats. Une 
exception était cette description par Al Waxman, éditeur du journal 
d'Eastside, un journal est de la communauté de Los Angeles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando a origem exata do frouxo-encaixe do "terno 
zoot," desgastado por Mexicano-Americano e por juventudes 
Africano-Americanas nos 1940s, for obscura, suas raizes mais 
importantes eram entre juventudes Mexicano-Americanas, ou pachucos. 
No contexto da segunda guerra mundial, este gesto defiant da 
identidade do grupo pôs os suiters Mexicano-Americanos no conflito 
direto com um outro grupo da juventude -- recrutas brancos do zoot 
postados na costa ocidental. O wartime que raciona regulamentos 
proibiu eficazmente ternos do zoot porque desperdiçaram ostensibly a 
tela, assim que uma combinação do patriotism e os soldados brancos 
impelled racism denounce wearers Mexicano-Americanos do terno do zoot 
como slackers e hoodlums. Em junho 1943, provocado aparentemente
pelas histórias que os americanos mexicanos tinham batido acima de um
grupo de sailors anglo, recrutas na licença começou a atacar 
vizinhanças Mexicano-Americanas em Los Angeles. Estes motins 
anti-Mexicanos caracterizaram frequentemente descascar ritualistic dos
suiters do zoot. Apesar do brutality destes incidents, a maioria
de cobertura de imprensa era sympathetic aos recrutas. Uma 
exceção era esta descrição por Al Waxman, editor do jornal de 
Eastside, um jornal do leste da comunidade de Los Angeles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre l'origine esatta del allentato-montaggio 
"vestito dello zoot," portato da messicano-american e dalle gioventù 
Africano-Americane nei 1940s, è oscura, le relative radici più 
importanti erano fra le gioventù di messicano-american, o i pachucos. 
Nel contesto della seconda guerra mondiale, questo ribelle 
gesture dell'identità del gruppo ha messo i suiters nel conflitto 
diretto con un altro gruppo della gioventù -- tecnici di manutenzione
bianchi dello zoot di messicano-american disposti sul litorale ad 
ovest. Il wartime che raziona le regolazioni ha vietato 
efficacemente i vestiti dello zoot perché hanno sprecato 
apparentemente il tessuto, in modo da una combinazione di patriotism 
ed i soldati bianchi impelled il razzismo denunciano gli indossatori 
di messicano-american del vestito dello zoot come gli slackers e 
hoodlums. Nel mese di giugno del 1943, provocato apparentemente 
dalle storia che gli Americani messicani avevano battuto su un 
gruppo dei marinai anglo, tecnici di manutenzione in permesso ha 
cominciato ad attacare le vicinanze di messicano-american a Los 
Angeles. Questi tumulti di anti-messicano hanno caratterizzato 
spesso mettere a nudo ritualistic dei suiters dello zoot. 
Malgrado il brutality di questi avvenimenti, la maggior parte 
della accoglienza della stampa era simpatica ai tecnici di 
manutenzione. Un'eccezione era questa descrizione da Al Waxman, 
editore del giornale di Eastside, un giornale orientale della 
Comunità de Los Angeles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενώ η ακριβής προέλευση του άνετου "κοστουμιού 
zoot," φορημένος από τις Μεξικανοαμερικάές και 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικές νεολαίες στη δεκαετία του '40, είναι 
σκοτεινή, οι σημαντικότερες ρίζες της ήταν μεταξύ των 
Μεξικανοαμερικάών νεολαιών, ή των pachucos. Στα πλαίσια 
του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ, αυτή η προκλητική χειρονομία της 
ταυτότητας ομάδας έβαλε τα Μεξικανοαμερικάά suiters zoot 
στην άμεση σύγκρουση με μια άλλη ομάδα νεολαίας -- λευκά 
servicemen που τοποθετήθηκαν στη δυτική ακτή. Οι εν καιρώ
πολέμου κανονισμοί διανομής με δελτίο απαγόρευσαν αποτελεσματικά
zoot τα κοστούμια επειδή σπατάλησαν φαινομενικά το ύφασμα, 
έτσι ένας συνδυασμός πατριωτισμού και ρατσισμού ώθησε τους 
λευκούς στρατιώτες για να καταγγείλει τους Μεξικανοαμερικάούς 
κομιστές του κοστουμιού zoot ως slackers και κακοποιούς. 
Τον Ιούνιο του 1943, που προκλήθηκε προφανώς από τις 
ιστορίες ότι μεξικάνικοι Αμερικανοί είχαν κτυπήσει επάνω μια 
ομάδα ναυτικών Anglo, servicemen στην άδεια άρχισαν να 
επιτίθενται στις Μεξικανοαμερικάές γειτονιές στο Λος Αντζελες. 
Αυτές οι ταραχές αντι-μεξικανός χαρακτήρισαν συχνά το 
τελετουργικό γδύσιμο των suiters zoot. Παρά τη 
βιαιότητα αυτών των γεγονότων, η περισσότερη κάλυψη Τύπου ήταν 
συμπονετική servicemen. Μια εξαίρεση ήταν αυτή η 
περιγραφή από το Al Waxman, επεξεργαστής του Eastside 
περιοδικού, μια κοινοτική εφημερίδα του ανατολικού Λος Αντζελες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que el origen exacto de la 
flojo-guarnicio'n "juego del zoot," desgastado por 
Mexicano-mexican-American y las juventudes Africano-Americanas en los 
años 40, es obscuro, sus raíces más importantes estaban entre 
juventudes Mexicano-Americanas, o pachucos. En el contexto de la
Segunda Guerra Mundial, este gesto desafiante de la identidad del 
grupo puso los suiters Mexicano-Americanos en conflicto directo con 
otro grupo de la juventud -- mecánicos blancos del zoot colocados en 
la costa del oeste. El tiempo de guerra que racionaba 
regulaciones prohibió con eficacia juegos del zoot porque aparentemente 
perdieron la tela, así que una combinación del patriotismo y los 
soldados blancos impulsados racismo denunci a portadores 
Mexicano-Americanos del juego del zoot como slackers y matones. 
En junio de de 1943, provocado al parecer por las historias que 
los americanos mexicanos habían batido encima de un grupo de 
marineros anglo, mecánicos en licencia comenzó a atacar vecindades 
Mexicano-Americanas en Los Ángeles. Estos alborotos 
contra-Mexicanos ofrecieron a menudo eliminar ritualista de los 
suiters del zoot. A pesar de la brutalidad de estos incidentes, 
la mayoría de la cobertura de prensa era comprensiva a los 
mecánicos. Una anomalía era esta descripción de Al Waxman, 
editor del diario de Eastside, un periódico del este de la comunidad 
de Los Ángeles.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087217</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105491</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/were-looking-for-zoot-suits-to-burn-mexican-americans-and-the-zoot-suit-riots</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
