<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102933</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102933</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086498</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"My Heart Was So Full of Love That It Overflowed": Charles Grandison Finney Experiences Conversion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"mein Inneres war von der Liebe das so voll, das 
sie" überlief: Charles Grandison Finney Erfährt Konvertierung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"mon coeur était si plein de l'amour cela qu'il a
débordé" : Charles Grandison Finney Éprouve La Conversion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"meu coração estava assim cheio do amor isso que
transbordou": Charles Grandison Finney Experimenta A Conversão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il mio cuore era così pieno di amore quello che 
ha traboccato": Charles Grandison Finney Avverte La Conversione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η καρδιά μου ήταν τόσο πλήρης της αγάπης που 
ξεχείλισε": Θ*Θχαρλες Grandison Finney Experiences 
Conversion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"mi corazón era tan lleno de amor eso que 
desbordó": Charles Grandison Finney Experimenta La Conversión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the 1820s and 1830s, a new democratic and individualistic Protestantism appealed to the emerging middle class of the northeastern United States. The chief spokesperson for that revivalist movement was Charles Grandison Finney. Born in Litchfield County, Connecticut, and transplanted like many others to western New York, Finney found the practice of law unsatisfying. The conversion experience that he narrates in this selection from his  Memoirs of Rev. Charles G. Finney  (1876) altered the course of his life. For the next decade he focused his energies on preaching in western New York, the region known as the "Burned Over District" for its reputation as a hotbed of revivalism. Middle-class Americans were attracted to his doctrine, which emphasized the individual's need to assume moral responsibility, and rejected older beliefs about divine providence as the only route to salvation. His  Lectures on Revivals  (1835) became a handbook for American revivalists and Finney became a professor at, and later president of, Oberlin College.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im 1820s und im 1830s gefiel ein neues 
demokratisches und individualistisches Protestantism der auftauchenden
mittleren Kategorie der nordöstlichen Vereinigten Staaten. Der 
Hauptsprecher für diese revivalist Bewegung war Charles Grandison 
Finney. Getragen in der Litchfield Grafschaft, fand Connecticut 
und wie viele andere nach Westnew York verpflanzt, Finney die Praxis 
des Gesetzes unsatisfying. Die Konvertierung Erfahrung, die er 
in dieser Auswahl von seinen Abhandlungen von Rev. Charles G. Finney 
(1876) berichtet änderte den Kurs seiner Lebensdauer. Für die 
folgende Dekade richtete er seine Energie auf das Predigen in Westnew 
York, die Region, die als "gebrannt über Bezirk" für sein Renommee 
als Brutstätte von revivalism bekannt ist. 
Mittelklasseamerikaner wurden zu seiner Lehre angezogen, die die
Notwendigkeit der Einzelperson hervorhob, moralische 
Verantwortlichkeit zu übernehmen, und älteren Glauben über 
göttliche Vorsehung als der einzige Weg zur Rettung zurückwiesen. 
Seine Vorträge auf Wiederbelebung (1835) wurden ein Handbuch 
für amerikanische revivalists und Finney standen einem Professor und 
neuerem Präsidenten, von an der Oberlin Hochschule.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans le 1820s et le 1830s, un nouveau Protestantisme 
démocratique et individualiste a fait appel à la bourgeoisie 
naissante des Etats-Unis du nord-est. Le porte-parole en chef 
pour ce mouvement de revivalist était Charles Grandison Finney. 
Soutenu dans le comté de Litchfield, le Connecticut, et 
transplanté comme beaucoup d'autres à New York occidental, Finney a 
trouvé la pratique de la loi unsatisfying. L'expérience de 
conversion qu'il relate dans cette sélection à partir de ses 
mémoires d'Rev. Charles G. Finney (1876) a modifié le cours de sa 
vie. Pour la décennie suivante il a concentré ses énergies 
sur prêcher à New York occidental, la région connue sous le nom de 
"brûlé au-dessus de la zone" pour sa réputation comme germoir de 
revivalism. Des Américains de classe moyenne ont été attirés
à sa doctrine, qui a souligné la nécessité de l'individu d'assumer
la responsabilité morale, et ont rejeté une croyance plus ancienne 
au sujet de providence divine comme seul itinéraire au salut. 
Ses conférences sur les renaissances (1835) sont devenues un 
manuel pour des revivalists et Finney américains sont allées bien à
un professeur, et à un plus défunt président, derrière 
l'université d'Oberlin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 1820s e no 1830s, um Protestantism democrático
e individualistic novo apelou à classe média emergente dos estados 
unidos do nordeste. O spokesperson principal para esse movimento
do revivalist era Charles Grandison Finney. Carregado no condado
de Litchfield, Connecticut, e transplanted como muito outro a New York
ocidental, Finney encontrou a prática da lei unsatisfying. A 
experiência da conversão que narra nesta seleção de seus memoirs 
de Rev. Charles G. Finney (1876) alterou o curso de sua vida. 
Para a década seguinte focalizou suas energias em preaching em 
New York ocidental, a região sabida como "queimado sobre o distrito" 
para sua reputação como um hotbed do revivalism. Os americanos
do middle-class foram atraídos a sua doutrina, que emfatizou a 
necessidade do indivíduo supor a responsabilidade moral, e rejeitaram
uma opinião mais velha sobre o providence divine como a única rota 
ao salvation. Seus lectures nos revivals (1835) transformaram-se
um manual para revivalists e Finney americanos assentaram bem em um 
professor, e em um presidente mais atrasado, da faculdade de Oberlin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel 1820s e nel 1830s, un nuovo Protestantism 
democratico ed individualistic fatto appello al codice categoria 
centrale d'emersione del di nordest unito Dichiara. Lo 
spokesperson principale per quel movimento di revivalist era Charles 
Grandison Finney. Sopportato nella contea di Litchfield, 
Connecticut e trapiantato come molti altri a New York occidentale, 
Finney ha scoperto che la pratica di legge unsatisfying. 
L'esperienza di conversione che narra in questa selezione dalle 
sue memorie di Rev. Charles il G. Finney (1876) ha alterato il corso 
della sua vita. Per la decade prossima ha messo a fuoco le sue 
energie sulla predica a New York occidentale, la regione conosciuta 
come "bruciato sopra il distretto" per la relativa reputazione come 
hotbed del revivalism. Gli Americani della classe media sono 
stati attratti alla sua dottrina, che ha dato risalto alla necessità 
dell'individuo di assumere la responsabilità morale ed hanno 
rifiutato la più vecchia credenza circa providence divine come 
l'unico itinerario a salvezza. Le sue conferenze sulle 
rinascite (1835) si sono transformate in in un manuale per i 
revivalists e Finney americani hanno stato bene ad un professore a ed 
al presidente successivo, dell'università di Oberlin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο 1820s και το 1830s, ένας νέος δημοκρατικός 
και ατομικιστικός Προτεσταντισμός απευθύνθηκε αναδυόμενη μέση 
κλάση των βορειοανατολικών Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών. Ο προϊστάμενος 
εκπρόσωπος για εκείνη την μετακίνηση revivalist ήταν Charles
Grandison Finney. Γεννημένος Litchfield στο νομό, 
Κοννέκτικατ, και μεταμοσχευμένος όπως πολλούς άλλους στη δυτική 
Νέα Υόρκη, Finney βρήκε την πρακτική νόμου. Η εμπειρία 
μετατροπής που διηγείται σε αυτήν την επιλογή από τα 
απομνημονεύματα αναθ. του Charles G. Finney (1876) 
άλλαξε την πορεία της ζωής του. Για την επόμενη δεκαετία 
έστρεψε τις ενέργειές του στο κήρυγμα στη δυτική Νέα Υόρκη, η 
περιοχή γνωστή ως "πέρα από την περιοχή" για τη φήμη του όπως 
το α του revivalism. Η μεσαία τάξη Αμερικανοί 
προσελκύστηκε στο δόγμα του, που υπογράμμισε την ανάγκη του 
ατόμου να αναλάβει την ηθική ευθύνη, και απέρριψε τις 
παλαιότερες πεποιθήσεις για τη θεία πρόνοια ως μόνη διαδρομή στη
σωτηρία. Οι διαλέξεις του σχετικά με τις αναγεννήσεις 
(1835) έγιναν ένα εγχειρίδιο για τα αμερικανικά revivalists 
και Finney έγινε καθηγητής σε, και πιό πρώην Πρόεδρος, το 
κολλέγιο Oberlin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el 1820s y el 1830s, un Protestantism 
democrático e individualista nuevo abrogó a la clase media que 
emergía de los Estados Unidos del noreste. El principal 
portavoz para ese movimiento del revivalist era Charles Grandison 
Finney. Llevado en el condado de Litchfield, Connecticut, y 
trasplantado como muchos otros a Nueva York occidental, Finney 
encontró la práctica de la ley el unsatisfying. La experiencia
de la conversión que él narra en esta selección de sus memorias de 
Rev. Charles G. Finney (1876) alteró el curso de su vida. Para 
la década próxima él se centró sus energías en la predicación en
Nueva York occidental, la región conocida como "quemado sobre 
districto" para su reputación como hotbed del revivalism. 
Atrajeron a su doctrina, que acentuó la necesidad del individuo
de asumir responsabilidad moral, y rechazaron a los americanos de la 
clase media una más vieja creencia sobre providence divino como la 
única ruta a la salvación. Sus conferencias en los 
renacimientos (1835) se convirtieron en un manual para los revivalists
y Finney americanos sintieron bien a un profesor en, y a un presidente
más último, de la universidad de Oberlin.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086498</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102933</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/my-heart-was-so-full-of-love-that-it-overflowed-charles-grandison-finney-experiences-conversion</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
