<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108577</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108577</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207193</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Old Mormon Fort: Birthplace of Las Vegas, Nevada</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Alte Mormonische Fort: Geburtsort von 
Las Vegas, Nevada</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Vieux Fort Mormon : Lieu de naissance de 
Las Vegas, Nevada</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Fort Mormon Velho: Birthplace de Las 
Vegas, Nevada</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Vecchio Forte Mormonico: Luogo di 
nascita di Las Vegas, Nevada</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το παλαιό των Μορμόνων οχυρό: Τόπος γεννήσεως 
Las Vegas, Νεβάδα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Vieja Fortaleza Mormónica: Lugar de 
nacimiento de Las Vegas, Nevada</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recalls the individuals and events leading to the creation of Las Vegas. In 1855, Brigham Young sent 30 men to farm, convert Indians, and build a settlement along a trail to the Pacific. After the mission closed, a miner established a ranch, which grew to be the largest property in the county under later owner Helen Stewart. With the coming of the railroad, Las Vegas became a town. Railroad officials laid out a grid for the new city in 1905.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erinnert an die Einzelpersonen und die Fälle, die
zu die Kreation von Las Vegas führen. 1855 Brigham bauen junge 
geschickt 30 Männer zum Bauernhof, Bekehrter Inder und eine Regelung 
entlang einer Spur zum Pazifik auf. Nach der Mission schloß, 
ein Bergmann herstellte eine Ranch, die ist die größte Eigenschaft 
in der Grafschaft unter neuerem Inhaber Helen Stewart sich 
entwickelte. Mit dem Kommen der Eisenbahn, wurde Las Vegas eine 
Stadt. Eisenbahnbeamte britten ein Rasterfeld für die neue 
Stadt 1905 aus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">rappelle les individus et les événements menant 
à la création de Las Vegas. En 1855, jeunes de Brigham 
envoyés 30 hommes à la ferme, les Indiens de converti, et 
établissent un règlement le long d'une traînée au Pacifique. 
Après la mission s'est fermé, un mineur a établi un ranch, 
qui a devenu soit la plus grande propriété dans le comté sous un 
plus défunt propriétaire Helen Stewart. Avec venir du 
chemin de fer, Las Vegas est devenue une ville. Les 
fonctionnaires de chemin de fer ont présenté une grille pour la 
nouvelle ville en 1905.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">recorda os indivíduos e os eventos que conduzem 
à criação de Las Vegas. Em 1855, novos de Brigham emitidos 30
homens à fazenda, os indians do converso, e constroem um 
estabelecimento ao longo de uma fuga ao Pacífico. Após a 
missão fechou-se, um mineiro estabeleceu um rancho, que viesse fosse 
a propriedade a maior no condado sob um proprietário mais atrasado 
Helen Stewart. Com a vinda da estrada de ferro, Las Vegas 
transformou-se uma cidade. Os oficiais da estrada de ferro 
colocaram para fora de uma grade para a cidade nova em 1905.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ricorda gli individui e gli eventi che conducono 
alla creazione di Las Vegas. In 1855, giovani di Brigham 
trasmessi a 30 uomini al podere, gli indiani del convertito e 
sviluppano uno stabilimento lungo una traccia al Pacifico. Dopo 
la missione chiusa, un minatore ha stabilito un ranch, che è 
diventato è la più grande proprietà nella contea sotto il 
proprietario successivo Helen Stewart. Con venire della 
ferrovia, Las Vegas si è transformata in in una città. I 
funzionari della ferrovia hanno presentato una griglia per la nuova 
città in 1905.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">υπενθυμίζει τα άτομα και τα γεγονότα που οδηγούν στη 
δημιουργία Las Vegas. Το 1855, νέος Brigham που 
στέλνεται 30 άτομα στο αγρόκτημα, μετατρέπει Ινδούς, και 
χτίζει μια τακτοποίηση κατά μήκος ενός ίχνους στον Ειρηνικό. 
Αφότου έκλεισε η αποστολή, ένας ανθρακωρύχος καθιέρωσε 
ένα αγρόκτημα, το οποίο έτεινε να είναι η μεγαλύτερη ιδιοκτησία
στο νομό κάτω από τον πιό πρώην ιδιοκτήτη Helen Stewart. 
Με τον ερχομό του σιδηροδρόμου, Las Vegas έγινε μια 
πόλη. Οι ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι σιδηροδρόμου σχεδίασαν ένα 
πλέγμα για τη νέα πόλη το 1905.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">recuerda los individuos y los acontecimientos que 
conducen a la creación de Las Vegas. En 1855, jóvenes de 
Brigham enviados 30 hombres a la granja, los indios del convertido, y 
construyen un establecimiento a lo largo de un rastro al Pacífico. 
Después de la misión se cerró, un minero estableció un 
rancho, que vino sea la característica más grande del condado bajo 
un propietario más último Helen Stewart. Con venir del 
ferrocarril, Las Vegas se convirtió en una ciudad. Los 
funcionarios del ferrocarril presentaron a una rejilla para la ciudad 
nueva en 1905.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207193</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108577</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-old-mormon-fort-birthplace-of-las-vegas-nevada</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
