<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108010</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108010</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086820</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Shameful Treachery": Hearst's  Journal  Blames Spain</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Shameful Treachery": Journal Hearsts Tadelt
Spanien</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Trahison Honteuse" : Le Journal de Hearst 
Blâme l'Espagne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Treachery Shameful": O Jornal De Hearst 
Responsabiliza Spain</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Treachery Shameful": Il Giornale Del Hearst
Incolpa Della Spagna</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Επαίσχυντη προδοσία": Επιπλήξεις Ισπανία 
περιοδικών Hearst</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Traición Vergonzosa": El Diario De Hearst 
Culpa España</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On February 15, 1898, an explosion ripped through the American battleship  Maine , sinking the ship and killing 260 sailors. Americans responded with outrage, assuming that Spain, which controlled Cuba as a colony, had sunk the ship. Two months later, the slogan "Remember the  Maine " carried the U.S. into war with Spain. In the midst of the hysteria, few Americans paid much attention to the report issued two weeks before the U.S. entry into the war by a Court of Inquiry appointed by President McKinley. The report stated that the committee could not definitively assign blame to Spain for the sinking of the  Maine . Many historians have focused on the role of the "yellow press" (sensationalist newspapers so named because they waged cutthroat circulation battles over comic strips like the popular "Yellow Kid") in stirring up sentiment that propelled the U.S. into its first imperialist war. This editorial in William Randolph Hearst's New York  Journal , from February 17, 1898, pointedly blamed Spain for the sinking of the  Maine , providing an example of how the "yellow press" covered the incident.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf Februar 15, 1898, einer Explosion zerrissen 
durch das amerikanische Linienschiff Maine, das Schiff sinkend und 
beenden 260 Seeleute. Amerikaner reagierten mit dem Verbrechen 
und nahmen dieses Spanien an, dem kontrolliertes Kuba als Kolonie, das
Schiff gesunken hatte. Zwei Monate später, erinnern sich der 
Slogan ", daß das Maine" die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN in Krieg mit Spanien
trug. In der Mitte der Hysterie, lenkten wenige Amerikaner
viel Aufmerksamkeit auf den Report herausgaben zwei Wochen bevor der 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Eintrag in den Krieg durch eine 
Untersuchungskommission ernannt vom Präsidenten McKinley. Der 
Report gab an, daß der Ausschuß nicht Schuld nach Spanien für das 
Sinken des Maines endgültig zuweisen könnte. Viele Historiker 
haben auf die Rolle der "gelben Presse" (sensationalist Zeitungen also
benannt, weil sie komische Streifen des cutthroat Zirkulation 
Schlachtüberschusses wie das populäre "gelbe Zicklein" unternahmen),
beim Rühren herauf Gefühl konzentriert, das die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN 
in seinen ersten imperialist Krieg antrieb. Dieser Leitartikel 
im William Randolph Hearsts New York Journal, von einem Februar 17, 
1898, spitz getadeltes Spanien für das Sinken des Maines, 
bereitstellend ein Beispiel von, wie die "gelbe Presse" das Ereignis 
umfaßte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">15 février 1898, une explosion déchirée par le
cuirassé américain Maine, descendant le bateau et détruisant 260 
marins. Les Américains ont répondu avec l'outrage, assumant la
cette Espagne, que le Cuba commandé en tant que colonie, était 
descendu le bateau. Pendant deux mois plus tard, le slogan "se 
rappellent que le Maine" a porté les ETATS-UNIS dans la guerre avec 
l'Espagne. Au milieu de l'hystérie, peu d'Américains ont 
prêté beaucoup d'attention à l'état ont émis deux semaines avant 
que l'entrée des ETATS-UNIS dans la guerre par une cour d'enquête 
désignée par le Président McKinley. L'état a déclaré que 
le comité ne pourrait pas définitivement assigner le blâme en 
Espagne pour la descente du Maine. Beaucoup d'historiens se sont
concentrés sur le rôle "de la presse jaune" (les journaux 
sensationnalistes ainsi nommé parce qu'ils ont fait les présentations 
horizontales sur microfilm de circulation d'excédent impitoyable de 
batailles comme "le gosse jaune" populaire) dans l'agitation vers le 
haut du sentiment qui a propulsé les ETATS-UNIS dans sa première 
guerre impérialiste. Cet éditorial en journal de New York de 
William Randolph Hearst, à partir février de 17, 1898, Espagne de 
façon tranchante blâmée pour la descente du Maine, fournissant un 
exemple de la façon dont "la presse jaune" a couvert l'incident.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fevereiro em 15, 1898, em uma explosão rasgada 
através do cruzador de batalha americano Maine, afundando o navio e 
matando 260 sailors. Os americanos responderam com o ultraje, 
supondo esse Spain, que Cuba controlada como uma colônia, tinha 
afundado o navio. Dois meses mais tarde, o slogan "recorda que o
Maine" carregou os ESTADOS UNIDOS na guerra com o Spain. No meio
do hysteria, poucos americanos pagaram muita atenção ao relatório 
emitiram duas semanas antes que a entrada de ESTADOS UNIDOS na guerra 
por uma corte de inquérito apontada pelo presidente McKinley. O
relatório indicou que o comitê não poderia definitively atribuir a 
culpa a Spain para se afundar do Maine. Muitos historians 
focalizaram no papel "da imprensa amarela" (jornais do sensationalist 
assim que nomeado porque empreenderam tiras comic do excesso das 
batalhas da circulação do cutthroat como "o miúdo amarelo popular")
em agitar acima do sentiment que propeliu os ESTADOS UNIDOS em sua 
primeira guerra imperialist. Este editorial no jornal de New 
York de William Randolph Hearst, fevereiro de 17, 1898, Spain 
pointedly responsabilizado para afundar-se do Maine, fornecendo um 
exemplo de como "a imprensa amarela" cobriu o incident.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il 15 febbraio 1898, un'esplosione strappata 
tramite il battleship americano Maine, affondante la nave e mortale 
260 marinai. Gli Americani hanno risposto con l'oltraggio, 
ammettente la quella Spagna, che la Cuba controllata come colonia, 
aveva affondato la nave. Due mesi più successivamente, lo 
slogan "si ricorda di che la Maine" ha trasportato gli STATI UNITI 
nella guerra con la Spagna. In mezzo a il hysteria, pochi 
Americani ha prestato molta attenzione al rapporto ha pubblicato due 
settimane prima che l'entrata degli STATI UNITI nella guerra da una 
corte dell'inchiesta nominata dal presidente McKinley. Il 
rapporto ha dichiarato che il comitato non potrebbe definitivo 
assegnare la colpa in Spagna per l'abbassamento della Maine. 
Molti storici hanno messo a fuoco sul ruolo "della pressa 
gialla" (giornali di sensationalist in modo da chiamato perché hanno 
intrapreso le strisce comic dell'eccedenza di battaglie di 
circolazione del cutthroat come "il capretto giallo" popolare) nella 
mescolatura sul sentimento che ha azionato gli STATI UNITI nella 
relativa prima guerra imperialist. Questo editoriale in giornale
de New York del William Randolph Hearst, da 17 febbraio 1898, Spagna 
pointedly incolpata di per l'abbassamento della Maine, fornente un 
esempio di come "la pressa gialla" ha riguardato l'avvenimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις 15 Φεβρουαρίου ..1898, μια έκρηξη έσχισε 
μέσω του αμερικανικού θωρηκτού Maine, που βυθίζει το σκάφος 
και που σκοτώνει 260 ναυτικούς. Αμερικανοί αποκρίθηκαν με
την προσβολή, υποθέτοντας ότι η Ισπανία, που έλεγξε την Κούβα ως
αποικία, είχε βυθίσει το σκάφος. Δύο μήνες αργότερα, το 
σύνθημα "θυμάται ότι το Maine" έφερε τις ΗΠΑ στον πόλεμο με 
την Ισπανία. Στη μέση της υστερίας, λίγοι Αμερικανοί 
έδωσαν πολλή προσοχή στην έκθεση που παρουσιάστηκε δύο 
εβδομάδες πριν από την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ είσοδο μέσα σε τον πόλεμο από
ένα δικαστήριο της έρευνας που διορίστηκε από τον Πρόεδρο 
McKinley. Η έκθεση δήλωσε ότι η επιτροπή δεν θα μπορούσε
να αναθέσει οριστικά την επίπληξη στην Ισπανία για τη βύθιση του 
Maine. Πολλοί ιστορικοί έχουν εστιάσει στο ρόλο του 
"κίτρινου Τύπου" (sensationalist εφημερίδες που ονομάζονται 
έτσι επειδή οι μάχες κυκλοφορίας μαχαιροβγαλτών πέρα από τα 
χιουμοριστικά σκίτσα όπως το δημοφιλές "κίτρινο κατσίκι") να 
ανακατώσουν επάνω το συναίσθημα που ώθησε τις ΗΠΑ στον πρώτο 
ιμπεριαλιστικό πόλεμό του. Αυτό το κύριο άρθρο στο 
περιοδικό William Randolph Hearst's Νέα Υόρκη, από τις 
17 Φεβρουαρίου ..1898, κατηγόρησε pointedly την Ισπανία 
για τη βύθιση του Maine, που παρέχει ένα παράδειγμα για το πώς
ο "κίτρινος Τύποσ" κάλυψε το γεγονός.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">15 de febrero de 1898, una explosión rasgada a
través del acorazado americano Maine, hundiendo la nave y matando a 
260 marineros. Los americanos respondieron con el ultraje, si se
asume esa España, que Cuba controlada como colonia, había hundido la
nave. Dos meses más adelante, el lema "recuerda que el Maine" 
llevó los ESTADOS UNIDOS en guerra con España. En el medio de 
la histeria, pocos americanos prestaron mucha atención al informe 
publicaron dos semanas antes de que la entrada de ESTADOS UNIDOS en la
guerra por una corte de la pregunta designada por presidente McKinley.
El informe indicó que el comité no podría asignar definitivo 
culpa a España para hundirse del Maine. Muchos historiadores se
han centrado en el papel de la "prensa amarilla" (los periódicos del 
sensationalist así que nombrado porque emprendieron historietas del 
excedente de las batallas de la circulación del cutthroat como el 
"cabrito amarillo popular") en el revolvimiento encima del sentimiento
que propulsó los ESTADOS UNIDOS en su primera guerra imperialista. 
Este editorial en el diario de Nueva York de Guillermo Randolph 
Hearst, del de febrero 17 de 1898, España pointedly culpada para 
hundirse del Maine, proporcionando a un ejemplo de cómo la "prensa 
amarilla" cubrió el incidente.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086820</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108010</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/shameful-treachery-hearsts-journal-blames-spain</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
