<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104785</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104785</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087113</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"This Mysterious Road": Levi Coffin Describes his Work on the Underground Railroad in Newport, Indiana, 1820-1850</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Diese Geheimnisvolle Straße": Levi Sarg 
beschreibt seine Arbeit über die unterirdische Eisenbahn in Newport, 
Indiana, 1820-1850</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Cette Route Mystérieuse" : Le cercueil de 
Levi décrit son travail sur le chemin de fer souterrain dans Newport,
Indiana, 1820-1850</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Esta Estrada Misteriosa": O caixão de Levi
descreve seu trabalho na estrada de ferro subterrânea em Newport, 
Indiana, 1820-1850</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Questa Strada Mysterious": La bara di Levi 
descrive il suo lavoro sulla ferrovia sotterranea in Newport, Indiana,
1820-1850</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αυτός ο μυστήριος δρόμοσ": Θ*Λεβη Coffin 
Describes η εργασία του για τον υπόγειο σιδηρόδρομο σε 
Newport, Ινδιάνα, 1820-1850</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Este Camino Misterioso": El ataúd de Levi 
describe su trabajo sobre el ferrocarril subterráneo en Newport, 
Indiana, 1820-1850</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The "locomotives," "conductors," "depots," and "roads" Levi Coffin mentioned in this segment of his  Reminiscences  (published in 1876) are all metaphorical. The Underground Railroad was not composed of steel rails and puffing locomotives but was instead a system of routes, guides, and safe houses used by escaped slaves as they traveled to the freedom of the northern states and Canada. Because of the necessary secrecy of their journeys, it is impossible to know exactly how many slaves escaped on the Underground Railroad during the antebellum years. Historians estimate that the number ranged from several hundred to 1,000 per year. Even with the help of the Underground Railroad, the trip was difficult and dangerous. Escaped slaves typically traveled at night and hid during the day, always on the lookout for slave catchers. Levi Coffin, a Quaker shopkeeper who lived in Newport (now Fountain City), Indiana, worked on the Underground Railroad for many years. After emancipation, he devoted himself to assisting the freedmen.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der "metaphorische alle Lokomotiven," "Leiter," 
"Depots," und "Straßen" Levi Sarg, der in diesem Segment erwähnt 
wird seiner Erinnerungen (veröffentlicht 1876) sind. Die 
unterirdische Eisenbahn bestand nicht aus Stahlschienen und 
luftstoßenden Lokomotiven aber war anstatt ein System der Wege, der 
Anleitungen und der sicheren Häuser, die durch entgangene Sklaven 
benutzt wurden, während sie zur Freiheit der Nordzustände und des 
Kanadas reisten. Wegen der notwendigen Geheimhaltung ihrer 
Reisen, ist es unmöglich, genau zu wissen, wieviele Sklaven auf die 
unterirdische Eisenbahn während der antebellum Jahre entgingen. 
Historiker schätzen, daß die Zahl von mehrereen hundert bis 
1.000 pro Jahr reichte. Sogar mit Hilfe der unterirdischen 
Eisenbahn, war die Reise schwierig und gefährlich. Entgangene 
Sklaven reisten gewöhnlich nachts und versteckten sich während des 
Tages, immer auf dem Ausblick für Sklavenfangfederbleche. Levi 
Sarg, ein Quäkerladenbesitzer, der in Newport wohnte (jetzt 
Brunnen-Stadt), Indiana, bearbeitet auf der unterirdischen Eisenbahn 
für viele Jahre. Nach Emanzipation widmete sich er der 
Unterstützung der Freedmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les "locomotives," des "conducteurs," des 
"dépôts le cercueil de Levi," et de "routes" mentionné dans ce 
segment de ses réminiscences (éditées en 1876) sont toutes 
métaphoriques. Le chemin de fer souterrain ne s'est pas 
composé de rails en acier et de locomotives soufflantes mais était 
à la place un système des itinéraires, des guides, et des maisons 
sûres employées par les esclaves échappés pendant qu'elles 
voyageaient à la liberté des états et du Canada nordiques. En
raison du secret nécessaire de leurs voyages, il est impossible de 
connaître exactement combien d'esclaves se sont échappés sur le 
chemin de fer souterrain pendant les années d'avant-guerre. Les
historiens estiment que le nombre s'est étendu des plusieurs 
centaines à 1.000 par an. Même à l'aide du chemin de fer 
souterrain, le voyage était difficile et dangereux. Les 
esclaves échappés ont typiquement voyagé la nuit et se sont cachés
pendant le jour, toujours sur la surveillance pour les gants de 
baseball slaves. Cercueil de Levi, un commerçant de quaker
qui a habité dans Newport (maintenant ville de fontaine), Indiana, 
travaillé au chemin de fer souterrain pendant beaucoup d'années. 
Après émancipation, il s'est consacré à aider les freedmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As "locomotivas," "condutores," "depósitos o 
caixão de Levi," e das "estradas" mencionado neste segmento de seus 
reminiscences (publicados em 1876) são todas metaphorical. A 
estrada de ferro subterrânea não foi composta dos trilhos de aço e 
de locomotivas soprando mas era preferivelmente um sistema das rotas, 
das guias, e das casas seguras usadas por escravos escapados enquanto 
viajaram à liberdade dos estados e do Canadá do norte. Por 
causa do secrecy necessário de suas viagens, é impossível saber 
exatamente quantos escravos se escaparam na estrada de ferro 
subterrânea durante os anos antebellum. Os historians estimam 
que o número variou de diversos cem a 1.000 por o ano. Mesmo 
com a ajuda da estrada de ferro subterrânea, o desengate era difícil
e perigoso. Os escravos escapados viajaram tipicamente na noite 
e esconderam durante o dia, sempre no lookout para coletores slave. 
Caixão de Levi, um shopkeeper que vivesse em Newport (agora 
cidade da fonte), Indiana do quaker, trabalhado na estrada de ferro 
subterrânea por muitos anos. Após o emancipation, devotou-se a
ajudar aos freedmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"le locomotive," "conduttori," "depositi la bara 
di Levi delle strade" e "," accennata in questo segmento delle sue 
reminiscenze (pubblicate in 1876) sono tutte metaforiche. La 
ferrovia sotterranea non si è composta di rotaie d'acciaio e di 
locomotive soffianti ma era preferibilmente un sistema degli 
itinerari, guide e le case sicuri usate dagli schiavi fuoriusciti 
mentre hanno viaggiato alla libertà del nordico dichiara ed il
Canada. A causa della segretezza necessaria dei loro viaggi, è 
impossible da conoscere esattamente quanti schiavi hanno fuoriuscito 
sulla ferrovia sotterranea durante gli anni antebellum. Gli 
storici valutano che il numero ha variato dai diverse centinaia a 
1.000 all'anno. Anche per mezzo della ferrovia sotterranea, il 
viaggio era difficile e pericoloso. Gli schiavi fuoriusciti 
hanno viaggiato tipicamente alla notte e si sono nascosti durante il 
giorno, sempre sull'allerta per i collettori slave. Bara di 
Levi, un commerciante che ha vissuto in Newport (ora città della 
fontana), Indiana del quaker, lavorata alla ferrovia sotterranea per 
molti anni. Dopo emancipazione, si è dedicato ad aiutare i 
freedmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι "ατμομηχανές," "αγωγοί," "αποθήκες," και "δρόμοι" 
Levi Coffin ανέφεραν σε αυτό το τμήμα μνήμης 
reminiscences του (που δημοσιεύονται 1876) είναι όλα 
μεταφορικά. Ο υπόγειος σιδηρόδρομος δεν αποτελούταν από τις
ράγες χάλυβα και τις ξεφυσώντας ατμομηχανές αλλά ήταν αντ' 
αυτού ένα σύστημα των διαδρομών, των οδηγών, και των ασφαλών 
σπιτιών που χρησιμοποιήθηκαν από τους δραπετευμένους σκλάβους 
καθώς ταξίδεψαν στην ελευθερία των βόρειων κρατών και του 
Καναδά. Λόγω της απαραίτητης μυστικότητας των ταξιδιών 
τους, είναι αδύνατο να είναι γνωστό ακριβώς πόσοι σκλάβοι 
δραπέτευσαν στον υπόγειο σιδηρόδρομο κατά τη διάρκεια των 
προπολεμικών ετών. Οι ιστορικοί υπολογίζουν ότι ο αριθμός 
κυμάνθηκε από αρκετές έως 1.000 ετησίως. Ακόμη και με 
τη βοήθεια του υπόγειου σιδηροδρόμου, το ταξίδι ήταν δύσκολο και
επικίνδυνο. Οι δραπετευμένοι σκλάβοι ταξίδεψαν 
χαρακτηριστικά τη νύχτα και έκρυψαν κατά τη διάρκεια της ημέρας,
πάντα στην επιφυλακή για catchers σκλάβων. Ο Levi 
Coffin, ένας κουάκερος καταστηματάρχης που έζησε σε Newport 
(τώρα πόλη πηγών), Ινδιάνα, εργάστηκε στον υπόγειο σιδηρόδρομο 
για πολλά έτη. Μετά από την χειραφέτηση, αφιερώθηκε 
στην ενίσχυση των απελευθέρων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las "locomotoras," los "conductores," los 
"depósitos el ataúd de Levi," y de los "caminos" mencionado en este 
segmento de sus reminiscencias (publicadas en 1876) son todas 
metafóricas. El ferrocarril subterráneo no fue compuesto de 
los carriles de acero y de las locomotoras que soplaban sino era en 
lugar de otro un sistema de rutas, de guías, y de casas seguras 
usadas por los esclavos escapados mientras que viajaron a la libertad 
de los estados y del Canadá norteños. Debido a el secreto 
necesario de sus viajes, es imposible saber exactamente cuántos 
esclavos se escaparon en el ferrocarril subterráneo durante los años
antebellum. Los historiadores estiman que el número se 
extendió de varios cientos a 1.000 por año. Incluso con la 
ayuda del ferrocarril subterráneo, el viaje era difícil y peligroso.
Los esclavos escapados viajaron típicamente en la noche y 
ocultaron durante el día, siempre en el puesto de observación para 
los colectores auxiliares. Ataúd de Levi, comerciante que 
vivió en Newport (ahora ciudad de la fuente), Indiana del quaker, 
trabajada en el ferrocarril subterráneo por muchos años. 
Después de la emancipación, él se dedicó a asistir a los 
freedmen.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087113</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104785</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/this-mysterious-road-levi-coffin-describes-his-work-on-the-underground-railroad-in-newport-indiana-1820-1850</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
