<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104187</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104187</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205760</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Gilbert Stuart: Works</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gilbert Stuart: Arbeiten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Gilbert Stuart : Travaux</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Gilbert Stuart: Trabalhos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gilbert Stuart: Impianti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Gilbert stuart: Εργασίες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Gilbert Estuardo: Trabajos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">portrayed virtually all the notable men and women of the Federal period in the U.S., and was declared the Father of American Portraiture by his contemporaries. Stuart portrayed American and European figures, including George Washington, John and Abigail Adams, John Jay, and Robert Liston. In 1805 he painted the Gibbs-Coolidge Set, the only surviving depiction of the first five presidents.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">geschildert praktisch allen bemerkenswerten 
Männern und Frauen der Bundesperiode in den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN und 
wurde dem Vater von amerikanischem Portraiture von seinen Zeitgenossen
erklärt. Stuart schilderte die amerikanischen und europäischen
Abbildungen, einschließlich George Washington, John und Abigail 
Adams, John Eichelhäher und Robert Liston. 1805 malte er das 
Gibbs-Coolidge Set, die einzige Überlebenbeschreibung der ersten 
fünf Präsidenten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dépeint pratiquement tous les hommes et femmes 
notables de la période fédérale aux ETATS-UNIS, et a été 
déclaré le père de l'Art du portrait américain par ses contemporains. 
Stuart a dépeint les figures américaines et européennes, y 
compris George Washington, John et Abigail Adams, geai de John, et
Robert Liston. En 1805 il a peint le positionnement de 
Gibbs-Coolidge, la seule description de survie des cinq premiers 
présidents.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">portrayed virtualmente todos os homens e mulheres 
notáveis do período federal nos ESTADOS UNIDOS, e foi declarado o 
pai de Portraiture americano por seus comtemporâneos. Stuart 
portrayed figuras americanas e européias, including George 
Washington, John e Abigail Adams, jay de John, e Robert Liston. 
Em 1805 pintou o jogo de Gibbs-Coolidge, o único depiction 
sobreviver dos primeiros cinco presidentes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ritratto virtualmente tutti gli uomini e donne 
notevoli del periodo federale negli STATI UNITI ed è stato dichiarato
il padre di Portraiture americano dai suoi contemporanei. Stuart
ha ritratto le figure americane ed europee, compresi George 
Washington, John ed Abigail Adams, jay del John e Robert Liston. 
In 1805 ha verniciato l'insieme di Gibbs-Coolidge, l'unico 
depiction di sopravvivenza dei primi cinque presidenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">απεικονισμένος ουσιαστικά όλους τους ξεχωριστούς 
άνδρες και τις γυναίκες της ομοσπονδιακής περιόδου στις ΗΠΑ, και 
δηλώθηκε τον πατέρα του αμερικανικού πορτρέτου από τους 
συγχρόνους του. Stuart απεικόνισε τους αμερικανικούς και 
ευρωπαϊκούς αριθμούς, συμπεριλαμβανομένου George Ουάσιγκτον, 
John και της Abigail Adams, John Jay, και Robert 
Liston. Το 1805 χρωμάτισε το γηψψς- Coolidge σύνολο, 
η μόνη επιζούσα απεικόνιση των πρώτων πέντε Προέδρων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">retratado virtualmente todos los hombres y mujeres
notables del período federal en los ESTADOS UNIDOS, y fue declarado 
el padre de Portraiture americano por sus contemporáneos. 
Estuardo retrató figuras americanas y europeas, incluyendo 
George Washington, Juan y Abigail Adams, jay de Juan, y Roberto 
Liston. En 1805 él pintó el conjunto de Gibbs-Coolidge, la 
única pintura el sobrevivir de los primeros cinco presidentes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205760</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104187</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/gilbert-stuart-works</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
