<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103640</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103640</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205335</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">You Decide: Should the United States government reinstate the military draft?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sie Entscheiden: Sollte die Vereinigte 
Staaten Regierung den militärischen Entwurf wiedereinsetzen?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vous Décidez : Le gouvernement des 
Etats-Unis devrait-il rétablir l'ébauche militaire ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Você Decide-se: Deve o governo unido dos 
estados restabelecer o esboço militar?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Decidete: Dovrebbe unito Dichiara il
governo reintegrano la brutta copia militare?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αποφασίζετε: Θα έπρεπε η Ηνωμένη κυβέρνηση να 
επανεγκαταστήσει το στρατιωτικό σχέδιο;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usted Decide: ¿Debe el gobierno de Estados 
Unidos reinstalar el bosquejo militar?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This educational guide focuses on whether or not the United States government should reinstate the military draft. Students are invited to examine the arguments on both sides of the debate, developing critical thinking skills as they work through the activities. Students will learn how to support their arguments with evidence and reason. It is expected that at the end of this guide students will determine where they stand on this controversial issue.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese pädagogische Anleitung fokussiert an, ob oder nicht
die Vereinigte Staaten Regierung den militärischen Entwurf 
wiedereinsetzen sollte. Kursteilnehmer werden eingeladen, die 
Argumente auf beiden Seiten der Debatte zu überprüfen und entwickeln
kritische denkende Fähigkeiten, während sie durch die Aktivitäten 
arbeiten. Kursteilnehmer erlernen, wie man ihre Argumente mit 
Beweis und Grund unterstützt. Es wird erwartet, daß am Ende 
dieser Anleitung Kursteilnehmer feststellen, wo sie zu diesem 
umstrittenen Punkt stehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce guide éducatif se focalise en fonction, qu'ou pas le 
gouvernement uni d'états devrait rétablir l'ébauche militaire. 
Des étudiants sont invités à examiner les arguments des deux 
côtés de la discussion, développant des qualifications de pensée 
critiques pendant qu'ils travaillent par les activités. Les 
étudiants apprendront comment supporter leurs arguments avec 
l'évidence et la raison. On s'attend à ce qu'à l'extrémité 
de ce guide les étudiants déterminent où ils se tiennent sur cette 
question controversée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta guia educacional focaliza sobre se ou não o governo 
unido dos estados deve restabelecer o esboço militar. Os 
estudantes estão convidados examinar os argumentos em ambos os lados 
do debate, desenvolvendo habilidades pensando críticas enquanto 
trabalham com as atividades. Os estudantes aprenderão como 
suportar seus argumentos com evidência e razão. Espera-se que 
na extremidade desta guia os estudantes determinarão onde estão 
nesta edição controversa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa guida educativa mette a fuoco sopra se o non unito 
Dichiara il governo dovrebbe reintegrare la brutta copia 
militare. Gli allievi sono invitati ad esaminare gli argomenti 
da entrambi i lati del dibattito, sviluppanti le abilità pensanti 
critiche mentre lavorano con le attività. Gli allievi 
impareranno come sostenere i loro argomenti con prova e motivo. 
È previsto che all'estremità di questa guida allievi 
determinino dove si levano in piedi su questa edizione discutibile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο εκπαιδευτικός οδηγός εστιάζει εάν η Ηνωμένη 
κυβέρνηση πρέπει ή όχι να επανεγκαταστήσει το στρατιωτικό 
σχέδιο. Οι σπουδαστές καλούνται για να εξετάσουν τα 
ορίσματα και στις δύο πλευρές της συζήτησης, που αναπτύσσει τις 
κρίσιμες δεξιότητες σκέψης όπως λειτουργούν μέσω των 
δραστηριοτήτων. Οι σπουδαστές θα μάθουν πώς να υποστηρίξουν
τα ορίσματά τους με τα στοιχεία και το λόγο. Αναμένεται 
ότι στο τέλος αυτού του οδηγού οι σπουδαστές θα καθορίσουν όπου
στέκονται σε αυτό το αμφισβητούμενο ζήτημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta guía educativa se enfoca encendido si o no el 
gobierno de Estados Unidos debe reinstalar el bosquejo militar. 
Se invita a los estudiantes que examinen los argumentos en ambas
caras del discusión, desarrollando habilidades de pensamiento 
críticas mientras que trabajan con las actividades. Los 
estudiantes aprenderán cómo utilizar sus argumentos con evidencia y 
razón. Se espera que en el extremo de esta guía los 
estudiantes se determinen dónde están parados en esta edición 
polémica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205335</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103640</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/you-decide-should-the-united-states-government-reinstate-the-military-draft</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
