<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105599</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105599</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086359</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Jack London Looks at the "Simplified Language of Socialism"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jack London betrachtet die "vereinfachte Sprache 
von sozialismus"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jack Londres regarde "le langage simplifié du 
socialisme"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jack Londres olha "a língua simplificada do 
socialismo"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Jack Londra guarda "il linguaggio semplificato del
socialism"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Jack Λονδίνο εξετάζει τη "απλουστευμένη γλώσσα 
του σοσιαλισμού"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Gato Londres mira el "lenguaje simplificado del 
socialismo"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Not all Progressive-era crusades involved the regulation of economic and political practices. One of the oddest early twentieth-century reform movements was the effort to simplify the way words were spelled. Seemingly peripheral, spelling reform, with its emphasis on "order" and "rationality," actually typified the Progressive era. The lack of standardization in American spelling was viewed as chaotic, inefficient, and irrational. This quest for order and efficiency helped foster a growing faith in the technical expert and the professional, while equally fostering a distrust of political parties. Like spelling reform, many Progressive reforms took place outside the traditional channels of the political party. In this 1907 article (titled "Simplified Language of Socialism") from the radical newspaper  Appeal to Reason , author Jack London and fellow socialist Arthur George took aim at the "simplified spelling" movement--and at the inequalities of early twentieth-century industrial capitalism--with a humorous list of suggested deletions from the English language.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nicht alle Progressiv-Ära Kreuzzüge bezogen die 
Regelung der ökonomischen und politischen Praxis mit ein. Eine 
der ungeradesten frühen Zwanzigstjahrhundert Reformbewegungen war die
Bemühung, die Methode zu vereinfachen, die Wörter buchstabiert 
wurden. Scheinbar peripher, Verbesserung, mit seinem 
Hauptgewicht auf "Ordnung" und "Vernunft buchstabierend," verkörperte
wirklich die progressive Ära. Der Mangel an Normierung in der 
amerikanischen Rechtschreibung wurde angesehen, wie chaotisch, 
wirkungslos und vernunftwidriges. Diese Suche nach Ordnung und 
die geholfene Leistungsfähigkeit fördern einen wachsenden Glauben im
technischen Experten und im Fachmann, beim ein Mißtrauen der 
politischen Parteien gleichmäßig fördern. Wie 
Rechtschreibungverbesserung fanden viele progressive Verbesserungen 
außerhalb der traditionellen Führungen der politischen 
Partei statt. In diesem Artikel 1907 (betitelt 
"vereinfachte Sprache von sozialismus") vom radikalen Zeitung Anklang 
an Grund, nahmen Autor Jack London und Gefährte sozialistischer 
Arthur George anstreben die Bewegung "der vereinfachten 
Rechtschreibung" -- und an den Verschiedenheiten frühes 
Zwanzigstjahrhundert des industriellen Kapitalismus -- mit einer 
humorvollen Liste der vorgeschlagenen Auslassungen von der englischen 
Sprache.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Non toutes les croisades de Progressif-ère ont 
impliqué le règlement des pratiques économiques et politiques. 
Un des mouvements de réforme tôt les plus impairs de 
vingtième-siècle était l'effort de simplifier la voie que des mots 
ont été orthographiés. Apparemment périphérique, 
orthographiant la réforme, avec son emphase sur la "commande" et la 
"rationalité," a caractérisé réellement l'ère progressive. 
Le manque d'étalonnage dans l'épellation américaine a été 
visualisé comme chaotique, inefficace, et irrationnel. Cette 
recherche pour la commande et efficacité aidée stimulent une foi 
croissante dans l'expert technique et le professionnel, tout en 
également stimulant une méfiance des parties politiques. Comme
la réforme d'épellation, beaucoup de réformes progressives ont eu 
lieu en dehors des canaux traditionnels de la partie politique. 
En cet article 1907 (intitulé "langage simplifié de 
socialisme") de l'appel radical de journal à la raison, l'auteur Jack
Londres et le camarade Arthur socialiste George ont pris visent 
le mouvement "d'épellation simplifiée" -- et aux inégalités du 
capitalisme industriel de vingtième-siècle tôt -- avec une liste 
pleine d'humour de suppressions suggérées de l'anglais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Não todos os crusades da Progressivo-era 
envolveram o regulamento de práticas econômicas e políticas. 
Um dos movimentos de reforma adiantados os mais impares de 
vigésimo-século era o esforço simplificar a maneira que as palavras
foram soletradas. Seemingly periférico, soletrando a reforma, 
com sua ênfase na "ordem" e no "rationality," typified realmente a 
era progressiva. A falta da estandardização na soletração 
americana foi vista como chaotic, inefficient, e irrational. 
Este quest para a ordem e a eficiência ajudada promovem uma fé
crescente no perito técnico e no profissional, ao ingualmente 
promover um distrust de partidos políticos. Como a reforma da 
soletração, muitas reformas progressivas ocorreram fora das 
canaletas tradicionais do partido político. Neste artigo 1907 
(intitulado "língua simplificada do socialismo") da apelação 
radical do jornal à razão, o autor Jack Londres e o companheiro 
Arthur socialist George fizeram exame visam "o movimento da 
soletração simplificada" -- e nos desigualdades do capitalismo 
industrial de vigésimo-século adiantado -- com uma lista humorous de
apagamentos sugeridos da língua inglesa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Non tutti i crusades di Progressivo-era hanno 
coinvolto la regolazione delle pratiche economiche e politiche. 
Uno dei movimenti di riforma in anticipo più dispari di 
ventesimo-secolo era lo sforzo facilitare il modo che le parole sono 
state ortografate. Apparentemente periferico, ortografando la 
riforma, con la relativa enfasi "su ordine" e "sulla razionalità," 
realmente ha caratterizzato l'era progressiva. La mancanza di 
normalizzazione nell'ortografia americana è stata osservata come 
caotica, inefficiente ed irrazionale. Questa ricerca per ordine 
ed il risparmio di temi aiutato promuovono una fede crescente 
nell'esperto tecnico e nel professionista, mentre ugualmente 
promuovono una diffidenza dei partiti politici. Come la riforma 
di ortografia, molte riforme progressive hanno avvenuto fuori delle 
scanalature tradizionali del partito politico. In questo 
articolo 1907 (nominato "linguaggio semplificato del socialism") 
dall'appello radicale del giornale a motivo, l'autore Jack Londra ed 
il collega Arthur socialista George hanno preso puntano "sul movimento
di ortografia semplificata" -- ed alle diseguaglianze di capitalismo 
industriale di ventesimo-secolo in anticipo -- con una lista 
divertente delle omissioni suggerite dalla lingua inglese.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όχι όλες οι σταυροφορίες προοδευτικός-εποχής 
περιέλαβαν τον κανονισμό των οικονομικών και πολιτικών πρακτικών.
Ένα από τα πιό περίεργα πρόωρα κινήματα μεταρρύθμισης 
εικοστός-αιώνα ήταν η προσπάθεια να απλοποιηθεί ο τρόπος που τις
λέξεις συλλάβισαν. Φαινομενικά η απομακρυσμένη, 
μεταρρύθμιση συλλαβισμού, με την έμφασή της σε παραγγελία "" και 
"την ορθολογιστική ικανότητα," πραγματικά απεικόνισε την 
προοδευτική εποχή. Η έλλειψη τυποποίησης στην αμερικανική 
ορθογραφία εμφανίστηκε όπως χαοτική, ανεπαρκής, και παράλογη. 
Αυτή η αναζήτηση για την κατάταξη και αποδοτικότητα που 
ενισχύεται να ενθαρρύνει μια αυξανόμενη πίστη στον τεχνικό 
εμπειρογνώμονα και τον επαγγελματία, εξίσου ενθαρρύνοντας μια 
δυσπιστία των πολιτικών κομμάτων. Όπως τη μεταρρύθμιση 
ορθογραφίας, πολλές προοδευτικές μεταρρυθμίσεις πραγματοποιήθηκαν
έξω από τα παραδοσιακά κανάλια του πολιτικού κόμματος. Σε 
αυτό το άρθρο του 1907 (με τον τίτλο "απλουστευμένη γλώσσα του
σοσιαλισμού") από τη ριζική έκκληση εφημερίδων στο λόγο, ο 
συντάκτης Jack Λονδίνο και συντροφικός σοσιαλιστικός αρθούρος 
George πήραν το στόχο στη μετακίνηση "απλουστευμένης 
ορθογραφίασ" -- και στις ανισότητες της πρόωρης βιομηχανικής 
κεφαλαιοκρατίας εικοστός-αιώνα -- με έναν χιουμοριστικό κατάλογο
προτεινόμενων διαγραφών από την αγγλική γλώσσα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">No todas las cruzadas de la Progresivo-era 
implicaron la regulación de prácticas económicas y políticas. 
Uno de los movimientos de reforma tempranos más impares del 
vige'simo-siglo era el esfuerzo de simplificar la manera que las 
palabras fueron deletreadas. Aparentemente periférico, 
deletreando reforma, con su énfasis en "orden" y "racionalidad," 
caracterizó realmente la era progresiva. La carencia de la 
estandardización en el deletreo americano fue vista como caótica, 
ineficaz, e irracional. Esta búsqueda para la orden y la 
eficacia ayudada fomentan una fe cada vez mayor en el experto técnico
y el profesional, mientras que igualmente fomenta una desconfianza de 
partidos políticos. Como reforma del deletreo, muchas reformas 
progresivas ocurrieron fuera de los canales tradicionales del partido 
político. En este artículo 1907 (titulado "lenguaje 
simplificado del socialismo") de la súplica radical del periódico a 
la razón, el autor Gato Londres y el compañero Arturo socialista 
George tomaron tienen como objetivo el movimiento del "deletreo 
simplificado" -- y en las desigualdades del capitalismo industrial del
vige'simo-siglo temprano -- con una lista chistosa de cancelacínes 
sugeridas del lenguaje inglés.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086359</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105599</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/jack-london-looks-at-the-simplified-language-of-socialism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
