<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105739</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105739</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213123</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Weekly Volcanic Activity Report</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wöchentlicher Vulkanischer Tätigkeitsbericht</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Rapport d'activité Volcanique Hebdomadaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Relatório De Atividade Vulcânico Semanal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rapporto d'attività Vulcanico Settimanale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εβδομαδιαία ηφαιστειακή έκθεση δραστηριότητας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Informe De Actividad Volcánico Semanal</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Weekly Volcanic Activity Report is a cooperative project between the Global Volcanism Program of the Smithsonian's National Museum of Natural History and the US Geological Survey's Volcano Hazards Program. The project provides up-to-date worldwide volcanic activity information. Users can access regional maps as well as a map of volcanoes discussed each week. New eruption information is provided as well as updates for ongoing eruptions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der wöchentliche vulkanische Tätigkeitsbericht 
ist ein kooperatives Projekt zwischen dem globalen 
Vulkanismus-Programm des Smithsonian nationalen Museums der 
Naturgeschichte und der US geologischen Vulkan-Gefahr-dem Programm 
Übersicht. Das Projekt liefert aktuelle weltweite vulkanische 
Aktivität Informationen. Benutzer können auf regionale Karten 
sowie eine Karte behandelten Vulkane zugreifen jede der Woche. 
Neue Eruption Informationen werden zur Verfügung gestellt, 
sowie Aktualisierungsvorgänge für fortwährende Eruptionen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le rapport d'activité volcanique hebdomadaire est
un projet coopératif entre le programme global de volcanisme du 
musée national Smithsonien de l'histoire naturelle et le programme de
risques du volcan de l'enquête géologique des USA. Le projet 
fournit des informations volcaniques mondiales à jour d'activité. 
Les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux cartes régionales comme 
une carte des volcans discutés chaque semaine. De nouvelles 
informations d'éruption sont fournies comme des mises à jour pour 
des éruptions continues.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O relatório de atividade vulcânico semanal é um
projeto cooperativo entre o programa global do volcanism do museu 
nacional smithsonian do history natural e o programa dos perigos do 
vulcão do exame geological dos E. U.. O projeto fornece a 
informação vulcânica worldwide moderna da atividade. Os 
usuários podem alcançar mapas regionais assim como um mapa dos 
vulcões discutidos cada semana. A informação nova do eruption
é fornecida assim como updates para eruptions ongoing.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il rapporto d'attività vulcanico settimanale è 
un progetto cooperativo fra il programma globale di volcanism del 
museo nazionale smithsonian di storia naturale ed il programma di 
rischi del vulcano dell'indagine geologica degli Stati Uniti. Il
progetto fornisce le informazioni vulcaniche in tutto il mondo 
aggiornate di attività. Gli utenti possono accedere ai 
programmi regionali come pure un programma dei vulcani discussi ogni 
settimana. Le nuove informazioni di eruption sono fornite come 
pure gli aggiornamenti per i eruptions continui.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εβδομαδιαία ηφαιστειακή έκθεση δραστηριότητας είναι
ένα συνεταιριστικό έργο μεταξύ του σφαιρικού volcanism 
προγράμματος του σμιθσονιτικού εθνικού μουσείου της φυσικής 
ιστορίας και του προγράμματος κινδύνων ηφαιστείων της 
αμερικανικής γεωλογικής έρευνας. Το πρόγραμμα παρέχει τις 
ενημερωμένες παγκόσμιες ηφαιστειακές πληροφορίες δραστηριότητας. 
Οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στους περιφερειακούς 
χάρτες καθώς επίσης και έναν χάρτη των ηφαιστείων που 
συζητούνται κάθε εβδομάδα. Οι νέες πληροφορίες έκρηξης 
παρέχονται καθώς επίσης και αναπροσαρμογές για τις τρέχουσες 
εκρήξεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El informe de actividad volcánico semanal es un 
proyecto cooperativo entre el programa global del volcanismo del museo
nacional smithsonian de la historia natural y el programa de los 
peligros del volcán de la encuesta sobre geológica los E.E.U.U.. 
El proyecto proporciona a la información volcánica mundial 
actualizada de la actividad. Los utilizadores pueden tener 
acceso a correspondencias regionales tan bien como una correspondencia
de los volcanes discutidos cada semana. Se proporciona la nueva 
información de la erupción tan bien como las actualizaciones para 
las erupciones en curso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GLOBAL VOLCANISM PROGRAM
FN:GLOBAL VOLCANISM PROGRAM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213123</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105739</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/weekly-volcanic-activity-report</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
