<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104997</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104997</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973969</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Uchuhiko</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Uchuhiko</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Uchuhiko</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uchuhiko</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Uchuhiko</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Uchuhiko</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Uchuhiko</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">"Uchuhiko" (Japanese for Space Flight) is a wrapper for NASA/JPL's online Solar System Simulator running with both, QVGA and VGA Pocket PC screens. When you select date and time, view-to object (left combo box) and view-from object (right combo box) plus a field of view, Uchuhiko will download a computed and rendered image from the Solar System Simulator server. Tap and hold on a downloaded image to confirm settings. Simulate almost any exciting phenomena in the solar system by simply providing the date and time for a given event!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Uchuhiko" (japanisch für Platz-Flug) ist eine 
Verpackung für NASA/JPL's den Onlinesolarsystem Simulator, der mit 
beide, QVGA und VGA Tasche PC Bildschirmen läuft. Wenn Sie 
Datum und Zeit auswählen, Ansicht- zur Nachricht (linker kombinierter
Kasten) und Ansicht- von der Nachricht (rechter kombinierter Kasten) 
plus auffangene der Ansicht, downloadet Uchuhiko ein Berechnungs- 
und übertragenes Bild vom Solarsystem Simulatorserver. Klopfen 
Sie und halten Sie auf einem downloadeten Bild an, um Einstellungen zu
bestätigen. Simulieren Sie fast alle aufregenden Phänomene im 
Solarsystem, indem Sie einfach das Datum und die Zeit für einen 
gegebenen Fall zur Verfügung stellen!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Uchuhiko" (japonais pour le vol spatial) est un 
emballage pour le simulateur en ligne de système solaire de 
NASA/JPL's fonctionnant avec des écrans de PC de poche de tous les 
deux, de QVGA et de VGA. Quand vous choisissez la date et 
l'heure, vue- à l'objet (cadre combo gauche) et vue- de l'objet 
(cadre combo droit) plus un champ visuel, Uchuhiko téléchargera une 
image calculée et rendue du serveur de simulateur de système 
solaire. Tapez et tenez sur une image téléchargée pour 
confirmer des configurations. Simulez presque tous les 
phénomènes passionnants dans le système solaire en fournissant 
simplement la date et l'heure pour un événement donné !</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Uchuhiko" (japonês para o vôo de espaço) é um
envoltório para o simulador em linha do sistema solar de NASA/JPL's 
que funciona com as telas do PC do bolso ambos, de QVGA e de VGA. 
Quando você seleciona a data e a hora, vista- ao objeto (caixa 
combo esquerda) e vista- do objeto (caixa combo direita) mais um campo
de vista, Uchuhiko download uma imagem computada e rendida do server 
do simulador do sistema solar. Bata e prenda em uma imagem 
downloaded para confirmar ajustes. Simule quase todos os 
fenômenos emocionantes no sistema solar simplesmente fornecendo a 
data e a hora para um evento dado!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Uchuhiko" (giapponese per il volo spaziale) è un
involucro per il simulatore in linea del sistema solare di NASA/JPL's 
che funziona con gli schermi del pc della tasca entrambi, di QVGA e di
VGA. Quando selezionate la data ed il tempo, vista- ad oggetto 
(casella combinata di sinistra) e vista- da oggetto (casella combinata
di destra) più un campo di visibilità, Uchuhiko trasferirà 
un'immagine dal sistema centrale verso i satelliti computata e resa 
dal server del simulatore del sistema solare. Colpisca e tenga 
su un'immagine trasferita per confermare le regolazioni. Simuli 
quasi tutti i fenomeni emozionanti nel sistema solare semplicemente 
fornendo la data ed il tempo per un dato evento!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Uchuhiko" (ιαπωνικά για τη διαστημική πτήση) είναι
ένα περιτύλιγμα για το σε απευθείας σύνδεση προσομοιωτή ηλιακών 
συστημάτων της NASA/$l*JPL που τρέχει και με τους δύο, τις 
οθόνες PC τσεπών QVGA και VGA. Όταν επιλέγετε την 
ημερομηνία και το χρόνο, όψη-για να αντιτεθεί (αριστερό κιβώτιο 
combo) και όψη-από το αντικείμενο (σωστό κιβώτιο combo) συν
ένα οπτικό πεδίο, Uchuhiko θα μεταφορτώσει μια υπολογισμένη 
και εικόνα από τον κεντρικό υπολογιστή προσομοιωτών ηλιακών 
συστημάτων. Βρύση και λαβή σε μια μεταφορτωμένη εικόνα για 
να επιβεβαιώσει τις τιμές των παραμέτρων. Μιμηθείτε σχεδόν 
οποιαδήποτε συναρπαστικά φαινόμενα στο ηλιακό σύστημα με απλά να
παράσχει την ημερομηνία και το χρόνο για ένα δεδομένο γεγονός!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Uchuhiko" (japonés para el vuelo espacial) es 
una envoltura para el simulador en línea de la Sistema Solar de 
NASA/JPL's que se ejecuta con las pantallas de la PC del bolsillo 
ambos, de QVGA y de VGA. Cuando usted selecciona la fecha y la 
hora, vista- al objeto (rectángulo combo izquierdo) y vista- del 
objeto (rectángulo combo derecho) más un campo visual, Uchuhiko 
descargará una imagen computada y rendida del servidor del simulador 
de la Sistema Solar. Golpee ligeramente y sostenga en una imagen
descargada para confirmar configuraciones. ¡Simule casi 
cualquier fenómeno emocionante en la Sistema Solar simplemente 
proporcionando a la fecha y a la hora para un acontecimiento dado!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973969</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104997</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/uchuhiko</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
