<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108492</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108492</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207175</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Independence Hall: International Symbol of Freedom</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unabhängigkeit Hall: Internationales Symbol
der Freiheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Indépendance Hall : Symbole international
de la liberté</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Independência Salão: Símbolo 
internacional da liberdade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Indipendenza Corridoio: Simbolo 
internazionale di libertà</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αίθουσα ανεξαρτησίας: Διεθνές σύμβολο της 
ελευθερίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Independencia Pasillo: Símbolo 
internacional de la libertad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recounts the history of the building in Philadelphia where the Second Continental Congress signed the Declaration of Independence and where, a decade later, delegates to the Philadelphia Convention formulated the Constitution: the Pennsylvania State House. The Pennsylvania Assembly, which had been meeting in homes and taverns, moved into the building in September 1735. It was considered the most ambitious public building in the colonies.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zählt die Geschichte des Gebäudes in 
Philadelphia, in dem der zweite kontinentale Kongreß die 
Unabhängigkeitserklärung unterzeichnete und wo, eine Dekade später,
Delegierte zur Philadelphia Versammlung formulierte die Beschaffenheit
nach: das Pennsylvania Zustand-Haus. Das Pennsylvania, das
in den Häusern und in den Taverns getroffen hatte, bewog in das 
Gebäude im September 1735. Es galt als das ehrgeizigste 
allgemeine Gebäude in den Kolonien.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">raconte l'histoire du bâtiment à Philadelphie 
où le deuxième congrès continental a signé la déclaration de 
l'indépendance et où, une décennie plus tard, des délégués à la
convention de Philadelphie a formulé la constitution : la 
Chambre d'état de la Pennsylvanie. l'Assemblée de la 
Pennsylvanie, qui s'était réunie dans les maisons et les tavernes, 
est entrée dans le bâtiment en septembre 1735. On l'a 
considéré le bâtiment public le plus ambitieux dans les colonies.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">recounts o history do edifício em Filadélfia 
onde o segundo congress continental assinou a declaração de 
independência e onde, uma década mais tarde, delegados à 
convenção de Filadélfia formulou o constitution: a casa do 
estado de Pensilvânia. O conjunto de Pensilvânia, que se tem 
encontrado com nas HOME e nos taverns, moveu-se no edifício em 
setembro 1735. Considerou-se o edifício público o mais 
ambicioso nas colônias.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">racconta la storia della costruzione a Filadelfia 
in cui il secondo congresso continentale ha firmato la dichiarazione 
di indipendenza e dove, una decade più successivamente, delegati alla
convenzione de Filadelfia ha formulato la costituzione: la 
Pensilvania Dichiara la Camera. L'Assemblea della 
Pensilvania, che stava venendo a contatto di nelle sedi e nelle 
locande, ha entrato nella costruzione nel mese di settembre del 1735. 
È stato considerato la costruzione pubblica più ambiziosa 
nelle colonie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξιστορεί την ιστορία του κτηρίου στη Φιλαδέλφεια 
όπου το δεύτερο ηπειρωτικό συνέδριο υπέγραψε τη Διακήρυξη της 
ανεξαρτησίας και πού, μια δεκαετία αργότερα, οι εκπρόσωποι στη 
Συνθήκη της Φιλαδέλφειας διατύπωσαν το σύνταγμα: το κρατικό
σπίτι της Πενσυλβανίας. Η συμβολική γλώσσα της 
Πενσυλβανίας, η οποία συναντιόταν στα σπίτια και τις ταβέρνες, 
που κινήθηκαν στο κτήριο τον Σεπτέμβριο του 1735. 
Θεωρήθηκε πιό φιλόδοξο δημόσιο κτήριο στις αποικίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contó de nuevo la historia del edificio en 
Philadelphia en donde el segundo congreso continental firmó el 
declaración de la independencia y donde, una década más adelante, 
los delegados a la convención de Philadelphia formuló la 
constitución: la casa del estado de Pennsylvania. La 
asamblea de Pennsylvania, que había estado satisfaciendo en hogares y
tabernas, se movió en el edificio en septiembre de 1735. Era 
considerado el edificio público más ambicioso de las colonias.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207175</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108492</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/independence-hall-international-symbol-of-freedom</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
