<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107277</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107277</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203971</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Microbiology Unit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mikrobiologie-Maßeinheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Unité De Microbiologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Unidade Do Microbiology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Unità Di Microbiologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μονάδα μικροβιολογίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Unidad De la Microbiología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The site features a College Level Microbiology Unit. It is comprised of five lesson plans which cover content areas of microbial architecture, ecology, physiology, life cycles, and pathology. Each lesson plan includes student expectations, student and teacher materials, lesson format, teaching and learning strategies, assessment and evaluation tools, accommodations, extensions, resources, worksheets, and answer keys.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Situationsmerkmale eine Hochschulstufe 
Mikrobiologie-Maßeinheit. Sie wird von fünf Lektionplänen 
enthalten, die zufriedene Bereiche der Mikrobenarchitektur, der 
Ökologie, der Physiologie, der Lebenszyklen und der Pathologie 
umfassen. Jeder Lektionplan schließt Kursteilnehmererwartungen,
Kursteilnehmer und Lehrermaterialien, das Lektionformat ein und 
unterrichtet und Lernenstrategien, Einschätzung und Auswertung 
Hilfsmittel, Anpassungen, Extensionen, Betriebsmittel, Bogen und 
Antworttasten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les dispositifs de site une unité de 
microbiologie de niveau d'université. Elle est composée de 
cinq plans de leçon qui couvrent des domaines contents 
d'architecture, d'écologie, de physiologie, de cycles de vie, et de 
pathologie microbiens. Chaque plan de leçon inclut les 
espérances d'étudiant, l'étudiant et les matériaux de professeur, 
format de leçon, enseignant et des stratégies d'étude, des outils 
d'évaluation et d'évaluation, logement, des extensions, des 
ressources, des tableaux, et des clés de réponse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As características de local uma unidade do 
microbiology do nível de faculdade. É compreendida de cinco 
plantas da lição que cobrem áreas satisfeitas de arquitetura, de 
ecology, de physiology, de ciclos de vida, e de pathology microbial. 
Cada planta da lição inclui expectativas do estudante, 
estudante e materiais do professor, formato da lição, ensinando e 
estratégias de aprendizagem, ferramentas da avaliação e da 
avaliação, acomodações, extensões, recursos, folhas, e chaves da 
resposta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le caratteristiche di luogo un'unità di 
microbiologia del livello di università. È contenuta cinque 
programmi di lezione che riguardano i campi soddisfatti di 
architettura, dell'ecologia, della fisiologia, dei cicli di vita e 
della patologia microbici. Ogni programma di lezione include le 
aspettative dell'allievo, materiali dell'insegnante e dell'allievo, 
formato di lezione, insegnare e strategie di apprendimento, strumenti 
di valutazione e di stima, sistemazioni, estensioni, risorse, fogli di
lavoro e tasti di risposta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει μια μονάδα μικροβιολογίας 
επιπέδων κολλεγίου. Αποτελείται από πέντε σχέδια 
μαθήματος που καλύπτουν τους ικανοποιημένους τομείς της 
μικροβιακών αρχιτεκτονικής, της οικολογίας, της φυσιολογίας, των 
κύκλων ζωής, και της παθολογίας. Κάθε σχέδιο μαθήματος 
περιλαμβάνει τις προσδοκίες σπουδαστών, τα υλικά σπουδαστών και 
δασκάλων, τη μορφή μαθήματος, τις στρατηγικές διδασκαλίας και 
εκμάθησης, τα εργαλεία αξιολόγησης και αξιολόγησης, τις 
στεγάσεις, τις επεκτάσεις, τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς, τα φύλλα 
εργασίας, και τα πλήκτρα απάντησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las características de sitio una unidad de la 
microbiología del nivel de universidad. Se abarca de cinco 
planes de la lección que cubran áreas contentas de la 
configuración, de la ecología, de la fisiología, de los ciclos 
vitales, y de la patología microbianos. Cada plan de la 
lección incluye expectativas del estudiante, los materiales del 
estudiante y del profesor, formato de la lección, enseñanza y las 
estrategias que aprenden, las herramientas del gravamen y de la 
evaluación, las comodidades, las extensiones, los recursos, las hojas
de trabajo, y los claves de la respuesta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KAMLA REID
FN:KAMLA REID
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SCIENCE TEACHERS' ASSOCIATION OF ONTARIO
FN:SCIENCE TEACHERS' ASSOCIATION OF ONTARIO
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203971</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107277</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/microbiology-unit</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
