<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103576</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103576</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087078</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Women's Movement and Women in SDS: Cathy Wilkerson Recalls the Tensions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der die Bewegung und Frauen Frauen in SDS: 
Cathy Wilkerson erinnert an die Spannkräfte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mouvement et les femmes des femmes dans le SDS 
: Cathy Wilkerson rappelle les tensions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O movimento e mulheres das mulheres no SDS: 
Cathy Wilkerson recorda as tensões</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il movimento e donne delle donne nello SDS: 
Cathy Wilkerson ricorda i tensionamenti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κίνημα των γυναικών και οι γυναίκες σε SDS: 
Θ*Θατχυ Wilkerson Recalls οι εντάσεις</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El movimiento y mujeres de las mujeres en el SDS: 
Cathy Wilkerson recuerda las tensiones</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The New Left facilitated the emergence of a new women's movement in the late 1960's. The rebirth of American feminism emerged in part from the New Left's probing of the political dimension of personal life, but also from the discrimination many young women faced within the movement itself. While thousands of young women joined political groups with fervor and dedication, many were dismayed to find that their male comrades did not view them as equals. As SDS activist Cathy Wilkerson remembered, poor treatment from men within the movement sparked heated debates among women as to whether they should create a separate women's movement. Such a movement appeared, with tremendous impact, in the late 1960's and early 1970's. [The material in brackets was added to the transcript shortly after the recorded interview.]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das neue links erleichterte das Hervortreten einer
Bewegung der neuen Frauen in den späten sechziger Jahren. Die 
Wiedergeburt des amerikanischen Feminismus tauchte im Teil vom neuen 
Prüfen des links des politischen Maßes der persönlichen Lebensdauer
auf, aber auch von der Unterscheidung stellten viele junge Frauen 
innerhalb der Bewegung selbst gegenüber. Während Tausenden der
jungen Frauen politische Gruppen mit Leidenschaft und Widmung 
verbanden, wurden viele erschrocken, um zu finden, daß ihre 
männlichen Kameraden sie nicht als Gleichgestellte ansahen. Wie
SDS Aktivist Cathy Wilkerson sich erinnerte, funkte schlechte 
Behandlung von den Männern innerhalb der Bewegung lebhafte Debatten 
unter Frauen, ob sie eine Bewegung der unterschiedlichen Frauen 
erstellen sollten. Solch eine Bewegung erschien, mit enormer 
Auswirkung, in den späten sechziger Jahren und in den frühen 
siebziger Jahren. [ das Material in den Haltewinkeln wurde der 
Abschrift kurz nach dem gespeicherten Interview. hinzugefügt ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La nouvelle gauche a facilité l'apparition d'un 
mouvement de nouvelles femmes vers la fin des années 60. La 
renaissance du féminisme américain a émergé en partie de la 
nouvelle du sondage gauche de la dimension politique de la vie 
personnelle, mais également de la discrimination beaucoup de jeunes 
femmes ont fait face dans le mouvement lui-même. Tandis que les
milliers de jeunes femmes joignaient les groupes politiques avec la 
ferveur et l'attachement, beaucoup ont été consternés pour 
constater que leurs camarades mâles ne les ont pas visualisés en 
tant qu'égales. Comme l'activiste Cathy Wilkerson de SDS s'est 
rappelé, le traitement faible des hommes dans le mouvement a 
étincelé des discussions houleuses parmi des femmes comme s'ils 
devraient créer un mouvement de femmes séparées. Un tel 
mouvement est apparu, avec l'impact énorme, vers la fin des années 
60 et du début des années 70. [ le matériel entre 
parenthèses a été ajouté à la transcription peu de temps après 
l'entrevue enregistrée. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A esquerda nova facilitou o emergence de um 
movimento das mulheres novas nos 1960's atrasados. O rebirth do 
feminismo americano emergiu na parte de sondar da esquerda nova da 
dimensão política da vida pessoal, mas também da discriminação 
muitas mulheres novas enfrentaram dentro do movimento próprio. 
Quando os milhares de mulheres novas juntaram grupos políticos 
com fervor e dedication, muitos foram desanimados para encontrar que 
seus camaradas masculinos não os viram como iguais. Como a 
activista Cathy Wilkerson do SDS recordou, o tratamento deficiente dos
homens dentro do movimento acendeu debates aquecidos entre mulheres a 
respeito de se devem criar um movimento das mulheres separadas. 
Tal movimento apareceu, com impacto tremendo, nos 1960's 
atrasados e nos 1970's adiantados. [ o material nos suportes foi
adicionado ao transcript logo depois que a entrevista gravada. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La nuova parte di sinistra ha facilitato 
l'emersione di un movimento delle nuove donne verso la fine degli anni
60. Il rebirth di feminism americano è emerso in parte dal 
sondaggio della nuova parte di sinistra della dimensione politica di 
vita personale, ma egualmente dalla distinzione molte donne giovani 
hanno affrontato all'interno del movimento in se. Mentre i 
migliaia delle donne giovani hanno unito i gruppi politici con il 
fervor e la dedica, molti sono stati scoraggiati per trovare che i 
loro camerati maschii non li hanno osservati come uguali. 
L'attivista Cathy Wilkerson di SDS si è ricordato di, il 
povero trattamento dagli uomini all'interno del movimento ha 
scintillato dibattiti riscaldati fra le donne se dovrebbero creare un 
movimento delle donne separate. Un tal movimento è comparso, 
con effetto tremendo, verso la fine degli anni 60 e dell'inizio degli 
anni 70. [ il materiale tra parentesi è stato aggiunto alla 
trascrizione subito dopo l'intervista registrata. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το νέο αριστερό διευκόλυνε την εμφάνιση ενός νέου 
κινήματος των γυναικών προς το τέλος της δεκαετίας του '60. 
Η αναγέννηση του αμερικανικού φεμινισμού προέκυψε εν μέρει 
από την εξέταση του νέου αριστερού της πολιτικής διάστασης της 
προσωπικής ζωής, αλλά και από τη διάκριση που πολλές νέες 
γυναίκες αντιμετώπισαν μέσα η ίδια στη μετακίνηση. Ενώ 
χιλιάδες νέες γυναίκες προσχώρησαν στις πολιτικές ομάδες με τη 
ζέση και την αφιέρωση, πολλές ήταν τρομαγμένες για να 
διαπιστώσουν ότι οι αρσενικοί σύντροφοί τους δεν τις εμφάνισαν 
όπως είναι ίσος με. Όπως SDS το ενεργό στέλεχος 
Cathy Wilkerson θυμήθηκε, η φτωχή επεξεργασία από τους 
άνδρες μέσα στη μετακίνηση προκάλεσε τις θερμαμένες συζητήσεις 
μεταξύ των γυναικών ως προς το εάν πρέπει να δημιουργήσουν ένα 
χωριστό κίνημα των γυναικών. Μια τέτοια μετακίνηση 
εμφανίστηκε, με τον τεράστιο αντίκτυπο, προς το τέλος της 
δεκαετίας του '60 και της πρόωρης δεκαετίας του '70. [ Το
υλικό εντός παρενθέσεως προστέθηκε στο αντίγραφο αμέσως μετά 
από την καταγραμμένη συνέντευξη. ]</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La nueva izquierda facilitó la aparición de un 
movimiento de las nuevas mujeres en los últimos años 60. El 
renacimiento del feminismo americano emergió en parte de sondar de la
nueva izquierda de la dimensión política de la vida personal, pero 
también de la discriminación muchas mujeres jóvenes hicieron frente
dentro del movimiento sí mismo. Mientras que los millares de 
mujeres jóvenes ensamblaron a grupos políticos con fervor y el 
esmero, consternaron muchos para encontrar que sus camaradas 
masculinos no opinión los como iguales. Como el activista Cathy
Wilkerson del SDS recordó, el tratamiento pobre de hombres dentro del
movimiento chispeó los discusiones calentados entre mujeres si deben 
crear un movimiento de las mujeres separadas. Tal movimiento 
apareció, con enorme impacto, en los últimos años 60 y los años 70
tempranos. [ el material en corchetes fue agregado a la 
transcripción poco después la entrevista registrada. ]</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087078</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103576</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-womens-movement-and-women-in-sds-cathy-wilkerson-recalls-the-tensions</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
