<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106466</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106466</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087385</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"An American soldier of the Antitank Co., 34th Regiment who was killed by mortar fire."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein amerikanischer Soldat der Antitank Co., 34th 
Regiment, das wurde beendet durch Mörtelfeuer."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un soldat américain de la Cie. Antichar, 
trente-quatrième régiment qui a été détruit par le feu de 
mortier."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um soldado americano do Co. antitank, 3ô 
regiment que foi matado pelo fogo do almofariz."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un soldato americano del Co. antitank, 
trentaquattresimo regiment che è stato ucciso dal fuoco del mortaio."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένας αμερικανικός στρατιώτης Antitank Co., 34$ο 
σύνταγμα που σκοτώθηκε από την πυρκαγιά κονιάματος."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un soldado americano del Co. anti-tanque, 34to 
regimiento que fue matado por el fuego del mortero."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Combatants in World War II possessed far greater firepower than ever before. Consequently, the incidence of death and mutilation in units actually fighting the enemy was extremely high, sometimes one in three. World War II was the first war in which combat deaths actually outnumbered fatalities from disease or accident. President Franklin D. Roosevelt's wartime government carefully controlled what information reached the American public from the battle fronts. Until September, 1943, government censors blocked the publication of all photographs showing dead American soldiers. After that, censors continued to withhold many picturessuch as this photograph taken on Leyte Island in the Philippines on October 31, 1944that did not, even in death, conform to the heroic image of the American fighting man.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kämpfer im Zweiten Weltkrieg besassen weit grössere 
Feuerkraft als überhaupt vorher. Infolgedessen waren die 
Ausdehnung des Todes und die Verstümmelung in den Maßeinheiten, die 
wirklich den Feind kämpfen, manchmal einer in drei extrem hoch. 
Der Zweite Weltkrieg war der erste Krieg, in dem 
Kampftodesfälle wirklich Verhängnissen von der Krankheit oder vom 
Unfall waren. Präsident Franklin D. Roosevelts Kriegregierung 
steuerte sorgfältig, welche Informationen die amerikanische 
Öffentlichkeit von den Schlachtfrontseiten erreichten. Bis 
September 1943, blockten Regierung Zensoren die Publikation aller 
Fotographien, die tote amerikanische Soldaten zeigen. Nach dem 
fuhren Zensoren fort, viel picturessuch zurückzuhalten als diese 
Fotographie, die auf Leyte Insel in den Philippinen an Oktober 31, 
1944that nicht, sogar im Tod, an das heroische Bild des amerikanischen
kämpfenden Mannes sich anzupassen genommen wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les combattants dans la deuxième guerre mondiale ont 
possédé une puissance de feu bien plus grande que toujours avant. 
En conséquence, l'incidence de la mort et la mutilation dans 
les unités combattant réellement l'ennemi étaient extrêmement 
hautes, parfois un dans trois. La deuxième guerre mondiale 
était la première guerre dans laquelle les décès de combat ont 
dépassé réellement des morts en nombre de la maladie ou d'accident.
Le gouvernement de temps de guerre du Président Franklin D. 
Roosevelt's a soigneusement contrôlé quelle information a atteint le
public américain des avants de bataille. Jusqu'à septembre, 
1943, les censeurs de gouvernement ont bloqué la publication de 
toutes les photographies montrant les soldats américains morts. 
Après celui, les censeurs ont continué à retenir beaucoup de 
le picturessuch en tant que cette photographie prise sur l'île de 
Leyte aux Philippines 31 octobre 1944that pas , même dans la mort, 
se conformer à l'image héroïque de l'homme de combat américain.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os combatentes na segunda guerra mundial possuíram um 
firepower distante mais grande do que sempre antes. 
Conseqüentemente, a incidência da morte e a mutilação nas 
unidades que lutam realmente o inimigo eram extremamente elevadas, às
vezes um em três. A segunda guerra mundial era a primeira 
guerra em que as mortes do combate outnumbered realmente fatalities da
doença ou do acidente. O governo do wartime do presidente 
Franklin D. Roosevelt controlou com cuidado que informação alcançou
o público americano das partes dianteiras da batalha. Até 
setembro, 1943, os censores do governo obstruíram a publicação de 
todas as fotografias que mostram soldados americanos inoperantes. 
Após aquele, os censores continuaram a reter muito o 
picturessuch como esta fotografia feita exame no console de Leyte nas 
Filipinas outubro em 31, 1944that não , mesmo na morte, para 
conformar-se à imagem heroic do homem de combate americano.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I combattenti nella seconda guerra mondiale hanno 
posseduto la potenza di fuoco ben più grande che mai prima. Di 
conseguenza, l'incidenza della morte e la mutilazione nel combattimento 
delle unità realmente il nemico erano estremamente alte, a volte uno 
in tre. La seconda guerra mondiale era la prima guerra in cui le
morti di combattimento realmente hanno oltrepassato gli infortuni 
mortali dalla malattia o dall'incidente. Il governo di wartime 
del presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt ha gestito con attenzione le che 
informazioni hanno raggiunto il pubblico americano dalle parti 
anteriori di battaglia. Fino a settembre, del 1943, i censori di
governo hanno ostruito la pubblicazione di tutte le fotografie che 
mostrano i soldati americani guasti. Dopo quello, i censori 
hanno continuato a ritenere molto il picturessuch come questa 
fotografia presa sull'isola di Leyte nelle Filippine il 31 ottobre, 
1944that non, anche nella morte, essere conforme all'immagine eroica 
dell'uomo americano di combattimento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολεμιστές στον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ μακρινή 
μεγαλύτερη δύναμη πυρός από πάντα πριν. Συνεπώς, η 
συχνότητα του θανάτου και ο ακρωτηριασμός στις μονάδες που 
παλεύουν πραγματικά τον εχθρό ήταν εξαιρετικά υψηλοί, μερικές 
φορές μια σε τρία. Ο παγκόσμιος πόλεμος ΙΙ ήταν ο πρώτος 
πόλεμος στον οποίο οι θάνατοι αγώνα ξεπέρασαν αριθμητικώς 
πραγματικά τα μοιραία περιστατικά από την ασθένεια ή το 
ατύχημα. Η εν καιρώ πολέμου κυβέρνηση Προέδρου Franklin 
D. Roosevelt's έλεγξε προσεκτικά ποιες πληροφορίες έφθασαν 
στο αμερικανικό κοινό από τα μέτωπα μάχης. Μέχρι τον 
Σεπτέμβριο, του 1943, οι κυβερνητικοί λογοκριτές εμπόδισαν τη 
δημοσίευση όλων των φωτογραφιών που εμφανίζουν νεκρούς 
αμερικανικούς στρατιώτες. Μετά από αυτόν, οι λογοκριτές 
συνέχισαν να παρακρατούν πολύ picturessuch ως αυτήν την 
φωτογραφία που λήφθηκε στο νησί Leyte στις Φιλιππίνες στις 
31 Οκτωβρίου, 1944that, ακόμη και στο θάνατο, δεν 
προσαρμόστηκε στην ηρωική εικόνα του αμερικανικού παλεύοντας 
ατόμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los combatientes en la Segunda Guerra Mundial poseyeron 
potencia de fuego lejos mayor que siempre antes. Por lo tanto, 
la incidencia de la muerte y la mutilación en las unidades que 
luchaban realmente al enemigo eran extremadamente altas, a veces uno 
en tres. La Segunda Guerra Mundial era la primera guerra en la 
cual las muertes del combate excedieron en número realmente 
fatalidades de la enfermedad o del accidente. El gobierno del 
tiempo de guerra de presidente Franklin D. Roosevelt controló 
cuidadosamente qué información alcanzó a público americano de los 
frentes de la batalla. Hasta septiembre de 1943, los censores 
del gobierno bloquearon la publicación de todas las fotografías que 
mostraban a soldados americanos muertos. Después de ése, los 
censores continuaron reteniendo mucho el picturessuch como esta 
fotografía tomada en la isla de Leyte en las Filipinas de octubre el 
31, 1944that no , incluso en muerte, conformarse con la imagen heroica
del hombre que luchaba americano.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087385</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106466</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/an-american-soldier-of-the-antitank-co-34th-regiment-who-was-killed-by-mortar-fire</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
