<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105049</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105049</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206130</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) Virtual Museum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Virtuelles Museum des National- Institute of 
Standards and Technology(NIST)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Musée virtuel du National Institute of Standards 
and Technology (NIST)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Museu virtual do National Institute of Standards 
and Technology (NIST)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Museo virtuale di National Institute of Standards 
and Technology (NIST)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνικό ίδρυμα προτύπων και εικονικού μουσείου 
τεχνολογίας (NIST)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Museo virtual del National Institute of Standards 
and Technology (NIST)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features the work of a federal agency that has helped keep U.S. technology at the leading edge. Visit the online exhibits to learn about the standardization of women's clothing, weights and measures (crucial to industrialization), technology development during World War II, the first government computer with an internal program, the fall of parity, OCR machines, weathering of stone, Jacob Rabinow, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet die Arbeit eines Bundesamtes, das 
Unterhalt VEREINIGTE STAATEN Technologie am führenden Rand geholfen 
hat. Besuchen Sie die Onlineausstellungen, um über die 
Normierung der Kleidung der Frauen zu erlernen, der Gewichte und der 
Masse (entscheidend zur Industrialisierung), der 
Technologieentwicklung während des Zweiten Weltkrieges, der erste 
Regierung Computer mit einem internen Programm, der Fall der Parität,
DER OCR Maschinen, des Weathering des Steins, des Jacob Rabinow und 
mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte les travaux d'une agence fédérale qui a 
aidé la technologie des ETATS-UNIS de subsistance au principal bord. 
Visitez les objets exposés en ligne pour se renseigner sur 
l'étalonnage de l'habillement des femmes, les poids et les mesures 
(cruciaux à l'industrialisation), le développement de technologie 
pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale, le premier ordinateur de 
gouvernement avec un programme interne, la chute de la parité, des 
machines de ROC, de la désagrégation de la pierre, du Jacob Rabinow, et 
de plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza o trabalho de uma agência federal que 
ajude à tecnologia de ESTADOS UNIDOS do sustento na borda principal. 
Visite as exibições em linha para aprender sobre a 
estandardização da roupa das mulheres, os pesos e as medidas 
(cruciais ao industrialization), o desenvolvimento durante a segunda 
guerra mundial, o primeiro computador da tecnologia do governo com um 
programa interno, a queda da paridade, das máquinas de OCR, do 
weathering da pedra, do Jacob Rabinow, e de mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza i lavori di un ente federale che ha 
aiutato la tecnologia degli STATI UNITI di conservazione al bordo 
principale. Visiti le esposizioni in linea per imparare circa la
normalizzazione dei vestiti delle donne, pesi e misure (cruciali 
all'industrializzazione), sviluppo durante la seconda guerra mondiale,
il primo calcolatore di tecnologia di governo con un programma 
interno, la caduta della parità, dei lettori ottici, del weathering 
della pietra, di Jacob Rabinow e di più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει την εργασία μιας ομοσπονδιακής 
αντιπροσωπείας που έχει βοηθήσει κρατά την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ τεχνολογία
στην αιχμή. Επισκεφτείτε τα σε απευθείας σύνδεση εκθέματα 
για να μάθετε για την τυποποίηση του ιματισμού των γυναικών, των 
βαρών και των μέτρων (κρίσιμων για την εκβιομηχάνιση), της 
ανάπτυξης τεχνολογίας κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου 
ΙΙ, του πρώτου κυβερνητικού υπολογιστή με ένα εσωτερικό 
πρόγραμμα, της πτώσης της ισότητας, των μηχανών 
OCR-MIHANI'MATOS οπτικής αναγνώρισης χαρακτήρων, της διάβρωσης 
της πέτρας, Jacob Rabinow, και περισσότεροι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece el trabajo de una agencia federal que ha 
ayudado a la tecnología de ESTADOS UNIDOS del mantiene en el borde 
principal. Visite los objetos expuestos en línea para aprender 
sobre la estandardización de la ropa de las mujeres, los pesos y las 
medidas (cruciales a la industrialización), el desarrollo durante la 
Segunda Guerra Mundial, el primer ordenador de la tecnología del 
gobierno con un programa interno, la caída de la paridad, de las 
máquinas de OCR, del desgaste por la acción atmosférica de la 
piedra, de Jacob Rabinow, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206130</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105049</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-institute-of-standards-and-technology-nist-virtual-museum</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
