<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103549</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103549</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205790</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">British Painting</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Britischer Anstrich</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Peinture Britannique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pintura Britânica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pittura Britannica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βρετανική ζωγραφική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pintura Británica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides a brief history of painting in Britain during the 18th and 19th centuries, when English artists began developing their own styles in marine, allegorical, and landscape painting. Paintings are organized in online tours of British conversation pieces and portraits, landscapes of Constable and Turner, the Royal Academy of Art, British and American grand manner portraits, and British and American history paintings.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt eine kurze Geschichte des Malens in 
Großbritannien während der 18. und 19. Jahrhunderte, als englische 
Künstler anfingen, ihre eigenen Arten in Marine zu entwickeln, 
allegorisch, und des Landschaftsanstriches zur Verfügung. 
Anstriche werden in den Onlinetouren der britischen 
Gesprächsstoffe und der Portraits, der Landschaften des Polizisten 
und des Turners, die königliche Akademie der kunst, der britischen 
und amerikanischen großartigen Weiseportraits und der britischen und 
amerikanischen Geschichte Anstriche organisiert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit une brève histoire de peindre en 
Grande-Bretagne pendant les 18èmes et 19èmes siècles, quand les 
artistes anglais ont commencé à développer leurs propres modèles 
dans marin, allégorique, et peinture d'horizontal. Des 
peintures sont organisées dans des excursions en ligne des morceaux 
et les verticales de conversation britanniques, les horizontaux de 
l'agent de police et le Turner, l'académie royale de l'art, les 
verticales grandes britanniques et américaines de façon, et les 
peintures britanniques et américaines d'histoire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece um history breve de pintar em Grâ 
Bretanha durante os 18os e 1øs séculos, quando os artistas ingleses 
começaram a desenvolver seus próprios estilos em marinho, 
allegorical, e pintura da paisagem. As pinturas são organizadas
em excursões em linha de partes e retratos britânicos de 
conversação, paisagens do constable e Turner, academy real da arte, 
retratos grandes britânicos e americanos da maneira, e pinturas 
britânicas e americanas do history.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce una breve storia di verniciatura in 
Gran-Bretagna durante i diciottesimi e diciannovesimi secoli, quando 
gli artisti inglesi hanno cominciato a sviluppare i loro propri stili 
in marino, allegorico e pittura di paesaggio. Le pitture sono 
organizzate nei giri in linea delle parti e ritratti di 
conversazione britannici, paesaggi del constable e Turner, 
l'Accademia reale dell'arte, grandi ritratti britannici ed 
americani di modo e pitture britanniche ed americane di storia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει μια συνοπτική ιστορία της ζωγραφικής στη 
Μεγάλη Βρετανία κατά τη διάρκεια των 18$ων και 19$ων αιώνων, 
όταν άρχισαν οι αγγλικοί καλλιτέχνες τις μορφές τους θαλάσσια, 
στην αλληγορική, και ζωγραφική τοπίων. Τα έργα ζωγραφικής 
οργανώνονται στους σε απευθείας σύνδεση γύρους των βρετανικών 
κομματιών συνομιλίας και τα πορτρέτα, τοπία του αστυφύλακα και 
του τορναδόρου, της βασιλικής ακαδημίας της τέχνης, των 
βρετανικών και αμερικανικών μεγάλων πορτρέτων τρόπου, και των 
βρετανικών και αμερικανικών έργων ζωγραφικής ιστορίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a una historia abreviada de pintar en 
Gran Bretaña durante los décimo octavos y diecinueveavo siglos, 
cuando los artistas ingleses comenzaron a desarrollar sus propios 
estilos en marina, alegórico, y pintura del paisaje. Las 
pinturas se ordenan en viajes en línea de los pedazos y los retratos 
británicos de conversación, los paisajes del guardia y Turner, la 
academia real de arte, los retratos magníficos británicos y 
americanos de la manera, y las pinturas británicas y americanas de la
historia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205790</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103549</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/british-painting</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
