<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106573</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106573</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086295</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Started Filling Rifles": A Woman Strike Supporter Remembers the 1914 Ludlow Massacre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ich Fing An, Gewehre Zu füllen": Ein 
Frau-Schlag-Verfechter erinnert sich das an Ludlow Blutbad 1914</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"J'ai commencé Le Remplissage Fusille" : 
Un défenseur de grève de femme se rappelle le Massacre 1914 
de Ludlow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Eu Comecei Encher Rifles": Um supporter da 
batida da mulher recorda o massacre 1914 de Ludlow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Ho cominciato Riempire I Fucili": Un 
sostenitore di colpo della donna si ricorda del massacre 1914 di 
Ludlow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"άρχισα τα τουφέκια": Ένας υποστηρικτής 
απεργίας γυναικών θυμάται τη σφαγή Ludlow του 1914</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Comencé A Llenar Los Rifles": Un partidario
de la huelga de la mujer recuerda la Masacre 1914 de Ludlow</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The brutal southern Colorado coal strike reached its nadir on Easter night, 1914, with the horrendous deaths by fire of three women and eleven children at the hands of the Colorado state militia. Mary Thomas, whose husband was on strike, was interviewed at age eighty eight by historian Sherna Gluck in 1974 for the Feminist History Research Project. Thomas vividly recalled the horror of the infamous Ludlow Massacre, described her efforts to save the lives of women and children by hiding them in a dry well, and her jailing in the aftermath the massacre. She was the only woman strike supporter to be jailed during the strike.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der brutale südliche Kolorado Kohleschlag 
erreichte seinen Nadir auf Ostern Nacht, geben 1914, mit den 
horrenden Todesfällen durch Feuer von drei Frauen und elf Kinder 
an den Händen des Kolorados Miliz an. Mary Thomas, dessen 
Ehemann auf Schlag war, wurde an Alter achtzig acht vom Historiker 
Sherna Gluck 1974 für das feministische Geschichte Forschung Projekt 
interviewt. Thomas erinnerte an vividly die Grausigkeit des 
unbeliebten Ludlow Blutbads, beschrieben ihren Bemühungen, die Leben 
der Frauen und der Kinder zu sichern, indem er gut sie in einem 
trockenem versteckte, und ihr in der Nachmahd das Blutbad 
gefangensetzend. Sie war der einzige während des Schlages 
gefangengesetzt zu werden Frauschlagverfechter.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La grève méridionale brutale de charbon du 
Colorado a atteint son nadir la nuit de Pâques, 1914, avec les 
décès affreuses par le feu de trois femmes et onze enfants aux mains
du Colorado énoncent la milice. Mary Thomas, dont le mari 
était en grève, a été interviewée à l'âge quatre-vingts huit 
par l'historien Sherna Gluck en 1974 pour le projet de recherche 
féministe d'histoire. Thomas a vividly rappelé l'horreur du 
Massacre infâme de Ludlow, décrite ses efforts de sauvegarder les 
vies des femmes et des enfants en les cachant dans un sec bien, et lui
emprisonnant dans la conséquence le massacre. Elle était le 
seul défenseur de grève de femme à emprisonner pendant la grève.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A batida do sul brutal de carvão de Colorado 
alcançou seu nadir na noite de Easter, 1914, com as mortes horrendous
por um fogo de três mulheres e onze crianças nas mãos do Colorado 
indicam a milícia. Mary Thomas, cujo o marido estava na batida,
foi entrevistada na idade eighty oito pelo historian Sherna Gluck em 
1974 para o projeto de pesquisa feminista do history. Thomas 
recordou vividly o horror do massacre infamous de Ludlow, descrito 
seus esforços conservar as vidas das mulheres e das crianças 
escondendo os em um seco bem, e lhe que jailing no aftermath o 
massacre. Era o único supporter da batida da mulher a jailed 
durante a batida.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il colpo del sud brutale del carbone del Colorado 
ha raggiunto il relativo nadir sulla notte di Pasqua, 1914, con le 
morti horrendous da un fuoco di tre donne ed undici bambini alle mani 
del Colorado dichiarano la milizia. Mary Thomas, di cui il 
marito era sul colpo, è stata intervistata all'età ottanta otto 
dallo storico Sherna Gluck in 1974 per il progetto di ricerca 
femminista di storia. Thomas vividly ha ricordato l'orrore del 
massacre malfamato di Ludlow, descritto i suoi sforzi salvare le vite 
delle donne e dei bambini nascondendoli in un asciutto bene e lei che 
imprigiona nel guaime il massacre. Era l'unico sostenitore di 
colpo della donna da imprigionare durante il colpo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η βάναυση νότια απεργία άνθρακα του Κολοράντο έφθασε
στο ναδίρ της στη νύχτα Πάσχας, 1914, με τους φρικτούς 
θανάτους από την πυρκαγιά τριών γυναικών και ένδεκα παιδιών στα
χέρια της κρατικής πολιτοφυλακής του Κολοράντο. Θ*Μαρυ 
Thomas, ο της οποίας σύζυγος ήταν στην απεργία, πέρασε από 
συνέντευξη στην ηλικία ογδόντα οκτώ από τον ιστορικό Sherna 
Gluck το 1974 για το φεμινιστικό ερευνητικό πρόγραμμα 
ιστορίας. Ο Thomas υπενθύμισε ζωντανά τη φρίκη της 
κακόφημης σφαγής Ludlow, την περιέγραψε τις προσπάθειές της να
σώσει τις ζωές των γυναικών και των παιδιών με να κρύψει τους σε 
έναν ξηρό καλά, και που φυλακίζει στη συνέπεια τη σφαγή. 
Ήταν ο μόνος υποστηρικτής απεργίας γυναικών που 
φυλακίζεται κατά τη διάρκεια της απεργίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La huelga meridional brutal del carbón de Colorado
alcanzó su nadir el la noche de Pascua, 1914, con las muertes 
horrendas por el fuego de tres mujeres y once niños en las manos del 
Colorado indica a milicia. Maria Thomas, que marido estaba en 
huelga, fue entrevistada con en la edad ochenta ocho por el 
historiador Sherna Gluck en 1974 para el proyecto de investigación 
feminista de la historia. Thomas vividly recordó el horror de 
la Masacre infame de Ludlow, descrito sus esfuerzos de salvar las 
vidas de mujeres y de niños ocultándolos en un seco bien, y le que 
encarcelaba en las consecuencias la masacre. Ella era el 
único partidario de la huelga de la mujer que se encarcelará durante
la huelga.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086295</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106573</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-started-filling-rifles-a-woman-strike-supporter-remembers-the-1914-ludlow-massacre</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
