<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104949</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104949</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206080</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Bridge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Brücke</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Passerelle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Ponte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Ponticello</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η γέφυρα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Puente</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a place where teachers can find marine science education resources that are screened by science educators and research scientists. The site features Scuttlebutt, a discussion list, and tells about the National Ocean Science and Technologys Bowl (NOSB), a fast-paced academic competition for high school students.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein Platz, in dem Lehrer Marinewissenschaft 
Ausbildung Betriebsmittel finden können, die von den Wissenschaft 
Erziehern und von den Forschung Wissenschaftlern gerastert werden. 
Die Situationsmerkmale Scuttlebutt, eine Diskussion Liste und 
erklärt über die nationale Ozean-Wissenschaft und die Technologys 
Schüssel (NOSB), eine schnell-geschrittene akademische Konkurrenz 
für High School Kursteilnehmer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un endroit où les professeurs peuvent trouver
les ressources marines d'éducation de la science qui sont examinées 
par des éducateurs de la science et des scientifiques de recherches. 
Les dispositifs de site Scuttlebutt, une liste de discussion, et
indique au sujet de la Science d'océan et de la cuvette nationales de
Technologys (NOSB), une concurrence rapide-entraînée d'universitaire 
pour des étudiants de lycée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um lugar onde os professores possam encontrar 
os recursos marinhos da instrução da ciência que são selecionados 
por educadores da ciência e por cientistas de pesquisa. As 
características de local Scuttlebutt, uma lista da discussão, e 
dizem sobre a ciência do oceano e a bacia nacionais de Technologys 
(NOSB), uma competição academic rápido-passeada para estudantes da 
High School.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un posto in cui gli insegnanti possono trovare 
le risorse marine di formazione di scienza che sono selezionate dagli 
educatori di scienza e dai ricercatori. Le caratteristiche di 
luogo Scuttlebutt, una lista di discussione e dice a circa la scienza 
dell'oceano e la ciotola nazionali di Technologys (NOSB), una 
concorrenza accademica veloce-percorsa per gli allievi della High 
School.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια θέση όπου οι δάσκαλοι μπορούν να βρούν τα 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς εκπαίδευσης ναυτιλιακών επιστημών που 
εξετάζονται από τους εκπαιδευτικούς επιστήμης και τους 
ερευνητικούς επιστήμονες. Η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει 
Scuttlebutt, ένας κατάλογος συζήτησης, και λέει για την εθνικά
ωκεάνια επιστήμη και το κύπελλο Technologys (NOSB), ένας 
γρήγορος- ακαδημαϊκός ανταγωνισμός για τους σπουδαστές 
γυμνασίου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un lugar en donde los profesores pueden 
encontrar los recursos marinas de la educación de la ciencia que son 
defendidos por los educadores de la ciencia y los científicos de 
investigación. Las características de sitio Scuttlebutt, una 
lista de la discusión, y habla de la ciencia y del tazón de fuente 
nacionales de Technologys (NOSB), una competición académica 
ra'pido-establecida el paso del océano para los estudiantes de la 
High School secundaria.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206080</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104949</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-bridge</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
