<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108041</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108041</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087047</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Sentiments of a Labourer ": William Manning Inquires in the Key of Liberty, 1798</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Gefühle eines Arbeiters": William das 
Bemannen erkundigt sich in der Taste von Freiheit, 1798</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"les sentiments d'un travailleur" : Équiper
de William s'enquiert dans la clé de la liberté, 1798</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"os sentiments de um labourer": Equipar de 
William inquire na chave da liberdade, 1798</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"i sentimenti di un lavoratore": 
Equipaggiare del William domanda nel tasto della libertà, 1798</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τα συναισθήματα ενός εργάτη": Θ*Ωηλληαμ 
Manning Inquires στο πλήκτρο της ελευθερίας, 1798</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"los sentimientos de un trabajador": El 
servir de Guillermo investiga en el clave de la libertad, 1798</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many ordinary Americans entered into political debates in the revolutionary era and its republican aftermath. While the innovative political ideas that appeared during the constitutional debates in Philadelphia are well known, creative thinking at the grassroots level is harder to locate. William Manning, a farmer, revolutionary foot soldier, and political theorist, became agitated during the postwar political debates and economic crisis. In 1798, he completed a treatise called "The Key of Liberty." Manning hoped to take advantage of the growing availability of newspapers and pamphlets during the post-revolutionary period to distribute his ideas. "The Key of Liberty" outlined a plan for a national association of American laboring men and their political allies, and also offered a broader historical commentary on the social origins of American politics. The Billerica, Massachusetts, farmer wrote several drafts but failed in his efforts at publication. Family members later deposited his papers in the Harvard University library.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele gewöhnliche Amerikaner nahmen an den 
politischen Debatten in der revolutionären Ära und in seiner 
republikanischen Nachmahd teil. Während die erfinderischen 
politischen Ideen, die während der konstitutionellen Debatten in 
Philadelphia erschienen, weithin bekannt sind, ist das kreative Denken
an der Basis gleich härter zu finden. William das 
Bemannen, ein Landwirt, revolutionärer Fußsoldat und politischer 
Theoretiker, wurden während der politischen Nachkriegsdebatten und 
der Wirtschaftskrise aufgeregt. 1798 führte er eine Abhandlung 
durch, die genannt wurde "die Taste der Freiheit." Das Bemannen 
hoffte, Nutzen aus der wachsenden Verwendbarkeit der Zeitungen und der
Flugschriften während der Pfosten-revolutionären Periode zu ziehen, 
um seine Ideen zu verteilen. "die Taste der Freiheit" umriß 
einen Plan für eine nationale Verbindung der amerikanischen 
bearbeitenmänner und ihrer politischen Verbündeten und bot auch 
einen ausgedehnteren historischen Kommentar auf den Sozialursprung der
amerikanischen Politiken an. Das Billerica, Massachusetts, 
Landwirt schrieb, einige Entwürfe aber fiel in seinen Bemühungen an 
der Publikation aus. Familie Bauteile legten später seine 
Papiere in der Universität Harvardbibliothek nieder.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Beaucoup d'Américains ordinaires ont entamé des 
discussions politiques dans l'ère révolutionnaire et sa conséquence
républicaine. Tandis que les idées politiques innovatrices qui
sont apparues pendant les discussions constitutionnelles à 
Philadelphie sont bien connues, il est de niveau plus difficile de 
situer pensée créatrice aux bases. Équiper de William, un 
fermier, soldat révolutionnaire de pied, et le théoricien politique,
sont devenus agités pendant les discussions politiques 
d'après-guerre et la crise économique. En 1798, il a rempli un
traité appelé "la clé de la liberté." Équiper a espéré 
tirer profit de la disponibilité croissante des journaux et des 
brochures pendant la période poteau-révolutionnaire pour distribuer 
ses idées. "la clé de la liberté" a tracé les grandes lignes
d'un plan pour une association nationale des hommes travaillants 
américains et de leurs alliés politiques, et a également offert un 
plus large commentaire historique sur les origines sociales de la 
politique américaine. Le Billerica, le Massachusetts, fermier a
écrit plusieurs ébauches mais a échoué dans ses efforts à la 
publication. Les membres de famille plus tard ont déposé ses 
papiers dans la bibliothèque d'université de Harvard.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muitos americanos ordinários participaram em 
debates políticos na era revolucionária e em seu aftermath 
republicano. Quando as idéias políticas inovativas que 
apareceram durante os debates constitutional em Filadélfia forem 
sabidas bem, pensar creativo nos grassroots é ao nível mais duro de 
localizar. Equipar de William, um fazendeiro, soldado 
revolucionário do pé, e o theorist político, tornaram-se agitados 
durante os debates políticos postwar e a crise econômica. Em 
1798, terminou um treatise chamado "a chave da liberdade." 
Equipar esperou fazer exame da vantagem da disponibilidade 
crescente dos jornais e dos panfletos durante o período 
borne-revolucionário para distribuir suas idéias. "a chave da 
liberdade" esboçou uma planta para uma associação nacional de 
homens trabalhando americanos e de seus aliados políticos, e ofereceu
também um commentary histórico mais largo nas origens sociais da 
política americana. O Billerica, Massachusetts, fazendeiro 
escreveu diversos esboços mas falhou em seus esforços na 
publicação. Os membros da família depositaram mais tarde seus
papéis na biblioteca da universidade de harvard.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molti Americani ordinari hanno preso parte ai 
dibattiti politici nell'era rivoluzionaria e nel relativo guaime 
repubblicano. Mentre le idee politiche innovarici che sono 
comparso durante i dibattiti costituzionali a Filadelfia sono ben 
note, pensare creativo ai grassroots a livello è più duro da 
individuare. Equipaggiare del William, un coltivatore, soldato 
rivoluzionario del piede ed il teorico politico, sono stato agitati 
durante i dibattiti politici dopoguerra e la crisi economica. In
1798, ha completato un trattato chiamato "il tasto della libertà." 
Equipaggiare ha sperato di approfittare della disponibilità 
crescente dei giornali e degli opuscoli durante il periodo 
alberino-rivoluzionario per distribuire le sue idee. "il tasto 
della libertà" ha descritto un programma per un'associazione 
nazionale degli uomini lavoranti americani e dei loro alleati politici
ed egualmente ha offerto un più vasto commento storico sulle origini 
sociali delle politiche americane. Il Billerica, Massachusetts, 
coltivatore ha scritto parecchie brutte copie ma è venuto a mancare 
nei suoi sforzi alla pubblicazione. I membri della famiglia più
successivamente hanno depositato le sue carte nella libreria 
dell'università di Harvard.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλοί συνηθισμένοι Αμερικανοί εισήγαγαν στις 
πολιτικές συζητήσεις στην επαναστατική εποχή και τη δημοκρατική 
συνέπειά του. Ενώ οι καινοτόμες πολιτικές ιδέες ότι 
εμφανισμένος κατά τη διάρκεια των συνταγματικών συζητήσεων στη 
Φιλαδέλφεια είναι καλά γνωστή, δημιουργική σκέψη στο επίπεδο σε
επίπεδο βάσης είναι πιό δύσκολες να εντοπίσουν. Θ*Ωηλληαμ 
Manning, ένας αγρότης, ένας επαναστατικός στρατιώτης ποδιών, 
και ένας πολιτικός θεωρητικός, έγιναν ταραγμένοι κατά τη 
διάρκεια των μεταπολεμικών πολιτικών συζητήσεων και της 
οικονομικής κρίσης. Το 1798, ολοκλήρωσε μια πραγματεία 
αποκαλούμενη "πλήκτρο της ελευθερίας." Η επάνδρωση ήλπισε 
να εκμεταλλευθεί την αυξανόμενη διαθεσιμότητα των εφημερίδων και 
των τευχών κατά τη διάρκεια της μετα-επαναστατικής περιόδου για 
να διανείμει τις ιδέες του. "Το πλήκτρο της ελευθερίασ" 
περιέγραψε ένα σχέδιο για μια εθνική ένωση των αμερικανικών 
εργαμένος ατόμων και των πολιτικών συμμάχων τους, και πρόσφερε 
επίσης ευρύτερα ιστορικά σχόλια στην κοινωνική προέλευση της 
αμερικανικής πολιτικής. Το Billerica, Μασαχουσέτη, 
αγρότης έγραψε διάφορα σχέδια αλλά απέτυχε στις προσπάθειές 
του στη δημοσίευση. Τα οικογενειακά μέλη κατάθεσαν αργότερα
τα έγγραφά του στην πανεπιστημιακή βιβλιοθήκη του Χάρβαρντ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Muchos americanos ordinarios entraron en 
discusiones políticos en la era revolucionaria y sus consecuencias 
republicanas. Mientras que las ideas políticas innovadoras que 
aparecieron durante los discusiones constitucionales en Philadelphia 
son bien sabido, el pensamiento creativo en los pueblos llano es más 
duro de localizar. El servir de Guillermo, un granjero, soldado 
revolucionario del pie, y el teórico político, se agitaron durante 
los discusiones políticos de la posguerra y la crisis económica. 
En 1798, él terminó un tratado llamado "el clave de la 
libertad." El servir esperaba aprovecharse de la disponibilidad 
cada vez mayor de periódicos y de folletos durante el período 
poste-revolucionario para distribuir sus ideas. "el clave de la 
libertad" contorneó un plan para una asociación nacional de hombres 
que trabajaban americanos y de sus aliados políticos, y también 
ofreció un comentario histórico más amplio en los orígenes 
sociales de políticas americanas. El Billerica, Massachusetts, 
granjero escribió varios bosquejos pero falló en sus esfuerzos en la
publicación. Los miembros de la familia depositaron más 
adelante sus papeles en la biblioteca de la universidad de Harvard.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087047</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108041</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-sentiments-of-a-labourer-william-manning-inquires-in-the-key-of-liberty-1798</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
