<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107478</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107478</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212717</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Secchi Disk</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Secchi Platte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Disque de Secchi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Disco De Secchi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Disco Di Secchi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο δίσκος Secchi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Disco De Secchi</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Great North American Secchi Dip-In website offers a comprehensive guide to Secchi disk use. It features links to a series of pages that answer questions such as: what is a Secchi disk; what (or who) is Secchi; and why are Secchi disks black and white. The links also include information such as considerations in Secchi disk design and procedure, monitoring methods, and evaluating eutrophication by Secchi depth.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses große nordamerikanische Secchi Eintauchen-
in der Web site bietet eine komplette Anleitung zum Secchi 
Plattegebrauch an. Es kennzeichnet Links zu einer Reihe Seiten, 
die Fragen wie beantworten Sie: was eine Secchi Platte ist; 
was (oder wer) Secchi ist; und warum Secchi Platten 
Schwarzes und Weiß sind. Die Links schließen auch 
Informationen wie Erwägungen im Secchi Plattedesign und -prozedur 
ein, überwachen Methoden, und werten eutrophication durch Secchi 
Tiefe aus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce grand Secchi américain du nord 
Plonger-Dans le site Web offre un guide complet d'utilisation de 
disque de Secchi. Il comporte des liens à une série de pages 
telles que lesquelles répondez aux questions : ce qui est un 
disque de Secchi ; ce que (ou qui) est Secchi ; et 
pourquoi sont les disques noir et blanc de Secchi. Les liens 
incluent également l'information telle que des considérations dans 
la conception et le procédé de disque de Secchi, surveillant des 
méthodes, et évaluant l'eutrophication par profondeur de Secchi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Secchi norte-americano grande Mergulh- no Web
site oferece uma guia detalhada ao uso do disco de Secchi. 
Caracteriza as ligações a uma série das páginas que responda
a perguntas tais como: o que é um disco de Secchi; o que 
(ou quem) é Secchi; e porque são os discos preto e branco de 
Secchi. As ligações incluem também a informação tal como 
considerações no projeto e no procedimento do disco de Secchi, 
monitorando métodos, e avaliando o eutrophication pela profundidade 
de Secchi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Secchi nordamericano grande Tuff- nel Web 
site offre una guida completa ad uso del disco di Secchi. 
Caratterizza i collegamenti ad una serie di pagine che risponda 
alle domande come: che cosa è un disco di Secchi; che 
cosa (o chi) è Secchi; e perchè sono i dischi nero ed il 
bianco di Secchi. I collegamenti egualmente includono le 
informazioni quali le considerazioni nel disegno e nella procedura del
disco di Secchi, controllanti i metodi e valutanti il eutrophication 
dalla profondità del Secchi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μεγάλο βορειοαμερικανικό Secchi εμβύθιση- 
στον ιστοχώρο προσφέρει έναν περιεκτικό οδηγό στη χρήση δίσκων 
Secchi. Χαρακτηρίζει τις συνδέσεις με μια σειρά σελίδων 
που η απάντηση εξετάζει όπως: αυτό που είναι ένας δίσκος 
Secchi  αυτό που (ή ποιος) είναι Secchi  και 
γιατί είναι δίσκοι Secchi μαύροι και άσπροι. Οι 
συνδέσεις περιλαμβάνουν επίσης τις πληροφορίες όπως οι 
εκτιμήσεις στο σχέδιο δίσκων Secchi και τη διαδικασία, μέθοδοι
ελέγχου, και αξιολόγηση του ευτροφισμού από Secchi το βάθος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este gran Secchi norteamericano Sumergir-En Web 
site ofrece una guía comprensiva al uso del disco de Secchi. 
Ofrece conexiones a una serie de paginaciones tales como las 
cuales conteste a las preguntas: cuál es un disco de Secchi; 
cuál (o quién) es Secchi; y porqué son los discos negro
y blanco de Secchi. Las conexiones también incluyen la 
información tal como consideraciones en el diseño y el procedimiento
del disco de Secchi, vigilando métodos, y evaluando el eutrophication
por la profundidad de Secchi.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GREAT NORTH AMERICAN SECCHI DIP-IN
FN:GREAT NORTH AMERICAN SECCHI DIP-IN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KENT STATE UNIVERSITY DEPARTMENT OF BIOLOGICAL SCIENCES
FN:KENT STATE UNIVERSITY DEPARTMENT OF BIOLOGICAL SCIENCES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212717</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107478</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-secchi-disk</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
