<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107294</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107294</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206873</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The American Revolution and Its Era: Maps and Charts of North America and the West Indies, 1750-1789</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die amerikanische Umdrehung und seine Ära: 
Karten und Diagramme von Nordamerika und von Westinseln, 
1750-1789</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La révolution américaine et son ère : 
Cartes et diagrammes de l'Amérique du nord et des Indes 
occidentales, 1750-1789</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A volta americana e sua era: Mapas e cartas 
de America do Norte e das Índias ocidentais, 1750-1789</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rivoluzione americana e la relativa era: 
Programmi e tabelle dell'America del Nord e delle Indie ad 
ovest, 1750-1789</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αμερικανική επανάσταση και η εποχή του: Χάρτες
και διαγράμματα της Βόρειας Αμερικής και των δυτικών Ινδιών, 
1750-1789</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La revolución americana y su era: 
Correspondencias y cartas de Norteamérica y de Indias del 
oeste, 1750-1789</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features more than 2,000 items, many with distinct coloration and annotations. Cartographers can compare multiple editions, states, and impressions of several of the most important maps of the period, follow the development of a particular map from the manuscript sketch to the finished printed version and its foreign derivatives, and examine the cartographic styles and techniques of surveyors and mapmakers from seven countries: Great Britain, France, Germany, Spain, Holland, Italy, and the U.S.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet mehr als 2.000 Einzelteile, viele mit
eindeutiger Färbung und Anmerkungen. Kartenzeichner können 
mehrfache Ausgaben, Zustände und Eindrücke von mehreren der 
wichtigsten Karten der Periode vergleichen, der Entwicklung einer 
bestimmten Karte von der Manuskriptskizze zur fertigen gedruckten 
Version und zu seinen fremden Ableitungen folgen, und die 
kartographischen Arten und die Techniken der Feldmesser und die 
mapmakers aus sieben Ländern überprüfen: Großbritannien, 
Frankreich, Deutschland, Spanien, Holland, Italien und die US.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte plus de 2.000 éléments, beaucoup avec 
la coloration distincte et annotations. Les cartographes peuvent
comparer les éditions multiples, les états, et les impressions de 
plusieurs des cartes les plus importantes de la période, suivre le 
développement d'une carte particulière du croquis de manuscrit à la
version imprimée terminée et à ses dérivés étrangers, et 
examiner les modèles et les techniques des arpenteurs et les 
mapmakers cartographiques de sept pays : La Grande-Bretagne, la 
France, l'Allemagne, l'Espagne, la Hollande, l'Italie, et les 
États-Unis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza mais de 2.000 artigos, muitos com 
coloration distinto e anotações. Os cartographers podem 
comparar edições múltiplas, estados, e impressões de diversos dos 
mapas os mais importantes do período, seguir o desenvolvimento de um 
mapa particular do esboço do manuscrito à versão impressa terminada
e a seus derivatives extrangeiros, e examinar os estilos e as 
técnicas dos surveyors e os mapmakers cartographic de sete países: 
Grâ Bretanha, France, Germany, Spain, Holland, Italy, e os E. 
U..</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza più di 2.000 articoli, molti con 
colorazione distinta e le annotazioni. I cartographers possono 
confrontare le edizioni multiple, dichiara ed impressioni di 
vari dei programmi più importanti del periodo, seguono lo sviluppo di
un programma particolare dall'abbozzo del manoscritto alla versione 
stampata rifinita ed ai relativi derivati stranieri ed esaminano gli 
stili e le tecniche degli ispettori ed i mapmakers cartografici da 
sette paesi: La Gran Bretagna, la Francia, la Germania, la 
Spagna, l'Olanda, l'Italia e gli Stati Uniti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει περισσότερα από 2.000 αντικείμενα, 
πολλών με τον ευδιάκριτο χρωματισμό και τους σχολιασμούς. Οι
χαρτογράφοι μπορούν να συγκρίνουν τις πολλαπλάσιες εκδόσεις, τα 
κράτη, και τις εντυπώσεις αρκετοί από τους σημαντικότερους 
χάρτες της περιόδου, να παρακολουθήσουν την ανάπτυξη ενός 
ιδιαίτερου χάρτη από το σκίτσο χειρογράφων στην τελειωμένη 
τυπωμένη έκδοση και τα ξένα παράγωγά του, και να εξετάσουν τις 
χαρτογραφικά μορφές και τις τεχνικές επιθεωρητών και τα 
mapmakers από επτά χώρες: Μεγάλη Βρετανία, Γαλλία, 
Γερμανία, Ισπανία, Ολλανδία, Ιταλία, και οι ΗΠΑ</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece más de 2.000 items, muchos con la 
coloración distinta y anotaciones. Los cartógrafos pueden 
comparar las ediciones múltiples, los estados, y las impresiones de 
varias de las correspondencias más importantes del período, seguir 
el desarrollo de una correspondencia determinada del bosquejo del 
manuscrito a la versión impresa acabada y a sus derivados no nativos,
y examinar los estilos y las técnicas de topógrafos y los mapmakers 
cartográficos a partir de siete países: Gran Bretaña, 
Francia, Alemania, España, Holanda, Italia, y los E.E.U.U..</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206873</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107294</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-american-revolution-and-its-era-maps-and-charts-of-north-america-and-the-west-indies-1750-1789</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
