<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106647</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106647</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087241</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Witchcraft.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Witchcraft.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sorcellerie.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Witchcraft.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Witchcraft.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Witchcraft.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Brujería.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Law and custom in seventeenth-century New England gave male property owners authority over the women, children, and other dependents of their families. Women who spoke up or stood out merited suspicion, and many were accused, prosecuted, and occasionally executed for the crime of witchcraft. Women could be excommunicated, as Ann Hibben was in 1641, for usurping" her husband's role</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gesetz und Gewohnheit im Seventeenthjahrhundert 
Neu-England gaben männlichen Eigenschaft Inhabern Berechtigung über 
den Frauen, den Kindern und anderen Abhängigen ihrer Familien. 
Frauen, die oben sprachen oder aus verdientem Misstrauen standen
und viele wurden gelegentlich für das Verbrechen von Witchcraft 
beschuldigt, verfolgt und durchgeführt. Frauen konnten, 
während Ann Hibben 1641 war, für das Bemächtigen "der Rolle ihres 
Ehemanns exkommuniziert werden</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La loi et la coutume en dix-septième-siècle Nouvelle 
Angleterre ont donné aux propriétaires mâles l'autorité au-dessus 
des femmes, des enfants, et d'autres personnes à charge de leurs 
familles. Des femmes qui ont parlé vers le haut ou se sont 
tenues hors du soupçon mérité, et beaucoup ont été accusées, 
poursuivies, et de temps en temps exécutées pour le crime de la 
sorcellerie. Des femmes pourraient être excommuniées, pendant 
qu'Ann Hibben était dans 1641, pour usurper de "le rôle son mari</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A lei e o costume no décimo-século Nova Inglaterra deram
aos proprietários de propriedade masculinos a autoridade sobre as 
mulheres, crianças, e outros dependentes de suas famílias. As 
mulheres que falaram acima ou estiveram para fora da suspeita 
merecida, e muitas foram acusadas, prosecuted, e executadas 
ocasionalmente para o crime do witchcraft. As mulheres poderiam 
excommunicated, enquanto Ann Hibben estava em 1641, usurping do "o 
papel seu marido</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La legge e l'abitudine nel diciassettesimo-secolo Nuova 
Inghilterra hanno dato a proprietari di proprietà maschii l'autorità
sopra le donne, i bambini ed altri dipendenti delle loro famiglie. 
Le donne che hanno parlato in su o si sono evidenziate sospetto 
meritato e molte sono state accusate, proseguito state ed 
occasionalmente sono eseguito state per il crimine di witchcraft. 
Le donne potrebbero excommunicated, mentre Ann Hibben era in 
1641, per l'usurpazione "del ruolo del suo marito</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο νόμος και η συνήθεια στον δέκατος-αιώνα Νέα Αγγλία
έδωσαν την αρσενική αρχή ιδιοκτητών ιδιοκτησίας πέρα από τις 
γυναίκες, τα παιδιά, και άλλους υποτελείς των οικογενειών τους. 
Οι γυναίκες που μίλησαν επάνω ή εξεχώρισαν την αξιμένη 
υποψία, και πολλές κατηγορήθηκαν, διήχθησαν, και εκτελέσθηκαν 
περιστασιακά για το έγκλημα witchcraft. Οι γυναίκες θα 
μπορούσαν να είναι, δεδομένου ότι ANN Hibben ήταν το 
1641, για το σφετερισμό του "ρόλου του συζύγου της</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La ley y el costumbre en el decimose'ptimo-siglo Nueva 
Inglaterra dieron a propietarios de característica masculinos 
autoridad sobre las mujeres, los niños, y otros dependientes de sus 
familias. Acusaron, fueron procesadas, y ejecutadas de vez en 
cuando a las mujeres que hablaron para arriba o estaban paradas fuera 
de la suspicacia merecida, y muchas para el crimen de la brujería. 
Las mujeres podrían excommunicated, mientras que Ana Hibben 
estaba en 1641, para usurpar de "el papel su marido</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087241</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106647</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/witchcraft</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
