<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108029</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108029</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207147</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Amana Colonies</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Amana Kolonien</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Colonies d'Amana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As Colônias De Amana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le Colonie Di Amana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι αποικίες Amana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las Colonias De Amana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at the historic utopian society established in the 1850s along the Iowa River by German-speaking settlers from a religious group known as the Community of True Inspiration. The group, which originated in Himbach, Germany, in 1714, created a communal system of living of seven villages, each with mills, shops, homes, communal kitchens, schools, and churches. This website looks at the group's history, beliefs, buildings, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf die historische utopische Gesellschaft 
hergestellt im 1850s entlang dem Iowa Fluß von den German-speaking 
Siedleren von einer frommen Gruppe bekannt als die Gemeinschaft der 
zutreffenden Inspiration. Die Gruppe, die in Himbach, 
Deutschland, 1714 entstand, stellte ein Kommunalsystem des Lebens von 
sieben Dörfern, jedes mit Tausendsteln, Systeme, Häuser, 
Kommunalküchen, Schulen und Kirchen her. Diese Web site 
betrachtet der die Geschichte, Glauben, Gebäude und mehr Gruppe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regards à la société utopique historique 
établie dans le 1850s le long du fleuve de l'Iowa par des colons de 
German-speaking d'un groupe religieux connu sous le nom de Communauté
de l'inspiration vraie. Le groupe, qui a provenu de Himbach, 
Allemagne, en 1714, a créé un système communal de la vie de sept 
villages, chacun avec des moulins, des systèmes, des maisons, des 
cuisines communales, des écoles, et des églises. Ce site Web 
regarde l'histoire, la croyance, les bâtiments, et plus du groupe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olhares na sociedade utópica historic 
estabelecida no 1850s ao longo do rio de Iowa por settlers de 
German-speaking de um grupo religioso sabido como a comunidade da 
inspiração verdadeira. O grupo, que originou em Himbach, 
Germany, em 1714, criou um sistema communal de uma vida de sete vilas,
cada um com os moinhos, lojas, HOME, cozinhas communal, escolas, e 
igrejas. Este Web site olha o history, a opinião, os 
edifícios, e o mais do grupo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sguardi alla società utopian storica stabilita 
nel 1850s lungo il fiume dello Iowa dai settlers del German-speaking 
da un gruppo religioso conosciuto come Comunità di ispirazione 
allineare. Il gruppo, che ha provenuto da Himbach, Germania, in 
1714, ha creato un sistema comunale di una vita di sette villaggi, 
ciascuno con i laminatoi, i negozi, le sedi, le cucine comunali, le 
scuole e le chiese. Questo Web site guarda la storia, la 
credenza, le costruzioni e più del gruppo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει την ιστορική ουτοπιστική κοινωνία που 
καθιερώνεται στο 1850s κατά μήκος του ποταμού του Iowa από 
τους γερμανόφωνους αποίκους από μια θρησκευτική ομάδα γνωστή ως 
Κοινότητα της αληθινής έμπνευσης. Η ομάδα, που 
δημιουργήθηκε σε Himbach, Γερμανία, το 1714, δημιούργησε ένα
κοινοτικό σύστημα της διαβίωσης επτά χωριών, κάθε μια με τους 
μύλους, τα καταστήματα, τα σπίτια, τις κοινοτικές κουζίνες, τα 
σχολεία, και τις εκκλησίες. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος εξετάζει την 
ιστορία, τις πεποιθήσεις, τα κτήρια, και περισσότερους της 
ομάδας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">miradas en la sociedad utópica histórica 
establecida en el 1850s a lo largo del río de Iowa por los colonos 
German-speaking de un grupo religioso conocido como la comunidad de la
inspiración verdadera. El grupo, que originó en Himbach, 
Alemania, en 1714, creó un sistema comunal de la vida de siete 
aldeas, cada uno con los molinos, departamentos, hogares, cocinas 
comunales, escuelas, e iglesias. Este Web site mira la historia,
la creencia, los edificios, y más del grupo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207147</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108029</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-amana-colonies</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
