<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107796</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107796</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086312</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"If A Diogenes Prefers Poverty": Lewelling Defends the Rights of the Unemployed</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wenn Ein Diogenes Armut" Bevorzugt: 
Lewelling verteidigt die Rechte der Arbeitslosen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Si Un Diogène Préfère La Pauvreté" : 
Lewelling défend les droites des chômeurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Se Um Diogenes Prefere A Pobreza": 
Lewelling defende as direitas dos desempregados</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Se Un Diogenes Preferisce La Povertà": 
Lewelling difende i diritti dei disoccupati</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Εάν ένα Diogenes προτιμά την ένδεια": Το 
Lewelling υπερασπίζει τα δικαιώματα των ανέργων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Si Un Diogenes Prefiere Pobreza": Lewelling
defiende las derechas de los parados</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The word "tramp" came into common usage in the 1870s as a disparaging description of homeless men thrown out of work by the economic depression and forced to take to the road in search of a job or food. Many Americans viewed tramps with a combination of fear and disgust. Fears of the "tramp menace" that had been so strong in the seventies were revived during the even more devastating depression that began in 1893. Most government officials and business leaders reacted with horror at the prospect of jobless men wandering the roads. A notable exception was the Populist governor of Kansas, Lorenzo Dow Lewelling. His executive proclamation of December 4, 1893, defended the rights of the homeless against arbitrary arrest by local police. His proclamation, published in the Topeka  Daily Capital  on December 5, 1893, became known as the "Tramp Circular." Lewelling's sympathy for the tramping unemployed may have come, in part, from personal experience; he himself had wandered the roads in search of work in the 1870s depression.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Wort "Tramp" kam in geläufigen Verbrauch im 
1870s als herabsetzende Beschreibung der heimatlosen Männer, die aus 
Arbeit heraus durch die Wirtschaftskrise geworfen wurden und erzwungen
waren, zur Straße auf der Suche nach einem Job oder einer Nahrung zu 
nehmen. Viele angesehene Amerikaner tramps mit einer Kombination
von Furcht und von Ekel. Furcht vor der "Trampdrohung", die 
gewesen war, also starke in den Siebzigern wurden während des sogar 
verheerenderen Tiefstands wieder belebt, der 1893 anfing. Die 
meisten Regierungsbeamten und die führenden Vertreter der Wirtschaftn
reagierten mit Grausigkeit an der Aussicht der arbeitslosen wandering 
Männer die Straßen. Eine bemerkenswerte Ausnahme war der 
Volksregler von Kansas, Lorenzo Dow Lewelling. Seine 
Executivproklamation von Dezember 4, 1893, verteidigte die Rechte des 
Homeless gegen willkürliches Anhalten durch lokale Polizei. 
Seine Proklamation, täglich veröffentlicht im Topeka Kapital 
an Dezember 5, 1893, wurde bekannt, wie das "Tramp-Rundschreiben." 
Sympathie Lewellings für die tramping Arbeitslosen kann, in 
Teil, von der persönlichen Erfahrung gekommen sein; er selbst 
wandered die Straßen auf der Suche nach Arbeit im Tiefstand 1870s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mot "bruit" a hérité l'utilisation commune 
dans le 1870s comme description de dépréciation des hommes sans 
foyer jetés sans emploi par la dépression économique et forcés de 
prendre à la route à la recherche d'un travail ou d'un aliment. 
Beaucoup d'Américains visualisés marche à pas marqués avec 
une combinaison de la crainte et du dégoût. Des craintes de la
"menace de bruit" qui avait été si forts dans les années '70 ont 
été rétablis pendant la dépression bien plus dévastatrice qui a 
commencé en 1893. La plupart des fonctionnaires de gouvernement
et chefs de file des affaires ont réagi avec l'horreur à la 
perspective des hommes sans emploi errant les routes. Une 
exception notable était le gouverneur populiste du Kansas, Lorenzo 
Dow Lewelling. Son proclamation exécutive décembre de 4, 1893,
a défendu les droites du sans-abri contre l'arrestation arbitraire 
par la police locale. Sa proclamation, éditée dans la capitale
de Topeka tous les jours 5 décembre 1893, est devenue notoire comme 
la "circulaire de bruit." La sympathie de Lewelling pour les 
chômeurs de vagabondage a pu être venue, en partie, d'une 
expérience personnelle ; il lui-même avait erré les routes à
la recherche du travail dans la dépression 1870s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A palavra "caminhada" veio no uso comum no 1870s 
como uma descrição despreciando dos homens desabrigados jogados fora
do trabalho pelo depression econômico e forçados a fazer exame à 
estrada na busca de um trabalho ou de um alimento. Muitos 
americanos vistos vagam com uma combinação do medo e da aversão. 
Os medos da "da ameaça caminhada" que tinha sido assim que 
fortes nos seventies revived durante o depression mesmo mais 
devastating que começou em 1893. A maioria oficiais de governo 
e de líderes de negócio reagiram com o horror no prospeto dos homens
jobless que vagueiam as estradas. Uma exceção notável era o 
regulador populist de Kansas, Lorenzo Dow Lewelling. Seu 
proclamation executivo dezembro de 4, 1893, defendeu as direitas do 
desabrigado de encontro à apreensão arbitrária por polícias 
locais. Seu proclamation, publicado no capital do Topeka 
diariamente dezembro em 5, 1893, tornou-se sabido como da "a circular 
caminhada." O sympathy de Lewelling para os desempregados 
vagando pode ter vindo, na parte, da experiência pessoal; ele 
mesmo tinha vagueado as estradas na busca do trabalho no depression 
1870s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La parola "vagabondo" ha entrato nell'uso comune 
nel 1870s come descrizione di sottovalutazione degli uomini senza casa
gettati senza lavoro dalla depressione economica e costretti a 
prendere alla strada alla ricerca di un lavoro o di un alimento. 
Molti Americani osservati preme il piede con una combinazione di
timore e di repulsione. I timori "della minaccia del vagabondo" 
che era stata così forti negli anni settanta sono stati fatti 
rivivere durante la depressione ancor più devastating che ha 
cominciato in 1893. La maggior parte di funzionario di governo e
dei capi di affari hanno reagito con l'orrore al prospetto 
degli uomini senza lavoro che vagano le strade. Un'eccezione 
notevole era il regolatore populistico di Kansas, Lorenzo il Dow 
Lewelling. La sua proclamazione esecutiva de 4 dicembre 1893, ha
difeso i diritti del nomade contro l'arresto arbitrario dalla polizia 
locale. La sua proclamazione, pubblicata quotidianamente nel 
capitale de Topeka il 5 dicembre 1893, è stato conosciuta come "la 
circonvallazione del vagabondo." La compassione del Lewelling 
per i disoccupati prementi il piede può venire, in parte, da 
esperienza personale; egli stesso aveva vagato le strade alla 
ricerca di lavoro nella depressione 1870s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η λέξη "αγύρτησ" μπήκε στην κοινή χρήση 1870s ως 
περιγραφή δυσφήμησης των άστεγων ατόμων που ρίχτηκαν άνεργων 
από την οικονομική ύφεση και που αναγκάστηκαν να πάρουν στο 
δρόμο σε αναζήτηση μιας εργασίας ή τροφίμων. Πολλοί 
Αμερικανοί εμφάνισαν τους αγύρτες με έναν συνδυασμό φόβου και 
αποστροφής. Οι φόβοι της "απειλής αγυρτών" που ήταν τόσο 
ισχυρή στη δεκαετία του '70 αναβιώθηκαν κατά τη διάρκεια της 
ακόμα πιό καταστρεπτικής κατάθλιψης που άρχισε σε 1893, 
Οι περισσότεροι κυβερνητικοί ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι και 
επιχειρησιακοί ηγέτες αντέδρασαν με τη φρίκη στην προοπτική των 
άνεργων ατόμων που περιπλανιούνται οι δρόμοι. Μια 
αξιοσημείωτη εξαίρεση ήταν ο λαϊκιστικός κυβερνήτης του Κάνσας,
Lorenzo Dow Lewelling. Η εκτελεστική προκήρυξή του 
της 4ης Δεκεμβρίου ..1893, υπεράσπισε τα δικαιώματα των αστέγων
ενάντια στην αυθαίρετη σύλληψη από την τοπική αστυνομία. Η
προκήρυξή του, που δημοσιεύθηκε στο καθημερινό κεφάλαιο Topeka
στις 5 Δεκεμβρίου ..1893, έγινε γνωστή ως "εγκύκλιος αγυρτών."
Η συμπόνοια του Lewelling για τους αγυρτεύοντας ανέργους 
μπορεί να είχε προέλθει, εν μέρει, από την προσωπική εμπειρία  
ο ίδιος είχε περιπλανηθεί οι δρόμοι σε αναζήτηση της 
εργασίας στη 1870s κατάθλιψη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La palabra "vagabundo" vino en uso común en el 
1870s como descripción que desacreditaba de los hombres sin hogar 
lanzados sin trabajo por la depresión económica y forzados llevar el
camino en búsqueda de un trabajo o de un alimento. Muchos 
americanos vistos andan por con una combinación del miedo y de la 
repugnancia. Los miedos de la "amenaza del vagabundo" que había
sido así que fuertes en los años 70 fueron restablecidos durante la 
depresión aún más devastadora que comenzó en 1893. La 
mayoría de los oficiales del gobierno y de los arranques de cinta de 
negocio reaccionaron con horror en la perspectiva de los hombres 
desempleados que vagaban los caminos. Una anomalía notable era 
el gobernador populista de Kansas, Lorenzo Dow Lewelling. Su 
proclamación ejecutiva del de diciembre 4 de 1893, defendió las 
derechas del nómada contra la detención arbitraria del policía 
local. Su proclamación, publicada en el capital del Topeka 
diariamente 5 de diciembre de 1893, se sabía como la "circular del
vagabundo." La condolencia de Lewelling para los parados que 
andan por pudo haber venido, en parte, de experiencia personal; 
él sí mismo había vagado los caminos en la búsqueda del 
trabajo en la depresión 1870s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086312</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107796</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/if-a-diogenes-prefers-poverty-lewelling-defends-the-rights-of-the-unemployed</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
