<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103302</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103302</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207112</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">George Washington: First in War, First in Peace, and First in the Hearts of His Countrymen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">George Washington: Zuerst im Krieg, zuerst 
im Frieden und zuerst in den Inneren seiner Landsmänner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">George Washington : D'abord dans la 
guerre, d'abord dans la paix, et d'abord aux coeurs de ses 
compatriotes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">George Washington: Primeiramente na guerra, 
primeiramente na paz, e primeiramente nos corações de seus 
compatriotas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">George Washington: In primo luogo nella 
guerra, in primo luogo nella pace ed in primo luogo nei cuori dei suoi
countrymen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Γεοργε Ουάσιγκτον: Πρώτα στον πόλεμο, πρώτα εν
την ειρήνη, και πρώτα στις καρδιές των χωρικών του</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">George Washington: Primero en guerra, 
primero en paz, y primero en los corazones de sus paisanos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site consists of three lessons examining George Washington's leadership in the French and Indian War, at the Federal Convention, and as chief executive. They are based on primary source documents from the George Washington Papers, 1741-1799. The lessons are intended for secondary students, grades 8-12. The documents from Washington's Letterbooks include focus questions that may be used in Socratic seminars and in cooperative learning groups.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site besteht aus drei Lektionen, die George 
Washingtons Führung im französischen und Inder-Krieg, an der 
Bundesversammlung und als Hauptgeschäftsführer überprüfen. 
Sie basieren auf Primärquelldokumenten von den George 
Washington Papieren, 1741-1799. Die Lektionen sind für 
Sekundärkursteilnehmer, Grade 8-12 bestimmt. Die Dokumente von 
Letterbooks Washingtons schließen Fokusfragen ein, die in den 
Socratic Seminaren und in den kooperativen erlernengruppen verwendet 
werden können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site se compose de trois leçons examinant la 
conduite de George Washington dans la guerre française et 
d'Indien, à la convention fédérale, et en tant que cadre 
supérieur. Ils sont basés sur les documents de source 
primaires des papiers de George Washington, 1741-1799. Les 
leçons sont destinées pour les étudiants secondaires, catégories 
8-12. Les documents de Letterbooks de Washington incluent les 
questions de foyer qui peuvent être utilisées dans des conférences 
socratiques et dans les groupes d'étude coopératifs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local consiste em três lições que examinam
a liderança de George Washington na guerra francesa e de indian, na 
convenção federal, e como o executivo principal. São baseados
nos originais de fonte preliminares dos papéis de George Washington, 
1741-1799. As lições são pretendidas para estudantes 
secundários, classes 8-12. Os originais de Letterbooks de 
Washington incluem as perguntas do foco que podem ser usadas em 
seminários de Socratic e em grupos de aprendizagem cooperativos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo consiste di tre lezioni che esaminano
la direzione di George Washington nella guerra di indiano e francese, 
alla convenzione federale e come esecutivo principale. Sono 
basati sui documenti di origine primari dalle carte da George 
Washington, 1741-1799. Le lezioni sono intese per gli allievi 
secondari, gradi 8-12. I documenti da Letterbooks de Washington 
includono le domande del fuoco che possono essere usate nei seminari 
di Socratic e nei gruppi imparanti cooperativi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή αποτελείται από τρία μαθήματα που 
εξετάζουν την ηγεσία George Ουάσιγκτον στο γαλλικό και ινδικό 
πόλεμο, στην ομοσπονδιακή Συνθήκη, και όπως προϊστάμενος 
εκτελεστική. Είναι βασισμένοι στα αρχικά έγγραφα πηγής 
από τα έγγραφα George Ουάσιγκτον, 1741-1799. Τα 
μαθήματα προορίζονται για τους δευτεροβάθμιους σπουδαστές, βαθμοί
8-12. Τα έγγραφα από Letterbooks της Ουάσιγκτον 
περιλαμβάνουν τις ερωτήσεις εστίασης που μπορούν να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν στα σωκρατικά σεμινάρια και στις συνεταιριστικές 
μαθαίνοντας ομάδες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio consiste en tres lecciones que examinan
la dirección de George Washington en la guerra francesa y de indio, 
en la convención federal, y como ejecutivo. Los basan en los 
documentos de fuente primarios de los papeles de George Washington, 
1741-1799. Las lecciones se piensan para los estudiantes 
secundarios, grados 8-12. Los documentos de Letterbooks de 
Washington incluyen las preguntas del foco que se pueden utilizar en 
los seminarios de Socratic y en grupos que aprenden cooperativos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207112</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103302</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/george-washington-first-in-war-first-in-peace-and-first-in-the-hearts-of-his-countrymen</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
