<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104929</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104929</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086291</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Never Met a Black Person Who Was in the Communist Party Because of the Soviet Union:" Jack O'Dell on Fighting Racism in the 1940s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich traf nie eine schwarze Person, die war in der
kommunistischen Partei wegen des Sowjet-Anschlußes:" 
Jack O'Dell auf kämpfendem Rassismus in den vierziger Jahren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je n'ai jamais rencontré une personne noire qui 
était en parti communiste en raison d'Union Soviétique :" Jack 
o'Dell sur le racisme de combat dans les années 40</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu nunca encontrei-me com uma pessoa preta que 
estivesse no partido comunista por causa da Soviete-união:" 
Jack O'Dell no racism de combate nos 1940s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"non ho venuto a contatto mai di una persona nera 
che fosse nel partito comunista a causa dell'Soviet-unione:" 
Jack O'Dell su razzismo di Combattimento nei 1940s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν συνάντησα ποτέ ένα μαύρο πρόσωπο που ήταν στο 
Κομμουνιστικό Κόμμα λόγω της Σοβιετικής Ένωσης:" Θ*Ιαθκ 
O'Dell στην πάλη του ρατσισμού στη δεκαετία του '40</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"nunca satisfice a persona negra que estaba en el 
partido comunista debido a la Soviet-unio'n:" Gato O'Dell en 
racismo que lucha en los años 40</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Jack O'Dell was a union organizer, a civil rights leader, and a member of the Communist Party. His political consciousness formed in the 1940's, when the African-American community became more assertive in their efforts to improve conditions and expand civil rights. Like many blacks, including one of his role models, Paul Robeson, O'Dell was drawn to the Communist Party because of their staunch stand against racism and segregation. During the 1940's, O'Dell found a welcoming environment in the National Maritime Union. Later, he worked for the director of the Southern Christian Leadership Counsel (SCLC) office in New York, before becoming SCLC's voter registration director in seven southern states.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jack O'Dell war ein Anschlußorganisator, ein 
Zivilrechtführer und ein Bauteil der kommunistischen Partei. 
Sein politisches Bewußtsein bildete sich in den vierziger 
Jahren, als die Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Gemeinschaft in ihren 
Bemühungen, Bedingungen zu verbessern und Zivilrechte zu erweitern 
assertive wurde. Wie viele Schwarze einschließlich eins seiner 
Rolle Modelle, wurde Paul Robeson, O'Dell zur kommunistischen 
Partei wegen ihres staunch Standplatzes gegen Rassismus und 
Abtrennung gezeichnet. Während der vierziger Jahre fand O'Dell 
eine begrüßende Umgebung im nationalen Seeanschluß. Später 
arbeitete er für den Direktor des südlichen christlichen Büros der 
Führung-Ratschläge (SCLC) in New York, vor werdenem SCLC's 
Wähler-Registrierungdirektor in sieben südlichen Zuständen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jack o'Dell était un organisateur des syndicats, 
une amorce de droits civiques, et un membre du parti communiste. 
Sa conscience politique a formé dans les années 40, quand la 
communauté afro-américaine est devenue plus autoritaire dans leurs 
efforts d'améliorer des conditions et d'augmenter des droits 
civiques. Comme beaucoup de noirs, y compris un de ses modèles 
de rôle, Paul Robeson, o'Dell a été dessiné au parti communiste en
raison de leur stand dévoué contre le racisme et la ségrégation.
Pendant les années 40, o'Dell a trouvé un environnement 
d'accueil dans l'union maritime nationale. Plus tard, il a 
travaillé pour le directeur du bureau chrétien méridional des 
avocats-conseils de conduite (SCLC) à New York, avant directeur 
devenant d'enregistrement d'électeur de SCLC's dans sept états 
méridionaux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jack O'Dell era um organizer da união, chefes dos
direitos civis, e um membro do partido comunista. Seu 
consciousness político deu forma nos 1940's, quando a comunidade 
Africano-Americana se tornou mais assertive em seus esforços melhorar
circunstâncias e expandir direitas civis. Como muitos pretos, 
including um de seus modelos do papel, Paul Robeson, O'Dell foi 
desenhado ao partido comunista por causa de seu carrinho staunch de 
encontro ao racism e ao segregation. Durante os 1940's, O'Dell 
encontrou um ambiente dando boas-vindas na união marítima nacional. 
Mais tarde, trabalhou para o diretor do escritório christian do
sul dos conselhos da liderança (SCLC) em New York, antes do diretor 
tornando-se do registo do eleitor de SCLC's em sete estados do sul.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Jack O'Dell era un organizzatore del sindacato, un
capo di diritti civili e un membro del partito comunista. 
La sua coscienza politica ha formato nei 1940's, quando la 
Comunità Africano-Americana è diventato più assertive nei loro 
sforzi migliorare le circostanze ed espandere i diritti civili. 
Come molti neri, compreso uno dei suoi modelli di ruolo, Paul 
Robeson, O'Dell è stato dissipato al partito comunista a causa del 
loro basamento staunch contro il razzismo e la segregazione. 
Durante i 1940's, O'Dell ha trovato un ambiente dante il 
benvenuto nell'unione marittima nazionale. Successivamente, ha 
lavorato per il direttore dell'ufficio cristiano del sud dei 
consulenti legali di direzione (SCLC) a New York, prima che il 
direttore diventante di registro dell'elettore di SCLC's in sette del 
sud dichiarasse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Jack O'Dell ήταν διοργανωτής ένωσης, ηγέτης 
αστικών δικαιωμάτων, και μέλος του Κομμουνιστικού Κόμματος. 
Η πολιτική συνείδησή του διαμόρφωσε στη δεκαετία του '40, 
όταν η αφρικανικός-αμερικανική κοινότητα έγινε πιό 
κατηγορηματική στις προσπάθειές τους να βελτιώσουν τους όρους και
να επεκτείνουν τα αστικά δικαιώματα. Όπως τους πολλούς 
Μαύρους, συμπεριλαμβανομένου ενός από τα μοντέλα ρόλου του, 
Paul Robeson, O'Dell σύρθηκε στο Κομμουνιστικό Κόμμα λόγω
της staunch στάσης τους κατά του ρατσισμού και του διαχωρισμού.
Κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '40, O'Dell βρήκε ένα
περιβάλλον υποδοχής στην εθνική θαλάσσια ένωση. Αργότερα, 
εργάστηκε για το σκηνοθέτη του νότιου χριστιανικού γραφείου 
συμβουλής ηγεσίας (SCLC) στη Νέα Υόρκη, πρίν γίνεται 
σκηνοθέτης εγγραφής ψηφοφόρων SCLC σε επτά νότια κράτη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Gato O'Dell era un organizador de la unión, un 
arranque de cinta de las derechas civiles, y un miembro del partido 
comunista. Su sentido político formó en los años 40, cuando 
la comunidad Africano-Americana hizo más asertiva en sus esfuerzos de
mejorar condiciones y de ampliar las derechas civiles. Como 
muchos negros, incluyendo uno de sus modelos del papel, trazaron a 
Paul Robeson, O'Dell al partido comunista debido a su soporte 
firme contra racismo y la segregación. Durante los años 
40, O'Dell encontró un ambiente que daba la bienvenida en la unión 
marítimo nacional. Más adelante, él trabajó para el director
de la oficina cristiana meridional de los consejos de la dirección 
(SCLC) en Nueva York, antes de director del registro del votante de 
SCLC's que se convertía en siete estados meridionales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086291</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104929</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-never-met-a-black-person-who-was-in-the-communist-party-because-of-the-soviet-union-jack-odell-on-fighting-racism-in-the-1940s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
