<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104906</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104906</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973926</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Literature Games: Lord of the Flies</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Literatur-Spiele: Lord der Fliegen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Littérature : Seigneur des mouches</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Literatura: Senhor das moscas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Della Letteratura: Signore dei 
mosche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια λογοτεχνίας: Λόρδος των μυγών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Literatura: Señor de las 
moscas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! William Golding's first novel, "Lord of the Flies," 1954, rapidly became a world success and has remained so. It has reached tens of millions of readers. If you are one of them, you may challenge your memory with this game. If you haven't read the book, read it and come back! It's a very entertaining and exciting book about a group of young boys who are isolated on a desert island.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
William Goldings erster Roman, "Lord der Fliegen," 1954, schnell
wurde ein Welterfolg und ist so geblieben. Er hat 10 Millionen 
Leser erreicht. Wenn Sie einer von ihnen sind, können Sie Ihren
Speicher mit diesem Spiel herausfordern. Wenn Sie nicht das Buch
gelesen haben, lesen Sie es und kommen Sie zurück! Es ist sehr 
unterhalten und ein aufregendes Buch eine ungefähr Gruppe junge 
Jungen, die auf einer Wüste Insel lokalisiert werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Le 
premier roman de William Golding, "seigneur des mouches," 1954, est 
rapidement devenu un succès du monde et est resté ainsi. Il a 
atteint des dizaines de millions de lecteurs. Si vous êtes l'un
d'entre eux, vous pouvez défier votre mémoire avec ce jeu. Si 
vous n'avez pas lu le livre, lisez-l'et revenez ! C'est très un
divertissement et un livre passionnant environ un groupe de jeunes 
garçons qui sont isolés sur une île de désert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! A 
primeira novela de William Golding, "senhor das moscas," 1954, 
ràpidamente transformou-se um sucesso do mundo e remanesceu assim. 
Alcançou dez dos milhões dos leitores. Se você for um 
deles, você pode desafiar sua memória com este jogo. Se você 
não ler o livro, leia-o e volte-o! É muito entertaining e um 
livro emocionante aproximadamente um grupo dos meninos novos que são 
isolados em um console do deserto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Il primo romanzo del William 
Golding, "signore dei mosche," 1954, velocemente si è transformato in
in un successo del mondo ed è rimasto così. Ha raggiunto i 
dieci di milioni di lettori. Se siete un di loro, potete sfidare
la vostra memoria con questo gioco. Se non avete letto il libro,
leggalo e ritorni! È molto intrattenere e un libro emozionante 
circa un gruppo dei ragazzi giovani che sono isolati su un'isola del 
deserto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Το 
πρώτο μυθιστόρημα William Golding's, "Λόρδος των μυγών," το 
1954, έγινε γρήγορα μια παγκόσμια επιτυχία και έχει 
παραμείνει έτσι. Έχει φθάσει στις δεκάδες των εκατομμυρίων
των αναγνωστών. Εάν είστε ένας από τους, μπορείτε να 
προκαλέσετε τη μνήμη σας με αυτό το παιχνίδι. Εάν δεν 
έχετε διαβάσει το βιβλίο, το διαβάστε και επιστρέψτε! Είναι 
ένα πολύ βιβλίο διασκέδαση και διέγερση για μια ομάδα 
νέων αγοριών που είναι απομονωμένα σε ένα νησί ερήμων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! La 
primera novela de Guillermo Golding, "señor de las moscas," 1954, se 
convirtió en un éxito del mundo y ha permanecido rápidamente tan. 
Ha alcanzado diez de millones de programas de lectura. Si 
usted es una de ellos, usted puede desafiar su memoria con este juego.
¡Si usted no ha leído el libro, léalo y vuélvase! Es 
muy el entretener y un libro emocionante alrededor de un grupo 
de los muchachos jóvenes que se aíslan en una isla del desierto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973926</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104906</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/literature-games-lord-of-the-flies</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
