<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/1237349346</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>1237349346</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204566</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Rock around the rock cycle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Felsen um die Felsenschleife</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Roche autour du cycle de roche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Rocha em torno do ciclo da rocha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Roccia intorno al ciclo della roccia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βράχος γύρω από τον κύκλο βράχου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Roca alrededor del ciclo de la roca</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students will study the rock cycle to understand the relationship between the three types of rocks, sedimentary, metamorphic, and igneous, and the conditions needed to transform one type of rock into another. This hopefully will be accomplished through visual learning with computer activities and the demonstration and through auditory learning with the discussion. The student can then apply the knowledge they learned through a story.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer studieren die Felsenschleife, um 
das Verhältnis zwischen den drei Typen der Felsen, sedimentär, 
metamorph, und Eruptiv und den Bedingungen zu verstehen, die benötigt
werden, um einen Typen Felsen in andere umzuwandeln. Dieses 
hoffnungsvoll wird durch das Sichtlernen mit Computeraktivitäten und 
der Demonstration und durch das Gehörlernen mit der Diskussion 
vollendet. Der Kursteilnehmer kann das Wissen dann anwenden, das
sie durch eine Geschichte erlernten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants étudieront le cycle de roche pour 
comprendre le rapport entre les trois types de roches, sédimentaire, 
métamorphique, et igné, et les conditions requises pour transformer 
un type de roche en des autres. Ceci si tout va bien sera 
accompli par l'étude visuelle avec des activités d'ordinateur et la 
démonstration et par l'étude auditive avec la discussion. 
L'étudiant peut alors appliquer la connaissance qu'ils ont 
apprise par une histoire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes estudarão o ciclo da rocha para 
compreender o relacionamento entre os três tipos de rochas, 
sedimentary, metamorphic, e igneous, e as circunstâncias necessitadas
transformar um tipo de rocha em outro. Isto será realizado 
esperançosamente com da aprendizagem visual com atividades do 
computador e a demonstração e com da aprendizagem auditory com a 
discussão. O estudante pode então aplicar o conhecimento que 
aprenderam com uma história.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi studeranno il ciclo della roccia per 
capire il rapporto fra i tre tipi di roccie, sedimentario, metamorfico
ed igneo e le circostanze state necessarie per trasformare un tipo di 
roccia in un altro. Ciò eventualmente sarà compiuta con 
imparare visivo con le attività del calcolatore e la dimostrazione e 
con imparare uditivo con la discussione. L'allievo può allora 
applicare la conoscenza che hanno imparato con una storia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές θα μελετήσουν τον κύκλο βράχου για να 
καταλάβουν τη σχέση μεταξύ των τριών τύπων βράχων, ιζηματώδης, 
μεταμορφικός, και πύρινος, και των όρων που απαιτούνται για να 
μετασχηματίσουν έναν τύπο βράχου σε άλλο. Αυτό 
ενδεχομένως θα ολοκληρωθεί μέσω της οπτικής εκμάθησης με τις 
δραστηριότητες υπολογιστών και την επίδειξη και μέσω της 
ακουστικής εκμάθησης με τη συζήτηση. Ο σπουδαστής μπορεί 
έπειτα να εφαρμόσει τη γνώση που έμαθαν μέσω μιας ιστορίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes estudiarán el ciclo de la roca 
para entender el lazo entre los tres tipos de rocas, sedimentario, 
metamórfico, e ígneo, y las condiciones necesitadas para transformar
un tipo de roca en otro. Esto esperanzadamente será lograda con
aprender visual con actividades del ordenador y la demostración y con
aprender auditivo con la discusión. El estudiante puede 
entonces aplicar el conocimiento que aprendieron con una historia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GEOL 130
FN:GEOL 130
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204566</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>1237349346</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/rock-around-the-rock-cycle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
