<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108094</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108094</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200387</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Algae Experiments</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Algen Experimente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Expériences d'Algues</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Experiências Das Algas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esperimenti Delle Alghe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πειράματα αλγών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Experimentos De las Algas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This two-part lesson offers students the opportunity to view two types of algae (freshwater and Great Salt Lake species) and assess the survival of each when placed in altered habitats. Students will make observations and record their observations on a recording sheet where they will describe what they see through drawing and words. They will help prepare slides of algae and will learn to identify different qualities such as cell structure, movement and other behavioristic qualities of the two different types of algae. The resource includes background knowledge, reference to Utah elementary core curriculum standards, prior resource assessment, reproducible handouts, materials list, teaching recommendations, and final assessment strategies.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese zweiteilige Lektion bietet Kursteilnehmern 
die Gelegenheit an, zwei Typen Algen (Frischwasser- und großes Salt 
Seesorte) anzusehen und das Überleben von jedem festzusetzen, wenn 
sie in geänderte Lebensräume gelegt wird. Kursteilnehmer 
bilden Beobachtungen und ihre Beobachtungen auf einer Aufnahme zu 
speichern bedecken Sie, wo sie beschreiben, was sie durch das Zeichnen
und die Wörter sehen. Sie helfen, Plättchen der Algen 
vorzubereiten und erlernen, unterschiedliche Qualitäten wie Zelle 
Struktur, Bewegung und andere behavioristic Qualitäten der zwei 
unterschiedlichen Typen der Algen zu kennzeichnen. Das 
Hilfsmittel schließt Hintergrundwissen, Referenz auf Utah 
grundlegenden Kern-Lehrplanstandards, vorherige 
Hilfsmitteleinschätzung, reproduzierbare Mitteilungsblätter, 
Materialien ausdrucken ein und unterrichtet Empfehlungen und 
abschließende Einschätzung Strategien.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette leçon en deux parties donne à des 
étudiants l'occasion de visualiser deux types d'algues (des 
espèces de lac salt d'eau douce et grand) et d'évaluer la 
survie de chacun une fois placée dans les habitats modifiés. 
Les étudiants feront des observations et enregistrer leurs 
observations sur un enregistrement couvrez où elles décriront ce 
qu'elles voient par le dessin et les mots. Ils aideront à 
préparer des glissières des algues et apprendront à identifier 
différentes qualités telles que la structure de cellules, le 
mouvement et d'autres qualités behavioristic des deux types 
différents d'algues. La ressource inclut les connaissances de 
base, référence aux normes élémentaires de programme d'études de 
noyau de l'Utah, évaluation antérieure de ressource, aumônes 
reproductibles, matériaux énumèrent, enseignant des 
recommandations, et des stratégies finales d'évaluation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta lição two-part oferece a estudantes a 
oportunidade de ver dois tipos de algas (espécie do lago salt 
freshwater e grande) e de avaliar a sobrevivência de cada um quando 
colocada em habitats alterados. Os estudantes farão 
observações e para gravar suas observações em uma gravação sheet
onde descreverão o que vêem com desenhar e palavras. Ajudarão
preparar corrediças das algas e aprenderão identificar qualidades 
diferentes tais como a estrutura da pilha, o movimento e outras 
qualidades behavioristic dos dois tipos diferentes de algas. O 
recurso inclui o conhecimento de fundo, referência aos padrões 
elementares do curriculum do núcleo de Utá, avaliação prévia do 
recurso, handouts reproducible, materiais alista, ensinando 
recomendações, e estratégias finais da avaliação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa lezione in due parti offre ad allievi 
l'opportunità di osservare due tipi di alghe (d'acqua dolce e specie 
del Gran Lago Salato) e di valutare la sopravvivenza di ciascuno una 
volta disposta in habitat alterati. Gli allievi faranno le 
osservazioni e registrare le loro osservazioni su una registrazione 
rivesta dove descriveranno che cosa vedono con dissipare e le parole. 
Contribuiranno a preparare gli scorrevoli delle alghe ed 
impareranno identificare le qualità differenti quali la struttura 
delle cellule, il movimento ed altre qualità behavioristic dei due 
tipi differenti di alghe. La risorsa include la conoscenza di 
base, il riferimento agli standard elementari di programma di studi di
nucleo dell'Utah, la valutazione anteriore delle risorse, le dispense 
riproducibili, materiali elenca, insegnando le raccomandazioni e le 
strategie finali di valutazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το διμερές μάθημα προσφέρει στους σπουδαστές την
ευκαιρία να εμφανίσει δύο τύπους αλγών (του γλυκού νερού και 
είδη του Γκρέιτ Σωλτ Λέηκ) και να αξιολογήσει την επιβίωση κάθε 
ένας όταν τοποθετείται στους αλλαγμένους βιότοπους. Οι 
σπουδαστές θα κάνουν τις παρατηρήσεις και θα καταγράψουν τις 
παρατηρήσεις τους σε ένα φύλλο καταγραφής όπου θα περιγράψουν τι
βλέπουνε μέσω του σχεδίου και των λέξεων. Θα 
βοηθήσουν να προετοιμάσουν τις φωτογραφικές διαφάνειες των αλγών 
και θα μάθουν να προσδιορίζουν τις διαφορετικές ιδιότητες τέτοιες
ως δομή κυττάρων, μετακίνηση και άλλες συμπεριφοριστικές 
ιδιότητες των δύο διαφορετικών τύπων αλγών. Το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς περιλαμβάνει τη γνώση υποβάθρου, την αναφορά στα 
στοιχειώδη πρότυπα προγράμματος σπουδών πυρήνων του Utah, την 
προγενέστερη αξιολόγηση των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς, τα 
αναπαραγώγιμα φυλλάδια, τον κατάλογο υλικών, τις συστάσεις 
διδασκαλίας, και τις τελικές στρατηγικές αξιολόγησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta lección bipartita ofrece a estudiantes la 
oportunidad de visión dos tipos de algas (especie del lago salt de 
agua dulce y grande) y de evaluar la supervivencia de cada uno cuando 
está colocada en habitat alterados. Los estudiantes harán 
observaciones y registrar sus observaciones respecto a una grabación 
cubra donde describirán lo que consideran con trazar y palabras. 
Ayudarán a preparar diapositivas de algas y aprenderán 
identificar diversas calidades tales como estructura de la célula, 
movimiento y otras calidades behavioristic de los dos diversos tipos 
de algas. El recurso incluye el conocimiento de fondo, 
referencia a los estándares elementales del plan de estudios de la 
base de Utah, gravamen anterior del recurso, folletos reproductivos, 
materiales enumera, enseñando recomendaciones, y estrategias finales 
del gravamen.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KIM DUFFY
FN:KIM DUFFY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WESTMINSTER COLLEGE GREAT SALT LAKE PROJECT
FN:WESTMINSTER COLLEGE GREAT SALT LAKE PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200387</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108094</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/algae-experiments</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
