<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104035</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104035</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087235</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Whom I Must Join": Elizabeth Ashbridge, an 18th-Century Englishwoman, Becomes a Quaker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wem Muß Ich Verbinden": Elizabeth 
Ashbridge, eine Engländerin 18th-Century, steht einem Quäker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Qui Je Dois Me joindre" : Elizabeth 
Ashbridge, une anglaise 18th-Century, va bien à un quaker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Quem Eu Devo Juntar": Elizabeth Ashbridge, 
um englishwoman 18th-Century, assenta bem em um quaker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Chi Devo Unirsi": Elizabeth Ashbridge, un 
englishwoman 18th-Century, sta bene ad un quaker</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ποιων πρέπει να ενώσω": Θ*Εληζαψετχ Ashbridge,
ένας 18$ος-αιώνας Englishwoman, γίνεται μια κουάκερη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Quién Debo Ensamblar": Elizabeth 
Ashbridge, englishwoman 18th-Century, siente bien a un quaker</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Elizabeth Ashbridge (1713-1755) began life as a vivacious girl with a _wild and airy? temperament and ended it as a sober Quaker. Born in England, Ashbridge eloped at fourteen and was widowed five months later. After rejection by her family and a three-year sojourn with relatives in Ireland, she sailed for America as an indentured servant, arriving in New York in July, 1732. This selection from her autobiography begins as Ashbridge sets out from her home in Long Island to visit relatives in Philadelphia. By then she had undergone an intensely felt spiritual search and had married her second husband, a teacher with a penchant for violence and drink. Ashbridge's dispute with her second husband over her Quakerism ended only with his enlistment in the army and subsequent death. She married a third time, to a Quaker named Aaron Ashbridge, and died while visiting Quakers in England and Ireland.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Elizabeth Ashbridge (1713-1755) fing das Leben als
vivacious Mädchen mit einem _ wildem und airy an? 
Temperament und beendet ihm als nüchterner Quäker. 
Getragen in England, eloped Ashbridge bei vierzehn und war 
widowed fünf Monate später. Nach Rückweisung durch ihre 
Familie und einem dreijährigen sojourn mit Verwandten in Irland, 
segelte sie für Amerika, während Bediensteten indentured und kam in 
New York im Juli, 1732 an. Diese Auswahl von ihrer 
Autobiographie fängt an, wie Ashbridge von ihrem Haus im Long Island 
darlegte, um Verwandte in Philadelphia zu besuchen. Bis dahin 
hatte sie glaubte intensiv geistiger Suche und hatte verbunden ihren 
zweiten Ehemann, einen Lehrer mit einem Hang für Gewalttätigkeit und
Getränk durchgemacht. Debatte Ashbridges mit ihrem zweiten 
Ehemann über ihrem Quakerism beendete nur mit seiner Eintragung in 
der Armee und im folgenden Tod. Sie verband ein drittes Mal, zu 
einem Quäker, der Aaron Ashbridge benannt wurde und starb beim 
Besuchen der Quäker in England und in Irland.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Elizabeth Ashbridge (1713-1755) a commencé la 
vie en tant que fille vivace par _ un sauvage et bien aéré ? 
tempérament et terminé lui en tant que quaker sobre. 
Soutenu en Angleterre, Ashbridge eloped à quatorze et était 
des cinq mois veufs plus tard. Après que le rejet par sa
famille et un séjour de trois ans avec des parents en Irlande, 
elle aient navigué pour l'Amérique pendant qu'indentured 
l'domestique, arrivant à New York en juillet, 1732. Cette 
sélection à partir de son autobiographie commence comme Ashbridge 
s'est mis de sa maison en longue île à rendre visite à des parents 
à Philadelphie. D'ici là elle avait subi a intensément senti 
la recherche spirituelle et avait marié son deuxième mari, un 
professeur avec un penchant pour la violence et la boisson. Le 
conflit d'Ashbridge avec son deuxième mari au-dessus de son Quakerism
a terminé seulement avec son enrôlement dans l'armée et la mort 
ultérieure. Elle a marié une troisième fois, à un quaker 
nommé Aaron Ashbridge, et est morte tout en rendant visite à des 
quakers en Angleterre et en Irlande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Elizabeth Ashbridge (1713-1755) começou a vida 
como uma menina vivacious com _ um selvagem e airy? temperament 
e terminado lhe como um quaker sober. Carregado em Inglaterra, 
Ashbridge eloped em quatorze e era widowed cinco meses mais tarde. 
Após a rejeção por sua família e um sojourn three-year com 
os parentes em Ireland, sailed para América enquanto indentured o 
empregado, chegando em New York em julho, 1732. Esta seleção 
de seu autobiography começa enquanto Ashbridge se ajusta para fora de
sua HOME no console longo para visitar parentes em Filadélfia. 
Pela tinha-se submetido então ao sentiu intensa a busca 
espiritual e tinha casado seu segundo marido, um professor com um 
penchant para a violência e a bebida. A disputa de Ashbridge 
com seu segundo marido sobre seu Quakerism terminou somente com seu 
enlistment no exército e na morte subseqüente. Casou uma 
terceira vez, a um quaker nomeado Aaron Ashbridge, e morreu ao visitar
quakers em Inglaterra e em Ireland.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Elizabeth Ashbridge (1713-1755) ha cominciato la 
vita come ragazza vivacious con _ un selvaggio ed airy? 
temperament e concluso esso come quaker sobrio. Sopportato
in Inghilterra, Ashbridge eloped a quattordici ed era widowed cinque 
mesi più successivamente. Dopo il rifiuto dalla sua famiglia e 
un sojourn triennale con i parenti in Irlanda, ha navigato per 
l'America mentre indentured il servo, arrivando a New York in luglio, 
del 1732. Questa selezione dal suo autobiography comincia come 
Ashbridge ha precisato dalla sua sede in isola lunga per visitare i 
parenti a Filadelfia. Per allora aveva subito intensamente ha 
ritenuto la ricerca spiritosa ed aveva sposato il suo secondo marito, 
un insegnante con un penchant per la violenza e la bevanda. La 
disputa del Ashbridge con il suo secondo marito sopra il suo Quakerism
si è conclusa soltanto con il suo enlistment nell'esercito e nella 
morte successiva. Ha sposato una terza volta, ad un quaker 
chiamato Aaron Ashbridge ed è morto mentre visitava i quakers in 
Inghilterra ed in Irlanda.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Εληζαψετχ Ashbridge (1713-1755) άρχισε τη ζωή ως
ζωηρό κορίτσι με _ άγριος και αερώδης; ιδιοσυγκρασία και 
τελειωμένος το ως νηφάλιο κουάκερο. Γεννημένος στην Αγγλία,
Ashbridge σε δεκατέσσερις και ήταν χηρευάμενος πέντε μήνες 
αργότερα. Μετά από την απόρριψη από την οικογένειά της 
και μια τρίχρονη παραμονή με τους συγγενείς στην Ιρλανδία, 
έπλευσε για την Αμερική δεδομένου ότι ο υπάλληλος, που φθάνει 
στη Νέα Υόρκη τον Ιούλιο, του 1732. Αυτή η επιλογή από 
την αυτοβιογραφία της αρχίζει όπως Ashbridge καθορίζει από το 
σπίτι της στο μακρύ νησί να επισκεφτεί τους συγγενείς στη 
Φιλαδέλφεια. Έως τότε είχε υποβληθεί σε μια έντονα 
αισθητή πνευματική αναζήτηση και είχε παντρεψει το δεύτερο 
σύζυγό της, έναν δάσκαλο με μια τάση για τη βία και το ποτό. 
Η διαφωνία του Ashbridge με το δεύτερο σύζυγό της πέρα 
από το Quakerism της τελείωσε μόνο με την κατάταξή του στο 
στρατό και τον επόμενο θάνατο. Πάντρεψε έναν τρίτο χρόνο,
με τον κουάκερο ονομασμένο Aaron Ashbridge, και πέθανε 
επισκεμμένος Quakers στην Αγγλία και την Ιρλανδία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Elizabeth Ashbridge (1713-1755) comenzó vida 
como muchacha vivacious con _ un salvaje y airy? temperamento y 
terminado le como quaker sobrio. Llevado en Inglaterra, 
Ashbridge eloped en catorce y era widowed cinco meses más adelante. 
Después del rechazamiento de su familia y de un sojourn de tres
años con los parientes en Irlanda, ella navegó para América como 
indentured a criado, llegando en Nueva York en julio de 1732. 
Esta selección de su autobiografía comienza como Ashbridge 
precisó de su hogar en la isla larga para visitar a parientes en 
Philadelphia. Para entonces ella había experimentado sentía 
intenso búsqueda espiritual y había casado su segundo marido, un 
profesor con una inclinación para la violencia y la bebida. El 
conflicto de Ashbridge con su segundo marido sobre su Quakerism 
terminó solamente con su alistamiento en el ejército y la muerte 
subsecuente. Ella casó una tercera vez, con un quaker nombrado 
Aaron Ashbridge, y murió mientras que visitaba a quakers en 
Inglaterra e Irlanda.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087235</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104035</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/whom-i-must-join-elizabeth-ashbridge-an-18th-century-englishwoman-becomes-a-quaker</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
