<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108680</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108680</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087278</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Case of Black and White: White Women Protest the Hiring of Black "Wage-Slaves"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Fall von Schwarzem und vom Weiß: Weiße
Frauen protestieren die Einstellung der schwarzen "Lohn-Sklaven"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un cas de noir et de blanc : Les femmes 
blanches protestent la location des "Salaire-Esclaves" noirs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um exemplo de preto e do branco: As mulheres
brancas protestam empregar de "Salário-Escravos pretos"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un caso di nero e di bianco: Le donne 
bianche protestano assumere "degli Stipendio-Schiavi" neri</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια περίπτωση μαύρου και του λευκού: Οι λευκές 
γυναίκες διαμαρτύρονται τη μίσθωση των μαύρων "αμοιβή-σκλάβων"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un caso de negro y del blanco: Las mujeres 
blancas protestan emplear de "Salario-Esclavos negros"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Before the Civil War, some enslaved African Americans labored in Southern textile mills, especially in the spinning and weaving rooms. But with the jump in the price of slaves in the 1850s, manufacturers decided that poor white farmers provided a cheaper labor force. After the Civil War, the textile mill workforce remained entirely white for a number of reasons: landlords wanted African Americans to work in cotton fields; white leaders promoted industrialization as the salvation of poor whites; and the dominant racial ideology forbade the mixing of white women and black men in the workplace. Although planters and manufacturers had the most to gain from a segregated work force, white workers--as this 1898 protest from the women of Atlanta's Fulton Mills indicated--accepted the idea that factory work was the privilege of "loyal white citizens." There were few opportunities for white women to earn cash wages in this period, and family farms yielded little cash. The only jobs open to black women--domestic service--paid even less.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vor dem Bürgerkrieg bearbeiteten einige 
versklavte afrikanische Amerikaner in den südlichen 
Textiltausendsteln, besonders in den spinnenden und spinnenden 
Räumen. Aber mit dem Sprung im Preis der Sklaven im 1850s, 
entschieden Hersteller, daß arme weiße Landwirte preiswertere 
Arbeitskräfte zur Verfügung stellten. Nach dem Bürgerkrieg 
blieb die Textiltausendstelmannschaft für eine Anzahl von Gründen 
völlig weiß: Hauswirte wünschten afrikanische Amerikaner in 
der Baumwolle arbeiten auffängt; weiße Führer 
förderten Industrialisierung als die Rettung des schlechten Weiß; 
und die dominierende rassische Ideologie verbot das Mischen der 
weißen Frauen und der schwarzen Männer an dem Arbeitsplatz. 
Obgleich Pflanzer und Hersteller die von hatten einer getrennten
Arbeit Kraft zu gewinnen die meisten,, nahmen weiße Arbeiter -- als 
dieser Protest 1898 von den Frauen von Fulton Atlantas prägt 
angezeigt -- die Idee an, daß Fabrikarbeit war das Privileg "der 
loyalen weißen Bürger." Es gab wenige Gelegenheiten, damit 
weiße Frauen Bargeldlöhne in dieser Periode erwerben, und Familie 
Bauernhöfe erbrachten wenig Bargeld. Die einzigen Jobs öffnen 
zu den schwarzen Frauen -- inländischer Service -- zahlend sogar 
kleiner.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avant la guerre civile, quelques Américains 
africains asservis ont travaillé dans les moulins méridionaux de 
textile, particulièrement dans les salles de rotation et de tissage. 
Mais avec le saut dans le prix des esclaves dans le 1850s, les 
constructeurs ont décidé que les pauvres fermiers blancs ont fourni 
une force de main d'oeuvre à prix réduit. Après la guerre 
civile, la main d'oeuvre de moulin de textile est demeurée 
entièrement blanche pour un certain nombre de raisons : les 
propriétaires ont voulu que les Américains africains travaillassent 
dans des domaines de coton ; les amorces blanches ont favorisé 
l'industrialisation comme salut des blancs pâles ; et 
l'idéologie raciale dominante a interdit le mélange des femmes 
blanches et des hommes noirs dans le lieu de travail. Bien que 
les planteurs et les constructeurs aient eu les la plupart à gagner 
d'une main-d'oeuvre isolée, les ouvriers blancs -- en tant que cette 
protestation 1898 des femmes de Fulton d'Atlanta fraise indiqué -- 
ont reçu l'idée que le travail d'usine était le privilège "des 
citoyens blancs fidèles." Il y avait peu d'occasions pour que 
les femmes blanches gagnent des salaires d'argent comptant dans cette 
période, et les fermes de famille ont rapporté peu d'argent 
comptant. Les seuls travaux ouvrent aux femmes noires -- service
domestique -- payées même moins.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Antes da guerra civil, alguns americanos africanos
enslaved trabalharam em moinhos do sul de textile, especial nos 
quartos girando e tecendo. Mas com o salto no preço dos 
escravos no 1850s, os fabricantes decidiram-se que os fazendeiros 
brancos deficientes forneceram uma força labor mais barata. 
Após a guerra civil, o workforce do moinho de textile 
remanesceu inteiramente branco para um número de razões: os 
landlords quiseram americanos africanos trabalhar em campos do 
algodão; os líderes brancos promoveram o industrialization 
como o salvation de brancos deficientes; e o ideology racial 
dominante proibiu misturar das mulheres brancas e de homens pretos no 
workplace. Embora os plantadores e os fabricantes tivessem o a 
maioria a ganhar de uma força de trabalho segregada, os trabalhadores
brancos -- como este protesto 1898 das mulheres de Fulton de Atlanta 
mói indicado -- aceitaram a idéia que o trabalho da fábrica era o 
privilégio "de cidadãos brancos leais." Havia poucas 
oportunidades para que as mulheres brancas ganhem salários do 
dinheiro neste período, e as fazendas da família renderam pouco 
dinheiro. Os únicos trabalhos abrem às mulheres pretas -- 
serviço doméstico -- pagas mesmo menos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prima della guerra civile, alcuni Americani 
africani asserviti hanno lavorato nei laminatoi del sud della tessile,
particolarmente nelle stanze di filatura e di tessitura. Ma con 
il salto nel prezzo degli schiavi nel 1850s, i fornitori hanno deciso 
che i poveri coltivatori bianchi hanno fornito una forza 
di lavoro più poco costosa. Dopo la guerra civile, la mano 
d'opera del laminatoio della tessile è rimasto interamente bianca per
un certo numero di motivi: i proprietari hanno desiderato gli 
Americani africani lavorare nei campi del cotone; i capi 
bianchi hanno promosso l'industrializzazione come la salvezza di 
poveri bianchi; e l'ideologia razziale dominante ha proibito
alla miscelazione delle donne bianche e degli uomini neri nel posto di
lavoro. Anche se le piantatrici ed i fornitori hanno avuti il la
maggior parte da guadagnare da una forza di lavoro segregata, gli 
operai bianchi -- come questa protesta 1898 dalle donne di Fulton de 
Atlanta macina indicato -- hanno accettato l'idea che il lavoro della 
fabbrica era il privilegio "dei cittadini bianchi leali." Ci 
erano poche occasioni affinchè le donne bianche guadagnino gli 
stipendi dei contanti in questo periodo ed i poderi della famiglia 
hanno reso pochi contanti. Gli unici lavori aprono alle donne 
nere -- servizio domestico -- paid persino di meno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πριν από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο, μερικοί υποδουλωμένοι 
αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί εργάστηκαν στους νότιους υφαντικούς 
μύλους, ειδικά στα περιστρεφόμενα και υφαίνοντας δωμάτια. 
Αλλά με το άλμα στην τιμή των σκλάβων στο 1850s, οι 
κατασκευαστές αποφάσισαν ότι οι φτωχοί λευκοί αγρότες παρείχαν 
ένα φτηνότερο εργατικό δυναμικό. Μετά από τον εμφύλιο 
πόλεμο, το εργατικό δυναμικό υφαντικών μύλων παρέμεινε εξ 
ολοκλήρου λευκό για διάφορους λόγους: οι ιδιοκτήτες 
θέλησαν αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς για να εργαστούν στα πεδία 
βαμβακιού  οι λευκοί ηγέτες προώθησαν την εκβιομηχάνιση ως 
σωτηρία των φτωχών λευκών  και η κυρίαρχη φυλετική 
ιδεολογία απαγόρευσε τη μίξη των λευκών γυναικών και των μαύρων 
ανδρών στον εργασιακό χώρο. Αν και οι καλλιεργητές και οι 
κατασκευαστές είχαν των περισσότερων που κερδίζουν από ένα 
διαχωρισμένο εργατικό δυναμικό, οι λευκοί εργαζόμενοι -- καθώς 
αυτή η διαμαρτυρία 1898 από τις γυναίκες Fulton της 
Ατλάντας αλέθει δειγμένος -- αποδέχθηκαν την ιδέα ότι η εργασία
εργοστασίων ήταν το προνόμιο των "πιστών λευκών πολιτών." 
Υπήρξαν λίγες ευκαιρίες για τις λευκές γυναίκες να 
κερδίσουν τις αμοιβές μετρητών σε αυτήν την περίοδο, και τα 
οικογενειακά αγροκτήματα παρήγαγαν λίγα μετρητά. Οι μόνες 
εργασίες ανοικτές στις μαύρες γυναίκες -- εσωτερική υπηρεσία -- 
που πληρώνεται ακόμα λιγότερο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Antes de la guerra civil, algunos americanos 
africanos esclavizados trabajaron en molinos meridionales del textil, 
especialmente en los cuartos que hacían girar y que tejían. 
Pero con el salto en el precio de esclavos en el 1850s, los 
fabricantes decidían que los granjeros blancos pobres proporcionaron 
a una mano de una obra más barata. Después de la guerra civil,
la mano de obra del molino del textil seguía siendo enteramente 
blanca por un número de razones: los propietarios quisieran que
los americanos africanos trabajaran en campos del algodón; los 
arranques de cinta blancos promovieron la industrialización como la 
salvación de blancos pobres; y la ideología racial dominante 
prohibió mezclarse de las mujeres blancas y de los hombres negros en 
el lugar de trabajo. Aunque los plantadores y los fabricantes 
tenían el la mayoría a ganar de una fuerza de trabajo segregada, los
trabajadores blancos -- como esta protesta 1898 de las mujeres de 
Fulton de Atlanta muele indicado -- validaron la idea que el trabajo 
de la fábrica era el privilegio de "ciudadanos blancos leales." 
Había pocas oportunidades para que las mujeres blancas ganen 
salarios del efectivo en este período, y las granjas de la familia 
rindieron poco efectivo. Los únicos trabajos abren en las 
mujeres negras -- servicio doméstico -- pagadas incluso menos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087278</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108680</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-case-of-black-and-white-white-women-protest-the-hiring-of-black-wage-slaves</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
