<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105511</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105511</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207167</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Freeman School: Building Prairie Communities</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Ehrenbürger-Schule: 
Gebäude-Grasland-Gemeinschaften</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'École de Citoyen d'honneur : Les 
Communautés de Prairie de Bâtiment</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Escola Do Freeman: Comunidades Da Pradaria
Do Edifício</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Scuola Del Freeman: Comunità Del Prairie
Della Costruzione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το σχολείο ελεύθερων πολιτών: Χτίζοντας 
Κοινότητες λιβαδιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Escuela Del Freeman: Comunidades De la 
Pradera Del Edificio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines a once common feature on the American West landscape: the one-room schoolhouse. This particular one-room school, originally known as the Red-Brick School House, served the community of Blakely Township, Nebraska, from 1872 to 1967. When closed, it was the oldest continuously used one-room school in Nebraska. It served not only as a school, but also as a church, meeting hall, polling place, and social and political center of the community.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft ein einmal geläufiges Merkmal auf der
amerikanischen Westlandschaft: das Einraum Schulhaus. 
Diese bestimmte Einraum Schule, ursprünglich bekannt als das 
Rot-Ziegelstein Schule-Haus, die Gemeinschaft von Blakely 
Gemeinde, Nebraska gedient, von 1872 bis 1967. Als 
geschlossen, war es die älteste ununterbrochen benutzte Einraum 
Schule in Nebraska. Es diente nicht nur als Schule, aber auch 
als Kirche und traf Halle, Wahlort und Sozial- und politische 
Mitte der Gemeinschaft.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine un dispositif une fois commun sur 
l'horizontal occidental américain : l'école d'un-pièce. 
Cette école particulière d'un-pièce, initialement connue sous
le nom de Chambre d'école de Rouge-Brique, servie la communauté de 
la banlieue noire de Blakely, Nébraska, de 1872 à 1967. Une 
fois clôturé, c'était l'école sans interruption utilisée 
d'un-pièce la plus ancienne au Nébraska. Il a servi non 
seulement comme école, mais également d'église, rencontrant le 
hall, l'endroit d'interrogation, et le centre social et politique de 
la communauté.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina uma característica uma vez comum na 
paisagem ocidental americana: o schoolhouse do um-quarto. 
Esta escola particular do um-quarto, sabida originalmente como a
casa da escola do Vermelho-Tijolo, servida a comunidade do township de
Blakely, Nebraska,  1872 a 1967. Quando fechado, era a escola 
continuamente usada a mais velha do um-quarto em Nebraska. 
Serviu não somente como uma escola, mas também como uma 
igreja, encontrando-se com o salão, o lugar da votação, e o centro 
social e político da comunidade.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina una caratteristica una volta comune sul 
paesaggio ad ovest americano: la scuola della un-stanza. 
Questa scuola particolare della un-stanza, originalmente 
conosciuta come la Camera della scuola del Rosso-Mattone, servita la 
Comunità della borgata di Blakely, Nebraska, 1872 - 1967. Una 
volta chiuso, era la più vecchia scuola continuamente usata 
della un-stanza nel Nebraska. Ha servito non soltanto come 
scuola, ma anche da chiesa, venente a contatto del corridoio, del 
posto di votazione e del centro sociale e politico della Comunità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει ένα μιά φορά κοινό χαρακτηριστικό γνώρισμα
στο αμερικανικό δυτικό τοπίο: το σχολείο ένας-δωματίων. 
Αυτό το ιδιαίτερο σχολείο ένας-δωματίων, αρχικά γνωστό ως
τούβλινο σχολικό σπίτι, εξυπηρέτησε την κοινότητα Blakely του 
δήμου, Νεμπράσκα, από 1872 έως το 1967. Όταν 
κλείνεται, ήταν το παλαιότερο συνεχώς χρησιμοποιημένο σχολείο 
ένας-δωματίων στη Νεμπράσκα. Εχρησίμευσε όχι μόνο ως 
σχολείο, αλλά και ως μια εκκλησία, συνανμένος αίθουσα, θέση 
ψήφισης, και κοινωνικό και πολιτικό κέντρο της κοινότητας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina una característica una vez común en el 
paisaje del oeste americano: la escuela del uno-cuarto. 
Esta escuela determinada del uno-cuarto, conocida originalmente 
como la casa de la escuela del Rojo-Ladrillo, servida la comunidad del
Municipio de Blakely, Nebraska, a partir la 1872 a 1967. Cuando
estaba cerrado, era la escuela continuamente usada más vieja del 
uno-cuarto de Nebraska. Sirvió no solamente como escuela, pero 
también como iglesia, resolviendo el pasillo, el lugar de la 
interrogación, y el centro social y político de la comunidad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207167</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105511</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-freeman-school-building-prairie-communities</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
