<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107750</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107750</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086294</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Should Be Reimbursed For All This Consciousness-Raising That I Do:" Cynthia Long Describes Conditions for Women Breaking into Skilled Trades</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ich Sollte Für Alles Zurückerstattet werden, 
das Dieses, Das Bewußtsein-Anheben Dieses Ich:" Cynthia, die 
lang ist, beschreibt Bedingungen für die Frauen, die in erfahrenen 
Handel einbrechen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Je Devrais Être remboursé Pour Le Tout Que Ceci
Conscience-Soulèvement Ce Je  :" Cynthia longue décrit des 
conditions pour des femmes pénétrant par effraction dans les 
commerces habiles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Eu Devo Ser reembolsado Para O Todo o Que Isto 
Consciousness-Levantar Esse Eu :" Cynthia longa descreve 
condições para as mulheres que quebram em comércios hábeis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Dovrei Essere rimborsato Per Il Tutto Che Questo 
Coscienza-Alzarsi Quel:" Cynthia lunga descrive i termini per le
donne che si rompono nei nei commerci esperti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πρέπει να επιστραφώ για όλο αυτό το 
consciousness-Raising ότι:" Θ*Θυντχηα Long Describes 
Conditions για τις γυναίκες που σπάζουν στα ειδικευμένα εμπόρια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Debo Ser reembolsado Para Todo el Lo que Esto El 
Sentido-Levantar Ese :" Cynthia larga describe las condiciones 
para las mujeres que se rompen en comercios expertos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">One result of the women's movement of the 1970's was to open non-traditional trade union jobs to small numbers of women brave enough to weather opposition and harassment from male supervisors and co-workers. When she decided to leave the low pay of traditional office work, Cynthia Long sought training as an electrician and became one of the first women to gain access to the electrician's union in New York in 1978. While she experienced pride she also faced hardships, sexual harassment, and feelings of isolation.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Resultat der Bewegung der Frauen der siebziger
Jahre sollte nicht traditionele Gewerkschaftjobs zu eine geringe 
Anzahl Frauen öffnen, die genug, Opposition und Belästigung von den 
männlichen Überwachungsprogrammen und von den Mitarbeitern zu 
verwittern tapfer sind. Als sie entschied, die niedrige 
Bezahlung der traditionellen Büroarbeit zu lassen, Cynthia wurde 
langes gesuchtes Training als Elektriker und eine der ersten Frauen, 
zum zum Anschluß des Elektrikers in New York 1978 Zutritt zu 
erhalten. Während sie Stolz erfuhr, stellte sie auch Härten, 
sexuelle Belästigung und Gefühle der Lokalisierung gegenüber.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un résultat du mouvement des femmes des années 
70 devait ouvrir les travaux non traditionnels de syndicat à un 
nombre restreint de femmes bravent assez pour survivre à
à l'opposition et au harcèlement des superviseurs et des collègues 
mâles. Quand elle a décidé de laisser le bas salaire du 
travail traditionnel de bureau, la longue formation recherchée de 
Cynthia en tant qu'électricien et est devenue l'une des premières 
femmes à accéder à l'union de l'électricien à New York en 1978. 
Tandis qu'elle éprouvait la fierté elle a également fait face
à des difficultés, au harcèlement sexuel, et à des sentiments de 
l'isolement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um resultado do movimento das mulheres dos 1970's 
devia abrir trabalhos non-traditional da união de comércio a um 
pequeno número de mulheres bravas bastante resistir à oposição e 
ao harassment dos supervisores e dos colegas de trabalho masculinos. 
Quando se decidiu deixar o pagamento baixo do trabalho 
tradicional do escritório, o treinamento procurado longo de Cynthia 
como um eletricista e transformou-se uma das primeiras mulheres para 
ganhar o acesso à união do eletricista em New York em 1978. 
Quando experimentou o orgulho enfrentou também hardships, o 
harassment sexual, e os sentimentos da isolação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un risultato del movimento delle donne degli anni 
70 doveva aprire i lavori non tradizionali del sindacato ad un piccolo
numero di donne abbastanza brave esporre all'aria l'opposizione ed il 
harassment dai soprintendenti e dai colleghe maschii. Quando ha 
deciso lasciare la paga bassa del lavoro tradizionale dell'ufficio, 
l'addestramento cercato lungo della Cynthia come elettricista e si è 
transformato in in una delle prime donne da accedere all'unione 
dell'elettricista a New York in 1978. Mentre ha avvertito 
l'orgoglio egualmente ha affrontato le difficoltà, il harassment 
sessuale e le sensibilità di isolamento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα αποτέλεσμα του κινήματος των γυναικών της 
δεκαετίας του '70 ήταν να ανοιχτούν οι μη παραδοσιακές εργασίες 
συνδικάτων στους μικρούς αριθμούς γυναικών αρκετά γενναίων να 
ξεπεράσει την αντίθεση και την παρενόχληση από τους αρσενικούς 
επόπτες και τους συναδέλφους. Όταν αποφάσισε να αφήσει τη 
χαμηλή αμοιβή της παραδοσιακής εργασίας γραφείων, η Cynthia 
Long επιδίωξε την κατάρτιση ως ηλεκτρολόγο και έγινε μια από 
τις πρώτες γυναίκες για να αποκτήσει πρόσβαση στην ένωση του 
ηλεκτρολόγου στη Νέα Υόρκη το 1978. Ενώ δοκίμασε την 
υπερηφάνεια αντιμετώπισε επίσης τις δυσκολίες, τις σεξουαλικές 
παρενοχλήσεις, και τα συναισθήματα της απομόνωσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un resultado del movimiento de las mujeres de los 
años 70 era abrir trabajos no tradicionales del sindicato en una 
pequeña cantidad de mujeres bastante valientes de resistir a la 
oposición y al hostigamiento de los supervisores y de los compañeros
de trabajo masculinos. Cuando ella decidía dejar la paga baja 
del trabajo tradicional de la oficina, el entrenamiento buscado largo 
de Cynthia como electricista y se convirtió en una de las primeras 
mujeres a acceder a la unión del electricista en Nueva York en 1978. 
Mientras que ella experimentó orgullo ella también hizo frente
a dificultades, al hostigamiento sexual, y a sensaciones del 
aislamiento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086294</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107750</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-should-be-reimbursed-for-all-this-consciousness-raising-that-i-do-cynthia-long-describes-conditions-for-women-breaking-into-skilled-trades</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
