<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108140</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108140</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086861</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Such Cases of Outrageous Unspeakable Abuse...": A Puerto Rican Migrant Protests Labor Conditions During World War I</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"solche Fälle unverschämten Unspeakable 
Mißbrauches...": Ein Puerto Rican Wanderer Protestiert 
Arbeitsbedingungen Während Des Ersten Weltkrieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">de "tels cas d'abus Indescriptible indigne..." : 
Un Migrant de Puerto Rican Proteste des Conditions de travail 
Pendant La Première Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"tais casos do abuso outrageous de Unspeakable...":
Um Emigrante De Puerto Rican Protesta Condições Labor Durante 
O World.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"tali casi di abuso outrageous di Unspeakable...": 
Termini Di lavoro Di Proteste Migratori Di Puerto Un Rican 
Durante Il World.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τέτοιες περιπτώσεις της προσβλητικής απερίγραπτης 
κατάχρησης...": Ένας μετανάστης Puerto Rican 
διαμαρτύρεται τους όρους εργασίας κατά τη διάρκεια του 
παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"tales casos del abuso indignante de 
Unspeakable...": Un Nómada De Puerto Rican Protesta Condiciones
De trabajo Durante Primera Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1917 the United States declared the inhabitants of Puerto Rico, a U.S. posession since 1898, to be citizens of the United States--a "gift" that many Puerto Ricans resented. Seeing an untapped source of inexpensive labor, the U.S. Labor Department worked with industry to facilitate the migration of Puerto Rican workers to America. During the First World War the War Department agreed to transport Puerto Rican workers to labor camps in the United States where they would be housed and fed while working on government construction contracts at defense plants and military bases, many of which subjected the new migrants to harsh conditions and even forced labor. Rafael Marchn was one of a group of Puerto Rican workers at Fort Bragg in North Carolina who protested to the commissioner of Puerto Rico over the intolerable conditions in the work camp. He gave this deposition in Washington, D.C., in October 1918.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In 1917 die Vereinigten Staaten erklärt den 
Einwohnern von Puerto Rico, ein VEREINIGTE STAATEN posession seit 
1898, Bürger der Vereinigten Staaten sein -- ein "Geschenk", das viel
Puerto Ricans übelnahm. Eine unangezapfte Quelle der billigen 
Arbeit sehend, arbeitete die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Arbeitsabteilung mit 
Industrie, um das Umsiedeln Puerto Rican Arbeiter nach Amerika zu 
erleichtern. Während des ersten WeltkriegesWAR die 
Krieg-Abteilung damit einverstanden, Puerto Rican Arbeiter zu den 
Arbeitslagern in den Vereinigten Staaten zu transportieren, in denen 
sie beim Arbeiten auf Regierung Aufbauverträgen an den 
Verteidigungbetrieben und an den militärischen Unterseiten 
untergebracht und eingezogen würden, von denen viele die neuen 
Wanderer rauhen Bedingungen unterwarfen und sogar Arbeit erzwangen. 
Rafael Marchn war einer einer Gruppe Puerto Rican Arbeiter am 
Fort Bragg in Nord-Carolina, das zum Beauftragten von Puerto Rico 
über den untragbaren Bedingungen im Arbeit Lager protestierte. 
Er gab diese Absetzung in Washington, Gleichstrom, im Oktober 
1918.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans 1917 les Etats-Unis avoués les habitants un 
posession de Porto Rico, ETATS-UNIS depuis 1898, pour être citoyens 
des Etats-Unis -- un "cadeau" que beaucoup de Puerto Ricans était 
offensé par. Voyant une source inexploitée de travail peu 
coûteux, le service de travail des ETATS-UNIS a travaillé avec 
l'industrie pour faciliter le transfert des ouvriers de Puerto Rican 
en Amérique. Pendant la première guerre mondiale le service de
guerre a accepté de transporter des ouvriers de Puerto Rican aux 
camps de travail aux Etats-Unis où ils seraient logés et alimentés 
tout en travaillant aux contrats de construction de gouvernement aux 
usines de la défense et aux bases militaires, dont beaucoup ont 
soumis les nouveaux migrants aux conditions dures et ont même forcé 
le travail. Rafaël Marchn était un d'un groupe d'ouvriers de 
Puerto Rican au fort Bragg en Caroline du nord qui a protesté au 
commissaire du Porto Rico au-dessus des conditions intolérables dans 
le camp de travail. Il a donné ce dépôt à Washington, C.C, 
en octobre 1918.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1917 os estados unidos declararam os habitantes 
de Puerto Rico, um posession de ESTADOS UNIDOS desde 1898, ser 
cidadãos dos estados unidos -- um "presente" por que muito Puerto 
Ricans se ressentisse. Vendo uma fonte untapped do trabalho 
barato, o departamento labor de ESTADOS UNIDOS trabalhou com 
indústria para facilitar a migração de trabalhadores de Puerto 
Rican a América. Durante a primeira guerra de mundo o 
departamento de guerra concordou transportar trabalhadores de Puerto 
Rican aos acampamentos labor nos estados unidos onde seriam abrigados 
e alimentados ao trabalhar em contratos da construção do governo nas
plantas da defesa e nas bases militares, muitas de que sujeitaram os 
emigrantes novos às circunstâncias ásperas e forçaram mesmo o 
trabalho. Rafael Marchn era um de um grupo de trabalhadores de 
Puerto Rican no fort Bragg em North.carolina que protestou ao 
comissário de Puerto Rico sobre as condições intolerable no 
acampamento do trabalho. Deu este deposition em Washington, 
C.C., em outubro 1918.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1917 uniti Dichiara ha dichiarato gli 
abitanti un posession del Porto Rico, STATI UNITI dal 1898, di essere 
cittadini del unito Dichiara -- il a "regalo" di che molto 
Puerto Ricans si è risentito. Vedendo una sorgente inbattuta 
del lavoro economico, il reparto Di lavoro degli STATI UNITI ha 
funzionato con industria per facilitare l'espansione degli operai di 
Puerto Rican in America. Durante la prima guerra mondiale il 
reparto di guerra accosentito per trasportare gli operai di 
Puerto Rican agli accampamenti di lavoro in unito Dichiara 
dove sarebbero alloggiati ed alimentato stati mentre lavoravano ai 
contratti della costruzione di governo alle piante della difesa ed 
alle basi militari, molti di cui hanno sottoposto i nuovi migranti 
alle circostanze dure e perfino hanno forzato il lavoro. 
Rafael Marchn era uno di un gruppo degli operai di Puerto Rican 
a Bragg Forte in North.carolina che ha protestato al commissario 
del Porto Rico sopra i termini intollerabili nell'accampamento del 
lavoro. Ha dato questo deposito in Washington, DC, nel mese di 
ottobre del 1918.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1917 οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες δήλωσαν τους 
κατοίκους του Πουέρτο Ρίκο, ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ posession από 1898, 
για να είναι πολίτης των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών -- ένα "δώρο" που 
πολύ Puerto Ricans αγανάκτησε με. Βλέποντας μια 
αναξιοποίητη πηγή ανέξοδης εργασίας, το τμήμα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ 
εργασίας συνεργάστηκε με τη βιομηχανία για να διευκολύνει τη 
μετανάστευση των εργαζομένων Puerto Rican στην Αμερική. 
Κατά τη διάρκεια του πρώτου παγκόσμιου πολέμου το πολεμικό
τμήμα συμφώνησε να μεταφέρει τους εργαζομένους Puerto Rican 
στα στρατόπεδα εργασίας στα ενωμένα κράτη όπου θα στεγάζονταν 
και θα ταΐζονταν εργαζόμενος στις συμβάσεις κυβερνητικής 
κατασκευής στις αμυντικές εγκαταστάσεις και τις στρατιωτικές 
βάσεις, πολλές από τις οποίες υπέβαλαν τους νέους μετανάστες 
στους σκληρούς όρους και ανάγκασαν ακόμη και την εργασία. Rafael Marchn ήταν μια από μια ομάδα εργαζομένων Puerto 
Rican στο οχυρό Bragg στη βόρεια Καρολίνα που διαμαρτυρήθηκε
στον Επίτροπο του Πουέρτο Ρίκο πέρα από τους ανυπόφορους όρους 
στο στρατόπεδο εργασίας. Έδωσε αυτήν την απόθεση στην 
Ουάσιγκτον, ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ, τον Οκτώβριο του 1918.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1917 los Estados Unidos declarados los 
habitantes ESTADOS UNIDOS un posession de Puerto Rico, desde 1898, ser
ciudadanos de los Estados Unidos -- un "regalo" que mucho Puerto 
Ricans se resentía. Considerando una fuente sin aprovechar del 
trabajo barato, el departamento de trabajo de ESTADOS UNIDOS trabajó 
con industria para facilitar la migración de los trabajadores de 
Puerto Rican a América. Durante la primera guerra mundial el 
departamento de guerra acordó transportar a trabajadores de Puerto 
Rican a los campos de trabajo en los Estados Unidos en donde los 
contendrían y fueron alimentados mientras que trabajaban en contratos
de la construcción del gobierno en las plantas de la defensa y las 
bases militares, muchas de las cuales sujetaron a nuevos nómadas a 
las condiciones ásperas e incluso forzaron el trabajo. Rafael 
Marchn era uno de un grupo de los trabajadores de Puerto Rican en la 
fortaleza Bragg en Carolina del Norte que protestó a la comisión de 
Puerto Rico sobre las condiciones intolerables en el campo del 
trabajo. Él dio esta deposición en Washington, C.C., en 
octubre de 1918.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086861</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108140</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/such-cases-of-outrageous-unspeakable-abuse-a-puerto-rican-migrant-protests-labor-conditions-during-world-war-i</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
