<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108007</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108007</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086212</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Hard Chewing": Supporting World War I at the Kitchen Table</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Stark Kauend": Unterstützender Erster 
Weltkrieg am Küche-Tisch</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Dur Mâchant" : Première Guerre Mondiale 
supportante à la table de cuisine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Duramente Chewing": World.war.i suportando 
na tabela de cozinha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Duro Masticando": World.war.i di sostegno 
alla Tabella di cucina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Σκληρά μασώντασ": Ενισχυτικός παγκόσμιος 
πόλεμος Ι στον πίνακα κουζινών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Difícilmente Masticando": Primera Guerra 
Mundial que utiliza en el vector de cocina</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Rationing was one way that World War I affected people on the home front. Seeking to manage domestic consumption in order to feed the U.S. Army and to assist Allied armies and civilians., the U.S. Food Administration declared "Food Will Win the War." In this droll reminiscence, Ethel George recalled one kind of home-front conservation effort: the hard work of chewing whole-grain foods. Born in 1903, George told her story to John Terreo, who interviewed her for the New Deal Oral History Project of the Montana Historical Society.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Rationieren war Einweg, daß der Erste 
Weltkrieg Leute auf der Hauptfrontseite beeinflußte. Suchend, 
Inlandsverbrauch zu handhaben, um die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Armee 
einzuziehen und verbündete Armeen und Zivilisten zu unterstützen, 
gewinnt die VEREINIGTE STAATEN Nahrungsmittelleitung erklärte 
"Nahrung den Krieg." In dieser droll Erinnerung erinnerte an 
Ethel George eine Art Haus-vordere Erhaltung Bemühung: die 
harte Arbeit des Kauens der Vollkornnahrungsmittel. Getragen 
1903, erklärte George John Terreo ihre Geschichte, der sie für das 
neues Abkommen-Mundgeschichte Projekt der Montana historischen 
Gesellschaft interviewte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le rationnement était à sens unique que la 
Première Guerre Mondiale ait affecté des personnes sur l'avant à la
maison. Recherchant à parvenir la consommation domestique afin 
d'alimenter l'armée des ETATS-UNIS et aider les armées et les civils
alliés, nourriture avouée par gestion de nourriture des ETATS-UNIS 
la "gagnera la guerre." Dans cette réminiscence drôle, Ethel 
George a rappelé un genre d'effort maison-avant d'économie : 
le travail dur de mâcher les nourritures entières. 
Soutenu en 1903, George a indiqué son histoire à John 
Terreo, qui l'a interviewée pour le projet oral d'histoire de 
nouvelle affaire de la société historique du Montana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Racionar era de sentido único que o world.war.i 
afetou povos na parte dianteira home. Procurando controlar o 
consumo doméstico a fim alimentar o exército de ESTADOS UNIDOS e 
ajudar a exércitos e a civis aliados, alimento declarado 
administração do alimento de ESTADOS UNIDOS o "ganhará a guerra." 
Neste reminiscence droll, Ethel George recordou um tipo do 
esforço HOME-DIANTEIRO do conservation: o trabalho duro de 
chewing os alimentos whole-grain. Carregado em 1903, George 
disse sua história a John Terreo, que a entrevistou para o projeto 
oral do history do negócio novo da sociedade histórica de Montana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il razionamento era unidirezionale che il 
world.war.i ha interessato la gente sulla parte anteriore domestica. 
Cercando di riuscire il consumo domestico per alimentare 
l'esercito degli STATI UNITI ed aiutare gli eserciti ed i civili 
alleati, l'alimento dichiarato gestione dell'alimento degli STATI 
UNITI "vincerà la guerra." In questa reminiscenza droll, Ethel 
George ha ricordato un genere di sforzo sede-anteriore di 
conservazione: il lavoro duro di masticare gli alimenti interi. 
Sopportato in 1903, George ha detto alla sua storia a John 
Terreo, che la ha intervistata per il progetto orale di storia di 
nuovo affare della società storica del Montana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η διανομή με δελτίο ήταν ένας τρόπος ότι παγκόσμιος
πόλεμος που είχα επιπτώσεις στους ανθρώπους στο βασικό μέτωπο. 
Η επιδίωξη να κατορθωθεί η εγχώρια κατανάλωση προκειμένου 
να ταϊστεί ο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΣ στρατός και για να βοηθήσει σύνδεσε 
τους στρατούς και οι πολίτες, τα δηλωμένα "διοίκηση τρόφιμα 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ τροφίμων θα κερδίσουν τον πόλεμο." Σε αυτό το 
κωμικό reminiscence, Ethel George υπενθύμισε ένα είδος 
σπίτι-μπροστινής προσπάθειας συντήρησης: η σκληρή εργασία 
του μασήματος των whole-grain τροφίμων. Γεννημένος το 
1903, George είπε την ιστορία της σε John Terreo, ο 
οποίος την πήρε συνέντευξη από για το νέο πρόγραμμα ιστορίας 
διαπραγμάτευσης προφορικό της ιστορικής κοινωνίας της Μοντάνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El racionar era unidireccional que la Primera 
Guerra Mundial afectó a gente en el frente casero. Intentando 
manejar la consumición doméstica para alimentar al ejército de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS y asistir a los ejércitos y a los civiles aliados, 
alimento declarado administración del alimento de ESTADOS UNIDOS el 
"ganará la guerra." En esta reminiscencia droll, Ethel George 
recordó una clase de esfuerzo hogar-delantero de la conservación: 
el trabajo duro de masticar los alimentos integrales. 
Llevado en 1903, George contó su historia a Juan Terreo, que se
entrevistó con la para el proyecto oral de la historia del nuevo 
reparto de la sociedad histórica de Montana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086212</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108007</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/hard-chewing-supporting-world-war-i-at-the-kitchen-table</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
