<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108463</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108463</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087476</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Cavalry charge at Fairfax court house, May 31, 1861."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Kavallerie laden am Fairfax Gerichtsgebäude, Mai
31, 1861." auf</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">la "cavalerie chargent à la maison de cour de 
Fairfax, 31 mai 1861."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">a "cavalaria carrega na casa de corte de Fairfax, 
maio 31, 1861."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il cavalry si carica alla casa di corte di 
Fairfax, maggio 31, 1861."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δαπάνη ιππικού στο σπίτι δικαστηρίων Fairfax, 
Μάιος 31, 1861."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">la "caballería carga en el Palacio de Justicia de
Fairfax, 31 de mayo de 1861."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Americans were not prepared for the ravages of modern warfare. Early in the war, artists often drew highly romantic and very inaccurate pictures. Soldiers in the field viewed such feats as firing from the saddle with great amusement; they enjoyed seeing illustrations of their exploits almost as much as they enjoyed criticizing their inaccuracies. As the war continued and the carnage mounted, increasingly realistic battlefield sketches conveyed the horrors of war to the northern public.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerikaner wurden nicht für die ravages der modernen 
Kriegsführung vorbereitet. Früh im Krieg, zeichneten Künstler
häufig die in hohem Grade romantischen und sehr ungenauen 
Abbildungen. Soldaten in auffangene sahen solche 
Meisterstücke wie Zündung vom Sattel mit großer Unterhaltung an; 
sie genossen, Abbildungen ihrer Großtaten fast zu sehen soviel 
wie, sie genossen, ihre Ungenauigkeiten zu kritisieren. Während
der Krieg und das eingehangene Massaker fortfuhr, übermittelten in 
zunehmendem Maße realistische Schlachtfeld Skizzen die Grausigkeiten 
des Krieges zur Nordöffentlichkeit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des Américains n'ont pas été disposés pour les 
ravages de la guerre moderne. Tôt dans la guerre, les 
artistes ont souvent dessiné les images fortement romantiques et 
très imprécises. Les soldats dans le domaine ont visualisé 
des exploits tels que la mise à feu de la selle avec le grand 
amusement ; ils ont eu plaisir à voir des illustrations de 
leurs exploits presque autant qu'ils ont eu plaisir à critiquer leurs
inexactitudes. Pendant que la guerre continuait et le carnage 
monté, les croquis de plus en plus réalistes de champ de bataille 
ont donné les horreurs de la guerre au public nordique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os americanos não foram preparados para os ravages da 
guerra moderna. Cedo na guerra, os artistas desenharam 
frequentemente retratos altamente românticos e muito inaccurate. 
Os soldados no campo viram feats como o despedimento da sela com
divertimento grande; apreciaram ver ilustrações de suas 
façanhas quase tanto quanto apreciaram criticar seus inaccuracies. 
Enquanto a guerra continuou e o massacre montado, os esboços 
cada vez mais realísticos do campo de batalha fizeram saber aos 
horrors da guerra ao público do norte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli Americani non sono stati preparati per devasta
di guerra moderna. Presto nella guerra, gli artisti hanno 
dissipato spesso le immagini altamente romantiche e molto inesatte. 
I soldati nel campo hanno osservato tali abilità come 
l'infornamento dalla sella con divertimento grande; hanno goduto
vedere le illustrazioni delle loro imprese quasi tanto come hanno 
goduto criticare le loro inesattezze. Mentre la guerra è 
continuato e la carneficina montata, gli abbozzi sempre più 
realistichi del campo di battaglia hanno trasportato gli orrori della 
guerra al pubblico nordico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αμερικανοί δεν προετοιμάστηκαν για τις καταστροφές της 
σύγχρονης εχθροπραξίας. Νωρίς στον πόλεμο, οι καλλιτέχνες 
έσυραν συχνά τις ιδιαίτερα ρομαντικές και πολύ ανακριβείς 
εικόνες. Οι στρατιώτες στο πεδίο εμφάνισαν τέτοιους άθλους
όπως την πυρκαγιά από τη σέλα με τη μεγάλη διασκέδαση  
απόλαυσαν τις απεικονίσεις των άθλων τους σχεδόν όσο 
απόλαυσαν τις ανακρίβειές τους. Δεδομένου ότι ο πόλεμος 
συνεχίστηκε και η σφαγή που επικολλήθηκε, τα όλο και περισσότερο 
ρεαλιστικά σκίτσα πεδίων μαχών μεταβίβασαν τις φρίκες του 
πολέμου στο βόρειο κοινό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los americanos no fueron preparados para los ravages de la
guerra moderna. Temprano en la guerra, los artistas trazaron a 
menudo cuadros altamente románticos y muy inexactos. Los 
soldados en el campo vieron las hazañas tales como la despedida de la
montura con la gran diversión; gozaron el ver de las 
ilustraciones de sus hazañas casi tanto como gozaron el criticar de 
sus inexactitudes. A medida que la guerra continuó y la 
carnicería montada, los bosquejos cada vez más realistas del campo 
de batalla transportaron los horrores de la guerra al público 
norteño.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087476</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108463</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/cavalry-charge-at-fairfax-court-house-may-31-1861</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
