<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106992</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106992</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206729</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Siege of Port Hudson: Forty Days and Nights in the Wilderness of Death</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Belagerung von Porthudson: Vierzig Tage 
und Nächte in der Wildnis des Todes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le siège de Hudson gauche : Quarante jours 
et nuits dans le désert de la mort</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O siege de Hudson portuário: Quarenta dias 
e noites na região selvagem da morte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il siege di Hudson port: Quaranta giorni e 
notti nella selva della morte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πολιορκία του λιμένα Hudson: Σαράντα ημέρες
και νύχτες στην αγριότητα του θανάτου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El sitio de Hudson portuario: Cuarenta días
y noches en el yermo de la muerte</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">describes the struggle for control of the vital Mississippi River during the Civil War. It discusses the tactics, theories, and ramifications of this battle between the North and the South. The site features maps, firsthand accounts, and photographs, as well as lessons and activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">beschreibt den Kampf zur Steuerung des 
lebenswichtigen Mississippi Flusses während des Bürgerkrieges. 
Er behandelt die Taktiken, die Theorien und die Verzweigungen 
dieser Schlacht zwischen dem Norden und dem Süden. Die 
Situationsmerkmalkarten, aus erster Hand bezogene Konten und 
Fotographien, sowie Lektionen und Aktivitäten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">décrit la lutte pour la commande du fleuve 
essentiel du Mississippi pendant la guerre civile. Elle discute 
la tactique, les théories, et les ramifications de cette bataille 
entre le nord et les Sud. Les cartes de 
dispositifs de site, comptes de première main, et photographies, 
aussi bien que des leçons et des activités.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">descreve o esforço para o controle do rio vital 
de Mississippi durante a guerra civil. Discute as táticas, as 
teorias, e os ramifications desta batalha entre o norte e o sul. 
Os mapas das características de local, clientes firsthand, e 
fotografias, as.well.as lições e atividades.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">descrive la lotta per controllo del fiume vitale 
del Mississippi durante la guerra civile. Discute le tattiche, 
le teorie e le ramificazioni di questa battaglia fra il nord ed il 
sud. I programmi delle caratteristiche di luogo, clienti di 
prima mano e fotografie, così come le lezioni e le attività.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιγράφει την προσπάθεια για τον έλεγχο του ζωτικής 
σημασίας ποταμού του Μισισιπή κατά τη διάρκεια του εμφύλιου 
πολέμου. Συζητά την τακτική, τις θεωρίες, και τις 
διακλαδώσεις αυτής της μάχης μεταξύ του Βορρά και του νότου. 
Η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τους χάρτες, τους από πρώτο χέρι 
απολογισμούς, και τις φωτογραφίες, καθώς επίσης και τα μαθήματα 
και τις δραστηριότητες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">describe la lucha para el control del río vital 
de Mississippi durante la guerra civil. Discute las táctica, 
las teorías, y las ramificaciones de esta batalla entre el norte y el
sur. Las correspondencias de las características de sitio, 
cuentas de primera mano, y fotografías, así como lecciones y 
actividades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206729</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106992</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-siege-of-port-hudson-forty-days-and-nights-in-the-wilderness-of-death</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
