<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105602</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105602</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202942</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Geometry Formulas and Facts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geometrie-Formeln und Tatsachen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Formules et faits de la géométrie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fórmulas e fatos da geometria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Formule e fatti della geometria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τύποι και γεγονότα γεωμετρίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fórmulas y hechos de la geometría</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This excerpt from the CRC Standard Mathematical Tables and Formulas covers geometry, excluding differential geometry. It is a reference for advanced students, and covers the material in quick, condensed sections of notes. Notes and diagrams are organized into sections and subsections, starting with coordinate systems, plane transformations, lines, and polygons in two-dimensional geometry. The section on three-dimensional geometry covers coordinate systems in space, space symmetries, directions, polyhedra, spheres, and quadrics. This resource is part of the Teaching Quantitative Skills in the Geosciences collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Excerpt von den zyklische Blockprüfung 
mathematischen Tabellen und Formelstandardabdeckungen Geometrie, 
ausschließlich der differentialen Geometrie. Es ist eine 
Referenz für hochentwickelte Kursteilnehmer und umfaßt das Material 
innen schnell, verkürzte Kapitel der Anmerkungen. Anmerkungen 
und Diagramme werden in Kapitel und Unterabschnitte, beginnend mit 
beigeordneten Systemen, flache Transformationen, Zeilen und Polygone 
in der zweidimensionalen Geometrie organisiert. Das Kapitel auf 
dreidimensionaler Geometrie umfaßt beigeordnete Systeme im Platz, in 
den Platzsymmetrie, in den Richtungen, in den Polyedern, in den 
Bereichen und in den Funktionen zweiter Ordnung. Dieses 
Hilfsmittel ist ein Teil der Unterricht quantitativen Fähigkeiten in 
der Geosciences Ansammlung http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet extrait la géométrie de CRC de Tableaux et 
de formules de couvertures mathématiques standard, à l'exclusion de 
la géométrie différentielle. C'est une référence pour les 
étudiants avançés, et couvre le matériel dedans vite, les sections
condensées des notes. Des notes et les diagrammes sont 
organisés en sections et sous-sections, commençant par les systèmes
du même rang, transformations plates, lignes, et polygones dans la 
géométrie bidimensionnelle. La section sur la géométrie 
tridimensionnelle couvre les systèmes du même rang dans l'espace, 
des symétries de l'espace, des directions, des polyèdres, des 
sphères, et des quadriques. Cette ressource fait partie des 
qualifications quantitatives d'enseignement dans la collection 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este excerpt geometria das tampas matemáticas 
padrão das tabelas e das fórmulas do CRC, excluding a geometria 
diferencial. É uma referência para estudantes avançados, e 
cobre o material dentro rapidamente, seções condensadas das notas. 
As notas e os diagramas são organizados nas seções e nas 
subseções, começando com sistemas coordenados, transformações 
planas, linhas, e polygons na geometria bidimensional. A seção
na geometria tridimensional cobre sistemas coordenados no espaço, nas
simetrias do espaço, nos sentidos, nos polyhedra, nas esferas, e nas 
quádrico. Este recurso é parte das habilidades quantitative do
ensino na coleção http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de 
Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo brano la geometria di CRC dalle coperture 
matematiche standard delle Tabelle e di formule, a parte la geometria 
differenziale. È un riferimento per gli allievi avanzati e 
riguarda il materiale dentro rapidamente, sezioni condensate delle 
note. Le note e gli schemi sono organizzati nelle sezioni e 
sottosezioni, cominciando dai sistemi coordinati, trasformazioni 
piane, righe e poligoni nella geometria bidimensionale. La 
sezione sulla geometria tridimensionale riguarda i sistemi coordinati 
nello spazio, nelle simmetria dello spazio, nei sensi, nei poliedri, 
in sfere e nelle quadriche. Questa risorsa fa parte delle 
abilità quantitative di insegnamento nell'accumulazione 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ di Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το απόσπασμα από τους πρότυπους μαθηματικούς 
πίνακες και τους τύπους κέντρου ανίχνευσης και ελέγχου καλύπτει 
τη γεωμετρία, αποκλείοντας τη διαφορική γεωμετρία. Είναι 
μια αναφορά για τους προηγμένους σπουδαστές, και καλύπτει το 
υλικό στα γρήγορα, συμπυκνωμένα τμήματα των σημειώσεων. Οι 
σημειώσεις και τα διαγράμματα οργανώνονται στα τμήματα και τις 
υποενότητες, αρχίζοντας από τα ισότιμα συστήματα, τους 
μετασχηματισμούς αεροπλάνων, τις γραμμές, και τα πολύγωνα στη 
δισδιάστατη γεωμετρία. Το τμήμα τρισδιάστατων καλύψεων 
γεωμετρίας συντονίζει τα συστήματα στις διαστημικές, διαστημικές 
συμμετρίες, τις κατευθύνσεις, polyhedra, τις σφαίρες, και 
quadrics. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι μέρος των 
ποσοτικών δεξιοτήτων διδασκαλίας στη Geosciences συλλογή 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este extracto geometría del CRC de las cubiertas 
matemáticas estándares de los vectores y de los fórmulas, excepto 
geometría diferenciada. Es una referencia para los estudiantes 
avanzados, y cubre el material adentro aprisa, las secciones 
condensadas de notas. Las notas y los diagramas se ordenan en 
secciones y las subdivisiones, comenzando con sistemas coordinados, 
las transformaciones planas, las líneas, y los polígonos en 
geometría de dos dimensiones. La sección en geometría 
tridimensional cubre sistemas coordinados en espacio, simetrías del 
espacio, direcciones, poliedros, esferas, y cuadricas. Este 
recurso es parte de las habilidades cuantitativas de la enseñanza en 
la colección http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SILVIO LEVY
FN:SILVIO LEVY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202942</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105602</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/geometry-formulas-and-facts</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
