<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102858</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102858</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205913</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Vergil Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Vergil Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Projet de Vergil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Projeto De Vergil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Progetto Vergil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρόγραμμα Vergil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Proyecto De Vergil</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is dedicated to collecting, creating, and disseminating resources for teaching and research about Vergil. Its main goal is to develop an online, interactive hypertext database of all materials that might be of interest to any student of Vergil, from the novice to the professional scholar, from the passionate amateur to the casual browser.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">wird dem Sammeln, dem Erstellen und der Verbreitung
der Betriebsmittel für das Unterrichten und Forschung über Vergil 
eingesetzt. Sein Hauptziel ist, eine Online-, interaktive 
Hypertextdatenbank aller Materialien zu entwickeln, die vom Interesse 
zu jedem möglichem Kursteilnehmer Vergil, vom Anfänger zum 
professionellen Gelehrten, vom leidenschaftlichen Bewunderer zur 
beiläufigen Datenbanksuchroutine sein konnten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est consacré à rassembler, à créer, et à 
diffuser des ressources pour l'enseignement et la recherche au sujet 
de Vergil. Son but principal est de développer une base de 
données en ligne et interactive d'hypertexte de tous les matériaux 
qui pourraient être d'intérêt à n'importe quel étudiant de 
Vergil, du débutant au disciple professionnel, de l'amateur 
passionné au navigateur occasionnel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é dedicado a coletar, a criar, e a disseminating 
recursos para ensinar e pesquisa sobre Vergil. Seu objetivo 
principal é desenvolver uma base de dados em linha, interativa do 
hypertext de todos os materiais que puderam ser do interesse a todo o 
estudante de Vergil, do novice ao scholar profissional, do amador 
passionate ao browser ocasional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è dedicato alla raccolta, alla creazione ed a 
diffondere delle risorse per l'istruzione e la ricerca circa Vergil. 
Il relativo obiettivo principale è di elaborare una base di 
dati in linea e interattiva di hypertext di tutti i materiali che 
potrebbero essere di interesse a tutto l'allievo di Vergil, dal 
debuttante all'erudito professionale, dal dilettante appassionato al 
browser casuale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αφιερώνεται στη συλλογή, τη δημιουργία, και τη διάδοση
των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς για τη διδασκαλία και την έρευνα για 
Vergil. Ο βασικός στόχος του είναι να αναπτύξει μια σε 
απευθείας σύνδεση, διαλογική βάση δεδομένων υπερκειμένων όλων 
των υλικών που να είναι ενδιαφέρον ενδιαφέρον σε οποιοδήποτε 
σπουδαστή Vergil, από τον αρχάριο στον επαγγελματικό μελετητή,
από τον εμπαθή ερασιτέχνη στον περιστασιακό ξεφυλλιστή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">se dedica a recoger, a crear, y a diseminar los 
recursos para enseñar y la investigación sobre Vergil. Su meta
principal es desarrollar una base de datos en línea, interactiva del 
hypertext de todos los materiales que pudieron estar de interés a 
cualquier estudiante de Vergil, del principiante al erudito 
profesional, del aficionado apasionado al browser ocasional.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205913</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102858</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-vergil-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
