<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108498</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108498</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087392</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"An Iron Furnace of Affliction": Abigail Abbot Bailey Endures the Abuse of her Husband, New Hampshire, 1790-1791</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein Eisen-Ofen des Kummers": Abigail Abt 
Bailey hält den Mißbrauch ihres Ehemanns, New-Hampshire, 1790-1791 
aus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un four de fer d'affliction" : L'abbé 
Bailey d'Abigail supporte l'abus de son mari, New Hampshire, 
1790-1791</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"uma fornalha do ferro do affliction": O 
abade Bailey de Abigail resiste o abuso de seu marido, New Hampshire, 
1790-1791</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"una fornace del ferro dell'afflizione": 
L'abbot Bailey di Abigail resiste all'abuso del suo marito, New 
Hampshire, 1790-1791</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένας φούρνος σιδήρου της κατάθλιψησ": Θ*Αψηγαηλ
Abbot Bailey Endures η κακοποίηση του συζύγου της, Νιού 
Χάμσαιρ, 1790-1791</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un horno del hierro de la aflicción": El 
abad Bailey de Abigail aguanta el abuso de su marido, New Hampshire, 
1790-1791</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During their 26 years of marriage, New Englanders Abigail Abbot and Asa Bailey lived on farms in Haverhill and Landaff, New Hampshire, and had 14 children. In 1770, Asa conducted an affair with one of the farm's hired women. Three years later, a second farm servant accused him of rape. Asa also beat his wife. In the eighteenth century, the social and economic consequences of divorce for women were grave, and Abigail chose to remain with her husband. But in late 1788, Asa perpetrated an act of incest on their 17-year-old daughter, a crime his wife could not forgive. Abigail sent him away, endured his return on several occasions, and finally divorced him in 1793. As the marriage unraveled, a religious revival unfolded in the region around her New Hampshire town. Influenced by the revival, Abigail's memoir, from which this selection is drawn, is as much a record of her relationship with God as it is a story of her trials with her husband.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während ihrer 26 Jahre der Verbindung, lebten neue
Engländer Abigail Abt und ASA Bailey auf Bauernhöfen in Haverhill 
und in Landaff, New-Hampshire und hatten 14 Kinder. 1770 leitete
ASA eine Angelegenheit mit einer der angestellten Frauen des 
Bauernhofes. Drei Jahre später, beschuldigte ein zweiter 
Bauernhofbediensteter ihn vom Raub. ASA schlug auch seine Frau. 
Im achtzehnten Jahrhundert waren die Sozial- und ökonomischen 
Konsequenzen der Scheidung für Frauen ernst, und Abigail beschloß, 
mit ihrem Ehemann zu bleiben. Aber spätem 1788, verübte ASA 
eine Tat des Inzests auf ihrer Tochter 17-year-old, ein Verbrechen, 
das seine Frau nicht verzeihen könnte. Abigail sendete ihn weg,
hielt seine Rückkehr bei einigen Gelegenheiten aus und schied ihn 
schließlich 1793. Während die Verbindung entwirrte, 
britt eine fromme Wiederbelebung in der Region um ihre New-Hampshire 
Stadt aus. Beeinflußt durch die Wiederbelebung, ist Abhandlung 
Abigails, von der diese Auswahl gezeichnet wird, so viel ein Satz 
ihres Verhältnisses zum Gott, wie es eine Geschichte ihrer Versuche 
mit ihrem Ehemann ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant leurs 26 années de mariage, l'abbé et 
l'asa Bailey d'Abigail de nouveaux Anglais ont vécu aux fermes dans 
Haverhill et Landaff, New Hampshire, et ont eu 14 enfants. En 
1770, l'asa a conduit une affaire avec une des femmes louées de la 
ferme. Trois ans après, un deuxième domestique de ferme 
l'accuse du viol. L'asa a également battu son épouse. Au
dix-huitième siècle, les conséquences sociales et économiques du 
divorce pour des femmes étaient graves, et Abigail a choisi de rester
avec son mari. Mais vers la fin de 1788, l'asa a commis un acte 
d'inceste sur leur fille 17-year-old, un crime que son épouse ne 
pourrait pas pardonner. Abigail l'a envoyé loin, a supporté 
son retour à plusieurs occasions, et l'a finalement divorcé en 1793.
Pendant que le mariage se démêlait, une renaissance 
religieuse a dévoilé dans la région autour de sa ville du New 
Hampshire. Influencé par la renaissance, le mémoire d'Abigail,
dont cette sélection est tirée, est autant un enregistrement de son 
rapport avec Dieu que c'est une histoire de ses épreuves avec son 
mari.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante seus 26 anos da união, o abade de Abigail 
dos englanders novos e o Asa Bailey viveram em fazendas em Haverhill e
em Landaff, New Hampshire, e tiveram 14 crianças. Em 1770, o 
Asa conduziu um caso com uma das mulheres empregadas da fazenda. 
Três anos mais tarde, um segundo empregado da fazenda acusa-o 
da violação. O Asa bateu também sua esposa. No décimo 
oitavo século, as conseqüências sociais e econômicas do divórcio 
para mulheres eram graves, e Abigail escolheu remanescer com seu 
marido. Mas em 1788 atrasado, o Asa perpetrated um ato do incest
em sua filha 17-year-old, um crime que sua esposa não poderia 
perdoar. Abigail emitiu-o afastado, resistiu-o seu retorno em 
diversas ocasiões, e divorciou-o finalmente em 1793. Enquanto a
união unraveled, um revival religioso unfolded na região em torno de
sua cidade de New Hampshire. Influenciado pelo revival, o memoir
de Abigail, de que esta seleção é desenhada, é tanto quanto um 
registro de seu relacionamento com deus como é uma história de suas 
experimentações com seu marido.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante i loro 26 anni dell'unione, l'abbot di 
Abigail dei nuovi englanders e l'asa Bailey hanno vissuto sui poderi 
in Haverhill ed in Landaff, New Hampshire ed hanno avuti 14 bambini. 
In 1770, l'asa ha condotto un affare con una delle donne assunte
dell'azienda agricola. Tre anni più successivamente, un secondo
servo dell'azienda agricola lo accusa della violenza. L'asa 
egualmente ha battuto la sua moglie. Nel diciottesimo secolo, le
conseguenze sociali ed economiche del divorzio per le donne erano 
gravi ed Abigail ha scelto rimanere con il suo marito. Ma verso 
la fine del 1788, l'asa perpetrated un atto del incest sulla loro 
figlia 17-year-old, un crimine che la sua moglie non potrebbe 
perdonare. Abigail lo ha trasmesso via, ha resistito al suo 
ritorno in parecchie occasioni ed infine lo ha divorziato in 1793. 
Mentre l'unione unraveled, una rinascita religiosa ha spiegato 
nella regione intorno alla sua città del New Hampshire. 
Influenzato dalla rinascita, la memoria del Abigail, da cui 
questa selezione è dissipata, è tanto un record del suo rapporto con
il dio come è una storia delle sue prove con il suo marito.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια 26 ετών γάμου τους, νέο 
Englanders Abigail Abbot και το ASA Bailey έζησαν στα 
αγροκτήματα σε Haverhill και Landaff, Νιού Χάμσαιρ, και 
είχαν 14 παιδιά. Το 1770, το ASA διεύθυνε μια 
υπόθεση με μια από τις αγροτικές μισθωμένες γυναίκες. Τρία
έτη αργότερα, ένας δεύτερος αγροτικός υπάλληλος τον κατηγόρησε 
για το βιασμό. Το ASA κτύπησε επίσης τη σύζυγό του. 
Στο δέκατο όγδοο αιώνα, οι κοινωνικές και οικονομικές 
συνέπειες του διαζυγίου για τις γυναίκες ήταν σοβαρές, και η 
Abigail επέλεξε να παραμείνει με το σύζυγό της. Αλλά σε 
πρόσφατα 1788, το ASA διέπραξε μια πράξη της αιμομιξίας στην
17-χρονών κόρη τους, ένα έγκλημα η σύζυγός που του δεν 
θα μπορούσε να συγχωρήσει. Η Abigail τον έστειλε μακριά, 
υπόμεινε την επιστροφή του σε διάφορες περιπτώσεις, και τον 
χώρισε τελικά το 1793. Σαν γάμο που διευκρινίστηκε, μια 
θρησκευτική αναγέννηση ξετύλιξε στην περιοχή γύρω από την πόλη 
του Νιού Χάμσαιρ της. Επηρεασμένα από την αναγέννηση, τα 
απομνημονεύματα της Abigail, από τα οποία αυτή η επιλογή 
προέρχεται, είναι τόσο πολύ ένα αρχείο της σχέσης της με το 
Θεό όπως είναι μια ιστορία των δοκιμών της με το σύζυγό της.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante sus 26 años de la unión, el abad y el Asa
Bailey de Abigail de los nuevos ingleses vivieron en granjas en 
Haverhill y Landaff, New Hampshire, y tenían 14 niños. En 
1770, el Asa condujo un asunto con una de las mujeres empleadas de la 
granja. Tres años más adelante, un segundo criado de la granja
lo acusa de la violación. El Asa también batió a su esposa. 
En el décimo octavo siglo, las consecuencias sociales y 
económicas del divorcio para las mujeres eran graves, y Abigail 
eligió permanecer con su marido. Pero en finales de 1788, Asa 
perpetrado un acto del incesto en su hija 17-year-old, un crimen
que su esposa no podría perdonar. Abigail lo envió lejos, 
aguantó su vuelta en varias ocasiones, y finalmente lo divorció en 
1793. Mientras que la unión desenredó, un renacimiento 
religioso reveló en la región alrededor de su ciudad de New 
Hampshire. Influenciado por el renacimiento, la memoria de 
Abigail, de la cual se traza esta selección, es tanto un expediente 
de su lazo con el dios como es una historia de sus ensayos con su 
marido.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087392</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108498</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/an-iron-furnace-of-affliction-abigail-abbot-bailey-endures-the-abuse-of-her-husband-new-hampshire-1790-1791</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
