<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103691</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103691</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201376</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Observatory: Data and Images</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Sternwarte: Daten und Bilder</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Observatoire de la Terre : Données et 
images</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Obervatório Da Terra: Dados e imagens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Osservatorio Della Terra: Dati ed immagini</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γήινο παρατηρητήριο: Στοιχεία και εικόνες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Observatorio De la Tierra: Datos e 
imágenes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Earth Observatory site contains data and images from NASA's Earth Observatory project. The purpose of NASA's Earth Observatory is to provide an accessible publication on the Internet where the public can obtain new satellite imagery and scientific information about our home planet. The focus is on Earth's climate and environmental change. The site is useful to public media and educators. Data and images can be obtained for a variety of subjects, the Earth's atmosphere, land, life on earth, oceans and heat and energy. Users can enter data on a variety of topics and produce animations depicting the data entered. The site also contains a helpful section explaining how to build animations and globe animations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Masse Sternwarte Site enthält Daten und 
Bilder vom Projekt Sternwarte Masse der NASAS. Der Zweck der 
Sternwarte Masse der NASAS ist, eine zugängliche Publikation auf dem 
Internet zur Verfügung zu stellen, in dem die Öffentlichkeit neue 
Satellitenbilder und Fachinformation über unseren Hauptplaneten 
einholen kann. Der Fokus ist auf Klima und Klimaänderung der 
Masse. Die Site ist allgemeine Media und Erzieher nützlich. 
Daten und Bilder können für eine Vielzahl der Themen, der 
Atmosphäre der Masse, des Landes, des Lebens auf Masse erhalten 
werden, der Ozeane und der Hitze und der Energie. Benutzer 
können Daten bezüglich einer Vielzahl von Themen eingeben und die 
Animationen produzieren, welche die eingegebenen Daten bildlich 
darstellen. Die Site enthält auch ein nützliches Kapitel, das 
wie man Animationen und Kugelanimationen beschreibt, aufbaut.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site d'observatoire de la terre contient des 
données et des images du projet d'observatoire de la terre de la 
NASA. Le but de l'observatoire de la terre de la NASA est de 
fournir une publication accessible sur l'Internet où le public peut 
obtenir le nouveau langage figuré satellite et l'information 
scientifique au sujet de notre planète à la maison. Le foyer 
est sur le climat et le changement environnemental de la terre. 
Le site est utile aux medias publics et aux éducateurs. 
Des données et les images peuvent être obtenues pour une 
variété de sujets, l'atmosphère de la terre, terre, vie sur terre, 
océans et chaleur et énergie. Les utilisateurs peuvent saisir 
des données sur une variété de sujets et produire des animations 
dépeignant les données saisies. Le site contient également 
une section utile expliquant comment établir des animations et des 
animations de globe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local do obervatório da terra contem dados e
imagens do projeto do obervatório da terra da NASA. A 
finalidade do obervatório da terra da NASA é fornecer uma 
publicação acessível no Internet onde o público pode obter o 
imagery satellite novo e a informação científica sobre nosso 
planeta home. O foco está no clima e na mudança ambiental da 
terra. O local é útil aos media públicos e aos educadores. 
Os dados e as imagens podem ser obtidos para uma variedade dos 
assuntos, a atmosfera da terra, terra, vida na terra, oceanos e calor 
e energia. Os usuários podem incorporar dados em uma variedade 
dos tópicos e produzir os animations que descrevem os dados 
incorporados. O local contem também uma seção útil que 
explica como construir animations e animations do globo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo dell'osservatorio della terra 
contiene i dati e le immagini dal progetto dell'osservatorio della 
terra della NASA. Lo scopo dell'osservatorio della terra della 
NASA è fornire una pubblicazione accessibile sul Internet in cui il 
pubblico può ottenere le nuove immagini proveniente dal satellite e 
l'informazione scientifica sul nostro pianeta domestico. Il 
fuoco è sul clima e sul cambiamento ambientale della terra. Il 
luogo è utile ai media pubblici ed agli educatori. I dati e le 
immagini possono essere ottenuti per una varietà di oggetti, 
l'atmosfera della terra, terra, vita su terra, oceani e calore ed 
energia. Gli utenti possono digitare i dati su una varietà di 
soggetti e produrre le animazioni che descrivono i dati digitati. 
Il luogo egualmente contiene una sezione utile che spiega come 
sviluppare le animazioni e le animazioni del globo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή γήινων παρατηρητήριων περιέχει τα 
στοιχεία και τις εικόνες από το πρόγραμμα γήινων παρατηρητήριων 
της NASA. Ο σκοπός του γήινου παρατηρητήριου της NASA 
είναι να παρασχεθεί μια προσιτή δημοσίευση στο διαδίκτυο όπου το
κοινό μπορεί να λάβει τα νέα δορυφορικά καλολογικά στοιχεία και
τις επιστημονικές πληροφορίες για το βασικό πλανήτη μας. Η 
εστίαση είναι στο γήινες κλίμα και την περιβαλλοντική αλλαγή. 
Η περιοχή είναι χρήσιμη στα δημόσιους μέσα και τους 
εκπαιδευτικούς. Τα στοιχεία και οι εικόνες μπορούν να 
ληφθούν για ποικίλα θέματα, τη γήινη ατμόσφαιρα, το έδαφος, τη 
ζωή στη γη, τους ωκεανούς και τη θερμότητα και την ενέργεια. 
Οι χρήστες μπορούν να εισαγάγουν τα στοιχεία όσον αφορά 
ποικίλα θέματα και να παραγάγουν τις ζωτικότητες απεικονίζοντας 
τα στοιχεία που εισάγονται. Η περιοχή περιέχει επίσης ένα 
χρήσιμο τμήμα που εξηγεί πώς να χτίσει τις ζωτικότητες και τις 
ζωτικότητες σφαιρών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio del observatorio de la tierra contiene 
datos e imágenes del proyecto del observatorio de la tierra de la 
NASA. El propósito del observatorio de la tierra de la NASA es 
proporcionar a una publicación accesible en el Internet en donde el 
público puede obtener nuevas imágenes basadas en los satélites y la
información científica sobre nuestro planeta casero. El foco 
está en el clima y el cambio ambiental de la tierra. El sitio 
es útil a los media públicos y a los educadores. Los datos y 
las imágenes se pueden obtener para una variedad de temas, la 
atmósfera de la tierra, pista, vida en la tierra, los océanos y 
calor y energía. Los utilizadores pueden incorporar datos sobre
una variedad de asuntos y producir las animaciones que representan los
datos incorporados. El sitio también contiene una sección 
provechosa que explica cómo construir animaciones y animaciones del 
globo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201376</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103691</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-observatory-data-and-images</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
