<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106567</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106567</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201601</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Examining a Potential Paper Topic</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Überprüfen eines möglichen Papierthemas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Examiner un sujet de papier potentiel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Examinando um tópico de papel potencial</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esaminare un soggetto di carta potenziale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξέταση ενός πιθανού θέματος εγγράφου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Examinar un asunto de papel potencial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This writing exercise, designed by the department of English at Northern Illinois University, provides students with the opportunity to think through paper topics before actually writing essays. The activity it allows two classmates to respond to the topic and ask questions regarding the topic. Then the original student is asked to respond to her/his classmates questions and concerns. Students also develop computer skills such as word processing. This exercise is part of a greater NIU writing module.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Schreiben Übung, konzipiert durch die 
Abteilung von Englisch an der Nordillinois Universität, versieht 
Kursteilnehmer mit der Gelegenheit, durch Papierthemen zu denken, 
bevor sie wirklich Versuche schreibt. Die Aktivität erlaubt sie
zwei Mitschülern, auf das Thema zu reagieren und die Fragen 
betreffend sind das Thema zu stellen. Dann wird der 
ursprüngliche Kursteilnehmer gebeten, auf her/his Mitschüler zu 
reagieren fragt und Interessen. Kursteilnehmer entwickeln auch 
Computerfähigkeiten wie Textverarbeitung. Diese Übung ist ein 
Teil eines grösseren NIU Schreiben Moduls.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet exercice d'écriture, conçu par le service de
l'anglais à l'université nordique de l'Illinois, fournit à des 
étudiants l'occasion de penser par les sujets de papier avant 
d'écrire réellement des essais. L'activité il permet à deux 
camarades de classe de répondre au sujet et de poser des questions 
concernant le sujet. Alors l'étudiant initial est invité à 
répondre aux camarades de classe de her/his interroge et des soucis. 
Les étudiants développent également des qualifications 
d'ordinateur telles que le traitement de texte. Cet exercice 
fait partie d'un plus grand module d'écriture de NIU.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este exercício da escrita, projetado pelo 
departamento do inglês na universidade do norte de Illinois, fornece 
estudantes com a oportunidade de pensar com os tópicos de papel antes
realmente de escrever essays. A atividade permite que dois 
classmates respondam ao tópico e façam as perguntas a respeito do 
tópico. O estudante original é pedido então para responder 
aos classmates de her/his questiona e interesses. Os estudantes 
desenvolvem também habilidades do computador tais como processar de 
palavra. Este exercício é peça de um módulo mais grande da 
escrita de NIU.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa esercitazione di scrittura, progettata dal 
reparto dell'inglese all'università nordica dell'Illinois, fornisce 
agli allievi l'occasione pensare con i soggetti di carta prima 
realmente della scrittura dei saggi. L'attività permette che 
due classmates rispondano al soggetto e facciano le domande per quanto
riguarda il soggetto. Allora l'allievo originale è chiesto di 
rispondere ai classmates di her/his interroga e preoccupazioni. 
Gli allievi egualmente sviluppano le abilità del calcolatore 
come elaborazione di testi. Questa esercitazione fa parte di un 
modulo più grande di scrittura di NIU.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η άσκηση γραψίματος, που σχεδιάζεται από το 
τμήμα των αγγλικών στο βόρειο πανεπιστήμιο του Ιλλινόις, παρέχει
στους σπουδαστές την ευκαιρία να σκεφτεί μέσω των θεμάτων 
εγγράφου πριν από πραγματικά να γράψει τα δοκίμια. Η 
δραστηριότητα αυτό επιτρέπει σε δύο συμμαθητές για να αποκριθεί 
στο θέμα και να υποβάλει τις ερωτήσεις σχετικά με το θέμα. 
Κατόπιν ο αρχικός σπουδαστής καλείται να αποκριθεί στις 
ερωτήσεις και τις ανησυχίες συμμαθητών τισσες/του. Οι 
σπουδαστές αναπτύσσουν επίσης τις δεξιότητες υπολογιστών όπως η 
επεξεργασία κειμένου. Αυτή η άσκηση είναι μέρος μιας 
μεγαλύτερης ενότητας γραψίματος NIU.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este ejercicio de la escritura, diseñado por el 
departamento del inglés en la universidad norteña de Illinois, 
provee de estudiantes la oportunidad de pensar con los asuntos de 
papel antes realmente de escribir ensayos. La actividad permite 
que dos classmates respondan al asunto y hagan preguntas con respecto 
al asunto. Entonces piden el estudiante original responder a los
classmates de her/his pregunta y las preocupaciones. Los 
estudiantes también desarrollan habilidades del ordenador tales como 
tratamiento de textos de textos. Este ejercicio es parte de un 
mayor módulo de la escritura de NIU.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201601</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106567</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/examining-a-potential-paper-topic</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
