<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106076</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106076</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086239</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hiram Revels</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hiram Revels</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Hiram Revels</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Hiram Revels</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Hiram Revels</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Hiram Revels</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hiram Revels</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1870, the Boston firm of Louis Prang and Company published a chromolithograph (an inexpensive type of color print) portrait of the first African-American United States senator. One prominent admirer of the portrait was Frederick Douglass: "Whatever may be the prejudices of those who may look upon it," he wrote to Prang, "they will be compelled to admit that the Mississippi senator is a man, and one who will easily pass for a man among men. We colored men so often see ourselves described and painted as monkeys, that we think it a great piece of good fortune to find an exception to this general rule."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1870 veröffentlichten das Boston Unternehmen von 
Louis Prang und Company ein chromolithograph (ein billiger Typ Farbe 
Druck) Portrait des ersten Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Vereinigte 
Staaten Senators. Ein vorstehender Bewunderer des Portraits war 
Frederick Douglass: "was auch immer die Vorurteile von denen 
sein können, die nach ihm schauen können," schrieb er Prang, "sie 
werden gezwungen, um zuzulassen, daß der Mississippi Senator ein Mann
ist, und einer, wer leicht für einen Mann unter Männern 
überschreitet. Wir färbten Männer uns sehen so häufig, daß 
als Fallhammer, der beschrieben und malten, den wir es ein großes 
Stück Glück denken, um eine Ausnahme zu dieser allgemeinen 
Richtlinie zu finden."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1870, la société de Boston de Louis Prang et 
Company ont édité une verticale du chromolithograph (un type peu 
coûteux de copie de couleur) du premier sénateur afro-américain des 
Etats-Unis. Un admirateur en avant de la verticale était 
Frederick Douglass : "celui qui puissent être les préjudices 
de ceux qui peuvent considérer lui," il a écrit à Prang, "elles 
seront obligées pour admettre que le sénateur du Mississippi est un 
homme, et un qui passera facilement pour un homme parmi les hommes. 
Nous avons coloré des hommes nous voyons tellement souvent que 
ont décrit et ont peint comme singes, celui que nous le pensons un 
grand morceau de bonne fortune pour trouver une exception à cette 
règle générale."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1870, a firma de Boston de Louis Prang e 
Companhia publicaram um retrato do chromolithograph (um tipo barato de
cópia da cor) do primeiro senator unido Africano-Americano dos 
estados. Um admirador proeminente do retrato era Frederick 
Douglass: "o que quer que podem ser os preconceitos daqueles que
podem olhar em cima dele," escreveu a Prang, "serão compelidas para 
admitir que o senator de Mississippi é um homem, e um quem passará 
fàcilmente para um homem entre homens. Nós colorimos homens 
vemo-nos assim frequentemente que descreveram e pintaram como macacos,
aquele que nós pensamos d uma parte grande de fortuna boa para 
encontrar uma exceção a esta régua geral."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1870, la ditta de Boston di Louis Prang e 
Company hanno pubblicato un ritratto del chromolithograph (un tipo
economico di stampa di colore) del primo Africano-Americano unito 
Dichiara il senatore. Un ammiratore prominente del 
ritratto era Frederick Douglass: "qualunque possono essere i
pregiudizi di coloro che può considerare esso," ha scritto a Prang, 
"saranno costretti per ammettere che il senatore del Mississippi è un
uomo ed uno chi passerà facilmente per un uomo fra gli uomini. 
Abbiamo colorato gli uomini così spesso ci vediamo che hanno 
descritto e verniciato come scimmie, quella lo pensiamo una parte 
grande di buona fortuna per trovare un'eccezione a questa regola 
generale."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1870, η εταιρία της Βοστώνης του Louis Prang
και η επιχείρηση δημοσίευσαν πορτρέτο chromolithograph (ένας 
ανέξοδος τύπος τυπωμένης ύλης χρώματος) του πρώτου 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικού Ηνωμένου γερουσιαστή. Ένας 
προεξέχων θαυμαστής του πορτρέτου ήταν Frederick Douglass: 
"Οποιεσδήποτε μπορούν να είναι οι προκαταλήψεις εκείνοι που
μπορούν να κοιτάξουν επάνω σε το," έγραψε σε Prang, "θα 
αναγκαστούν για να αναγνωρίσουν ότι ο γερουσιαστής του Μισισιπή 
είναι άτομο, και ένα που θα περάσει εύκολα για ένα άτομο 
μεταξύ των ατόμων. Έγχρωμα άτομα τόσο συχνά 
βλέπουμε που περιγραφόμαστε και που χρωματιζόμαστε ως 
πίθηκοι, ότι το σκεφτόμαστε ένα μεγάλο κομμάτι της καλής τύχης
για να βρούμε μια εξαίρεση σε αυτόν τον γενικό κανόνα."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1870, la firma de Boston de Louis Prang y 
Company publicaron un retrato del chromolithograph (un tipo barato de 
impresión del color) del primer senador Africano-Americano de Estados
Unidos. Un admirador prominente del retrato era Frederick 
Douglass: "lo que puede ser los prejudicar de los que puedan 
mirar sobre él," él escribió a Prang, a "les obligarán que admitan
que el senador de Mississippi sea un hombre, y uno quién pasará 
fácilmente para un hombre entre hombres. Coloreamos a hombres 
nos vemos tan a menudo que describieron y que pintaron como monos, de 
que que lo pensamos un gran pedazo de buena fortuna para encontrar una
anomalía a esta regla general."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086239</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106076</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/hiram-revels</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
