<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105381</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105381</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086474</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Milton Eisenhower Justifies the Internment of Japanese Americans</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Milton Eisenhower schließt die Internierung der 
japanischen Amerikaner aus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Milton Eisenhower justifie l'internement des 
Américains japonais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Milton Eisenhower justifica o internamento de 
americanos japoneses</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Milton Eisenhower giustifica l'internamento degli 
Americani giapponesi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Milton Eisenhower δικαιολογεί τον περιορισμό 
ιαπωνικών Αμερικανών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Milton Eisenhower alinea la internación de 
americanos japoneses</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">America fought World War II to preserve freedom and democracy, yet that same war featured the greatest suppression of civil liberties in the nation's history. In an atmosphere of hysteria, President Roosevelt, encouraged by officials at all levels of the federal government, authorized the internment of tens of thousands of American citizens of Japanese ancestry and resident aliens from Japan. On March 18, 1942, Roosevelt authorized the establishment of the War Relocation Authority (WRA) to govern these detention camps. He chose as its first head Milton Eisenhower, a New Deal bureaucrat in the Department of Agriculture and brother of General Dwight D. Eisenhower. In a 1942 film entitled  Japanese Relocation , produced by the Office of War Information, Eisenhower offered the U.S. government's rationale for the relocation of Japanese-American citizens. He claimed that the Japanese "cheerfully" participated in the relocation process, a statement belied by all contemporary and subsequent accounts of the 1942 events.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Amerika kennzeichnete der gekämpfte Zweite 
Weltkrieg, zum von von Freiheit und von von Demokratie zu 
konservieren, dennoch das der gleiche Krieg den größten Ausgleich 
von Zivilfreiheiten in der Geschichte der Nation. In einer 
Atmosphäre der Hysterie, autorisierte Präsident Roosevelt, 
angeregt von den Beamten auf allen Stufen der Bundesregierung, die 
Internierung von 10 Tausenden der amerikanischen Bürger japanischen 
Geschlechtes und der Residentausländer von Japan. An März 18, 
1942, Roosevelt autorisierte die Einrichtung der Krieg-Verschiebung 
Berechtigung (WRA) diese Internierungslager zu regeln. Er 
wählte als sein erster Kopf Milton Eisenhower, ein Bürokrat des 
neuen Abkommens im Landwirtschaftsministerium und im Bruder des 
Generals Dwight D. Eisenhower. In einem Film 1942 bot die 
erlaubte japanische Verschiebung, produziert durch das Büro der 
Krieg-Informationen, Eisenhower das Grundprinzip der VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Regierung für die Verschiebung der Japanisch-Amerikanischen 
Bürger an. Er behauptete, daß der Japaner "freundlich" am 
Verschiebung Prozeß, eine Anweisung teilnahm, die durch alle 
zeitgenössischen und folgenden Konten der 1942 Fälle widerlegt 
wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">ParAmérique la deuxième guerre mondiale 
combattue celle pour préserver la liberté et la démocratie, 
pourtant la même guerre a comporté la plus grande suppression des 
libertés civiles dans l'histoire de la nation. Dans une 
atmosphère d'hystérie, le Président Roosevelt, encouragé par des 
fonctionnaires à tous les niveaux du gouvernement fédéral, a 
autorisé l'internement des dizaines de milliers de citoyens 
américains d'ascendance japonaise et d'étrangers résidents du 
Japon. 18 mars 1942, Roosevelt a autorisé l'établissement de 
l'autorité de réadressage de guerre (WRA) à régir ces camps de 
détention. Il a choisi en tant que sa première tête Milton 
Eisenhower, un bureaucrate de nouvelle affaire dans le ministère de 
l'agriculture et le frère du Général Dwight D. Eisenhower. 
Dans un film 1942 le réadressage japonais autorisé, produit 
par le bureau d'information de guerre, Eisenhower a offert le 
raisonnement du gouvernement des ETATS-UNIS pour le réadressage des 
citoyens Japonais-Américains. Il a réclamé que le Japonais a 
participé "gaiement" au processus de réadressage, un rapport 
démonté par tous les comptes contemporains et ultérieurs des 1942 
événements.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">América a segunda guerra mundial lutada aquela 
para preservar a liberdade e a democracia, contudo a mesma guerra 
caracterizou a supressão a mais grande de liberdades civis no history
da nação. Em uma atmosfera do hysteria, o presidente 
Roosevelt, incentivado por oficiais em todos os níveis do governo 
federal, autorizou o internamento dos dez dos milhares de cidadãos 
americanos do ancestry japonês e dos estrangeiros residentes de 
Japão. Março em 18, 1942, Roosevelt autorizou o 
estabelecimento da autoridade do relocation da guerra (WRA) governar 
estes acampamentos de detention. Escolheu como sua primeira 
cabeça Milton Eisenhower, um burocrata do negócio novo no 
departamento de agricultura e no irmão do general Dwight D. 
Eisenhower. Em uma película 1942 o relocation japonês 
intitulado, produzido pelo escritório da informação da guerra, 
Eisenhower ofereceu o rationale do governo de ESTADOS UNIDOS para o 
relocation de cidadãos Japonês-Americanos. Reivindicou que o 
japonês "cheerfully" participou no processo do relocation, uma 
indicação belied por todos os clientes contemporary e subseqüentes 
dos 1942 eventos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'America ha combattuto la seconda guerra mondiale
per conservare la libertà e la democrazia, tuttavia quella la stessa 
guerra ha caratterizzato la soppressione più grande delle libertà 
civili nella storia della nazione. In un atmosfera di hysteria, 
il presidente Roosevelt, consigliato a dai funzionari a tutti i 
livelli del governo federale, ha autorizzato l'internamento dei dieci 
dei migliaia dei cittadini americani dell'ascendenza giapponese e 
degli stranieri residenti dal Giappone. Il 18 marzo 1942, 
Roosevelt ha autorizzato l'istituzione dell'autorità di rilocazione 
di guerra (WRA) a governare questi accampamenti di detenzione. 
Ha scelto come relativa prima testa Milton Eisenhower, un 
burocrate di nuovo affare nel ministero dell'agricoltura e nel 
fratello del General Dwight D. Eisenhower. In una pellicola 1942
la rilocazione giapponese intitolata, prodotta dall'ufficio delle 
informazioni di guerra, Eisenhower ha offerto la spiegazione razionale
del governo degli STATI UNITI per la rilocazione dei cittadini 
Giapponese-Americani. Ha sostenuto che il giapponese ha 
partecipato "cheerfully" al processo di rilocazione, un'istruzione 
belied da tutti i clienti contemporanei e successivi dei 1942 eventi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Αμερική διεξήγαγε τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ για να 
συντηρήσει την ελευθερία και τη δημοκρατία, όμως εκείνος ο ίδιος
πόλεμος χαρακτήρισε τη μέγιστη καταστολή των αστικών ελευθεριών 
στην ιστορία του έθνους. Σε μια ατμόσφαιρα της υστερίας, ο 
Πρόεδρος Roosevelt, που ενθαρρύνθηκε από τους ανώτερους 
υπαλλήλους σε όλα τα επίπεδα της ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης, 
ενέκρινε τον περιορισμό των δεκάδων χιλιάδων αμερικανικοί 
πολίτες της ιαπωνικής καταγωγής και εδρεύοντες αλλοδαποί από την
Ιαπωνία. Στις 18 Μαρτίου ..1942, Roosevelt επέτρεψε 
στην καθιέρωση της αρχής πολεμικής επαναμετάθεσης (WRA) για να 
κυβερνήσει αυτά τα στρατόπεδα συγκεντρώσεως. Επέλεξε ως 
πρώτο επικεφαλής Milton του Eisenhower, ένας νέος 
γραφειοκράτης διαπραγμάτευσης στο τμήμα γεωργίας και τον αδελφό 
General Dwight Δ. Eisenhower. Σε μια έχουσα το 
δικαίωμα ταινία ιαπωνική επαναμετάθεση του 1942, που παρήχθη 
από το γραφείο των πολεμικών πληροφοριών, Eisenhower πρόσφερε 
τη λογική της ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ κυβέρνησης για την επαναμετάθεση των 
ιαπωνικός-αμερικανικών πολιτών. Υποστήριξε ότι οι Ιάπωνες 
"χαρωπά" συμμετείχαν στη διαδικασία επαναμετάθεσης, μια δήλωση 
που διαψεύδθηκε από όλους τους σύγχρονους και επόμενους 
απολογισμούς των γεγονότων του 1942.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">América la Segunda Guerra Mundial de combate ésa
para preservar la libertad y la democracia, con todo la misma guerra 
ofreció la supresión más grande de libertades civiles en la 
historia de la nación. En una atmósfera de la histeria, 
presidente Roosevelt, alentador por los funcionarios en todos los 
niveles del gobierno federal, autorizó la internación de diez de 
millares de ciudadanos americanos de ascendencia japonesa y de 
extranjeros residentes de Japón. De marcha la 18 de 1942, 
Roosevelt autorizó el establecimiento de la autoridad de la 
realocación de la guerra (WRA) a gobernar estos campos de detención.
Él eligió como su primera cabeza Milton Eisenhower, burócrata
del nuevo reparto en el Ministerio de Agricultura y el hermano de 
general Dwight D. Eisenhower. En una película 1942 la 
realocación japonesa dada derecho, producida por la oficina de la 
información de la guerra, Eisenhower ofreció el análisis razonado 
del gobierno de ESTADOS UNIDOS para la realocación de ciudadanos 
Japone's-Americanos. Él demandó que el japonés participó 
"alegre" en el proceso de la realocación, una declaración belied por
todas las cuentas contemporáneas y subsecuentes de los 1942 
acontecimientos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086474</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105381</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/milton-eisenhower-justifies-the-internment-of-japanese-americans</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
