<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102957</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102957</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205686</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Celebrating Stephen Sondheim</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Feiern Von von Stephen Sondheim</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Célébration de Stephen Sondheim</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Comemorando Stephen Sondheim</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Celebrazione Dello Stephen Sondheim</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γιορτάζοντας stephen Sondheim</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Celebración De Stephen Sondheim</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">helps introduce students to one of the most influential figures in musical theatre history. In addition to lesson ideas and learning activities, it offers a biography of the composer-lyricist, a timeline of his career, and the background and synopses of four of his most well-known musicals. The site was developed in conjunction with the Kennedy Center's Sondheim Celebration, which will be held throughout the spring and summer.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfen stellen Kursteilnehmer bis eine der 
einflußreichsten Abbildungen in der musikalischen Theatergeschichte 
vor. Zusätzlich zu den Lektionideen und Lernenaktivitäten, 
bietet sie eine Biographie des Komponist-Lyrikers, ein timeline seiner
Karriere und der Hintergrund und die Synopsen von vier seiner weithin 
bekanntesten Musikale an. Die Site wurde in Verbindung mit der 
Kennedy Mittelsondheim Feier entwickelt, die während des Frühlinges 
und des Sommers angehalten wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les aides présentent des étudiants à une des 
figures les plus influentes dans l'histoire musicale de théâtre. 
En plus des idées de leçon et étude, elle offre une 
biographie du compositeur-auteur lyrique, une chronologie de sa 
carrière, et le fond et les synthèses de quatre de ses musicaux plus
bien connus. Le site a été développé en même temps que la 
célébration centrale de Kennedy Sondheim, qui sera tenue tout au 
long du ressort et de l'été.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">as ajudas introduzem estudantes a uma das figuras 
as mais influential no history musical do theatre. Além às 
idéias da lição e as atividades de aprendizagem, oferece uma 
biografia do compositor-composer-lyricist, um timeline de sua 
carreira, e o fundo e os synopses de quatro de seus musicals mais 
well-known. O local foi desenvolvido conjuntamente com o 
celebration center de Kennedy Sondheim, que será prendido durante 
todo a mola e o verão.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">gli aiuti introducono gli allievi ad una delle 
figure più influenti nella storia musicale del teatro. Oltre 
che le idee di lezione ed attività imparanti, offre una biografia del
compositore-composer-lyricist, un timeline della sua carriera ed i 
precedenti e le sinossi di quattro dei suoi musicals più ben noti. 
Il luogo è stato sviluppato insieme con la celebrazione 
concenta di Kennedy Sondheim, che sarà tenuta durante la molla e 
l'estate.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">οι οδηγίες εισάγουν τους σπουδαστές σε ένας από τους 
επιδρύτερους αριθμούς στη μουσική ιστορία θεάτρων. Εκτός 
από τις ιδέες μαθήματος και τις δραστηριότητες εκμάθησης, 
προσφέρει μια βιογραφία του συνθέτης- lyricist, μιας υπόδειξης 
ως προς το χρόνο της σταδιοδρομίας του, και του υποβάθρου και των 
συνόψεων τεσσάρων από τα πιό γνωστά musicals του. Η 
περιοχή αναπτύχθηκε από κοινού με τον εορτασμό κεντρικού 
Kennedy Sondheim, ο οποίος θα κρατηθεί καθ' όλη τη διάρκεια 
της άνοιξης και του καλοκαιριού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las ayudas introducen a estudiantes a una de las 
figuras más influyentes de la historia musical del teatro. 
Además de ideas de la lección y las actividades que aprenden, 
ofrece una biografía del compositor-autor, un timeline de su carrera,
y el fondo y las sinopsis de cuatro de sus musicals más bien 
conocidos. El sitio fue desarrollado conjuntamente con la 
celebración de centro de Kennedy Sondheim, que será celebrada a 
través del resorte y del verano.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205686</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102957</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/celebrating-stephen-sondheim</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
