<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106489</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106489</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209765</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Formatting the Script</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Formatieren des Indexes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Formatage de la séquence type</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Formatando o certificado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Formattazione dello scritto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μορφοποίηση του αρχείου εντολών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Formatar la escritura</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">For the first lesson of this course, you are given a short story and you are told to format the story into the proper format for a motion picture script. Now is an excellent time to learn script formatting. This is a task that people do every day in Hollywood so this lesson give you excellent practice. You can download a free yet working demo version of Final Draft which is a script typing and script formatting program. This is the ideal program for learning script formatting. There are versions for both the Macintosh and Windows. Or you can download a free program called CeltX which is still under construction (version 0.99) and the manual is incomplete. However, it looks very interesting, it is free, and it works on Linux as well as Macintosh and Windows. .</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Für die erste Lektion dieses Kurses, werden Ihnen
eine kurze Geschichte gegeben und Sie werden erklärt, um die 
Geschichte in das korrekte Format für einen Bewegung Abbildung Index 
zu formatieren. Ist jetzt eine ausgezeichnete Zeit, 
Indexformatierung zu erlernen. Dieses ist eine Aufgabe, daß 
Leute jeden Tag in Hollywood also in diesem Lektiongeben Sie 
ausgezeichnete Praxis tun. Sie können eine freie dennoch 
Arbeitsdemoversion des abschließenden Entwurfes downloaden, der 
Indexschreiben und Indexformatierung Programm ist. Dieses ist 
das ideale Programm für das Lernen von von Indexformatierung. 
Es gibt Versionen für den Macintosh und Windows. Oder Sie
können ein freies Programm downloaden, das CeltX genannt wird, der 
noch im Bau (Version 0.99) ist und das Handbuch ist unvollständig. 
Jedoch schaut es sehr interessant, ist es frei, und es 
funktioniert auf Linux sowie Macintosh und Windows.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pour la première leçon de ce cours, vous êtes 
donné une histoire courte et vous êtes dit pour formater l'histoire 
dans le format approprié pour une séquence type de film 
cinématographique. Est maintenant un excellent temps pour 
apprendre le formatage de séquence type. C'est un charger 
que les gens font chaque jour dans Hollywood ainsi cette élasticité
de leçon vous excellente pratique. Vous pouvez télécharger 
une version libre pourtant fonctionnante de démo du projet 
définitif qui est taper d'une séquence type et programme de 
formatage de séquence type. C'est le programme idéal pour 
apprendre le formatage de séquence type. Il y a des versions 
pour Macintosh et Windows. Ou vous pouvez télécharger un 
programme libre appelé CeltX qui est toujours en construction (la 
version 0.99) et le manuel est inachevé. Cependant, il regarde 
très intéressant, il est libre, et il travaille à Linux aussi bien 
que Macintosh et Windows.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para a primeira lição deste curso, você é dado
uma história curta e você é dito para formatar a história no 
formato apropriado para um certificado do retrato de movimento. 
É agora uma estadia excelente aprender o formato do 
certificado. Esta é uma tarefa que os povos fazem cada dia em 
Hollywood assim que nesta elasticidade da lição você prática 
excelente. Você pode download uma versão livre contudo 
trabalhando do programa demostrativo do esboço final que é 
datilografar de um certificado e programa do formato do certificado. 
Este é o programa ideal para aprender o formato do certificado.
Há umas versões para  o Macintosh e Windows. Ou você 
pode download um programa livre chamado CeltX que está ainda sob a 
construção (versão 0.99) e o manual está incompleto. 
Entretanto, olha muito interessante, está livre, e trabalha em 
Linux as.well.as Macintosh e Windows.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per la prima lezione di questo corso, siete dati 
una storia corta e vi dite a per formattare la storia nel formato 
adeguato per uno scritto del cinema. Ora è un tempo eccellente 
imparare la formattazione dello scritto. Ciò è un'operazione 
che la gente fa ogni giorno in Hollywood in modo da in questo give di 
lezione voi pratica eccellente. Potete trasferire una versione 
dal sistema centrale verso i satelliti libera tuttavia di 
funzionamento del demo della brutta copia definitiva che è digitare 
dello scritto e programma di formattazione dello scritto. Ciò 
è il programma ideale per imparare la formattazione dello scritto. 
Ci sono versioni per sia il Macintosh che Windows. O 
potete trasferire un programma dal sistema centrale verso i satelliti 
libero chiamato CeltX che è ancora in costruzione (versione 0.99) ed 
il manuale è incompleto. Tuttavia, osserva molto interessante, 
è libero e lavora a Linux così come Macintosh e Windows.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για το πρώτο μάθημα αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων, σας 
δίνεται μια σύντομη ιστορία και έχετε την υποχρέωση για να 
σχηματοποιήσετε την ιστορία στην κατάλληλη μορφή για ένα αρχείο 
εντολών ταινιών. Τώρα είναι ένας άριστος χρόνος να 
μαθευτεί η μορφοποίηση αρχείων εντολών. Αυτό είναι μια 
στοιχειώδης εργασία ότι οι άνθρωποι κάνουν κάθε ημέρα σε 
Hollywood έτσι αυτό το μάθημα σας δίνει την άριστη πρακτική. 
Μπορείτε να μεταφορτώσετε μια ελεύθερη έκδοση επίδειξης 
ακόμα εργασίας του τελικού σχεδίου που είναι ένα πρόγραμμα 
δακτυλογράφηση αρχείων εντολών και μορφοποίηση αρχείων εντολών. 
Αυτό είναι το ιδανικό πρόγραμμα για τη μορφοποίηση αρχείων
εντολών. Υπάρχουν εκδόσεις και για το Macintosh και για τα
Windows. Ή μπορείτε να μεταφορτώσετε ένα ελεύθερο 
πρόγραμμα αποκαλούμενο CeltX που είναι ακόμα κάτω από την 
κατασκευή (η έκδοση 0.99) και το εγχειρίδιο είναι ελλιπείς. 
Εντούτοις, φαίνεται πολύ ενδιαφέρον, είναι ελεύθερο, και 
λειτουργεί σε Linux καθώς επίσης και Macintosh και τα 
Windows.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para la primera lección de este curso, le dan una
historia corta y le dicen para formatar la historia en el formato 
apropiado para una escritura de la película. Ahora está un 
rato excelente de aprender el formato de la escritura. Esto es 
una tarea que la gente hace cada día en Hollywood así que esta 
elasticidad de la lección usted práctica excelente. Usted 
puede descargar una versión libre con todo de trabajo de la versión 
parcial de programa del bosquejo final que es el pulsar de una 
escritura y programa del formato de la escritura. Éste es el 
programa ideal para aprender el formato de la escritura. Hay 
versiones para el Macintosh y Windows. O usted puede descargar 
un programa libre llamado CeltX que todavía esté bajo construcción 
(versión 0.99) y el manual es incompleto. Sin embargo, parece 
muy interesante, está libre, y trabaja en Linux así como Macintosh y
Windows.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209765</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">GNU Free Documentation License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106489</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/formatting-the-script</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
