<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103689</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103689</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206901</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ancestors in the Americas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vorfahren im Amerika</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ancêtres en Amériques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Antepassados nos Americas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Antenati nei Americas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρόγονοι στην Αμερική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Antepasados en las Américas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Welcome to the web site for the PBS series ANCESTORS IN THE AMERICAS by Loni Ding. Asian Americans are one of the fastest growing yet least known groups of immigrants in the United States. Join us for an exploration of their history and stories.

The ANCESTORS IN THE AMERICAS companion Web site helps to round out the stories and ideas presented in this groundbreaking series. Visit the Asian American Timeline to learn about specific moments and events that shaped Asian American history. Join an online discussion to talk about the series or related topics regarding Asian Americans. Use the Resource section to further explore the Asian American experience. For educators, the Web site includes classroom guides with discussion questions related to ANCESTORS IN THE AMERICAS.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Willkommen zur Web site für die PBS Serie 
VORFAHREN IM AMERIKA durch Loni Ding. Asiatische Amerikaner sind
eine des schnellsten Wachsens dennoch weniger bekannter Gruppen 
Immigranten in den Vereinigten Staaten. Verbinden Sie uns für 
eine Erforschung ihrer Geschichte und der stories.The VORFAHREN IN DEN
AMERIKA Begleiter Web site Hilfen zu rundem aus den Geschichten und 
den Ideen, die in dieser groundbreaking Serie dargestellt werden. 
Besuchen Sie das asiatische amerikanische Timeline, um über 
spezifische Momente und Fälle zu erlernen, die asiatische 
amerikanische Geschichte formten. Verbinden Sie eine 
Onlinediskussion, um sich der Serie oder mit den in Verbindung 
stehenden Themen betreffend sind asiatische Amerikaner zu befassen. 
Benutzen Sie das Hilfsmittelkapitel, um die asiatische 
amerikanische Erfahrung weiter zu erforschen. Für Erzieher 
schließt die Web site Klassenzimmeranleitungen mit den Diskussion 
Fragen ein, die auf VORFAHREN IM AMERIKA in Verbindung gestanden 
werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bienvenue au site Web pour les ANCÊTRES de série
de PBS EN AMÉRIQUES par Loni Ding. Les Américains asiatiques 
sont l'un de la croissance la plus rapide pourtant de moindres groupes
connus d'immigrés aux Etats-Unis. Joignez-nous pour une 
exploration de leur histoire et d'ANCÊTRES de stories.The DANS les 
aides de site de Web de compagnon des AMÉRIQUES à rond hors 
des histoires et des idées présentées de cette série d'inauguration.
Visitez la Chronologie américaine asiatique pour se renseigner 
sur les moments et les événements spécifiques qui ont formé 
l'histoire américaine asiatique. Joignez une discussion en 
ligne pour parler de la série ou des sujets relatifs concernant les 
Américains asiatiques. Employez la section de ressource pour 
explorer plus plus loin l'expérience américaine asiatique. 
Pour des éducateurs, le site de Web inclut des guides 
de salle de classe avec des questions de discussion liées aux 
ANCÊTRES EN AMÉRIQUES.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Boa vinda ao Web site para os ANTEPASSADOS da 
série de PBS NOS AMERICAS por Loni Ding. Os americanos asian 
são um do crescimento o mais rápido contudo de menos grupos 
conhecidos dos immigrants nos estados unidos. Junte-nos para uma
exploração de seu history e de ANTEPASSADOS de stories.The nas 
ajudas do Web site do companheiro de AMERICAS a redondo para fora das 
histórias e das idéias apresentadas nesta série groundbreaking. 
Visite o Timeline americano asian para aprender sobre os 
momentos e os eventos específicos que deram forma ao history 
americano asian. Junte uma discussão em linha à conversa sobre
a série ou os tópicos relacionados a respeito dos americanos asian. 
Use a seção do recurso explorar mais mais a experiência 
americana asian. Para educadores, o Web site inclui guias da 
sala de aula com as perguntas da discussão relacionadas aos 
ANTEPASSADOS NOS AMERICAS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Benvenuto al Web site per gli ANTENATI di serie di
PBS NEI AMERICAS da Loni Ding. Gli Americani asiatici sono uno 
del crescere più veloce tuttavia meno gruppi conosciuti degli 
immigranti in unito Dichiara. Uniscali per 
un'esplorazione della loro storia e degli ANTENATI di stories.The 
negli aiuti di Web site del compagno dei AMERICAS a rotondo verso 
l'esterno le storia e le idee presentate in questa serie approfondita. 
Visiti il Timeline americano asiatico per imparare circa i 
momenti specifici e gli eventi che hanno modellato la storia 
americana asiatica. Unisca una discussione in linea per parlare 
della serie o dei soggetti relativi per quanto riguarda gli Americani 
asiatici. Usi la sezione delle risorse più ulteriormente per 
esplorare l'esperienza americana asiatica. Per gli educatori, il
Web site include le guide dell'aula con le domande di discussione 
relative agli ANTENATI NEI AMERICAS.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποδοχή στον ιστοχώρο για τους ΠΡΟΓΌΝΟΥΣ σειράς PBS
στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΉ από Loni Ding. Ασιατικοί Αμερικανοί 
είναι ένας από τους γρηγορότερους αυξανόμενος ακόμα λιγότερες 
γνωστές ομάδες μετανάστης στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. Μας 
ενώστε για μια εξερεύνηση της ιστορίας και των ιστοριών τους 
Οι ΠΡΟΓΟΝΟΙ στον ιστοχώρο συντρόφων της ΑΜΕΡΙΚΗΣ βοηθούν να 
στρογγυλεψουν έξω τις ιστορίες και τις ιδέες που παρουσιάζονται σε
αυτήν την groundbreaking σειρά. Επισκεφτείτε την ασιατική
αμερικανική υπόδειξη ως προς το χρόνο που μαθαίνει για τις 
συγκεκριμένα στιγμές και τα γεγονότα που διαμόρφωσαν την ασιατική
αμερικανική ιστορία. Ενώστε μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση 
συζήτηση για να μιλήσετε για τις σειρές ή τα σχετικά θέματα 
σχετικά με ασιατικούς Αμερικανούς. Χρησιμοποιήστε το τμήμα 
των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς για να ερευνήσετε περαιτέρω την 
ασιατική αμερικανική εμπειρία. Για τους εκπαιδευτικούς, ο 
ιστοχώρος περιλαμβάνει τους οδηγούς τάξεων με τις ερωτήσεις 
συζήτησης σχετικές με τους ΠΡΟΓΟΝΟΥΣ στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΗ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recepción al Web site para los ANTEPASADOS de la 
serie de PBS EN LAS AMÉRICAS de Loni Ding. Los americanos 
asiáticos son uno del crecimiento más rápido con todo de menos 
grupos conocidos de inmigrantes en los Estados Unidos. 
Ensámblenos para una exploración de su historia y de los 
ANTEPASADOS de stories.The EN las ayudas del sitio del Web del 
compañero de AMÉRICAS a redondo fuera de las historias y de las 
ideas presentadas en esta serie groundbreaking. Visite el 
Timeline americano asiático para aprender sobre los momentos y los 
acontecimientos específicos que formaron historia americana 
asiática. Ensamble una discusión en línea para hablar de la 
serie o de los asuntos relacionados con respecto a americanos 
asiáticos. Utilice la sección del recurso para explorar más 
lejos la experiencia americana asiática. Para los educadores, 
el sitio del Web incluye guías de la sala de clase con las 
preguntas de la discusión relacionadas con los ANTEPASADOS EN LAS 
AMÉRICAS.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206901</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103689</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ancestors-in-the-americas</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
