<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104340</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104340</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086189</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">George Hewes' Recollection of the Boston Massacre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">George Hewes' Erinnerung des Boston Blutbads</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Souvenir de George Hewes du Massacre de 
Boston</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Recollection de George Hewes' do massacre de 
Boston</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ricordo di George Hewes del massacre de Boston</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανάμνηση George Hewes' της σφαγής της Βοστώνης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recuerdo de George Hewes de la Masacre de 
Boston</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Beginning in the mid-1760s, colonists began taking to the streets in Boston and other port cities. Crowds of artisans and laborers joined the elite in protesting British policies, although their differing points of view revealed the divisions within colonial society. Protests mounted in 1767 when Britain passed the Townsend Act, which included a series of unpopular taxes. In Boston, resentment and tension also grew over the presence of British troops, quartered in town to discourage demonstrations, who were also looking for jobs. A private seeking work at a ropemakers' establishment sparked a confrontation on Boston's King Street. When some in the crowd pelted the assembled British soldiers, the troops opened fire; five colonists were killed and six wounded. George Robert Twelves Hewes, a Boston shoemaker, participated in many of the key events of the Revolutionary crisis. Over half a century later, Hewes told James Hawkes about his presence at the Boston Massacre and the Boston Tea Party.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anfangend im mid-1760s, fingen Kolonisten an, zu 
den Straßen in Boston und in anderen Portstädte zu nehmen. 
Massen der Handwerker und der Arbeiter verbanden die Auslese, 
wenn sie britische Politik protestierten, obgleich ihre 
unterscheidenen Punkte der Ansicht die Abteilungen innerhalb der 
Kolonialgesellschaft aufdeckten. Proteste hingen 1767 ein, als 
Großbritannien die Townsend Tat führte, die eine Reihe unpopuläre 
Steuern einschloß. In Boston spannt Groll und wuchs auch über 
der Anwesenheit der britischen Truppen, geviertelt in der Stadt, um 
Demonstrationen zu entmutigen, die auch nach Jobs suchten. Eine 
private suchende Arbeit an einer Einrichtung der ropemakers' funkte 
eine Konfrontation auf König Street Bostons. Als einige in der 
Masse die zusammengebauten britischen Soldaten bewarfen, öffneten die
Truppen Feuer; fünf Kolonisten wurden beendet und sechs 
verwundeten. George Robert Twelves Hewes, ein Boston Schuster, 
teilgenommen an vielen der Schlüsselfälle der revolutionären Krise.
Über Hälfte ein Jahrhundert später, Hewes erklärtes James 
Hawkes über seine Anwesenheit am Boston Blutbad und an der Boston 
Tee-Partei.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Commençant dans le mid-1760s, les colons ont 
commencé à prendre aux rues à Boston et d'autres villes gauches. 
Les foules des artisans et des travailleurs ont joint l'élite 
en protestant des politiques britanniques, bien que leurs points 
différents de vue aient indiqué les divisions chez la société 
coloniale. Les protestations ont monté en 1767 où la 
Grande-Bretagne a passé la Loi de Townsend, qui a inclus une série 
d'impôts inpopulaires. À Boston, le ressentiment et tendent 
s'est également développé au-dessus de la présence des troupes 
britanniques, divisée en ville pour décourager les démonstrations, 
qui recherchaient également les travaux. Un travail recherchant
privé à un établissement des ropemakers a étincelé une 
confrontation sur le Roi Street de Boston. Quand certains dans 
la foule ont écorché les soldats britanniques rassemblés, les 
troupes ont ouvert le feu ; cinq colons ont été détruits et 
six ont blessé. George Robert Twelves Hewes, un cordonnier
de Boston, participé à plusieurs des événements principaux de la 
crise révolutionnaire. Plus de la moitié par siècle plus 
tard, Hewes James dit Hawkes au sujet de sa présence au 
Massacre de Boston et à la partie de thé de Boston.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Começando no mid-1760s, os colonos começaram a 
fazer exame às ruas em Boston e em outras cidades portuárias. 
As multidões dos artisans e dos laborers juntaram o elite em 
protestar políticas britânicas, embora seus pontos diferindo da 
vista revelassem as divisões dentro da sociedade colonial. Os 
protestos montaram em 1767 em que Grâ Bretanha passou o ato de 
Townsend, que incluiu uma série de impostos unpopular. Em 
Boston, o resentment e tensiona cresceu também sobre a presença de 
tropas britânicas, dividida na cidade para desanimar as 
demonstrações, que procuravam também trabalhos. Um trabalho 
procurando confidencial em um estabelecimento dos ropemakers' acendeu 
um confrontation no rei Rua de Boston. Quando alguns na 
multidão pelted os soldados britânicos montados, as tropas abriram o
fogo; cinco colonos foram matados e seis feriram-se. 
George Robert Twelves Hewes, um shoemaker de Boston, participado
em muitos dos eventos chaves da crise revolucionária. Sobre a 
metade um do século mais tarde, o Hewes James dito Hawkes sobre sua 
presença no massacre de Boston e no partido do chá de Boston.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cominciando nel mid-1760s, i colonizzatori hanno 
cominciato a prendere alle vie a Boston ed altre città port. Le
folle degli artigianale e dei lavoratori hanno fatto parte dell'elite 
nella protesta delle politiche britanniche, anche se i loro punti 
differenti della vista hanno rivelato le divisioni presso la società 
coloniale. Le proteste hanno montato in 1767 in cui la 
Gran-Bretagna ha passato la Legge di Townsend, che ha incluso una 
serie di tasse impopolari. A Boston, il rancore e sottopone 
egualmente si è sviluppato sopra la presenza delle truppe 
britanniche, divisa in città per scoraggiare le dimostrazioni, che 
egualmente stavano cercando i lavori. Un lavoro di ricerca 
riservato ad un'istituzione dei ropemakers ha scintillato un confronto
sul re Street de Boston. Quando alcuni nella folla hanno 
scuoiato i soldati britannici montati, le truppe hanno aperto il 
fuoco; cinque colonizzatori sono stati uccisi e sei si sono 
feriti. George Robert Twelves Hewes, un calzolaio de Boston, 
partecipato a molti degli eventi chiave della crisi rivoluzionaria. 
Più della metà un di secolo più successivamente, Hewes ha 
detto a James Hawkes circa la sua presenza al massacre de Boston ed al
partito del tè de Boston.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχίζοντας στα μέσα της 1760s, οι άποικοι άρχισαν 
στις οδούς στη Βοστώνη και άλλες πόλεις λιμένων. Τα πλήθη 
των artisans και των laborers προσχώρησαν στην ελίτ στη 
διαμαρτυρία των βρετανικών πολιτικών, αν και οι διαφορετικές 
απόψεις τους αποκάλυψαν τα τμήματα μέσα στην αποικιακή κοινωνία.
Οι διαμαρτυρίες επικόλλησαν το 1767 όταν πέρασε η Μεγάλη
Βρετανία το νόμο Townsend, ο οποίος περιέλαβε μια σειρά μη 
δημοφιλών φόρων. Στη Βοστώνη, η δυσαρέσκεια και η ένταση 
αυξήθηκαν επίσης πέρα από την παρουσία βρετανικών στρατευμάτων,
που διαιρέθηκε στα τέσσερα στην πόλη για να αποθαρρύνει τις 
επιδείξεις, οι οποίες αναζητούσαν επίσης τις θέσεις εργασίας. 
Μια ιδιωτική επιδιώκουσα εργασία σε μια καθιέρωση των 
ropemakers προκάλεσε μια αντιμετώπιση στην οδό βασιλιάδων της 
Βοστώνης. Όταν μερικοί στο πλήθος σφυροκόπησαν τους 
συγκεντρωμένους βρετανικούς στρατιώτες, τα στρατεύματα άνοιξαν 
την πυρκαγιά  πέντε άποικοι σκοτώθηκαν και πληγωμένος έξι.
Θ*Γεοργε Robert Twelves Hewes, ένας υποδηματοποιός 
της Βοστώνης, συμμετείχε σε πολλά από τα βασικά γεγονότα της 
επαναστατικής κρίσης. Κατά τη διάρκεια μισού αιώνα 
αργότερα, Hewes είπε james Hawkes για την παρουσία του στη
σφαγή της Βοστώνης και το συμβαλλόμενο μέρος τσαγιού της 
Βοστώνης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comenzando en el mid-1760s, los colonos comenzaron
a llevar las calles en Boston y otras ciudades portuarias. Las 
muchedumbres de artesanos y de trabajadores ensamblaron la élite en 
la protesta de políticas británicas, aunque sus puntas que 
diferenciaban de la visión revelaron las divisiones dentro de la 
sociedad colonial. Las protestas montaron en 1767 en que Gran 
Bretaña pasó el acto de Townsend, que incluyó una serie de 
impuestos impopulares. En Boston, el resentimiento y tense 
también creció sobre la presencia de tropas británicas, cuarteada 
en ciudad para desalentar las demostraciones, que también buscaban 
trabajos. Un trabajo que buscaba privado en un establecimiento 
de los ropemakers chispeó una confrontación en rey Street de Boston.
Cuando algunos en la muchedumbre lanzaron a soldados británicos
ensamblados, las tropas abrieron el fuego; mataron a cinco 
colonos y seises hirieron. George Roberto Twelves Hewes, 
zapatero de Boston, participado en muchos de los acontecimientos 
dominantes de la crisis revolucionaria. Sobre mitad del siglo 
más adelante, Hewes James dicho Hawkes sobre su presencia en la 
Masacre de Boston y el partido del té de Boston.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086189</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104340</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/george-hewes-recollection-of-the-boston-massacre</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
