<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104268</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104268</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086325</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">In the Richmond Slave Market</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im Richmond Sklavenmarkt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sur le marché Slave de Richmond</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No mercado slave de Richmond</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel mercato slave de Richmond</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στην αγορά σκλάβων του Ρίτσμοντ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el mercado auxiliar de Richmond</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1852-53, the popular British writer William Makepeace Thackeray toured the United States. While he lectured to enthralled American audiences, his secretary Eyre Crowe meticulously recorded the trip in words and pictures. Crowe, who studied painting in France, later published an illustrated memoir of the U.S. trip called  With Thackeray in America . Crowe included in his account a visit to the Richmond, Virginia, slave market where he witnessed and sketched a slave auction. As this excerpt demonstrates, his simple act of drawing the harsh circumstances of the slave trade was viewed by the auctioneer and planters as a threat. After his return to England, Crowe turned his sketches into a series of paintings that starkly depicted the auction and the subsequent forced separation of family members and friends.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1852-53 bereiste der populäre britische Verfasser
William Makepeace Thackeray die Vereinigten Staaten. Während er
zu bezauberten amerikanischen Publikum konferierte, speicherte seine 
Sekretärin Eyre Crowe genau die Reise in den Wörtern und in den 
Abbildungen. Crowe, das Anstrich in Frankreich studierte, 
veröffentlichte später eine erläuterte Abhandlung der VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Reise, die mit Thackeray in Amerika benannt wurde. 
Crowe, das in seinem Konto ein Besuch nach das Richmond, 
Virginia, Sklavenmarkt eingeschlossen ist, in dem er einen Sklaven 
zeugte und skizzierte, versteigern. Da dieses Excerpt zeigt,
wurde seine einfache Tat des Zeichnens der rauhen Umstände des Sklave
Handels vom Auktionator und von den Pflanzern als Drohung angesehen. 
Nachdem seine Rückkehr nach England, Crowe seine Skizzen zu 
eine Reihe Anstriche machte, die steif versteigerte und die folgende 
vorverlegte Trennung der Familie Bauteile und der Freunde bildlich 
darstellten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1852-53, l'auteur britannique populaire William
Makepeace Thackeray a voyagé les Etats-Unis. Tandis qu'il 
parlait aux assistances américaines fascinées, son secrétaire Eyre 
Crowe a méticuleusement enregistré le voyage dans les mots et les 
images. Crowe, qui a étudié la peinture en France, plus tard a
édité un mémoire illustré du voyage des ETATS-UNIS appelé avec 
Thackeray en Amérique. Crowe inclus dans son compte une visite 
à Richmond, la Virginie, marché slave où il était témoin et
a esquissé d'une enchère slave. Car cet extrait 
démontre, son acte simple de dessiner les circonstances dures du 
commerce slave a été visualisé par le commissaire-priseur et 
les planteurs comme menace. Après que son retour vers 
l'Angleterre, Crowe ait transformé ses croquis en série de peintures
qui ont rigide dépeint l'enchère et la séparation obligatoire 
ultérieure des membres et des amis de famille.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1852-53, o escritor britânico popular William 
Makepeace Thackeray excursionou os estados unidos. Quando 
lectured às audiências americanas enthralled, sua secretária Eyre 
Crowe gravou meticulosa o desengate nas palavras e nos retratos. 
Crowe, que estudou a pintura em France, publicou mais tarde um 
memoir ilustrado do desengate de ESTADOS UNIDOS chamado com o 
Thackeray em América. Crowe incluído em seu cliente uma visita
ao Richmond, Virgínia, mercado slave onde testemunhou e esboçou um 
auction slave. Porque este excerpt demonstra, seu ato simples de
desenhar as circunstâncias ásperas do comércio do escravo foi visto
pelo auctioneer e pelos plantadores como uma ameaça. Depois que
seu retorno a Inglaterra, Crowe girou seus esboços em uma série das 
pinturas que descreveram starkly o auction e a separação forçada 
subseqüente de membros e de amigos da família.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1852-53, il produttore che britannico popolare 
William Makepeace Thackeray ha fatto un giro del unito 
Dichiara. Mentre ha parlato ai pubblici americani 
enthralled, la sua segretaria Eyre Crowe meticoloso ha registrato il 
viaggio nelle parole e nelle immagini. Crowe, che ha studiato la
pittura in Francia, più successivamente ha pubblicato una memoria 
illustrata del viaggio degli STATI UNITI chiamato con Thackeray in 
America. Crowe incluso nel suo cliente una chiamata a Richmond, 
la Virginia, mercato slave in cui ha testimoniato ed abbozzato un'asta
slave. Poichè questo brano dimostra, il suo atto semplice di 
dissipare le circostanze dure del commercio dello schiavo è stato 
osservato dal auctioneer e dalle piantatrici come minaccia. Dopo
che il suo ritorno in Inghilterra, Crowe trasformi nei suoi abbozzi 
una serie di pitture che rigido hanno descritto l'asta e la 
separazione forzata successiva dei membri e degli amici della 
famiglia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1852-53, ο δημοφιλής βρετανικός συγγραφέας 
William Makepeace Thackeray περιόδευσε τις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες. Ενώ μίλησε τα αμερικανικά ακροατήρια, ο 
γραμματέας του eyre Crowe κατέγραψε σχολαστικά το ταξίδι 
στις λέξεις και τις εικόνες. Το Crowe, που μελέτησε τη 
ζωγραφική στη Γαλλία, δημοσίευσε αργότερα διευκρινισμένα 
απομνημονεύματα του ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ ταξιδιού που κλήθηκε με 
Thackeray στην Αμερική. Το Crowe περιέλαβε στον 
απολογισμό του μια επίσκεψη στο Ρίτσμοντ, Βιρτζίνια, αγορά 
σκλάβων όπου βεβαίωσε και σκιαγράφησε μια δημοπρασία σκλάβων. 
Όπως αυτό το απόσπασμα καταδεικνύει, η απλή πράξη του 
σχεδιασμού των σκληρών περιστάσεων του εμπορίου σκλάβων 
εμφανίστηκε από το auctioneer και τους καλλιεργητές ως απειλή. 
Μετά από την επιστροφή του στην Αγγλία, Crowe μετέτρεψε 
τα σκίτσα του σε σειρά έργων ζωγραφικής που απεικόνισε πλήρως τη
δημοπρασία και τον επόμενο αναγκασμένο χωρισμό των οικογενειακών 
μελών και των φίλων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1852-53, el programa de escritura británico 
popular Guillermo Makepeace Thackeray viajó los Estados Unidos. 
Mientras que él dio una conferencia a las audiencias americanas
cautivadas, su secretaria Eyre Crowe meticuloso registró el viaje en 
palabras y cuadros. Crowe, que estudió la pintura en Francia, 
publicó más adelante una memoria ilustrada del viaje de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS llamado con Thackeray en América. Crowe incluido en su 
cuenta una visita a la Richmond, Virginia, mercado auxiliar en donde 
él atestiguó y bosquejó una subasta auxiliar. Pues este 
extracto demuestra, su acto simple de trazar las circunstancias 
ásperas del comercio del esclavo fue visto por el auctioneer y los 
plantadores como amenaza. Después de que su vuelta a 
Inglaterra, Crowe diera vuelta a sus bosquejos en una serie de 
pinturas que rígido representaron la subasta y la separación forzada
subsecuente de los miembros y de los amigos de la familia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086325</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104268</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/in-the-richmond-slave-market</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
