<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105140</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105140</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087386</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">An Anarchist by Any Other Name: Albert Parsons and Anarchist Socialism</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Anarchist durch irgendeinen anderen Namen: 
Albert Pastor-und Anarchist sozialismus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un anarchiste par tout autre nom : 
Socialisme de pasteurs et d'anarchiste d'Albert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um anarquista por algum outro nome: 
Socialismo dos parsons e do anarquista de Albert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un anarchico da qualunque altro nome: 
Socialism dei parsons e dell'anarchico del Albert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας αναρχικός από οποιοδήποτε άλλοδήποτε όνομα: 
Αλβέρτος Parsons και σοσιαλισμός αναρχικών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un anarquista por cualquier otro nombre: 
Socialismo de los parsons y del anarquista de Albert</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Few terms have been surrounded with as much myth and misunderstanding as "anarchism." Part of the difficulty is that there are many kinds of anarchists. The high point of American anarchism surely came in the 1880s in the movement led by Chicago "Social Revolutionaries," such as Lucy and Albert Parsons. Contrary to the stereotype, anarchists like the Parsons did not object to order itself but to the oppressive forms of order imposed by the capitalist state. Albert Parsons also frankly acknowledged the belief shared by other anarchists in his circle that social transformation would only come through revolution, "through bloodshed and violence." What is perhaps less clear from the statement is Parsons's simultaneous commitment to trade unionism as the primary agency of social change. In this 1887 essay, "What Is Anarchism?" social revolutionary Parsons explained how his strain of anarchist socialism derived its name and purpose from the Greek words for "no" and "government."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wenige Bezeichnungen sind umgeben worden mit so 
vielem Mythus und Mißverständnis wie "Anarchie." Der Teil der 
Schwierigkeit ist, daß es viele Arten Anarchisten gibt. Der 
höchste Punkt der amerikanischen Anarchie kam sicher in das 1880s in 
der Bewegung, die durch Chicago "Sozialrevolutionäre," wie Lucy und 
Albert Pastoren geführt wurde. Gegenteil zum Stereotypen, 
Anarchisten wie die Pastoren wendete nicht gegen Ordnung selbst aber 
gegen die bedrückenden Formulare der Ordnung auferlegt durch den 
Kapitalistzustand ein. Albert Pastoren auch bestätigten 
aufrichtig den Glauben, der von anderen Anarchisten in seinem Kreis 
geteilt wurde, daß Sozialtransformation nur durch Umdrehung kommen 
würde, "durch Blutvergießen und Gewalttätigkeit." Was 
möglicherweise von der Anweisung weniger frei ist, ist die simultane 
Verpflichtung der Pastoren, zum von von unionism als die 
Primäragentur der Sozialänderung zu handeln. In diesem Versuch
1887 ", was ist Anarchie?" revolutionäre sozialpastoren 
erklärten, wie seine Belastung von Anarchist sozialismus berechnete 
seinen Namen und Zweck von den Griechewörtern für "nicht" und "von 
der Regierung."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Peu de limites ont été entourées avec autant 
mythe et malentendu que l'"anarchisme." Une partie de la 
difficulté est qu'il y a beaucoup de genres d'anarchistes. Le 
point élevé de l'anarchisme américain est sûrement venu dans le 
1880s dans le mouvement mené par Chicago "révolutionnaires sociaux,"
comme Lucy et pasteurs d'Albert. Le contraire au stéréotype, 
anarchistes comme les pasteurs ne s'est pas opposé à la commande 
elle-même mais aux formes accablantes de la commande imposées par 
l'état de capitaliste. Les pasteurs d'Albert également ont 
franchement reconnu la croyance partagée par d'autres anarchistes en 
son cercle que la transformation sociale viendrait seulement par la 
révolution, "par le carnage et la violence." Ce qui est 
peut-être moins clair du rapport est l'engagement simultané des 
pasteurs pour commercer le syndicalisme comme agence primaire de 
changement social. Dans cet essai 1887, "ce qui est 
l'anarchisme?" les pasteurs révolutionnaires sociaux ont 
expliqué comment sa contrainte de socialisme d'anarchiste a dérivé 
son nom et but des mots de Grec pour "pas" et du "gouvernement."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Poucos termos foram cercados com tantos mito e 
engano quanto o "anarchism." A parte da dificuldade é que há 
muitos tipos dos anarquistas. O ponto elevado do anarchism 
americano veio certamente no 1880s no movimento conduzido por Chicago 
"revolucionários sociais," como Lucy e parsons de Albert. O 
contrário ao stereotype, anarquistas como os parsons não objetou à 
ordem própria mas aos formulários oppressive da ordem impostos pelo 
estado do capitalista. Os parsons de Albert também reconheceram
frankly a opinião compartilhada por outros anarquistas em seu 
círculo que a transformação social viria somente com a volta, "com 
o bloodshed e a violência." O que está talvez mais menos 
desobstruído da indicação é compromisso simultâneo dos parsons 
para negociar o unionism como a agência preliminar da mudança 
social. Neste essay 1887, "o que é o anarchism?" os 
parsons revolucionários sociais explicaram como sua tensão do 
socialismo do anarquista derivou seus nome e finalidade das palavras 
do grego para "não" e do "governo."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pochi termini sono stati circondati con tanti mito
e misunderstanding quanto "l'anarchismo." La parte della 
difficoltà è che ci sono molti generi di anarchici. L'alto 
punto dell'anarchismo americano certamente è venuto nel 1880s nel 
movimento condotto da Chicago "rivoluzionari sociali," quali Lucy ed i
parsons del Albert. Il contrario allo stereotipo, anarchici come
i parsons non ha obiettato ad ordine in se ma alle forme oppressive di
ordine imposte dal capitalista dichiari. I parsons del 
Albert egualmente franco hanno riconosciuto la credenza compartecipe 
da altri anarchici nel suo cerchio che la trasformazione sociale 
verrebbe soltanto con il giro, "con massacro e la violenza." Che
cosa è forse meno chiaro dall'istruzione è impegno simultaneo dei 
parsons per commerciare il unionism come l'agenzia primaria di 
cambiamento sociale. In questo saggio 1887, "che cosa è 
l'anarchismo?" i parsons rivoluzionari sociali hanno spiegato 
come il suo sforzo del socialism dell'anarchico ha derivato il 
relativi nome e scopo dalle parole del Greco per "no" e "dal governo."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λίγοι όροι έχουν περιβληθεί με τόσους μύθο και 
παρανόηση όσος και "αναρχισμός." Μέρος της δυσκολίας είναι
ότι υπάρχουν πολλά είδη αναρχικών. Το υψηλό σημείο του 
αμερικανικού αναρχισμού ήρθε σίγουρα στο 1880s στη μετακίνηση 
που οδηγήθηκε από το Σικάγο "κοινωνικό Revolutionaries," όπως 
Lucy και Αλβέρτος Parsons. Το αντίθετο στο στερεότυπο, 
αναρχικοί όπως τους εφημερίους δεν αντιτέθηκε στην κατάταξη η 
ίδια αλλά στις καταπιεστικές μορφές της κατάταξης που 
επιβλήθηκαν από το κεφαλαιοκρατικό κράτος. Αλβέρτος 
Parsons επίσης ειλικρινά αναγνώρισε την πεποίθηση κοινή σε 
άλλους αναρχικούς στον κύκλο του ότι ο κοινωνικός 
μετασχηματισμός θα ερχόταν μόνο μέσω της επανάστασης, "μέσω της 
αιματοχυσίας και της βίας." Αυτό που είναι ίσως λιγότερο 
σαφές από τη δήλωση είναι ταυτόχρονη δέσμευση των εφημερίων για
τον εμπορικό συνδικαλισμό ως αρχική αντιπροσωπεία της κοινωνικής 
αλλαγής. Σε αυτό το δοκίμιο 1887, "τι είναι αναρχισμός;"
οι κοινωνικοί επαναστατικοί εφημέριοι εξήγησαν πώς η 
πίεσή του σοσιαλισμού αναρχικών άντλησε το όνομα και το σκοπό 
της από τις ελληνικές λέξεις για "το κανένα" και "την κυβέρνηση."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pocos términos se han rodeado con tanto mito y 
malentendido como el "anarquismo." La parte de la dificultad es 
que hay muchas clases de anarquistas. La alta punta del 
anarquismo americano vino seguramente en el 1880s en el movimiento 
conducido por Chicago "revolucionarios sociales," por ejemplo Lucy y 
los parsons de Albert. El contrario al estereotipo, anarquistas 
como los parsons no se opuso a la orden sí mismo sino a las formas 
opresivas de orden impuestas por el estado del capitalista. Los 
parsons de Albert también franco reconocieron la creencia compartida 
por otros anarquistas en su círculo que la transformación social 
vendría solamente con la revolución, "con matanza y violencia." 
Cuál está quizás menos claro de la declaración es 
consolidación simultánea de los parsons para negociar unionism como 
la agencia primaria del cambio social. En este ensayo 1887, 
"cuál es el anarquismo?" los parsons revolucionarios sociales 
explicaron cómo su tensión del socialismo del anarquista derivó su 
nombre y propósito de las palabras del Griego para "no" y del 
"gobierno."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087386</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105140</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/an-anarchist-by-any-other-name-albert-parsons-and-anarchist-socialism</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
