<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108740</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108740</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205973</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">MATHLINE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">MATHLINE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">MATHLINE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">MATHLINE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">MATHLINE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">MATHLINE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">MATHLINE</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a professional development program which provides Internet-based learning communities facilitated by experienced classroom teachers, a series of video lessons which allow teachers to make virtual visits to classrooms where teachers and students are engaged in standards-based instruction, and lesson guides along with suggested ideas for online discussions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein professionelles Entwicklungsprogramm, das 
die Internet-gegründeten erlernengemeinschaften liefert, die von 
erfahrenen Klassenzimmerlehrern, eine Reihe videolektionen erleichtert
werden, die Lehrern erlauben, virtuelle Besuche zu den Klassenzimmern 
zu bilden, in denen Lehrer und Kursteilnehmer an Standard-gegründeter
Anweisung teilnehmen, und Lektion führen zusammen mit vorgeschlagenen
Ideen für Onlinediskussionen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un programme de développement professionnel 
qui fournit les communautés d'étude Internet-basées facilitées par
les professeurs expérimentés de salle de classe, une série de 
leçons visuelles qui permettent à des professeurs de faire des 
visites virtuelles aux salles de classe où des professeurs et les 
étudiants sont engagés dans l'instruction norme-basée, et la leçon
guident avec des idées suggérées pour des discussions en ligne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um programa de desenvolvimento profissional que
forneça as comunidades de aprendizagem Internet-baseadas facilitadas 
por professores experientes da sala de aula, uma série das lições 
video que permitem que os professores façam visitas virtuais às 
salas de aula onde os professores e os estudantes são acoplados na 
instrução padrão-baseada, e a lição guia junto com idéias 
sugeridas para discussões em linha.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un programma di sviluppo professionale che 
fornisce alle Comunità imparanti Internet-basate facilitate dagli 
insegnanti con esperienza dell'aula, una serie di video lezioni che 
permettono che gli insegnanti facciano le chiamate virtuali alle aule 
in cui gli insegnanti e gli allievi sono agganciati nell'istruzione 
standard-basata e la lezione guida con le idee suggerite per le 
discussioni in linea.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένα επαγγελματικό πρόγραμμα ανάπτυξης που 
παρέχει τις Διαδίκτυο-βασισμένες μαθαίνοντας κοινότητες που 
διευκολύνονται από τους πεπειραμένους δασκάλους τάξεων, μια 
σειρά τηλεοπτικών μαθημάτων που επιτρέπουν στους δασκάλους για να
κάνουν τις εικονικές επισκέψεις στις τάξεις όπου οι δάσκαλοι και
οι σπουδαστές συμμετέχουν στην πρότυπο-βασισμένη στα οδηγία, και 
τους οδηγούς μαθήματος μαζί με τις προτεινόμενες ιδέες για τις σε
απευθείας σύνδεση συζητήσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un programa de desarrollo profesional que 
proporciona a las comunidades que aprenden Internet-basadas 
facilitadas por los profesores experimentados de la sala de clase, una
serie de lecciones video que permitan que los profesores hagan visitas
virtuales a las salas de clase en donde contratan a los profesores y a
los estudiantes a la instrucción esta'ndar-basada, y la lección 
dirige junto con las ideas sugeridas para las discusiones en línea.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205973</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108740</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mathline</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
