<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103083</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103083</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087449</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Broken Spirits: Letters on the Pullman Strike</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unterbrochener Geist: Zeichen auf dem 
Pullman-Schlag</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Spiritueux Cassés : Lettres sur la grève 
de pullman</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Espíritos Quebrados: Letras na batida do 
Pullman</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alcoolici Rotti: Lettere sul colpo del 
pullman</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σπασμένα πνεύματα: Επιστολές στην απεργία 
Pullman</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Alcoholes Quebrados: Cartas en la huelga del
pullman</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The American Railway Union's unsuccessful strike against the Pullman Palace Car Company in 1894 left many workers without jobs. Not only did the company take on hundreds of new workers in place of the strikers, but total employment in the shops dropped. On August 17, 1894, the desperate and destitute strikers appealed to Illinois Governor John P. Altgeld. The sympathetic governor wrote George Pullman a total of three times, asking him to do something about the "great distress" among his former workers. Typically, Pullman blamed the workers for their problems, arguing that if they had not struck they would not be suffering. He rejected the solutions proposed by Altgeld. The strikers' appeal to Altgeld and the governor's three letters to Pullman are included here. The public was more sympathetic with the plight of the Pullman workers. Contributions of food eased the distress and many Pullman residents eventually moved to find work elsewhere.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der amerikanischen Bahnerfolglose Schlag des 
anschlußes gegen Pullman Palace Car Company in 1894 ließ viele 
Arbeiter ohne Jobs. Nicht nur nahm die Firma auf Hunderten der 
neuen Arbeiter anstatt der Schlaggeräte, aber zählt Beschäftigung 
in den fallengelassenen Systemen zusammen. Auf August 17, 1894, 
den hoffnungslosen und hilflosen Schlaggeräten gefiel Illinois 
Gouverneur John P. Altgeld. Der sympatische Gouverneur schrieb 
George Pullman ein die Gesamtmenge von dreimal und bat ihn, etwas 
über die "große Bedrängnis" unter seinen ehemaligen Arbeitern zu 
tun. Gewöhnlich tadelte Pullman die Arbeiter für ihre Probleme
und argumentierte, daß, wenn sie nicht angeschlagen hatten, sie nicht
leiden würden. Er wies die Lösungen zurück, die von Altgeld 
vorgeschlagen wurden. Der Anklang der Schlaggeräte an Altgeld 
und die Zeichen des Reglers drei zum Pullman sind hier eingeschlossen.
Die Öffentlichkeit war mit der Lage der Pullmanarbeiter 
sympatischer. Beiträge der Nahrung erleichterten die 
Bedrängnis und viele Pullmanbewohner, die schließlich anderwohin auf
Entdeckungarbeit verschoben wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La grève non réussie des syndicats ferroviaires 
américains contre Pullman Palace Car Company dans 1894 a laissé 
beaucoup d'ouvriers sans travaux. Non seulement la compagnie 
a-t-elle pris des centaines de nouveaux ouvriers au lieu des butées, 
mais se monte-t-elle à l'emploi dans les systèmes lâchés. 
17 août 1894, les butées désespérées et indigentes a fait 
appel au Gouverneur John P. Altgeld de l'Illinois. Le gouverneur
bien disposé a écrit à pullman de George par total de trois 
fois, lui demandant de faire quelque chose au sujet de la "grande 
détresse" parmi ses anciens ouvriers. Typiquement, le pullman a
blâmé les ouvriers de leurs problèmes, arguant du fait que s'ils 
n'avaient pas heurté ils ne souffriraient pas. Il a rejeté les
solutions proposées par Altgeld. L'appel des butées à Altgeld
et les lettres du gouverneur trois au pullman sont inclus ici. 
Le public était plus bien disposé avec la situation difficile 
des ouvriers de pullman. Les contributions de la nourriture ont 
soulagé la détresse et beaucoup de résidants de pullman par la 
suite déplacés au travail de trouvaille ailleurs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A batida mal sucedida da união railway americana 
de encontro ao Pullman Palácio Carro Companhia em 1894 deixou muitos 
trabalhadores sem trabalhos. Não somente a companhia fêz exame
em centenas de trabalhadores novos no lugar dos grevistas, mas 
totaliza o emprego nas lojas deixadas cair. Agosto em 17, 1894, 
nos grevistas desesperados e destitute apelou ao regulador John P. 
Altgeld de Illinois. O regulador sympathetic escreveu a Pullman 
de George um um total de três vezes, pedindo que faça algo sobre "a 
aflição grande" entre seus trabalhadores anteriores. 
Tipicamente, o Pullman responsabilizou os trabalhadores por seus
problemas, discutindo que se não golpeassem não estariam sofrendo. 
Rejeitou as soluções propostas por Altgeld. A apelação
dos grevistas a Altgeld e as letras do regulador três ao Pullman são
incluídas aqui. O público era mais sympathetic com o plight 
dos trabalhadores do Pullman. As contribuições do alimento 
facilitaram a aflição e muitos residentes do Pullman movidos 
eventualmente para o trabalho do achado em outra parte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il colpo infruttuoso del sindacato ferroviario 
americano contro il Pullman Palace Car Company in 1894 ha lasciato 
molti operai senza lavori. L'azienda ha intrapreso non soltanto 
i centinaia di nuovi operai al posto dei percussori, ma ammonta 
all'occupazione nei negozi caduti. Il 17 agosto 1894, i 
percussori disperati ed indigenti ha fatto appello al regolatore John 
P. Altgeld dell'Illinois. Il regolatore simpatico ha scritto a 
pullman di George un un totale di tre volte, chiedentegli di fare 
qualcosa circa "l'afflizione grande" fra i suoi ex operai. 
Tipicamente, il pullman ha incolpato degli operai i loro 
problemi, sostenenti che se non avessero colpito non stavano 
soffrendo. Ha rifiutato le soluzioni proposte da Altgeld. 
L'appello dei percussori a Altgeld e le lettere del regolatore 
tre al pullman sono inclusi qui. Il pubblico era più simpatico 
con la situazione difficile degli operai del pullman. I 
contributi di alimento hanno facilitato l'afflizione e molti residenti
del pullman finalmente spostati verso il lavoro del ritrovamento 
altrove.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ανεπιτυχής απεργία της αμερικανικής ένωσης 
σιδηροδρόμων ενάντια στο Pullman Palace Car Company το 
1894 άφησε πολλούς εργαζομένους χωρίς εργασίες. Όχι 
μόνο η επιχείρηση πήρε τις εκατοντάδες των νέων εργαζομένων 
αντί των απεργών, αλλά συμπληρώνει συνολικά την απασχόληση στα 
καταστήματα που έπεσαν. Στις 17 Αυγούστου ..1894, οι 
απελπισμένοι και άποροι απεργοί απευθύνθηκαν στο Ιλλινόις 
Governor John Σελ. Altgeld. Ο συμπονετικός κυβερνήτης
έγραψε σε George Pullman συνολικά τρεις χρόνους, ζητώντας 
τον για να κάνει κάτι για το "μεγάλο κίνδυνο" μεταξύ των 
προηγούμενων εργαζομένων του. Χαρακτηριστικά, Pullman 
κατηγόρησε τους εργαζομένους για τα προβλήματά τους, που 
υποστηρίζουν ότι εάν δεν είχαν χτυπήσει δεν θα υπέφεραν. 
Απέρριψε τις λύσεις που προτάθηκαν από Altgeld. Η 
έκκληση των απεργών σε Altgeld και οι τρεις επιστολές του 
κυβερνήτη σε Pullman συμπεριλαμβάνονται εδώ. Το κοινό 
ήταν πιό συμπονετικό με τη δύσκολη θέση των εργαζομένων 
Pullman. Οι συνεισφορές των τροφίμων διευκόλυναν τον 
κίνδυνο και πολλούς κατοίκους Pullman που κινήθηκαν τελικά για
να βρούν την εργασία αλλού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La huelga fracasada de la unión ferroviaria 
americana contra el Pullman Palace Car Company en 1894 dejó a muchos 
trabajadores sin trabajos. La compañía adquirió no sólo 
centenares de nuevos trabajadores en lugar de los huelguistas, sino 
suma el empleo en los departamentos caídos. 17 de agosto de 
1894, los huelguistas desesperados e indigentes abrogó al gobernador 
Juan P. Altgeld de Illinois. El gobernador comprensivo escribió
a pullman de George al total de tres veces, pidiendo que él haga algo
sobre la "gran señal de socorro" entre sus trabajadores anteriores. 
Típicamente, el pullman culpó a trabajadores por sus 
problemas, discutiendo que si no pulso no estarían sufriendo. 
Él rechazó las soluciones propuestas por Altgeld. La 
súplica de los huelguistas a Altgeld y las cartas del gobernador tres
al pullman se incluyen aquí. El público era más comprensivo 
con el apuro de los trabajadores del pullman. Las contribuciones
del alimento facilitaron a la señal de socorro y a muchos residentes 
del pullman movidos eventual al trabajo del hallazgo a otra parte.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087449</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103083</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/broken-spirits-letters-on-the-pullman-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
