<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104196</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104196</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206523</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Raid on Deerfield: the Many Stories of 1704</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Überfall auf Deerfield: die vielen 
Geschichten von 1704</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Incursion sur Deerfield : les nombreuses 
histoires de 1704</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Invasão em Deerfield: muitas histórias de 
1704</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Incursione su Deerfield: le molte storia di 
1704</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιδρομή σε Deerfield: οι πολλές ιστορίες 
1704</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Incursión en Deerfield: las muchas 
historias de 1704</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the story that began when 300 French and Native allies invaded the English settlement of Deerfield, MA. They captured 112 Deerfield men, women, and children, whom they marched 300 miles to Canada. A number died or were killed on route; most were ransomed. Later, over one-third chose to remain among their captors. Events are examined from 5 perspectives: the Mohawk, Abenaki, Huron, French, and English. More than 100 artifacts, 13 interactive maps, and 100 illustrations are included.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichte, die, als 300 französisch
und gebürtige Verbündete die englische Regelung von Deerfield 
eindrangen, MA anfing. Sie erfaßten 112 Deerfield Männer, 
Frauen und Kinder, die sie 300 Meilen nach Kanada grenzten. Eine
Zahl starb oder wurde auf Weg beendet; die meisten waren 
ransomed. Später, über Drittel beschloß, unter ihren Fängern
zu bleiben. Fälle werden von 5 Perspektiven überprüft: 
der Mohikaner, das Abenaki, der Hurone, die Franzosen und 
Englisch. Mehr als 100 Kunstprodukte, 13 interaktive Karten und 
100 Abbildungen sind enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit l'histoire qui a commencé quand 300 français
et alliés indigènes ont envahi le règlement anglais de Deerfield, 
mA. Ils ont capturé 112 hommes, femmes, et enfants de 
Deerfield, qu'ils ont marchés 300 milles au Canada. Un nombre 
est mort ou a été détruit sur l'itinéraire ; les la plupart 
étaient ransomed. Plus tard, plus d'un tiers a choisi de rester
parmi leurs ravisseurs. Des événements sont examinés de 5 
perspectives : le Mohawk, l'Abenaki, l'Huron, le Français, et 
l'anglais. Plus de 100 objets façonnés, 13 cartes 
interactives, et 100 illustrations sont inclus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz a história que começou quando 300 franceses 
e os aliados nativos invadiram o estabelecimento inglês de Deerfield,
miliampère. Capturaram 112 homens, mulheres, e crianças de 
Deerfield, quem marcharam 300 milhas a Canadá. Um número 
morreu ou foi matado na rota; a maioria eram ransomed. 
Mais atrasado, sobre um terço escolheu remanescer entre seus 
captores. Os eventos são examinados de 5 perspectives: o 
mohawk, o Abenaki, o huron, o francês, e o inglês. Mais de 100
artifacts, 13 mapas interativos, e 100 ilustrações são incluídos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alla storia che ha cominciato quando 300 
francesi e gli alleati natali hanno invaso lo stabilimento inglese di 
Deerfield, mA. Hanno bloccato 112 uomini, donne e bambini di 
Deerfield, quale hanno marciato 300 miglia nel Canada. Un numero
è morto o è stato ucciso sull'itinerario; la maggior parte 
erano ransomed. Successivamente, oltre un terzo ha scelto 
rimanere fra i loro rapitori. Gli eventi sono esaminati da 5 
prospettive: il mohawk, il Abenaki, il huron, il francese e 
l'inglese. Più di 100 manufatti, 13 programmi interattivi e 100
illustrazioni sono inclusi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει την ιστορία που άρχισε όταν εισέβαλαν 300 
γαλλικοί και εγγενείς σύμμαχοι στην αγγλική τακτοποίηση 
Deerfield, μΑ. Συνέλαβαν τους 112 άνδρες Deerfield, 
γυναίκες, και παιδιά, οι οποίοι βάδισαν 300 μίλια στον 
Καναδά. Ένας αριθμός πέθανε ή σκοτώθηκε στη διαδρομή  
οι περισσότεροι εξαγοράστηκαν. Αργότερα, πέρα από το 
ένα τρίτο επέλεξε να παραμείνει μεταξύ των αιχμαλωτιζόντων τους.
Τα γεγονότα εξετάζονται από 5 προοπτικές: το 
Mohawk, το Abenaki, huron, οι Γάλλοι, και οι Αγγλοι. 
Περισσότερα από 100 χειροποίητα αντικείμενα, 13 
διαλογικοί χάρτες, και 100 απεικονίσεις συμπεριλαμβάνονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta la historia que comenzó cuando 300 
franceses y los aliados nativos invadieron el establecimiento inglés 
de Deerfield, mA. Capturaron a 112 hombres, mujeres, y niños de
Deerfield, a que marcharon 300 millas a Canadá. Un número 
murió o fue matado en la ruta; la mayoría eran ransomed. 
Más adelante, sobre una mitad eligió permanecer entre sus 
captores. Los acontecimientos se examinan a partir de 5 
perspectivas: el mohawk, el Abenaki, el huron, el francés, y el
inglés. Más de 100 artefactos, 13 correspondencias 
interactivas, y 100 ilustraciones son incluidos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206523</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104196</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/raid-on-deerfield-the-many-stories-of-1704</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
