<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104216</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104216</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087205</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Tho[ugh]t State Street Would Be Heaven Itself":  Black Migrants Speak Out</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wir Tho[ugh]t Zustand-Straße Würden Himmel 
Selbst" Sein: Schwarze Wanderer Sprechen Heraus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nous Rue D'État de Tho[ugh]t Serions Le Ciel 
Lui-même" : Les Migrants Noirs Parlent Dehors</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nós Rua Do Estado De Tho[ugh]t Seríamos O 
Heaven Próprio": Os Emigrantes Pretos Falam Para fora</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Che Tho[ugh]t Dichiara La Via Saremmo 
Cielo In se": I Migranti Neri Parlano Fuori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κρατική Tho[ugh]t οδός θα ήμαστε ο ίδιος 
ουρανόσ": Οι μαύροι μετανάστες μιλούν έξω</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Calle Del Estado De Tho[ugh]t Seríamos El Cielo 
Sí mismo": Los Nómadas Negros Hablan Hacia fuera</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the Great Migration, which peaked between 1916 and 1921, some 5 percent of all southern African Americans headed north. What were their experiences like in their new homes? Beginning in 1917, Charles Johnson, research investigator for the Chicago Urban League, began interviewing migrants in Chicago and Mississippi. Going door to door, Johnson questioned recent southern black migrants to Chicago about their histories and current thoughts about their experiences. Johnson's summaries of his interviews conveyed a sense of migrants' diverse response to life in Chicago.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während der großen Migration die zwischen 1916 
und 1921 emporragte, gehen irgendwelche 5 Prozent aller südlichen 
afrikanischen Amerikaner nördlich voran. Wie sahen ihre 
Erfahrungen in ihren neuen Häusern aus? Anfangend 1917, fing 
Charles Johnson, Forschung Forscher für die Chicago städtische Liga 
an, Wanderer in Chicago und in Mississippi zu interviewen. 
Gehende Tür zur Tür, Johnson fragte neue südliche schwarze 
Wanderer zu Chicago über ihre Geschichten und aktuellen Gedanken 
über ihre Erfahrungen. Zusammenfassungen Johnsons seiner 
Interviews übermittelten eine Richtung der verschiedenen Antwort der 
Wanderer zum Leben in Chicago.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant le grand transfert, qui a fait une pointe 
entre 1916 et 1921, environ 5 pour cent de tous les Américains 
africains méridionaux se dirigent au nord. À quoi 
ressemblaient leurs expériences de leurs nouvelles maisons ? 
Commençant en 1917, Charles Johnson, investigateur de 
recherches pour la ligue urbaine de Chicago, a commencé à 
interviewer des migrants à Chicago et au Mississippi. La porte 
allante à la porte, Johnson a interrogé les migrants noirs 
méridionaux récents à Chicago au sujet de leurs histoires et 
pensées actuelles au sujet de leurs expériences. Les sommaires
de Johnson de ses entrevues ont donné un sens de la réponse 
diverse des migrants à la vie Chicago.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante a migração grande, que peaked entre 1916
e 1921, uns 5 por cento de todos os americanos africanos do sul 
dirigem para o norte. Que eram suas experiências como em suas 
HOME novas? Começando em 1917, Charles Johnson, investigator da
pesquisa para a liga urbana de Chicago, começou a entrevistar 
emigrantes em Chicago e em Mississippi. A porta indo à porta, 
Johnson questionou emigrantes pretos do sul recentes a Chicago sobre 
seus histories e pensamentos atuais sobre suas experiências. Os
sumários de Johnson de suas entrevistas fizeram saber a um sentido da
resposta diversa dos emigrantes à vida em Chicago.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante l'espansione grande, che ha alzato fra 
1916 e 1921, circa 5 per cento di tutti gli Americani africani del sud
dirigono a nord. Che cosa erano le loro esperienze come delle 
loro nuove sedi? Cominciando in 1917, Charles Johnson, 
ricercatore di ricerca per la lega urbana del Chicago, ha cominciato 
ad intervistare i migranti Chicago e nel Mississippi. Il 
portello andante al portello, Johnson ha interrogato i migranti neri 
del sud recenti a Chicago circa i loro dati storici e pensieri 
correnti circa le loro esperienze. I sommari del Johnson delle 
sue interviste hanno trasportato un senso della risposta varia dei 
migranti a vita in Chicago.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια της μεγάλης μετανάστευσης, που όξυνε
μεταξύ 1916 και 1921, περίπου 5 τοις εκατό όλων των νότιων 
αφρικανικών Αμερικανών διεύθυναν το Βορρά. Ποια ήταν η 
εμπειρία τους όπως στα νέα σπίτια τους; Αρχίζοντας το 
1917, Charles Johnson, ερευνητικός ανακριτής για την 
αστική ένωση του Σικάγου, άρχισε τους μετανάστες στο Σικάγο και 
το Μισισιπή. Η μετάβαση από σπίτι σε σπίτι, Johnson 
εξέτασε τους πρόσφατους νότιους μαύρους μετανάστες στο Σικάγο 
για τις ιστορίες και τις παρούσες σκέψεις τους για την εμπειρία 
τους. Οι περιλήψεις του Johnson των συνεντεύξεών του 
μεταβίβασαν μια αίσθηση της διαφορετικής απάντησης των μεταναστών
στη ζωή στο Σικάγο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la gran migración, que enarboló entre 
1916 y 1921, un ciertos 5 por ciento de todos los americanos africanos
meridionales dirigieron al norte. ¿Cuáles eran sus experiencias
como en sus nuevos hogares? Comenzando en 1917, Charles Johnson,
investigador de la investigación para la liga urbana de Chicago, 
comenzó a entrevistarse con a nómadas en Chicago y Mississippi. 
La puerta que iba a la puerta, Johnson preguntó a nómadas 
negros meridionales recientes a Chicago sobre sus historias y 
pensamientos actuales sobre sus experiencias. Los resúmenes de 
Johnson de sus entrevistas transportaron un sentido de la respuesta 
diversa de los nómadas a la vida en Chicago.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087205</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104216</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-tho-ugh-t-state-street-would-be-heaven-itself-black-migrants-speak-out</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
