<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105025</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105025</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1879158218</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Excitatory Topics in Physics</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Excitatory Themen in der Physik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sujets excitatoires dans la physique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tópicos excitatory na física</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Soggetti excitatory nella fisica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενισχυτικά θέματα στη φυσική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Asuntos excitatory en la física</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">What sorts of things get physicists (or wannabe physicists, like the teacher of this class) excited? Is it the dream of building grand intellectual edifices capable of describing the Universe with amazing accuracy and elegance? Or, perhaps, discovering something so unexpected that it totally blows your mind? Maybe it's simply the act of doing physics! Whatever the case, there are certainly many things in physics to get excited about, and we'll explore some of them in this class.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Welche Sortierungen von Sachen erhalten Physiker 
(oder wannabe Physiker, wie der Lehrer dieser Kategorie) aufregten? 
Ist es der Traum der großartigen intellektuellen Gebäude des 
Gebäudes, die zum Beschreiben des Universums mit erstaunlicher 
Genauigkeit und Eleganz fähig sind? Oder etwas möglicherweise 
entdeckend so unerwartet, daß es total Ihren Verstand durchbrennt? 
Möglicherweise ist es einfach die Tat des Tuns von von Physik! 
Was auch immer der Fall, dort zweifellos viele Sachen in der 
Physik sind, zum ungefähr aufgeregt zu erhalten und wir erforscht 
einige von ihnen in dieser Kategorie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quels tris des choses obtiennent des physiciens 
(ou des physiciens de wannabe, comme le professeur de cette classe) 
ont excité ? Est-ce le rêve des édifices intellectuels grands
de bâtiment capables de décrire l'univers avec l'exactitude et 
l'élégance étonnantes ? Ou, peut-être, découvrant quelque 
chose si inattendue qu'elle souffle totalement votre esprit ? 
Peut-être c'est simplement l'acte de faire la physique ! 
Celui que le cas, là soient certainement beaucoup de choses 
dans la physique à obtenir passionnant'environ, et nous explorera 
certains d'entre eux dans cette classe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Que sortes das coisas começam físicos (ou 
físicos do wannabe, como o professor desta classe) excitaram? 
É o sonho dos edifices intelectuais grandes do edifício 
capazes de descrever o universo com exatidão e elegance 
surpreendentes? Ou, talvez, descobrindo algo assim inesperado 
que funde totalmente sua mente? Talvez é simplesmente o ato de 
fazer a física! O que quer que o caso, lá é certamente muitas
coisas na física a começar excitada aproximadamente, e nós 
explorará alguma deles nesta classe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Che ordinamenti delle cose ottengono i fisici (o i
fisici del wannabe, come l'insegnante di questo codice categoria) 
hanno eccitato? È il sogno di grandi strutture intellettuali 
della costruzione capaci di descrizione dell'universo con esattezza e 
l'eleganza stupefacenti? O, forse, scoprendo qualcosa così 
inattesa che completamente salta la vostra mente? Forse è 
semplicemente l'atto di fare la fisica! Qualunque il caso, là 
è certamente molte cose nella fisica da ottenere eccitata circa e noi
esplorerà loro alcune in questo codice categoria.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ποια είδη των πραγμάτων παίρνουν τους φυσικούς (ή 
wannabe τους φυσικούς, όπως το δάσκαλο αυτής της κλάσης) 
συγκινημένους; Είναι το όνειρο της οικοδόμησης των μεγάλων 
διανοητικών οικοδομημάτων ικανών τον κόσμο με την καταπληκτικές 
ακρίβεια και την κομψότητα; Ή, ίσως, ανακαλύπτοντας κάτι 
τόσο απροσδόκητο που φυσά συνολικά το μυαλό σας; Ίσως 
είναι απλά η πράξη να κάνει τη φυσική! Οποιοσδήποτε η 
περίπτωση, υπάρχουν βεβαίως πολλά πράγματα στη φυσική που 
παίρνει συγκινημένη περίπου, και θα εξερευνήσουμε μερικά από τα 
σε αυτήν την κλάση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Qué clases de cosas consiguen a físicos (o a 
físicos del wannabe, como el profesor de esta clase) excitaron? 
¿Es el sueño de los edificios intelectuales magníficos del 
edificio capaces de describir el universo con exactitud y elegancia 
asombrosas? ¿O, quizás, descubriendo algo tan inesperado que 
sopla totalmente su mente? ¡Es quizá simplemente el acto de 
hacer la física! Lo que el caso, allí es ciertamente muchas 
cosas en la física a conseguir excitada alrededor, y nosotros 
explorará a algunos de ellos en esta clase.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DIBELLA, NICHOLAS
FN:DIBELLA, NICHOLAS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1879158218</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105025</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/excitatory-topics-in-physics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
