<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105554</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105554</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086701</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Organize among Yourselves": Mary Gale on Unemployed Organizing in the Great Depression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"organisieren Sie unter": Mary Sturm auf den
Arbeitslosen, die im großen Tiefstand organisieren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"organisez parmi vous-mêmes" : Rafale de 
Mary sur des chômeurs organisant dans la grande dépression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"organize entre yourselves": Vendaval de 
Mary nos desempregados que organizam no depression grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"organizzi fra voi": Vento fortissimo della 
Mary sui disoccupati che organizzano nella depressione grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οργανώστε μεταξύ σασ": Θ*Μαρυ Gale στους 
ανέργους που οργανώνουν στη μεγάλη οικονομική κρίση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"ordene entre ustedes mismos": Vendaval de 
Maria en los parados que ordenan en la gran depresión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Communist-led Unemployed Councils were the first and the most active of the radical movements that sought to mobilize the jobless during the Great Depression. In this interview, which is taken from the radio series "Grandma Was an Activist," relief worker Mary Gale, who was sympathetic to radicals and the jobless, described how she worked behind the scenes to encourage her clients to organize and demand better treatment. The jobless and the poor had few advocates for them, and radicals like Gale not only became their champions but also pushed them to organize themselves.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Kommunistisch-führenden arbeitslosen Räte 
waren die ersten und der radikalen Bewegungen das aktivste, die 
suchten, das arbeitslose während des großen Tiefstands zu 
mobilisieren. In diesem Interview das von der Radioserie 
"genommen wird, Großmutter war ein Aktivist," Entlastung Arbeiter 
Mary Sturm, der zu den Radikalen und zum arbeitslosen sympatisch war, 
beschrieben, wie sie hinter den Szenen arbeitete, um ihre Klienten 
anzuregen, bessere Behandlung zu organisieren und zu verlangen. 
Das arbeitslose und die Armen hatten wenige Fürsprecher für 
sie und Radikale, wie Sturm nicht nur ihren Meistern stand, aber 
drückten sie auch, um sich zu organisieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Conseils sans emploi Communiste-menés 
étaient les premiers et les plus en activité des mouvements radicaux
qui ont recherché à mobiliser le sans emploi pendant la grande 
dépression. Dans cette entrevue, qui est prise de la série par
radio la "grand-maman était une activiste," la rafale de Mary 
d'ouvrier de soulagement, qui était sympathique aux radicaux et au 
sans emploi, décrit comment elle a travaillé dans les coulisses pour
encourager ses clients à organiser et exiger un meilleur traitement. 
Le sans emploi et les pauvres ont eu peu d'avocats pour eux, et 
radicaux comme la rafale allait bien non seulement à leurs champions 
mais les ont également poussés pour s'organiser.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os conselhos unemployed Comunista-conduzidos eram 
os primeiros e os mais ativos dos movimentos radicais que procuraram 
mobilize o jobless durante o depression grande. Nesta 
entrevista, que é feita exame da série de rádio o "grandma era uma 
activista," o vendaval de Mary do trabalhador do relevo, que era 
sympathetic aos radicais e ao jobless, descrito como trabalhou atrás 
das cenas para incentivar seus clientes organizar e exijir o 
tratamento melhor. O jobless e os pobres tiveram poucos 
advogados para eles, e radicais como o vendaval assentou bem não 
somente em seus campeões mas empurraram-nos também para 
organizar-se.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I Consigli disoccupati Comunista-condotti erano i 
primi ed i più attivi dei movimenti radicali che hanno cercato di 
mobilitare il senza lavoro durante la depressione grande. In 
questa intervista, che è presa dalla serie radiofonica "il grandma 
era un Attivista," vento fortissimo della Mary dell'operaio di 
rilievo, che era simpatico ai radicali ed al senza lavoro, descritto 
come ha lavorato dietro le scene per consigliare ai suoi clienti 
organizzare e richiedere il trattamento migliore. Il senza 
lavoro ed il povero hanno avuti pochi fautori per loro e radicali
come il vento fortissimo ha stato bene non soltanto ai loro campioni 
ma egualmente li hanno spinti per organizzarsi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα κομμουνιστικός-οδηγημένα άνεργα Συμβούλια ήταν οι 
πρώτες και οι πιό ενεργές των ριζικών μετακινήσεων που επιδίωξαν
να κινητοποιήσουν τους ανέργους κατά τη διάρκεια της μεγάλης 
οικονομικής κρίσης. Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη, που λαμβάνεται
από τη ραδιο σειρά "Grandma ήταν ενεργό στέλεχος," 
εργαζόμενος Mary Gale ανακούφισης, που ήταν συμπονετικός 
στους ριζοσπάστες και τους ανέργους, περιέγραψε πώς εργάστηκε 
πίσω από τις σκηνές για να ενθαρρύνει τους χρήστες της για να 
οργανώσει και να απαιτήσει την καλύτερη επεξεργασία. Οι 
άνεργοι και οι φτωχοί είχαν λίγους συνηγόρους για τους, και οι 
ριζοσπάστες όπως τη θύελλα όχι μόνο έγιναν οι πρωτοπόροι τους 
αλλά και τους ώθησαν για να οργανωθούν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los consejos parados Comunista-conducidos eran los
primeros y los más activos de los movimientos radicales que 
intentaron movilizar el desempleado durante la gran depresión. 
En esta entrevista, que se toma de la serie de radio el "grandma
era un activista," el vendaval de Maria del trabajador de la 
relevación, que era comprensivo a los radicales y al desempleado, 
descrito cómo ella trabajó detrás de las escenas para animar a sus 
clientes que ordenen y exijan un tratamiento mejor. El 
desempleado y los pobres tenían pocos abogados para ellos, y 
radicales como sintió bien el vendaval no solamente a sus campeones 
pero también los empujaron para ordenarse.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086701</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105554</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/organize-among-yourselves-mary-gale-on-unemployed-organizing-in-the-great-depression</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
