<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103324</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103324</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086156</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Fighting Discrimination in Mexican American Education</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kämpfende Unterscheidung in der mexikanischen 
amerikanischen Ausbildung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Discrimination de combat dans l'éducation 
américaine mexicaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Discriminação de combate na instrução 
americana mexicana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Distinzione di combattimento nella formazione 
americana messicana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πάλη της διάκρισης στη μεξικάνικη αμερικανική 
εκπαίδευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Discriminación que lucha en la educación 
americana mexicana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">With the annexation of Texas in 1848 at the end of the Mexican-American War, Tejanos--Texans of Mexican descent--lost property rights and political power in a society dominated by Anglos. Through discriminatory practices and violent force, Tejanos were kept at the bottom of the new political and socio-cultural order. From 1900-1930, as an influx of immigrants from Mexico came north to meet a growing demand for cheap labor in the developing commercial agriculture industries, Tejanos experienced continued discrimination in employment, housing, public facilities, the judicial system, and educational institutions. Many school districts segregated Tejano and Anglo children into separate facilities. The Mexican schools were grossly underfunded and often offered only a grade school education. In 1930, when 90% of the schools in South Texas were segregated, the League of United Latin American Citizens (LULAC), a Tejano advocacy group, supported a court challenge to school segregation. The Texas Court of Appeals, however, ruled that school districts could use such criteria as language and irregular attendance due to seasonal work to separate students. The struggle of Mexican Americans to end discriminatory practices accelerated following World War II. In 1948, LULAC and the newly formed American G.I. Forum, an advocacy group of Mexican American veterans, assisted in a lawsuit that eventuated in a federal district court decision prohibiting school segregation based on Mexican ancestry. Localities evaded the ruling, however, and de facto segregation continued. In 1955, LULAC and the Forum initiated a suit protesting the practice of placing Tejano children into separate classes for the first two grades of school and requiring four years to compete these grades. Ed Idar of the Forum, in an interview below, discussed this practice, which was finally outlawed in 1957. Student protests in the late 1960s--supported and complemented by a new civil rights organization, the Mexican American Legal Defense and Educational Fund (MALDEF)--achieved an end to more discriminatory practices and the introduction of bilingual and bicultural programs into schools. In the second interview, Pete Tijerina, the founder of MALDEF, related a successful student protest against discrimination.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mit der Annexion von Texas 1848 am Ende des 
Mexikanisch-Amerikanischen Krieges, vorherrsch Tejanos -- Texans des 
mexikanischen Abfalls -- verlorene Eigentumsrechte und politische 
Energie in einer Gesellschaft durch Anglos. Durch 
diskriminierende Praxis und heftige Kraft wurden Tejanos an der 
Unterseite der neuen politischen und soziologisch-kulturellen Ordnung 
gehalten. Von 1900-1930 während ein Zufluß der Immigranten von
Mexiko nördlich kam, eine steigende Nachfrage nach preiswerter Arbeit
in den sich entwickelnden kommerziellen Landwirtschaft Industrien zu 
treffen, erfuhr Tejanos anhaltende Unterscheidung in der 
Beschäftigung, im Gehäuse, in den allgemeinen Teildiensten, im 
Gerichtssystem und in den pädagogischen Anstalten. Viele 
Schulebezirke trennten Tejano und Anglokinder in unterschiedliche 
Teildienste. Die mexikanischen Schulen waren underfunded grob 
und anboten häufig nur eine Gradschuleausbildung. 1930 als 90% 
der Schulen in Südtexas getrennt wurden, unterstützte die Liga der 
vereinigten lateinamerikanischen Bürger (LULAC), eine Tejano 
Befürwortung Gruppe, eine Gerichtherausforderung, um Abtrennung zu 
schulen. Das Texas Gericht von Anklänge ordnete jedoch an, daß
Schulebezirke solche Kriterien wie die Sprache und unregelmäßige 
Anwesenheit verwenden konnten wegen der Saisonarbeit, Kursteilnehmer 
zu trennen. Der Kampf der mexikanischen Amerikaner, zum der 
diskriminierenden Praxis zu beenden beschleunigte den folgenden 
Zweiten Weltkrieg. 1948, LULAC und eben gebildete amerikanische 
G.I. Forum, gründete eine Befürwortung Gruppe mexikanische 
amerikanische Veterane, unterstützt in einem Prozeß, der in einer 
Bundesamtsgericht-Entscheidung verbietenden Schuleabtrennung 
eventuated, auf mexikanischem Geschlecht. Stellen wichen dem 
Anordnen aus, jedoch und de Facto Abtrennung fuhr fort. 1955 
initialisieren LULAC und das Forum eine Klage, welche die Praxis des 
Plazierens der Tejano Kinder in unterschiedliche Kategorien für die 
ersten zwei Grade der Schule und des Benötigens von von vier Jahren, 
um zu konkurrieren diese Grade protestiert. ED Idar des Forums, 
in einem Interview unten, behandelte diese Praxis, die schließlich 
1957 geächtet wurde. Kursteilnehmer protestiert in den späten 
sechziger Jahren -- unterstützt und durch eine neue 
Zivilrechtorganisation, die mexikanische amerikanische zugelassene 
Verteidigung und pädagogische Kapital ergägenzt (MALDEF) -- erzielte
ein Ende zur diskriminierenderen Praxis und die Einleitung der 
zweisprachigen und bikulturellen Programme in Schulen. Im 
zweiten Interview stand Peter Tijerina, der Gründer von MALDEF, einen
erfolgreichen Kursteilnehmerprotest gegen Unterscheidung in 
Verbindung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Avec l'annexation du Texas en 1848 à la fin de la
guerre Mexicain-Américaine, Tejanos -- Texan de descente 
mexicaine -- des droites de propriété perdues et puissance politique
dans une société a dominé par Anglos. Par les pratiques 
discriminatoires et la force violente, Tejanos ont été maintenus au 
bas de la nouvelle commande politique et socio-culturelle. De 
1900-1930, pendant qu'un afflux des immigrés du Mexique venait au 
nord pour satisfaire une demande croissante en main d'oeuvre à prix 
réduit dans les industries commerciales se développantes 
d'agriculture, Tejanos a éprouvé la discrimination continue dans 
l'emploi, le logement, les équipements publics, le système 
juridique, et les établissements éducatifs. Beaucoup de zones 
d'école ont isolé Tejano et enfants anglo dans les équipements 
séparés. Les écoles mexicaines étaient underfunded 
excessivement et ont souvent offert seulement une éducation d'école 
de catégorie. En 1930, quand 90% des écoles dans le Texas 
Du sud ont été isolés, la ligue des citoyens 
latino-américains unis (LULAC), un groupe de recommandation de 
Tejano, a supporté un défi de cour pour instruire la ségrégation. 
La cour du Texas des appels, cependant, a régné que les zones 
d'école pourraient utiliser des critères tels que le langage et 
le assistance irrégulier dus au travail saisonnier pour séparer des 
étudiants. La lutte des Américains mexicains pour terminer des
pratiques discriminatoires a accéléré la deuxième guerre mondiale 
suivante. En 1948, LULAC et G.I. Forum américain nouvellement 
formé, un groupe de recommandation de vétérans américains 
mexicains, aidé à un procès qui eventuated dans une ségrégation 
d'interdiction d'école de zone de décision fédérale de cour a 
basé sur l'ascendance mexicaine. Les localités ont éludé 
régner, cependant, et la ségrégation de fait a continué. En 
1955, LULAC et le forum lancent un costume protestant la pratique de 
placer des enfants de Tejano dans les classes séparées pour les deux
premières catégories de l'école et d'avoir besoin de quatre ans 
pour concurrencer ces catégories. ED Idar du forum, dans une 
entrevue ci-dessous, a discuté cette pratique, qui a été finalement
proscrite en 1957. L'étudiant proteste vers la fin des années 
60 -- supportées et complétées par une nouvelle organisation de 
droits civiques, la défense légale américaine mexicaine et les 
fonds éducatifs (MALDEF) -- a réalisé une extrémité à des 
pratiques plus discriminatoires et l'introduction des programmes 
bilingues et biculturels dans des écoles. Dans la deuxième 
entrevue, Peter Tijerina, le fondateur de MALDEF, a rapporté une 
protestation réussie d'étudiant contre la discrimination.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Com o annexation de Texas em 1848 no fim da guerra
Mexicano-Americana, Tejanos -- Texans da descida mexicana -- direitas 
de propriedade perdidas e potência política em uma sociedade 
dominaram por Anglos. Através das práticas discriminatory e da
força violenta, Tejanos foi mantido no fundo da ordem política e 
socio-socio-cultural nova. De 1900-1930, enquanto um influx dos 
immigrants de México veio para o norte se encontrar com uma demanda 
de crescimento para o trabalho barato nas indústrias comerciais se 
tornando da agricultura, Tejanos experimentou a discriminação 
continuada no emprego, na carcaça, em facilidades públicas, no 
sistema judicial, e em instituições educacionais. Muitos 
distritos da escola segregaram Tejano e crianças anglo em facilidades
separadas. As escolas mexicanas eram underfunded bruta e 
ofereceram frequentemente somente uma instrução da escola da classe.
Em 1930, quando 90% das escolas em Texas sul foram segregadas, a
liga dos cidadãos americanos latin unidos (LULAC), um grupo do 
advocacy de Tejano, suportou um desafio da corte para educar o 
segregation. A corte de Texas de apelações, entretanto, 
governou que os distritos da escola poderiam usar critérios como a 
língua e o comparecimento irregular  devido ao trabalho seasonal 
separar estudantes. O esforço dos americanos mexicanos para 
terminar práticas discriminatory acelerou seguinte segunda guerra 
mundial. Em 1948, em LULAC e no G.I. americano recentemente dado
forma Forum, um grupo do advocacy de veterans americanos mexicanos, 
ajudado em um lawsuit que eventuated em um segregation proibindo da 
escola da decisão federal da corte de distrito baseou no ancestry 
mexicano. Os localities evaded governar, entretanto, e o 
segregation de de facto continuou. Em 1955, LULAC e o forum 
inicíam um terno que protesta a prática de colocar crianças de 
Tejano em classes separadas para as primeiras duas classes da escola e
de reque quatro anos para competir estas classes. O Ed Idar do 
forum, em uma entrevista abaixo, discutiu esta prática, que outlawed 
finalmente em 1957. O estudante protesta nos 1960s atrasados -- 
suportados e complementados por uma organização nova das direitas 
civis, pela defesa legal americana mexicana e pelo fundo educacional 
(MALDEF) -- conseguiu uma extremidade às práticas mais 
discriminatory e a introdução de programas bilíngües e bicultural 
em escolas. Na segunda entrevista, Pete Tijerina, founder de 
MALDEF, relacionou um protesto bem sucedido do estudante de encontro 
à discriminação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Con il annexation del Texas in 1848 alla 
conclusione della guerra di messicano-american, Tejanos -- Texans 
della discesa messicana -- diritti di proprietà persi e potenza 
politica in una società si sono dominati da Anglos. Attraverso 
le pratiche discriminatorie e la forza violenta, Tejanos è stato 
mantenuto alla parte inferiore di nuovo ordine politico e 
socio-culturale. Da 1900-1930, mentre un afflusso degli 
immigranti dal Messico è venuto a nord venire a contatto di una 
domanda crescente del lavoro poco costoso nelle industrie 
commerciali di sviluppo di agricoltura, Tejanos ha avvertito la 
distinzione continuata nell'occupazione, in alloggiamento, nelle 
attrezzature pubbliche, nel sistema giudiziario e negli istituti 
scolastici. Molti distretti della scuola hanno segregato Tejano 
ed i bambini anglo nelle attrezzature separate. Le scuole 
messicane erano grossolanamente underfunded e spesso hanno offerto 
soltanto una formazione della scuola del grado. In 1930, quando 
90% delle scuole nel Texas del sud sono stati segregati, la lega dei 
cittadini dell'America latina uniti (LULAC), un gruppo di avvocatura 
di Tejano, ha sostenuto una sfida della corte per istruire la 
segregazione. La Corte d'Appello del Texas, tuttavia, ha 
regolato che i distretti della scuola potrebbero usare tali test di 
verifica come il linguaggio e la presenza irregolare dovuto lavoro 
stagionale separare gli allievi. La lotta degli Americani 
messicani per concludere le pratiche discriminatorie ha accelerato 
la seguente seconda guerra mondiale. In 1948, in LULAC e nel 
G.I. Forum americano recentemente formato, un gruppo di avvocatura dei
veterani americani messicani, aiutato in una causa che eventuated in
una segregazione proibente della scuola di distretto di decisione 
federale della corte ha basato sull'ascendenza messicana. Le 
località hanno eluso il regolamento, tuttavia e la segregazione de 
facto è continuato. In 1955, LULAC e la tribuna iniziano un 
vestito che protesta la pratica di disposizione dei bambini di Tejano 
nei codici categoria separati per i primi due gradi della scuola e di 
richiedere quattro anni per competere questi gradi. Il Ed Idar 
della tribuna, in un'intervista qui sotto, ha discusso questa pratica,
che infine è stata proscritta in 1957. L'allievo protesta verso
la fine degli anni 60 -- sostenuti e complementati da una nuova 
organizzazione di diritti civili, dalla difesa legale americana 
messicana e dal fondo monetario educativo (MALDEF) -- ha realizzato 
un'estremità alle pratiche più discriminatorie e l'introduzione dei 
programmi bilingue e biculturali nelle scuole. Nella seconda 
intervista, Pete Tijerina, il fondatore di MALDEF, ha riferito una 
protesta riuscita dell'allievo contro distinzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με την προσάρτηση του Τέξας το 1848 στο τέλος του 
Μεξικανοαμερικάνύ πολέμου, Tejanos -- Texans της μεξικάνικης
καταγωγής -- έχασαν τα δικαιώματα ιδιοκτησιών και την πολιτική 
δύναμη σε μια κοινωνία που εξουσιάστηκε από Anglos. Μέσω
των μεροληπτικών πρακτικών και της βίαιας δύναμης, Tejanos 
κρατήθηκε στο κατώτατο σημείο της νέας πολιτικής και 
κοινωνικοπολιτιστικής κατάταξης. Από το 1900-1930, καθώς 
μια εισροή των μεταναστών από το Μεξικό ήρθε βόρεια να 
ικανοποιήσει μια αυξανόμενη ζήτηση για τη φτηνή εργασία στις 
αναπτυσσόμενες εμπορικές βιομηχανίες γεωργίας, Tejanos 
δοκίμασε τη συνεχή διάκριση στην απασχόληση, την κατοικία, τις 
δημόσιες εγκαταστάσεις, το δικαστικό σύστημα, και τα εκπαιδευτικά
όργανα. Πολλές σχολικές περιοχές διαχώρισαν τα 
παιδιά Tejano και Anglo στις χωριστές εγκαταστάσεις. Τα
μεξικάνικα σχολεία ήταν συνολικά και πρόσφεραν συχνά μόνο μια 
σχολική εκπαίδευση βαθμού. Το 1930, όταν διαχωρίστηκαν 
90% των σχολείων στο νότιο Τέξας, η ένωση των ενωμένων 
λατινοαμερικανικών πολιτών (LULAC), μια ομάδα υπεράσπισης 
Tejano, υποστήριξε μια πρόκληση δικαστηρίων στο σχολικό 
διαχωρισμό. Το Εφετείο του Τέξας, εντούτοις, διέταξε ότι 
οι σχολικές περιοχές θα μπορούσαν να χρησιμοποιήσουν τέτοια 
κριτήρια όπως τη γλώσσα και την ανώμαλη συμμετοχή λόγω στην 
εποχιακή εργασία στους χωριστούς σπουδαστές. Η προσπάθεια 
μεξικάνικων Αμερικανών να τελειώσουν τις μεροληπτικές πρακτικές 
επιτάχυνε μετά από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ. Το 1948, 
LULAC και το πρόσφατα διαμορφωμένο αμερικανικό G.I. φόρουμ, 
μια ομάδα υπεράσπισης μεξικάνικων αμερικανικών παλαιμάχων, 
βοήθησε σε μια δίκη που σε μια ομοσπονδιακή απόφαση περιφερειακών
δικαστηρίων που απαγορεύει το σχολικό διαχωρισμό βασισμένο στη 
μεξικάνικη καταγωγή. Οι τοποθεσίες απέφυγαν την απόφαση, 
εντούτοις, και ο de facto διαχωρισμός συνεχίστηκε. Το 
1955, LULAC και το φόρουμ άρχισαν ένα κοστούμι 
διαμαρτυμένος την πρακτική της τοποθέτησης των παιδιών Tejano 
στις χωριστές κλάσεις για τις πρώτες δύο τάξεις του σχολείου και
της απαίτησης τεσσάρων ετών για να ανταγωνιστούν αυτοί οι 
βαθμοί. Οι ΕΔ Idar του φόρουμ, σε μια συνέντευξη 
κατωτέρω, συζήτησαν αυτήν την πρακτική, η οποία προγράφηκε 
τελικά σε 1957, διαμαρτυρίες σπουδαστών προς το τέλος της 
δεκαετίας του '60 -- που υποστηρίζεται και που συμπληρώνεται από 
μια νέα οργάνωση αστικών δικαιωμάτων, τη μεξικάνικη αμερικανική 
νομική υπεράσπιση και το εκπαιδευτικό Ταμείο (MALDEF) -- 
επέτυχε ένα τέλος σε περισσότερες μεροληπτικές πρακτικές και την
εισαγωγή των δίγλωσσων και διπολιτιστικών προγραμμάτων στα 
σχολεία. Στη δεύτερη συνέντευξη, pete Tijerina, ο 
ιδρυτής MALDEF, αφορούσε μια επιτυχή διαμαρτυρία σπουδαστών 
ενάντια στη διάκριση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Con la anexión de Tejas en 1848 en el final de la
guerra Mexicano-Americana, Tejanos -- Texans de la pendiente mexicana 
-- las derechas de característica perdidas y potencia política en 
una sociedad dominaron por Anglos. A través de prácticas 
discriminatorias y de fuerza violenta, Tejanos fue guardado en el 
fondo de la nueva orden política y socio-cultural. A partir de 
1900-1930, como una afluencia de inmigrantes de México vino al norte 
resolver una demanda creciente para el trabajo barato en las 
industrias comerciales de la agricultura que se convertían, Tejanos 
experimentó la discriminación continuada en el empleo, la cubierta, 
los recursos públicos, el sistema judicial, e instituciones 
educativas. Muchos districtos de la escuela segregaron a Tejano 
y a niños anglo en recursos separados. Las escuelas mexicanas 
eran underfunded grueso y ofrecieron a menudo solamente una educación
de la escuela del grado. En 1930, cuando los 90% de las escuelas
en Tejas del sur fueron segregados, la liga de los ciudadanos 
americanos latinos unidos (LULAC), grupo de la defensa de Tejano, 
utilizó un desafío de la corte para enseñar la segregación. 
El tribunal de apelación de Tejas, sin embargo, gobernó que 
los districtos de la escuela podrían utilizar los criterios tales 
como el lenguaje y la atención irregular  debido al trabajo 
estacional separar a estudiantes. La lucha de los americanos 
mexicanos para terminar prácticas discriminatorias aceleró la 
Segunda Guerra Mundial siguiente. En 1948, LULAC y el G.I. 
americano nuevamente formado Forum, un grupo de la defensa de 
veteranos americanos mexicanos, asistido a un pleito que eventuated en
una segregación de la escuela de districto que prohibía de la 
decisión federal de la corte basó en ascendencia mexicana. Los
lugares evadieron la decisión, sin embargo, y la segregación de 
hecho continuó. En 1955, LULAC y el foro iniciaron un juego que
protesta la práctica de colocar a niños de Tejano en las clases 
separadas para los primeros dos grados de la escuela y de requerir 
cuatro años para competir estos grados. El Ed Idar del foro, en
una entrevista abajo, discutió esta práctica, que finalmente fue 
proscrita en 1957. El estudiante protesta en los últimos años 
60 -- utilizados y complementados por una nueva organización de las 
derechas civiles, la defensa legal americana mexicana y el fondo 
educativo (MALDEF) -- alcanzó un extremo a prácticas más 
discriminatorias y la introducción de programas bilingües y 
biculturales en escuelas. En la segunda entrevista, Pete 
Tijerina, el fundador de MALDEF, relacionó una protesta acertada del 
estudiante contra la discriminación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086156</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103324</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/fighting-discrimination-in-mexican-american-education</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
