<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108610</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108610</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087339</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A society of patriotic ladies."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"eine Gesellschaft der patriotischen Damen."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"une société des dames patriotes."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"uma sociedade de senhoras patriotic."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"una società delle signore patriotic."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια κοινωνία των πατριωτικών κυριών."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"una sociedad de señoras patrióticas."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Cheap prints depicting current events were in great demand in both England and the colonies. This 1775 British print presented a scene in Edenton, North Carolina. Fifty-one women signed a declaration in support of nonimportation, swearing not to drink tea or purchase other British imports. Boycotts of British goods became a widespread form of protest to the Townshend Duties, enacted in 1767 to tax goods such as paint, paper, lead, glass, and tea when they arrived in America. Abstaining from European products and fashions became a mark of patriotism, and merchants who violated nonimportation were subjected to public ridicule. Tarring and feathering was common, as were attacks on conspicuous symbols of wealth. As this print suggests, ridicule existed on both sides of the Atlantic. The artist treated the Edenton women with scorn, portraying them as ugly, impressionable, and neglectful of their children.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die preiswerten Drucke, die aktuelle Fälle bildlich 
darstellen, waren in der großen Nachfrage in England und in den 
Kolonien. Dieses drucken 1775 Briten darstellten eine Szene in 
Edenton, Nord-Carolina. Fifty-one Frauen unterzeichneten eine 
Erklärung zur Unterstützung des nonimportation und schwuren, um Tee 
nicht zu trinken oder andere Briten Importe zu kaufen. Boykotts 
der britischen Waren wurden ein weitverbreitetes Formular des 
Protestes zu den Townshend Aufgaben, verordnet 1767, um Waren wie 
Farbe, Papier, Leitung, Glas und Tee zu besteuern, als sie in Amerika 
ankamen. Das Enthalten von den europäischen Produkten und von 
der Art und Weise wurde eine Markierung von Patriotismus, und 
Kaufleute, die nonimportation verletzten, wurden der lächerlichen 
Öffentlichkeit unterworfen. Tarring und Gefieder waren 
geläufig, wie Angriffe auf auffallenden Symbolen von Fülle waren. 
Wie dieser Druck vorschlägt, lächerlich machen Sie existiert von
beiden Seiten des Atlantiks. Der Künstler behandelte die 
Edenton Frauen verächtlich und schilderte sie, wie häßlich, 
impressionable und neglectful ihrer Kinder.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les copies bon marché dépeignant des événements 
actuels étaient dans une grande demande en Angleterre et les 
colonies. Ce les 1775 Anglais impriment ont présenté une 
scène dans Edenton, Caroline du nord. Les femmes de 
Fifty-one ont signé une déclaration à l'appui du nonimportation, 
jurant pour ne pas boire du thé ou pour ne pas acheter d'autres 
importations des Anglais. Les boycotts des marchandises 
britanniques sont devenus une forme répandue de protestation aux 
fonctions de Townshend, décrétée en 1767 pour imposer des 
marchandises telles que la peinture, le papier, le fil de sortie, le 
verre, et le thé quand ils sont arrivés en Amérique. 
L'abstention des produits européens et des modes est devenue 
une marque de patriotisme, et les négociants qui ont violé le 
nonimportation ont été soumis au ridicule public. Tarring 
et changement de pas étaient communs, de même que des attaques sur 
des symboles remarquables de la richesse. Car cette copie 
suggère, le ridicule a existé des deux côtés de l'Océan 
atlantique. L'artiste a traité les femmes d'Edenton 
dédaigneusement, les dépeignant comme laides, impressionnables, et 
négligentes de leurs enfants.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As cópias baratas que descrevem eventos atuais estavam na
demanda grande  em Inglaterra e nas colônias. Este 1775 
Ingleses imprimem apresentaram uma cena em Edenton, North.carolina. 
As mulheres de Fifty-one assinaram uma declaração na 
sustentação do nonimportation, jurando para não beber o chá ou 
não comprar outras importações de Ingleses. Os boycotts de 
bens britânicos transformaram-se um formulário difundido do protesto
aos deveres de Townshend, decretado em 1767 para tax bens tais como a 
pintura, o papel, a ligação, o vidro, e o chá quando chegaram em 
América. Abstaining dos produtos europeus e das formas 
transformou-se uma marca do patriotism, e os comerciantes que violated
o nonimportation foram sujeitados ao ridicule público. Tarring 
e o feathering eram comuns, como eram ataques em símbolos conspícuos
da riqueza. Porque esta cópia sugere, o ridicule existiu em 
ambos os lados do Atlântico. O artista tratou as mulheres de 
Edenton com scorn, portraying as como feias, impressionable, e 
neglectful de suas crianças.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le stampe poco costose che descrivono gli eventi correnti 
erano nella richiesta grande sia in Inghilterra che le colonie. 
Questo 1775 Britannici stampano hanno presentato una scena in 
Edenton, North.carolina. Le donne di Fifty-one hanno firmato una
dichiarazione a sostegno del nonimportation, giurando per non bere il 
tè o non comprare altre importazioni dei Britannici. I 
boicottaggi delle merci britanniche si sono transformati in in una 
forma diffusa della protesta alle funzioni di Townshend, promulgata in
1767 per tassare le merci quali vernice, carta, cavo, vetro e tè 
quando sono arrivato in America. Astenendosi dai prodotti 
europei e dalle mode si è transformata in in un contrassegno di 
patriotism ed i commercianti che hanno violato il nonimportation sono 
stati sottoposti a ridicule pubblico. Tarring ed il piumaggio 
erano comuni, come erano attacchi ai simboli cospicui di ricchezza. 
Poichè questa stampa suggerisce, il ridicule ha esistito da 
entrambi i lati dell'Atlantico. L'artista ha curato le donne di 
Edenton disdegnosamente, ritraendole come ugly, impressionable e 
neglectful dei loro bambini.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι φτηνές τυπωμένες ύλες που απεικονίζουν τα παρόντα 
γεγονότα ήταν στη μεγάλη απαίτηση και στην Αγγλία και στις 
αποικίες. Αυτή η βρετανική τυπωμένη ύλη 1775 παρουσίασε
μια σκηνή σε Edenton, βόρεια Καρολίνα. Πενήντα μια 
γυναίκες υπέγραψαν μια δήλωση υπέρ του nonimportation, 
ορκιμένος να μην πιουν το τσάι ή να μην αγοράσουν άλλες 
βρετανικές εισαγωγές. Τα μποϊκοταρίσματα των βρετανικών 
αγαθών έγιναν μια διαδεδομένη μορφή της διαμαρτυρίας στα 
καθήκοντα Townshend, που θεσπίστηκε το 1767 στα φορολογικά 
αγαθά όπως το χρώμα, το έγγραφο, ο μόλυβδος, το γυαλί, και το 
τσάι όταν έφθασαν στην Αμερική. Η αποχή από τα ευρωπαϊκά
προϊόντα και τις μόδες έγινε ένα σημάδι του πατριωτισμού, και 
οι έμποροι που παραβίασαν το nonimportation υποβλήθηκαν στο 
δημόσιο εμπαιγμό. Το Tarring και feathering ήταν 
κοινά, όπως ήταν οι επιθέσεις στα ευδιάκριτα σύμβολα του 
πλούτου. Όπως αυτή η τυπωμένη ύλη προτείνει, ο εμπαιγμός 
υπήρξε και στις δύο πλευρές του Ατλαντικού. Ο καλλιτέχνης 
θεράπευσε τις γυναίκες Edenton με περιφρόνηση, που απεικονίζουν
τις όπως άσχημες, ευσυγκίνητες, και αμελείς των παιδιών τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las impresiones baratas que representaban sucesos actuales
estaban en gran demanda en Inglaterra y las colonias. Este 1775 
Británicos imprimen presentaron una escena en Edenton, Carolina del 
Norte. Las mujeres de Fifty-one firmaron un declaración en la 
ayuda del nonimportation, jurando para no beber té o para no comprar 
otras importaciones de Británicos. Los boicoteos de mercancías
británicas se convirtieron en una forma extensa de protesta a los 
deberes de Townshend, decretada en 1767 para gravar mercancías tales 
como pintura, papel, terminal de componente, cristal, y té cuando 
llegaron en América. El abstener de productos europeos y de 
maneras se convirtió en una marca del patriotismo, y sujetaron a los 
comerciantes que violaron el nonimportation a la irrisión pública. 
Tarring y el cambio de paso eran comunes, al igual que ataques 
contra símbolos visibles de la abundancia. Pues esta impresión
sugiere, la irrisión existió en ambas caras del Atlántico. 
El artista trató a mujeres de Edenton desdeñosamente, 
retratándolas como feas, impresionables, y neglectful de sus niños.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087339</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108610</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-society-of-patriotic-ladies</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
