<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104182</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104182</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211862</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Recent Variations in Earth's Climate</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Neue Schwankungen des Klimas der Masse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Variations récentes du climat de la terre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Variações recentes no clima da terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Variazioni recenti nel clima della terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρόσφατες παραλλαγές στο γήινο κλίμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Variaciones recientes en el clima de la tierra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">These image-rich lecture notes from the Department of Geology at Bryn Mawr College offer information regarding climate change and how paleoclimate (past climate) is inferred using proxies. The notes, in slide form, discuss what affects climate and how climate has changed through time. The notes feature colorful photos, figures, and graphs to illustrate points. Topics discussed include extraterrestrial, short, and long term influences on climate, climate records through time (e.g. as influenced by carbon dioxide and Milankovich cycling), and future predictions/ramifications of climate change.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Bild-reichen Vortraganmerkungen von der 
Abteilung von Geologie an den Bryn Mawr Hochschulangebotinformationen 
betreffend sind Klima ändern und wie paleoclimate (hinter Klima) mit 
Vollmächten geschlossen wird. Die Anmerkungen, in der 
Plättchenform, behandeln, was Klima beeinflußt und wie Klima durch 
Zeit geändert hat. Die Anmerkungen kennzeichnen bunte Fotos, 
Abbildungen und Diagramme, um Punkte zu veranschaulichen. Die 
Themen, die behandelt werden, schließen die extraterrestrial, kurzen 
und langen Bezeichnung Einflüsse auf Klima, die Klimasätze durch 
Zeit (z.B., wie durch das einen Kreislauf durchmachende Kohlendioxyd 
und Milankovich beeinflußt) und Zukunft predictions/ramifications der
Klimaänderung ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ces notes image-riches de conférence du service 
de la géologie à l'information d'offre d'université de Bryn Mawr 
concernant le climat changent et comment le paleoclimate (après le 
climat) est impliqué en utilisant des procurations. Les notes, 
sous la forme de glissière, discutent ce qui affecte le climat et 
comment climat a changé par le temps. Les notes comportent les 
photos, les figures, et les graphiques colorés pour illustrer des 
points. Les sujets discutés incluent des influences 
extraterrestres, courtes, et de long terme sur le climat, des 
enregistrements de climat par le temps (par exemple comme influencé 
par l'anhydride carbonique et le Milankovich faisant un cycle), et le 
futur predictions/ramifications du changement de climat.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estas notas imagem-ricas do lecture do 
departamento da geologia na informação da oferta da faculdade de 
Bryn Mawr a respeito do clima mudam e como o paleoclimate (após o 
clima) inferred usando proxies. As notas, no formulário da 
corrediça, discutem o que afetam o clima e como clima mudou com o 
tempo. As notas caracterizam fotos, figuras, e gráficos 
coloridos para ilustrar pontos. Os tópicos discutidos incluem 
influências extraterrestrial, curtas, e do prazo no clima, registros 
do clima com o tempo (por exemplo como influenciado pelo dióxido de 
carbono e pelo Milankovich que dão um ciclo), e futuro 
predictions/ramifications da mudança do clima.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Queste note immagine-ricche di conferenza dal 
reparto della geologia alle informazioni di offerta dell'università 
di Bryn Mawr per quanto riguarda il clima cambiano e come il 
paleoclimate (oltre il clima) è arguito usando le procure. Le 
note, nella forma dello scorrevole, discutono che cosa interessa il 
clima e come clima è cambiato con tempo. Le note caratterizzano
le foto, le figure ed i grafici colorful per illustrare i punti. 
I soggetti discussi includono le influenze extraterrestrial, 
corte e di lungo termine sul clima, i record di clima con tempo (per 
esempio come influenzato dall'anidride carbonica e da Milankovich che 
ciclano) ed il futuro predictions/ramifications del cambiamento di 
clima.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτές οι εικόνα-πλούσιες σημειώσεις διάλεξης από το 
τμήμα γεωλογίας mawr Bryn στο κολλέγιο προσφέρουν τις 
πληροφορίες σχετικά με την αλλαγή κλίματος και πώς 
paleoclimate (κλίμα παρελθόντος) προκύπτει χρησιμοποιώντας τα 
πληρεξούσια. Οι σημειώσεις, με μορφή φωτογραφικών 
διαφανειών, συζητούν τι έχει επιπτώσεις στο κλίμα και πώς το 
κλίμα έχει αλλάξει μέσω του χρόνου. Οι σημειώσεις 
χαρακτηρίζουν τις ζωηρόχρωμες φωτογραφίες, τους αριθμούς, και τις 
γραφικές παραστάσεις για να επεξηγήσουν τα σημεία. Τα 
θέματα που συζητούνται περιλαμβάνουν τις εξωγήινες, σύντομες, και
μακροπρόθεσμες επιρροές στο κλίμα, τα αρχεία κλίματος μέσω του 
χρόνου (π.χ. όπως επηρεάζεται από το διοξείδιο του άνθρακα και 
Milankovich που ανακυκλώνουν), και τις μελλοντικές 
προβλέψεις/τις διακλαδώσεις της αλλαγής κλίματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estas notas imagen-ricas de la conferencia del 
departamento de la geología en la información de la oferta de la 
universidad de Bryn Mawr con respecto a clima cambian y cómo se 
deduce el paleoclimate (más allá de clima) usando poderes. Las
notas, en forma de la diapositiva, discuten qué afecta clima y cómo 
clima ha cambiado con tiempo. Las notas ofrecen las fotos, las 
figuras, y los gráficos coloridos para ilustrar puntas. Los 
asuntos discutidos incluyen influencias extraterrestres, cortas, y del
largo plazo en clima, expedientes del clima con tiempo (e.g. según lo
influenciado por el bióxido de carbono y Milankovich que completan un
ciclo), y el futuro predictions/ramifications del cambio del clima.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DON BARBER
FN:DON BARBER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DEPARTMENT OF GEOLOGY, BRYN MAWR COLLEGE
FN:DEPARTMENT OF GEOLOGY, BRYN MAWR COLLEGE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211862</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104182</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/recent-variations-in-earths-climate</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
