<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104041</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104041</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087268</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Encyclopedia of Earth</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Enzyklopädie von Masse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Encyclopédie de la terre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Enciclopédia da terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Enciclopedia di terra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εγκυκλοπαίδεια της γης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Enciclopedia de la tierra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Encyclopedia of Earth is an electronic reference about the earth, its natural environments, and their interaction with society. It is a collection of articles written by scholars, professionals, educators, and experts who collaborate and review each other's work. The articles are written in non-technical language and will be useful to students, educators, scholars, professionals, as well as to the general public.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Enzyklopädie von Masse ist eine elektronische
Referenz über die Masse, seine natürlichen Umgebungen und ihre 
Interaktion mit Gesellschaft. Es ist eine Ansammlung Artikel, 
die von den Gelehrten geschrieben werden, Fachleute, Erzieher und 
Experten, die jeder des anderen Arbeit zusammenarbeiten und 
wiederholen. Die Artikel werden in nicht technische Sprache 
geschrieben und werden Kursteilnehmer, Erzieher, Gelehrte, Fachleute, 
sowie zur Öffentlichkeit nützlich sein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'encyclopédie de la terre est une référence 
électronique au sujet de la terre, de ses environnements normaux, et 
de leur interaction avec la société. C'est une collection 
d'articles écrits par des disciples, des professionnels, des 
éducateurs, et des experts qui collaborent et passent en revue le 
travail de chacun. Les articles sont écrits en langage non 
technique et seront utiles aux étudiants, éducateurs, disciples, 
professionnels, aussi bien qu'au grand public.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A enciclopédia da terra é uma referência 
eletrônica sobre a terra, seus ambientes naturais, e sua interação 
com sociedade. É uma coleção dos artigos escritos por 
scholars, profissionais, educadores, e peritos que collaborate e se 
revêem trabalho. Os artigos são escritos na língua não 
técnica e serão úteis aos estudantes, educadores, scholars, 
profissionais, as.well.as ao público geral.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'enciclopedia di terra è un riferimento 
elettronico circa la terra, i relativi ambienti naturali e la loro 
interazione con la società. È una collezione di articoli 
scritti dagli eruditi, professionisti, educatori ed esperti che 
collaborano e rivedono il lavoro di ciascuno. Gli articoli sono 
scritti in linguaggio non tecnico e saranno utili agli allievi, gli 
educatori, gli eruditi, professionisti, così come al grande pubblico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η εγκυκλοπαίδεια της γης είναι μια ηλεκτρονική αναφορά
για τη γη, τα φυσικά περιβάλλοντά της, και την αλληλεπίδρασή τους
με την κοινωνία. Είναι μια συλλογή των άρθρων που γράφονται
από τους μελετητές, επαγγελματίες, εκπαιδευτικοί, και 
εμπειρογνώμονες που συνεργάζονται και αναθεωρούν την ο ένας του 
άλλου εργασία. Τα άρθρα γράφονται στη μη τεχνική γλώσσα 
και θα είναι χρήσιμα στους σπουδαστές, εκπαιδευτικοί, μελετητές, 
επαγγελματίες, καθώς επίσης και στο ευρύ κοινό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La enciclopedia de la tierra es una referencia 
electrónica sobre la tierra, sus ambientes naturales, y su 
interacción con la sociedad. Es una colección de artículos 
escritos por los eruditos, profesionales, educadores, y los expertos 
que colaboran y se repasan trabajo. Los artículos se escriben 
en lenguaje no técnico y serán útiles a los estudiantes, 
educadores, eruditos, profesionales, así como al público en general.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MULTIPLE
FN:MULTIPLE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087268</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104041</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/encyclopedia-of-earth</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
