<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104251</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104251</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207179</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Center for Advanced Research on Language Acquisition</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mitte für hochentwickelte Forschung auf 
Sprachendatenerfassung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Centre pour la recherche avançée sur la saisie 
de langage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Centro para pesquisa avançada sobre a aquisição
da língua</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Centro per ricerca avanzata su aquisizione di 
linguaggio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κέντρο για την προηγμένη έρευνα για τη γλωσσική 
απόκτηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Centro para la investigación avanzada sobre la 
adquisición del lenguaje</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers units, lessons, and classroom tasks for teachers of French, German, and Spanish. A virtual assessment center and a handbook are designed to help world language teachers with proficiency-oriented instruction and classroom-based performance measures. A database provides information on locations in North American where students may study less commonly taught languages.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet Maßeinheiten, Lektionen und 
Klassenzimmeraufgaben für Lehrer von französischem, von deutschem 
und Spanischen an. Eine virtuelle Einschätzung Mitte und ein 
Handbuch sind konzipiert, um Weltsprachenlehrern mit 
Leistungsfähigkeit-orientierter Anweisung und 
Klassenzimmer-gegründeten Leistungsmessungen zu helfen. Eine 
Datenbank stellt Informationen auf Standorten auf Nordamerikaner zur 
Verfügung, in denen Kursteilnehmer weniger geläufig 
Unterichtssprachen studieren können.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre des unités, leçons, et la salle de classe 
charge pour des professeurs de français, d'allemand, et 
Espagnol. Un centre virtuel d'évaluation et un manuel sont 
conçus pour aider des professeurs de langue du monde avec 
l'instruction compétence-orientée et les mesures d'exécution salle 
de classe-basées. Une base de données fournit des informations
sur des emplacements dans l'Américain du nord où les étudiants 
peuvent étudier des langages moins généralement enseignés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece unidades, lições, e tarefas da sala de 
aula para professores de francês, de alemão, e o espanhol. Um 
centro virtual da avaliação e um manual são projetados ajudar a 
professores da língua de mundo com instrução 
proficiência-orientada e medidas de desempenho sala de aula-baseadas.
Uma base de dados fornece a informação nas posições em 
north-american onde os estudantes podem estudar línguas mais menos 
geralmente ensinadas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre le unità, le lezioni e le mansioni 
dell'aula per gli insegnanti di francese, di tedesco e lo Spagnolo. 
Un centro virtuale di valutazione e un manuale sono destinati 
per aiutare gli insegnanti di lingue di mondo con istruzione 
competenza-orientata e le misure di prestazioni aula-basate. Una
base di dati fornisce le informazioni sulle posizioni in 
north-american dove gli allievi possono studiare i linguaggi meno 
comunemente insegnati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">μονάδες προσφορών, μαθήματα, και στοιχειώδεις 
εργασίες τάξεων για τους δασκάλους των γαλλικών, γερμανικών, και 
ισπανικών. Ένα εικονικό κέντρο αξιολόγησης και ένα 
εγχειρίδιο σχεδιάζονται για να βοηθήσουν τους παγκόσμιους 
καθηγητές γλωσσών με την ικανότητα-προσανατολισμένη στο οδηγία 
και τα τάξη-βασισμένα στο μέτρα απόδοσης. Μια βάση 
δεδομένων παρέχει τις πληροφορίες για τις θέσεις σε 
βορειοαμερικανικά όπου οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να μελετήσουν τις 
λιγότερο συνήθως διδαγμένες γλώσσες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece unidades, lecciones, y las tareas de la 
sala de clase para los profesores de francés, de alemán, y el 
español. Un centro virtual del gravamen y un manual se diseñan
para ayudar a profesores del lenguaje de mundo con la instrucción 
habilidad-orientada y medidas de funcionamiento sala de clase-basadas.
Una base de datos proporciona a la información en las 
localizaciones en norteamericano en donde los estudiantes pueden 
estudiar lenguajes menos comúnmente enseñados.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207179</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104251</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/center-for-advanced-research-on-language-acquisition</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
