<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104401</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104401</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087500</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Compare the Ship that bore them hither with Noah's Ark: Francis Daniel Pastorius Describes his impressions of Pennsylvania, 1683</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vergleichen Sie das Schiff, das sie hither mit 
Arche Noahs bohren: Francis Daniel Pastorius beschreibt seine 
Eindrücke von Pennsylvania, 1683</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comparez le bateau qui les alèsent ici avec 
l'arche de Noé : Francis Daniel Pastorius décrit ses 
impressions de la Pennsylvanie, 1683</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Compare o navio que os fura hither com arca de 
Noah: Francis Daniel Pastorius descreve suas impressões de 
Pensilvânia, 1683</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Confronti la nave che le alesa hither con l'arca 
del Noah: Francis Daniel Pastorius descrive le sue impressioni 
della Pensilvania, 1683</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συγκρίνετε το σκάφος που τους άντεξε προς τα εδώ με 
την κιβωτό του Νώε: Θ*Φρανθης Daniel Pastorius 
Describes οι εντυπώσεις Πενσυλβανίας του, 1683</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Compare la nave que las agujerea aquí con la arca
de Noah: Francis Daniel Pastorius describe sus impresiones de 
Pennsylvania, 1683</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Francis Daniel Pastorius arrived in Pennsylvania in 1683, commissioned by the Frankfort Land Company and a group of German merchants to obtain 15,000 acres of land for a settlement in the new colony of Pennsylvania. Pastorius, well educated in European universities, reported back to his friends in Germany. This report was later published as  Positive Information From America, concerning the Country of Pennsylvania by a German who Traveled There  (1684), a promotional tract to encourage other Germans to immigrate. Pastorius found the journey to be difficult but the prospects attractive. He remarked notably upon the ethnic and religious complexity of the colony. Pennsylvania attracted many colonists seeking religious freedom and communal prosperity. Pastorius went on to lead settlement of Mennonites and Quakers at Germantown.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Francis Daniel Pastorius kam in Pennsylvania 1683 
an, beauftragen durch Frankfort Land Company und eine Gruppe von den 
deutschen Kaufleuten, um 15.000 Morgen Land für eine Regelung in der 
neuen Kolonie von Pennsylvania zu erreichen. Pastorius, gut 
ausgebildet in den europäischen Universitäten, berichtet zurück zu 
seinen Freunden in Deutschland. Dieser Report wurde später als 
positive Informationen von Amerika, hinsichtlich des Landes von 
Pennsylvania von einem Deutschen, der dort reiste (1684), eine 
fördernde Fläche veröffentlicht, um andere Deutsche anzuregen 
einzuwandern. Pastorius fand die Reise, um schwierig zu sein 
aber die attraktiven Aussichten. Er erwähnte vornehmlich nach 
der ethnischen und frommen Kompliziertheit der Kolonie. 
Pennsylvania zog viele Kolonisten an, die fromme Freiheit und 
Kommunalwohlstand suchen. Pastorius fuhr fort, Regelung von 
Mennonites und von Quäkern bei Germantown zu führen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Francis Daniel Pastorius est arrivé en 
Pennsylvanie en 1683, commissionné par Frankfort Land Company et un 
groupe des négociants allemands pour obtenir 15.000 acres de terre 
pour un règlement dans la nouvelle colonie de la Pennsylvanie. 
Pastorius, instruit aux universités européennes, enregistrées
de nouveau à ses amis en Allemagne. Cet état plus tard a été
édité en tant qu'information positive d'Amérique, au sujet du pays 
de la Pennsylvanie par un Allemand qui a voyagé là (1684), une 
région promotionnelle pour encourager d'autres Allemands à immigrer.
Pastorius a trouvé le voyage pour être difficile mais les 
perspectives attrayantes. Il a remarqué notamment sur la 
complexité ethnique et religieuse de la colonie. La 
Pennsylvanie a attiré beaucoup de colons recherchant la liberté 
religieuse et la prospérité communale. Pastorius a continué 
pour mener le règlement de Mennonites et de quakers chez Germantown.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Francis Daniel Pastorius chegou em Pensilvânia em
1683, comissão pelo Frankfort Terra Companhia e um grupo de 
comerciantes alemães para obter 15.000 acres da terra para um 
estabelecimento na colônia nova de Pensilvânia. Pastorius, 
educado bem nas universidades européias, relatadas para trás a seus 
amigos em Germany. Este relatório foi publicado mais tarde como
a informação positiva de América, a respeito do país de 
Pensilvânia por um alemão que viajasse lá (1684), um intervalo 
promotional para incentivar outros alemães immigrate. Pastorius
encontrou a viagem para ser difícil mas os prospetos atrativos. 
Observou notàvelmente em cima da complexidade étnica e 
religiosa da colônia. Pensilvânia atraiu muitos colonos que 
procuram a liberdade religiosa e a prosperidade communal. 
Pastorius foi sobre conduzir ao estabelecimento de Mennonites e 
de quakers em Germantown.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Francis Daniel Pastorius è arrivato in 
Pensilvania in 1683, incaricato dal Frankfort Land Company e un gruppo
dei commercianti tedeschi per ottenere 15.000 acri di terra per uno 
stabilimento nella nuova colonia della Pensilvania. Pastorius, 
istruito in università europee, segnalate di nuovo ai suoi amici in 
Germania. Questo rapporto più successivamente è stato 
pubblicato come informazioni positive dall'America, riguardo al paese 
della Pensilvania da un tedesco che ha viaggiato là (1684), un tratto
promozionale per consigliare ad altri tedeschi immigrate. 
Pastorius ha trovato il viaggio per essere difficile ma i 
prospetti attraenti. Ha rilevato considerevolmente sulla 
complessità etnica e religiosa della colonia. La Pensilvania ha
attratto molti colonizzatori che cercano la libertà religiosa e la 
prosperità comunale. Pastorius ha continuato a condurre lo 
stabilimento di Mennonites e dei quakers a Germantown.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Francis Daniel Pastorius έφθασε στην 
Πενσυλβανία το 1683, ανατεθειμένος από Frankfort Land 
Company και μια ομάδα γερμανικών εμπόρων για να ληφθούν 
15.000 στρέμματα του εδάφους για μια τακτοποίηση στη νέα 
αποικία της Πενσυλβανίας. Pastorius, που εκπαιδεύεται 
καλά στα ευρωπαϊκά πανεπιστήμια, που αναφέρονται πίσω στους 
φίλους του στη Γερμανία. Αυτή η έκθεση δημοσιεύθηκε 
αργότερα ως θετικές πληροφορίες από την Αμερική, σχετικά με τη 
χώρα της Πενσυλβανίας από έναν Γερμανό που ταξίδεψε εκεί 
(1684), ένα προωθητικό κομμάτι για να ενθαρρύνει άλλους 
Γερμανούς για να μεταναστεύσει. Το Pastorius βρήκε το 
ταξίδι για να είναι δύσκολες αλλά τις προοπτικές ελκυστικές. 
Παρατήρησε ειδικότερα επάνω στην εθνική και θρησκευτική 
πολυπλοκότητα της αποικίας. Η Πενσυλβανία προσέλκυσε 
πολλούς αποίκους που επιδιώκουν τη θρησκευτική ελευθερία και την 
κοινοτική ευημερία. Το Pastorius πήγε για να οδηγηθεί η 
τακτοποίηση Mennonites και Quakers σε Germantown.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Francis Daniel Pastorius llegó en Pennsylvania en
1683, comisionado por el Frankfort Land Company y grupo de 
comerciantes alemanes para obtener 15.000 acres de pista para un 
establecimiento en la nueva colonia de Pennsylvania. Pastorius, 
instruído en las universidades europeas, señaladas de nuevo a sus 
amigos en Alemania. Este informe fue publicado más adelante 
como información positiva de América, referente al país de 
Pennsylvania por un alemán que viajó allí (1684), una zona 
promocional para animar a otros alemanes que immigrate. 
Pastorius encontró el viaje para ser difícil pero las 
perspectivas atractivas. Él comentó notablemente sobre la 
complejidad étnica y religiosa de la colonia. Pennsylvania 
atrajo a muchos colonos que buscaban la libertad religiosa y la 
prosperidad comunal. Pastorius continuó conducir el 
establecimiento de Mennonites y de quakers en Germantown.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087500</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104401</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/compare-the-ship-that-bore-them-hither-with-noahs-ark-francis-daniel-pastorius-describes-his-impressions-of-pennsylvania-1683</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
