<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106760</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106760</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207248</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Thurmond: A Town Born from Coal Mines and Railroads</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Thurmond: Eine Stadt getragen von den 
Kohlengruben und von den Eisenbahnen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Thurmond : Une ville soutenue des mines de 
houille et des chemins de fer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Thurmond: Uma cidade carregada das minas de 
carvão e das estradas de ferro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Thurmond: Una città sopportata dalle 
miniere di carbone e dalle ferrovie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Thurmond: Μια πόλη γεννημένη από τα ορυχεία 
άνθρακα και τους σιδηροδρόμους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Thurmond: Una ciudad llevada de minas de 
carbón y de ferrocarriles</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Recounts the story of the New River Gorge area in West Virginia. It is mountainous and remained sparsely populated and largely inaccessible until 1873, when the Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company laid track through the gorge. Coal mining companies, towns, and camps appeared almost overnight to mine the coal deposits. One of these towns, the railroading town of Thurmond, reached its peak as the major revenue producer for the C&amp;O Railroad during the early 1900s, a time when coal was king.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zählt die Geschichte des neuen 
Fluss-Schluchtbereiches in West Virginia nach. Es ist gebirgig 
und spärlich bevölkert und groß unzugänglich bis 1873 geblieben, 
als Chesapeake und Ohio Railway Company Spur durch die Schlucht 
legten. Kohlengrubefirmen, -städte und -lager sahen zu meinen 
die Kohleablagerungen fast Nacht aus. Eine dieser Städte, die 
railroading Stadt von Thurmond, erreichte seine Spitze als der 
Haupteinkommen Produzent für die C&amp;O Eisenbahn während der frühen 
1900s, eine Zeit, als Kohle König war.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Raconte l'histoire de la nouvelle région de gorge
de fleuve en Virginie Occidentale. Elle est montagneuse et 
restée peu abondamment peuplée et en grande partie inaccessible 
jusqu'en 1873, quand Chesapeake et l'Ohio Railway Company ont étendu 
la piste par la gorge. Les compagnies, les villes, et les camps 
de mine de houille ont semblé presque durant la nuit au mien les 
gisements de charbon. Une de ces villes, la ville railroading de
Thurmond, a atteint sa crête en tant que producteur principal de 
revenu pour le chemin de fer de C&amp;O pendant les années 1900 tôt, un 
moment où le charbon était roi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Recounts a história da área nova do gorge do rio
em Virgínia ocidental. É montanhosa e remanescida povoada 
escassa e pela maior parte inacessível até 1873, quando o Chesapeake
e o Ohio Estrada de ferro Companhia colocaram a trilha através do 
gorge. As companhias de mineração de carvão, as cidades, e os
acampamentos pareceram quase de noite a minhas os depósitos de 
carvão. Uma destas cidades, a cidade railroading de Thurmond, 
alcançou seu pico como o produtor principal do rendimento para a 
estrada de ferro durante os 1900s adiantados, uma época de C&amp;O em que
o carvão fosse rei.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Racconta la storia di nuova zona del gorge del 
fiume nella Virginia dell'Ovest. È montagnosa e rimasta 
popolata scarsamente ed in gran parte inaccessibile fino al 1873, 
quando il Chesapeake e l'Ohio Railway Company hanno posto la pista 
attraverso il gorge. Le aziende, le città e gli accampamenti di
miniera di carbone sono sembrato quasi di notte a mine i giacimenti di
carbone. Una di queste città, la città railroading di 
Thurmond, ha raggiunto il relativo picco come il produttore principale
del reddito per la ferrovia durante i 1900s in anticipo, un periodo di
C&amp;O in cui il carbone era re.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξιστορεί την ιστορία της νέας περιοχής φαραγγιών 
ποταμών στη δυτική Βιρτζίνια. Είναι ορεινό και παραμένοντα
αραιά εποικημένο και κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος απρόσιτο μέχρι 
1873, όταν έβαλαν chesapeake και η επιχείρηση σιδηροδρόμων 
του Οχάιου τη διαδρομή μέσω του φαραγγιού. Οι επιχειρήσεις 
μεταλλείας άνθρακα, οι πόλεις, και τα στρατόπεδα εμφανίστηκαν 
σχεδόν ολονύκτιες για να εξαγάγουν τις καταθέσεις άνθρακα. 
Μια από αυτές τις πόλεις, η railroading πόλη Thurmond,
έφθασε στην αιχμή της ως σημαντικότερο παραγωγό εισοδήματος για 
το C&amp;O σιδηρόδρομο κατά τη διάρκεια των πρόωρων δεκαετιών του 
20ου αιώνα, ένας χρόνος όταν ο άνθρακας ήταν βασιλιάς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Contó de nuevo la historia de la nueva área del 
gorge del río en Virginia Occidental. Es montañosa y seguida 
siendo poblada escaso y en gran parte inaccesible hasta 1873, cuando 
el Chesapeake y el Ohio Railway Company pusieron la pista a través 
del gorge. Las compañías, las ciudades, y los campos de la 
mina de carbón aparecían casi de noche las mías los depósitos del 
carbón. Una de estas ciudades, la ciudad railroading de 
Thurmond, alcanzó su pico como el productor principal del rédito 
para el ferrocarril durante los 1900s tempranos, una época de C&amp;O en 
que el carbón era rey.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207248</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106760</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/thurmond-a-town-born-from-coal-mines-and-railroads</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
