<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108060</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108060</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087394</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">An Old New York Cabinet Maker: Experiences of Ernest Hagen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Alter New York Schrank-Hersteller: 
Erfahrungen von Ernest Hagen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un Vieil Ébéniste de New York : 
Expériences d'Ernest Hagen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um Fabricante De Armário Velho De New York: 
Experiências de Ernest Hagen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Vecchio Creatore Del Governo De New York: 
Esperienze in Ernest Hagen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένας παλαιός κατασκευαστής γραφείου της Νέας Υόρκης:
Εμπειρία Ernest χάγη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Viejo Ebanista De Nueva York: Experiencias 
de Ernest Hagen</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The most visible signs of industrialization in mid nineteenth-century America occurred in mushrooming factory towns such as Lowell, Massachusetts, but changes in manufacturing also took place in metropolises like New York City. Waves of immigrants entered the port cities 'small workshops, sites of intense craft activity. Cabinetmaking resisted mechanization and unskilled labor because the trade required intricate work on complex pieces of furniture. In his unpublished memoir German immigrant Ernst Hagen recalled that many of the leading names in nineteenth-century furniture, well represented today in museum collections, presided over large shops of toiling workers. Some employed over two hundred hands. The post-Civil War rise of western factories disrupted this urban system; skilled workers either found other employment or were relegated to margins of the trade such as repair work.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die sichtbarsten Zeichen der Industrialisierung 
mittleres 19.-Jahrhundert Amerika traten in explosionsartig 
vermehrenfabrikstädten wie Lowell, Massachusetts auf, aber 
Änderungen, wenn sie auch herstellen, fanden in den Hauptstadt wie 
New York City statt. Wellen der Immigranten kleine Werkstätten 
kamen der Portstädte ', Sites der intensiven Fertigkeitaktivität. 
Cabinetmaking widerstand Mechanisierung und unerfahrener Arbeit,
weil der Handel schwierige Arbeit über komplizierte Möbelstücke 
benötigte. In seiner unveröffentlichten Abhandlung deutsches 
einwanderndes Ernst rief Hagen wieder auf, daß viele der führenden 
Namen in den 19.-Jahrhundert Möbeln, die Vertiefung, die heute in den
Museum Ansammlungen dargestellt wurde, große Systeme des 
Überschusses des abplagens der Arbeiter vorsassen. 
Einige eingesetzt über zweihundert Händen. Der 
PfostenZivilkrieganstieg der westlichen Fabriken störte dieses 
städtische System; erfahrene Arbeiter entweder fanden andere 
Beschäftigung oder wurden zu den Seitenrändern des Handels wie 
Reparaturarbeit relegiert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les signes les plus visibles de 
l'industrialisation en mi dix-neuvième-siècle Amérique se sont 
produits dans les villes de répandage d'usine telles que Lowell, le 
Massachusetts, mais les changements de la fabrication également sont 
intervenus dans les métropoles comme New York City. Les vagues 
des immigrés petits ateliers sont entrées dans villes gauches les ',
sites d'activité intense de métier. Cabinetmaking a résisté 
à la mécanisation et à la main-d'oeuvre nonne qualifié parce que 
le commerce a exigé le travail complexe sur les meubles complexes. 
Dans son mémoire non publié Ernst immigré allemand Hagen a 
rappelé que plusieurs des principaux noms dans des meubles de 
dix-neuvième-siècle, puits représenté aujourd'hui dans des 
collections de musée, ont présidé de grands systèmes d'excédent 
des ouvriers de travail. Certains utilisés plus de deux cents 
mains. L'élévation poteau-Civile de guerre d'usines 
occidentales a perturbé ce système urbain ; les ouvriers 
habiles ont trouvé l'autre emploi ou ont été relégués aux marges 
du commerce telles que le travail de réparation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os sinais os mais visíveis do industrialization 
no décimo-século mid América ocorreram em cidades crescendo 
rapidamente da fábrica tais como Lowell, Massachusetts, mas as 
mudanças em manufaturar também ocorreram nos metropolises como New 
York City. As ondas dos immigrants entraram as oficinas pequenas
nas cidades portuárias ', locais da atividade intensa do ofício. 
Cabinetmaking resistiu o mechanization e trabalho inábil porque
o comércio requereu o trabalho intricado em partes de furniture 
complexas. Em seu memoir unpublished Ernst immigrant alemão 
Hagen recordou que muitos dos nomes principais no furniture de 
décimo-século, poço representado hoje em coleções do museu, 
presided lojas grandes do excesso de trabalhadores labutando. 
Alguns empregados sobre dois cem mãos. A ascensão 
borne-Civil da guerra de fábricas ocidentais disrupted este sistema 
urbano; os trabalhadores hábeis encontraram o outro emprego ou 
relegated às margens do comércio tais como o trabalho do reparo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I segni più visibili dell'industrializzazione nel
metà di diciannovesimo-secolo America si sono presentati nelle città
crescenti della fabbrica quale Lowell, Massachusetts, ma i cambiamenti
nella produzione anche hanno avvenuto in metropolises come New York 
City. Le onde degli immigranti hanno entrato fabbriche di 
limitata entità nelle città port ', luoghi di attività intensa del 
mestiere. Cabinetmaking ha resistito alla meccanizzazione ed al 
lavoro non qualificato perché il commercio ha richiesto il 
lavoro complicato sulle parti di mobilia complesse. Nella sua 
memoria non pubblicata Ernst immigrato tedesco Hagen ha ricordato che 
molti dei nomi principali in mobilia di diciannovesimo-secolo, pozzo 
rappresentato oggi nelle collezioni del museo, hanno presieduto grandi
negozi dell'eccedenza degli operai lavoranti duramente. Alcuni 
impiegati oltre duecento mani. L'aumento alberino-Civile di 
guerra delle fabbriche occidentali ha interrotto questo sistema 
urbano; in operai esperti hanno trovato l'altra occupazione o 
sono stati relegati ai margini del commercio quale il lavoro di 
riparazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα πιό ορατά σημάδια της εκβιομηχάνισης στο μέσο 
δέκατος-αιώνα Αμερική εμφανίστηκαν ξεφυτρώνοντας στις κωμοπόλεις
εργοστασίων όπως το Lowell, Μασαχουσέτη, αλλά οι αλλαγές στην 
κατασκευή πραγματοποιήθηκαν επίσης στα metropolises όπως την 
πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης. Τα κύματα των μεταναστών μικρά 
εργαστήρια μπήκαν των λιμένων πόλεων ", περιοχές της έντονης 
δραστηριότητας τεχνών. Το Cabinetmaking αντιστάθηκε στη 
μηχανοποίηση και την ανειδίκευτη εργασία επειδή το εμπόριο 
απαίτησε την περίπλοκη εργασία για τα σύνθετα κομμάτια των 
επίπλων. Στα αδημοσίευτα απομνημονεύματά του ο γερμανικός 
που έχουν μεταναστεύσει Ernst η χάγη υπενθύμισε ότι πολλά 
από τα κύρια ονόματα στα έπιπλα δέκατος-αιώνα, αντιπροσώπευσαν 
καλά σήμερα στις συλλογές μουσείων, προήδρευσαν πέρα από τα 
μεγάλα καταστήματα των μοχθούντων εργαζομένων. Μερικοί 
χρησιμοποίησαν πάνω από διακόσια χέρια. Η μετα-αστική 
πολεμική άνοδος των δυτικών εργοστασίων αναστάτωσε αυτό το 
αστικό σύστημα  οι ειδικευμένοι εργαζόμενοι είτε βρήκαν 
άλλη απασχόληση είτε στάλησαν στα περιθώρια του εμπορίου όπως η
εργασία επισκευής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las muestras más visibles de la 
industrialización en el diecinueveavo-siglo mediados de América 
ocurrieron en ciudades de la fábrica que proliferaban rápidamente 
tales como Lowell, Massachusetts, pero los cambios en la fabricación 
también ocurrieron en metrópolis como New York City. Las ondas
de inmigrantes entraron en los talleres pequeños de las ciudades 
portuarias ', sitios de la actividad intensa del arte. 
Cabinetmaking resistió la mecanización y el trabajo inexperto 
porque el comercio requirió el trabajo intrincado sobre pedazos de 
muebles complejos. En su memoria inédita Ernst inmigrante 
alemán Hagen recordó que presidieron muchos de los nombres 
principales en los muebles del diecinueveavo-siglo, receptor de papel 
representado hoy en colecciones del museo, los departamentos grandes 
del excedente de trabajadores que trabajaban. Algunos empleados 
sobre doscientas manos. La subida poste-Civil de la guerra de 
fábricas occidentales interrumpió este sistema urbano; los 
trabajadores expertos encontraron el otro empleo o fueron relegados a 
los márgenes del comercio tales como trabajo de la reparación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087394</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108060</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/an-old-new-york-cabinet-maker-experiences-of-ernest-hagen</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
