<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105922</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105922</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206102</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Fermilab Resources for Students</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fermilab Betriebsmittel für Kursteilnehmer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ressources de Fermilab pour des étudiants</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Recursos de Fermilab para estudantes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Risorse di Fermilab per gli allievi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς Fermilab για τους σπουδαστές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recursos de Fermilab para los estudiantes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers materials for learning about particle physics and the pursuit of questions such as What is the smallest piece of matter? How did the universe begin? It includes streamed lectures by distinguished scientists and teachers, a newspaper for middle school students, classroom units and projects, physics data, games, and more. Fermilab is a high-energy physics laboratory, home of the world's most powerful particle accelerator, the Tevatron.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angebotmaterialien für das Lernen über 
Partikelphysik und die Verfolgung von Fragen wie, was das kleinste 
Stück des Stoffes ist? Wie fing das Universum an? Es 
schließt geströmte Vorträge durch bemerkenswerte Wissenschaftler 
und Lehrer, eine Zeitung für Kursteilnehmer der mittleren Schule, 
Klassenzimmermaßeinheiten und Projekte, Physikdaten, Spiele und mehr 
ein. Fermilab ist ein energiereiches Physiklabor, Haus des 
leistungsfähigsten Partikelgaspedals der Welt, das Tevatron.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">matériaux d'offres pour se renseigner sur la 
physique de particules et la poursuite des questions telles que ce qui
est le plus petit morceau de matière ? Comment l'univers a-t-il
commencé ? Il inclut des conférences coulées par les 
scientifiques et les professeurs distingués, un journal pour des 
étudiants de collège, des unités de salle de classe et des projets,
données de physique, jeux, et plus. Fermilab est un laboratoire
de grande énergie de physique, maison de l'accélérateur le plus 
puissant des particules du monde, le Tevatron.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">materiais das ofertas para a aprendizagem sobre a 
física da partícula e a perseguição das perguntas tais como o que 
é a parte a menor de matéria? Como o universo começou? 
Inclui lectures fluídos por distintos cientistas e professores,
um jornal para estudantes da escola média, unidades da sala de aula e
projetos, dados da física, jogos, e mais. Fermilab é um 
laboratório high-energy da física, HOME do accelerator o mais 
poderoso da partícula do mundo, o Tevatron.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">materiali di offerte per imparare circa la fisica 
della particella e l'inseguimento delle domande come che cosa è la 
più piccola parte della materia? Come l'universo ha cominciato?
Include le conferenze effluite dagli scienziati ed insegnanti 
distinti, un giornale per gli allievi della scuola centrale, unità 
dell'aula ed i progetti, dati di fisica, giochi e più. Fermilab
è un laboratorio ad alta energia di fisica, sede dell'acceleratore 
della particella più potente del mondo, il Tevatron.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τα υλικά για την εκμάθηση για τη φυσική 
μορίων και την αναζήτηση των ερωτήσεων όπως αυτό που είναι το 
μικρότερο κομμάτι του θέματος; Πώς ο κόσμος άρχισε; 
Περιλαμβάνει τις ρεσμένες διαλέξεις από τους διακεκριμένους
επιστήμονες και τους δασκάλους, μια εφημερίδα για τους μέσους 
σχολικούς σπουδαστές, τις μονάδες τάξεων και τα προγράμματα, 
στοιχεία φυσικής, παιχνίδια, και περισσότερο. Το Fermilab
είναι ένα υψηλής ενέργειας εργαστήριο φυσικής, σπίτι της 
συντομογραφίας παγκόσμιων ισχυρότερης μορίων, το Tevatron.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿materiales de las ofertas para aprender sobre la 
física de la partícula y la búsqueda de preguntas tales como cuál 
es el pedazo más pequeño de la materia? ¿Cómo el universo 
comenzó? Incluye conferencias fluidas de los científicos y los
profesores distinguidos, un periódico para los estudiantes de la 
escuela media, las unidades y los proyectos, datos de la física, 
juegos de la sala de clase, y más. Fermilab es un laboratorio 
de gran energía de la física, hogar del acelerador más de gran 
alcance de la partícula del mundo, el Tevatron.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206102</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105922</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/fermilab-resources-for-students</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
