<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106286</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106286</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205820</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Poetry Out Loud</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Poesie Heraus Loud</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Poésie Dehors Fort</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Poesia Para fora Ruidosamente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Poesia Fuori Alto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ποίηση έξω δυνατή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Poesía Hacia fuera Ruidosamente</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a national recitation contest aimed to encourage memorization and performance of great poems. Materials to support that aim are provided online: texts of 450 poems, sound recordings of 35 poetry readings and lectures, and contest information for students and teachers. See poems by more than 250 poets, including Dickinson, Donne, Dove, Eliot, Frost, Hughes, MacLeish, Keats, Shakespeare, Stevens, Wordsworth, Yeats, and others.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein nationaler recitation Wettbewerb, der 
darauf abgezielt wird, um Memorieren und Leistung der großen Gedichte
anzuregen. Zu unterstützen Materialien, daß Ziel online zur 
Verfügung gestellt werden: Texte von 450 Gedichten, 
Tonaufnahmen von 35 Poesiemesswerten und -vorträgen und 
Wettbewerbinformationen für Kursteilnehmer und Lehrer. Sehen 
Sie Gedichte durch mehr als 250 Dichter, einschließlich Dickinson, 
Donne, Taube, Eliot, Frost, Hughes, MacLeish, Keats, Shakespeare, 
Stevens, Wordsworth, Yeats und andere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un concours national de recitation visant pour
encourager la mémorisation et l'exécution de grandes poésies. 
Matériaux à supporter que le but sont fournis en ligne : 
textes de 450 poésies, enregistrements sonores de 35 lectures 
et conférences de poésie, et information de concours pour des 
étudiants et des professeurs. Voir les poésies par plus de 250
poèts, y compris Dickinson, Donne, colombe, Eliot, gel, Hughes, 
MacLeish, Keats, Shakespeare, Stevens, Wordsworth, Yeats, et d'autres.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma competição nacional do recitation 
apontada incentivar o memorization e o desempenho de poemas grandes. 
Materiais a suportar que o alvo está fornecido em linha: 
textos de 450 poemas, gravações sadias de 35 leituras e 
lectures da poesia, e informação da competição para estudantes e 
professores. Veja poemas por mais de 250 poetas, including 
Dickinson, Donne, pomba, Eliot, geada, Hughes, MacLeish, Keats, 
Shakespeare, Stevens, Wordsworth, Yeats, e outro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un concorso nazionale di recitation mirante per
consigliare alla memorizzazione ed alle prestazioni dei poems grandi. 
Materiali da sostenere che lo scopo è fornito in linea: i
testi di 450 poems, lle registrazioni del suono di 35 letture e 
conferenze di poesia e le informazioni di concorso per gli allievi e 
gli insegnanti. Veda i poems da più di 250 poets, compreso 
Dickinson, Donne, colomba, Eliot, gelo, Hughes, MacLeish, Keats, 
Shakespeare, Stevens, Wordsworth, Yeats ed altri.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένας εθνικός διαγωνισμός απαγγελίας που 
στοχεύει να ενθαρρύνει την αποστήθιση και την απόδοση των μεγάλων
ποιημάτων. Υλικά που υποστηρίζουν ότι ο στόχος παρέχεται 
on-line: κείμενα 450 ποιημάτων, υγιείς καταγραφές 
35 αναγνώσεων και διαλέξεων ποίησης, και πληροφορίες 
διαγωνισμού για τους σπουδαστές και τους δασκάλους. 
Δείτε τα ποιήματα από περισσότερους από 250 
ποιητές, συμπεριλαμβανομένου Dickinson, Donne, του 
περιστεριού, Eliot, του παγετού, του Hughes, MacLeish, 
Keats, Shakespeare, Stevens, Wordsworth, Yeats, και 
άλλων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una competencia nacional del recitation estado 
dirigida para animar la memorización y el funcionamiento de grandes 
poemas. Materiales a utilizar que la puntería está 
proporcionada en línea: textos de 450 poemas, grabaciones de 
sonidos de 35 lecturas y conferencias de la poesía, e información de
la competencia para los estudiantes y los profesores. Vea los 
poemas de más de 250 poetas, incluyendo Dickinson, Donne, paloma, 
Eliot, helada, Hughes, MacLeish, Keats, Shakespeare, Stevens, 
Wordsworth, Yeats, y otros.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205820</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106286</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/poetry-out-loud</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
