<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107389</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107389</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212977</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Using the Internet to Promote Inquiry-Based Learning</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verwenden des Internets, um das 
Anfrage-Gegründete Lernen zu fördern</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Utilisation de l'Internet pour favoriser l'étude 
Enquête-Basée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Usando o Internet promover a aprendizagem 
Inquérito-Baseada</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Usando il Internet per promuovere imparare 
Inchiesta-Basato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χρησιμοποίηση του Διαδικτύου για να προωθήσει την 
έρευνα-βασισμένη εκμάθηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usar el Internet para promover aprender 
Pregunta-Basado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site is an e-paper that describes a structured approach to inquiry-based learning using the World Wide Web as a primary information resource. Specifically, the paper addresses an 8-step process that begins with an essential question and ends with a product produced by students, typically completed in a cooperative setting. The paper also discusses the skills required by both student and teacher to make inquiry-based learning with the internet a successful endeavor. Finally, the paper discusses the components of a Project Page, an online document that facilitates the learning process and supports the reader with Web links relating to inquiry-based learning.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site ist ein Epapier, das eine strukturierte
Annäherung zum Anfrage-gegründeten Lernen mit dem World Wide Web als
Primärinformationen Hilfsmittel beschreibt. Spezifisch 
adressiert das Papier einen Prozeß 8-step, der mit einer wesentlichen
Frage und Enden mit einem Produkt anfängt, das von den 
Kursteilnehmern produziert wird, gewöhnlich durchgeführt in einer 
kooperativen Einstellung. Das Papier behandelt auch die 
Fähigkeiten, die vom Kursteilnehmer und vom Lehrer benötigt werden, 
um zu bilden Anfrage-gegründet, mit dem Internet eine erfolgreiche 
Bemühung erlernend. Schließlich behandelt das Papier die 
Bestandteile einer Projekt-Seite, ein Onlinedokument, das den 
Lernprozeß erleichtert und den Leser mit Web bindet in bezug auf das 
Anfrage-gegründete Lernen unterstützt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site est un e-papier qui décrit une approche 
structurée à l'étude enquête-basée en utilisant le Web 
mondial comme ressource primaire de l'information. 
Spécifiquement, le papier adresse un processus 8-step qui 
commence par une question essentielle et des extrémités avec un 
produit produit par des étudiants, typiquement complété dans une 
configuration coopérative. Le papier discute également les 
qualifications exigées par l'étudiant et le professeur pour faire 
enquête-basé apprenant avec l'Internet un effort réussi. En 
conclusion, le papier discute les composants d'une page de projet, un 
document en ligne qui facilite l'apprentissage et supporte le lecteur 
avec le Web joint concernant l'étude enquête-basée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local é um e-papel que descreva uma 
aproximação estruturada à aprendizagem inquérito-baseada usando o 
World Wide Web como um recurso preliminar da informação. 
Especificamente, o papel dirige-se a um processo 8-step que 
comece com uma pergunta essencial e as extremidades com um produto 
produzido por estudantes, terminado tipicamente em um ajuste 
cooperativo. O papel discute também as habilidades requeridas  
pelo estudante e pelo professor para fazer inquérito-baseado 
aprendendo com o Internet um esforço bem sucedido. Finalmente, 
o papel discute os componentes de uma página do projeto, um original 
em linha que facilite o processo de aprendizagem e suporte o leitor 
com Web ligue se relacionar à aprendizagem inquérito-baseada.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo è una e-carta che descrive un metodo
strutturato ad imparare inchiesta-basato usando il World Wide Web come
risorsa primaria delle informazioni. Specificamente, la carta 
richiama un processo 8-step che comincia con una domanda essenziale e 
le estremità con un prodotto prodotto dagli allievi, realizzato 
tipicamente in una regolazione cooperativa. La carta egualmente 
discute le abilità richieste sia dall'allievo che dall'insegnante per
fare inchiesta-basato imparando con il Internet un'attività riuscita.
Per concludere, la carta discute i componenti di una pagina di 
progetto, un documento in linea che facilita l'apprendimento e 
sostiene il lettore con il Web si collega concernente imparare 
inchiesta-basato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή είναι ένα ε-χαρτί που περιγράφει μια 
δομημένη προσέγγιση στην έρευνα-βασισμένη στον εκμάθηση 
χρησιμοποιώντας το World Wide Web ως αρχική πηγή 
πληροφοριών. Συγκεκριμένα, το έγγραφο εξετάζει μια 
διαδικασία 8-βημάτων που αρχίζει με μια ουσιαστική ερώτηση και 
τελειώνει με ένα προϊόν που παράγεται από τους σπουδαστές, που 
ολοκληρώνονται χαρακτηριστικά σε μια συνεταιριστική τιμή τών 
παραμέτρων. Το έγγραφο συζητά επίσης τις δεξιότητες που 
απαιτούνται και από το σπουδαστή και από το δάσκαλο για να 
κάνουν έρευνα-βασισμένος στο μαθαίνοντας με το Διαδίκτυο μια 
επιτυχή προσπάθεια. Τέλος, το έγγραφο συζητά τα συστατικά 
μιας σελίδας προγράμματος, ένα σε απευθείας σύνδεση έγγραφο που 
διευκολύνει τη διαδικασία εκμάθησης και υποστηρίζει τον αναγνώστη
με τις συνδέσεις Ιστού σχετικά με την έρευνα-βασισμένη στον 
εκμάθηση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio es un e-papel que describe un 
acercamiento estructurado a aprender pregunta-basado usando el 
Web mundial como recurso primario de la información. 
Específicamente, el papel trata un proceso 8-step que comience 
con una pregunta esencial y los extremos con un producto producido por
los estudiantes, terminado típicamente en una configuración 
cooperativa. El papel también discute las habilidades 
requeridas por el estudiante y el profesor para hacer pregunta-basado 
aprendiendo con el Internet un esfuerzo acertado. Finalmente, el
papel discute los componentes de una paginación del proyecto, un 
documento en línea que facilite el proceso de aprendizaje y apoye a 
programa de lectura con el Web conecte referente a aprender 
pregunta-basado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DAVE JAKES
FN:DAVE JAKES
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212977</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107389</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/using-the-internet-to-promote-inquiry-based-learning</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
