<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106209</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106209</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209762</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Fundamentals of Narrative Film Editing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Grundlagen des erzählenden Film-Bearbeitens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Principes fondamentaux de l'édition narrative de 
film</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fundamentos da edição narrativa da película</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fondamenti di stampa narrativa della pellicola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βασικές αρχές αφηγηματικό να επιμεληθεί ταινιών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fundamentales de corregir narrativo de la 
película</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This course covers the basics of editing a conversation. This is dramatic scene with scripted dialog. Editing dialog is the most basic form of editing in motion pictures. This is what you need to learn first. This series of lessons gives you hands-on experience editing actual motion pictures and television dramas. It's the real thing! </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Kurs umfaßt die Grundlagen des Bearbeitens
eines Gespräches. Dieses ist drastische Szene mit scripted 
Dialog. Dialog zu bearbeiten ist das grundlegendste Formular des
Bearbeitens in den Bewegung Abbildungen. Dieses ist, was Sie 
zuerst erlernen müssen. Diese Reihe Lektionen gibt Ihnen die 
praktischen Übungen, die tatsächliche Bewegung Abbildungen und 
Fernsehendramen bearbeiten. Es ist die reale Sache!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce cours couvre les fondations d'éditer une 
conversation. C'est scène excessive avec le dialogue 
préétablir. L'édition du dialogue est la forme la plus 
fondamentale de l'édition dans des films cinématographiques. 
Est ce ce que vous devez apprendre d'abord. Cette série 
de leçons vous donne une expérience à commande manuelle éditant 
les films cinématographiques et les drames réels de télévision. 
C'est la vraie chose !</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este curso cobre os princípios de editar uma 
conversação. Esta é cena dramática com scripted o diálogo. 
Editar o diálogo é o formulário o mais básico da edição em
retratos de movimento. Este é o que você necessita aprender 
primeiramente. Esta série das lições dá-lhe a experiência 
hands-on que edita retratos de movimento e dramas reais da televisão.
É a coisa real!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo corso riguarda i principi fondamentali di 
stampa della conversazione. Ciò è scena drammatica con 
scripted il dialogo. La stampa del dialogo è la forma più 
fondamentale di stampa nel cinema. Ciò è che cosa dovete 
imparare in primo luogo. Questa serie di lezioni vi dà 
l'esperienza hands-on che stampa il cinema ed i drammi reali della 
televisione. È la cosa reale!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων καλύπτει τα βασικά να 
επιμεληθεί μια συνομιλία. Αυτό είναι δραματική σκηνή με το
προκαθορισμένο διαλογικό παράθυρο. Να επιμεληθεί το 
διαλογικό παράθυρο είναι η πιό βασική μορφή να επιμεληθεί στις 
ταινίες. Αυτό είναι αυτό που πρέπει να μάθετε πρώτα. 
Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων σας δίνει την εμπράγματη εμπειρία 
επιμεμένος τις πραγματικά ταινίες και τα τηλεοπτικά δράματα. 
Είναι το πραγματικό πράγμα!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este curso cubre los fundamentos de corregir una 
conversación. Ésta es escena dramática con scripted diálogo.
Corregir diálogo es la forma más básica de corregir en 
películas. Esto es lo que usted necesita aprender primero. 
Esta serie de lecciones le da la experiencia con manos que 
corrige películas y dramas reales de la televisión. ¡Es la 
cosa verdadera!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209762</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">GNU Free Documentation License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106209</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/fundamentals-of-narrative-film-editing</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
