<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103837</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103837</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202929</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Geology Collection: Rocks and Minerals Homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geologie-Ansammlung: Felsen und 
Mineral-homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Collection de Géologie : Roches et homepage
de minerais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Coleção Da Geologia: Rochas e homepage de 
minerais</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Accumulazione Di Geologia: Roccie e homepage
dei minerali</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συλλογή γεωλογίας: Αρχική σελίδα βράχων και 
μεταλλευμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Colección De la Geología: Rocas y homepage
de los minerales</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features rock and mineral photographs that can be used for teaching or research. There are pictures of minerals, fossils, and sedimentary, metamorphic, and igneous rocks. There are also images of thin sections of igneous and metamorphic rocks. Sets of images are presented as collections for geology courses. The site also provides information on igneous and metamorphic petrology topics such as metacarbonates, contact metamorphism, regional metamorphism, and blueschists, granulites, and eclogites. There is also a mineral web quiz. This resource is part of the Teaching Petrology collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Situationsmerkmalfelsen- und 
-mineralfotographien, die für das Unterrichten oder Forschung benutzt
werden können. Es gibt Abbildungen der Mineralien, der 
Fossilien und der sedimentären, metamorphen und Eruptivgesteine. 
Es gibt auch Bilder der dünnen Kapitel der Eruptiv- und 
metamorphen Felsen. Sets Bilder werden als Ansammlungen für 
Geologiekurse dargestellt. Die Site stellt auch Informationen 
auf den Eruptiv- und metamorphen Petrologythemen wie metacarbonates, 
Kontaktmetamorphismus, regionaler Metamorphismus und blueschists, 
granulites und Eclogites zur Verfügung. Es gibt auch einen 
Mineralweb-Quiz. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Teil der 
unterrichtenden Petrologyansammlung 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ces photographies de roche et de minerai de 
dispositifs de site qui peuvent être utilisées pour l'enseignement 
ou la recherche. Il y a des images des minerais, des fossiles, 
et des roches sédimentaires, métamorphiques, et plutoniques. 
Il y a également des images des sections minces des roches 
ignées et métamorphiques. Des ensembles d'images sont 
présentés comme collections pour des cours de géologie. Le 
site fournit également des informations sur des sujets ignés et 
métamorphiques de petrology tels que des metacarbonates, 
métamorphisme de contact, métamorphisme régional, et des 
blueschists, des granulites, et des éclogites. Il y a 
également un jeu minéral de Web. Cette ressource fait partie 
de la collection d'enseignement 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html de 
petrology</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estas fotografias da rocha e do mineral das 
características de local que podem ser usadas para ensinar ou 
pesquisa. Há uns retratos dos minerais, dos fossils, e de 
rochas sedimentary, metamorphic, e igneous. Há também umas 
imagens de seções finas de rochas igneous e metamorphic. Os 
jogos das imagens são apresentados como coleções para cursos da 
geologia. O local fornece também a informação em tópicos 
igneous e metamorphic da petrologia tais como metacarbonates, 
metamorphism do contato, metamorphism regional, e blueschists, 
granulites, e eclogites. Há também um quiz mineral do Web. 
Este recurso é parte da coleção ensinando 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html da 
petrologia</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Queste fotografie della roccia e del minerale 
delle caratteristiche di luogo che possono essere usate per 
l'istruzione o la ricerca. Ci sono immagini dei minerali, dei 
fossili e delle rocce eruttive sedimentarie, metamorfiche e. Ci 
sono egualmente immagini delle sezioni sottili delle roccie ignee e 
metamorfiche. Gli insiemi delle immagini sono presentati come 
collezioni per i corsi di geologia. Il luogo egualmente fornisce
le informazioni sui soggetti ignei e metamorfici di petrology quali i 
metacarbonates, metamorphism del contatto, metamorphism regionale e 
blueschists, granulites ed eclogites. Ci è egualmente un quiz 
minerale di Web. Questa risorsa fa parte dell'accumulazione 
d'istruzione 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html di 
petrology</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει το βράχο και τις ορυκτές 
φωτογραφίες που μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν για τη διδασκαλία ή 
την έρευνα. Υπάρχουν εικόνες των μεταλλευμάτων, των 
απολιθωμάτων, και των ιζηματωδών, μεταμορφικών, και πύρινων 
βράχων. Υπάρχουν επίσης εικόνες των λεπτών τμημάτων των 
πύρινων και μεταμορφικών βράχων. Τα σύνολα εικόνων 
παρουσιάζονται ως συλλογές για τις σειρές μαθημάτων γεωλογίας. 
Η περιοχή παρέχει επίσης τις πληροφορίες για τα πύρινα και 
μεταμορφικά θέματα πετρολογίας όπως τα metacarbonates, 
metamorphism επαφών, περιφερειακό metamorphism, και τα 
blueschists, granulites, και eclogites. Υπάρχει 
επίσης ένας ορυκτός διαγωνισμός γνώσεων Ιστού. Αυτό το 
στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι μέρος της συλλογής 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html 
πετρολογίας διδασκαλίας</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estas fotografías de la roca y del mineral de las
características de sitio que se pueden utilizar para enseñar o la 
investigación. Hay cuadros de minerales, de fósiles, y de 
rocas sedimentarias, metamórficas, e ígneas. Hay también 
imágenes de las secciones finas de rocas ígneas y metamórficas. 
Los conjuntos de imágenes se presentan como colecciones para 
los cursos de la geología. El sitio también proporciona a la 
información en asuntos ígneos y metamórficos de la petrología 
tales como metacarbonates, metamorfismo del contacto, metamorfismo 
regional, y los blueschists, los granulites, y los eclogites. 
Hay también un concurso mineral del Web. Este recurso es 
parte de la colección de enseñanza 
http://serc.carleton.edu/NAGTWorkshops/petrology03/index.html de la 
petrología</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBERT MARSH
FN:ROBERT MARSH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202929</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103837</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/geology-collection-rocks-and-minerals-homepage</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
