<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103143</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103143</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087303</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A German Jewish Woman Settles in North Dakota</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine deutsche jüdische Frausettles in North 
Dakota</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Stabilisations juives allemandes d'une femme au 
Dakota du nord</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Settles jewish alemães de uma mulher em dakota 
norte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Settles ebrei tedeschi della donna nel Dakota del 
Nord</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια γερμανική εβραϊκή γυναίκα εγκαθιστά στη βόρεια 
Ντακότα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Settles judíos alemanes de una mujer en Dakota 
del Norte</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Women who settled the West in the years after the Civil War often faced harsh and unremitting toil. Laboring from well before dawn until well after the sun had set, women helped plant and harvest crops, raised large families, and kept house with the most rudimentary of equipment. Long periods of isolation from neighbors and kin were common; social occasions or visits by travelers and kin were rare and cherished events. Sarah Thal, a German Jew who immigrated to North Dakota in 1882, recalled that "getting mail was a big event" on their North Dakota farm and that when she looked out the window onto the flat prairie she was "still unable to realize the completeness of our isolation."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Frauen, die den Westen in den Jahren vereinbarten,
nachdem der Bürgerkrieg häufig rauhe und unaufhörliche 
Mühe gegenüberstellte. Bearbeitung von gut vor 
Dämmerung bis gut, nachdem die Sonne eingestellt hatte, Frauen 
geholfene Betriebs- und Erntegetreide, angehobene große Familien und 
gehaltenes Haus mit dem rudimentärsten der Ausrüstung. Lange 
Perioden der Lokalisierung von den Nachbarn und von den Stämmen waren
geläufig; Sozialgelegenheiten oder Besuche durch Reisende und 
Stämme waren seltene und geschätzte Fälle. Sarah Thal, ein 
deutscher Jude, der zu North Dakota 1882 einwanderte, wieder 
aufgerufen, daß, "Post zu erhalten ein grosser Fall" auf ihrem North 
Dakota Bauernhof war und daß, als sie aus dem Fenster auf das flache 
Grasland sie schaute, war "noch nicht imstande, die 
Vollständigkeit unserer Lokalisierung zu verwirklichen."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les femmes qui ont arrangé l'ouest en années 
après la guerre civile ont souvent fait face au travail dur dur et 
ininterrompu. Travaillant de bien avant aube jusqu'à ce que 
bien après que le soleil ait placé, collectes d'usine aidées par 
femmes et de moisson, familles nombreuses élevées, et maison gardée
avec le plus rudimentaire du matériel. Les longues périodes de
l'isolement dans des voisins et des parents étaient communes ; 
les occasions ou les visites sociales par des voyageurs et des 
parents étaient des événements rares et aimés. Sarah Thal, 
un juif allemand qui a immigré au Dakota du nord en 1882, 
rappelé que "obtenir le courrier était un grand événement" à leur
ferme du nord du Dakota et que quand elle l'a regardée hors de 
la fenêtre sur la prairie plate ne pouvait pas "encore réaliser la 
perfection de notre isolement."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As mulheres que estabeleciram o oeste nos anos 
após a guerra civil enfrentaram frequentemente a labuta áspera e 
unremitting. Trabalhando de bem antes do alvorecer até que bem 
depois que o sol se tinha ajustado, colheitas ajudadas mulheres da 
planta e da colheita, famílias grandes levantadas, e casa mantida com
o mais rudimentary do equipamento. Os períodos longos da 
isolação dos vizinhos e dos parentes eram comuns; as ocasiões
ou as visitas sociais por viajantes e por parentes eram eventos raros 
e estimados. Sarah Thal, um jew alemão que immigrated a dakota 
norte em 1882, recordado que "começar o correio era um evento grande"
em sua fazenda de dakota norte e que quando a olhou para fora da 
janela na pradaria lisa era "ainda incapaz de realizar a integralidade
de nossa isolação."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le donne che hanno depositato l'ovest durante gli 
anni dopo la guerra civile hanno affrontato spesso il lavoro duro ed 
assiduo. Lavorando da bene prima dell'alba fino a che bene dopo 
che il sole si regoli, i raccolti della raccolta e della pianta 
aiutati donne, grandi famiglie alzate e casa mantenuta con il più 
rudimentale di apparecchiatura. I periodi lunghi di isolamento 
dai vicinoi e dalle parentele erano comuni; le occasioni o le 
chiamate sociali dai viaggiatori e dalle parentele erano eventi rari 
ed affezionati. Sarah Thal, un ebreo tedesco che immigrated al 
Dakota del Nord in 1882, ricordato che "ottenere la posta era un 
evento grande" sul loro podere del Dakota del Nord e che quando la ha 
osservata verso l'esterno la finestra sul prairie piano non poteva 
"ancora realizzare la totalità del nostro isolamento."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι γυναίκες που εγκατέστησαν τη δύση στα έτη μετά 
από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο αντιμετώπισαν συχνά το σκληρό και 
αδιάλειπτο κόπο. Εργαμένος από πολύ πριν από την αυγή 
μέχρι καλά αφότου είχε θέσει ο ήλιος, οι γυναίκες βοήθησαν να 
φυτεψουν και να συγκομίσουν τις συγκομιδές, μεγάλες οικογένειες, 
και κράτησαν το σπίτι με τον πιό στοιχειώδη του εξοπλισμού. 
Οι μεγάλες περίοδοι απομόνωσης από τους γείτονες και το 
σόι ήταν κοινές  οι κοινωνικές περιπτώσεις ή οι 
επισκέψεις από τους ταξιδιώτες και το σόι ήταν σπάνιες και 
ελάτρεψαν τα γεγονότα. Το Sarah Thal, ένας γερμανικός 
Εβραίος που μετανάστευσε στη βόρεια Ντακότα το 1882, 
υπενθύμισε ότι "να πάρει το ταχυδρομείο ήταν ένα μεγάλο 
γεγονόσ" στο αγρόκτημα της βόρειας Ντακότας τους και ότι όταν 
φάνηκε έξω το παράθυρο επάνω στο επίπεδο λιβάδι ήταν "ακόμα 
ανίκανη να πραγματοποιήσει την πληρότητα της απομόνωσής μας."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las mujeres que colocaron el oeste en los años 
después de la guerra civil hicieron frente a menudo a trabajo áspero
y continuo. Trabajando de bien antes de amanecer hasta que bien 
después de que el sol hubiera fijado, cosechas ayudadas mujeres de la
planta y de la cosecha, familias grandes levantadas, y casa guardada 
con el más rudimentario del equipo. Los períodos largos del 
aislamiento de vecinos y de parentescos eran comunes; las 
ocasiones o las visitas sociales de las hojas de ruta (traveler) y de 
los parentescos eran acontecimientos raros y acariciados. Sarah 
Thal, judío alemán que immigrated a Dakota del Norte en 1882, 
recordado que "conseguir el correo era un acontecimiento grande" en su
granja de Dakota del Norte y que cuando ella la miraba fuera de la 
ventana sobre la pradera plana no podía "todavía realizar lo 
completo de nuestro aislamiento."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087303</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103143</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-german-jewish-woman-settles-in-north-dakota</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
