<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107367</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107367</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205706</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Teaching Our Youngest: A Guide for Preschool Teachers and Child Care and Family Providers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unterrichten Unser Jüngstes: Eine Anleitung
für Vorschullehrer und Kind-Obacht und Familie Versorger</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enseignement de Notre Plus jeune : Un guide 
pour les professeurs préscolaires et l'assistance à l'enfance et les
fournisseurs de famille</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ensinando Nosso Mais novo: Uma guia para 
professores prées-escolar e cuidado de criança e fornecedores da 
família</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Istruzione Del Nostro Più giovane: Una 
guida per gli insegnanti prescolari e la cura di bambino ed i 
fornitori della famiglia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διδασκαλία νεώτερού μας: Ένας οδηγός για τους 
προμηθευτές προσχολικής μέριμνας δασκάλων και παιδικής και 
οικογένειας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Enseñanza De Nuestro Más joven: Una guía 
para los profesores preescolares y el cuidado de niño y los 
abastecedores de la familia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">suggests how to read aloud to children, develop their listening and speaking skills, teach about letters and numbers, and build their background knowledge and thinking skills. The booklet is designed to help people who work with young children create rich learning environments.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">schlägt vor, wie man laut zu den Kindern liest, 
ihre hörenden und sprechenden Fähigkeiten entwickelt, über Zeichen 
und Zahlen unterrichtet und ihr Hintergrundwissen und denkenden 
Fähigkeiten aufbaut. Die Broschüre ist konzipiert, um zu 
helfen, Völker, wem Arbeit mit jungen Kindern reiche 
erlernenumgebungen erstellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">suggère comment lire à haute voix aux enfants, 
développer leurs qualifications d'écoute et parlantes, les enseigner
au sujet des lettres et des nombres, et établir leurs connaissances 
de base et qualifications de pensée. Le livret est conçu pour 
aider à peuple qui le travail avec les enfants en bas âge créent 
les environnements d'étude riches.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">sugere como ler alto às crianças, desenvolver 
suas habilidades escutando e faladoras, ensiná-las sobre letras e 
números, e construir seus conhecimento de fundo e habilidades 
pensando. O livreto é projetado ajudar povoar quem o trabalho 
com crianças novas cría ambientes de aprendizagem ricos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">suggerisce come leggere ad alta voce ai bambini, 
sviluppare le loro abilità ascoltanti e parlanti, insegnare circa le 
lettere ed i numeri e sviluppare la loro conoscenza di base ed 
abilità pensanti. Il libretto è destinato per contribuire a 
popolare chi il lavoro con i bambini in giovane età crea gli ambienti
imparanti ricchi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προτείνει πώς να διαβάσει μεγαλοφώνως στα παιδιά, να 
αναπτύξει τις δεξιότητές τους ακούσματος και ομιλίας, να διδάξει
για τις επιστολές και τους αριθμούς, και να χτίσει τις δεξιότητές
τους γνώσης υποβάθρου και σκέψης. Το βιβλιάριο σχεδιάζεται 
για να βοηθήσει τους ανθρώπους που συνεργάζονται με τα μικρά 
παιδιά δημιουργούν τα πλούσια μαθησιακά περιβάλλοντα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">sugiere cómo leer en voz alta a los niños, 
desarrollar sus habilidades que escuchan y de discursos, enseñarlas 
sobre cartas y números, y construir su conocimiento de fondo y 
habilidades de pensamiento. El librete se diseña para ayudar a 
poblar quién crea el trabajo con los niños jóvenes ambientes que 
aprenden ricos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205706</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107367</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/teaching-our-youngest-a-guide-for-preschool-teachers-and-child-care-and-family-providers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
