<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107649</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107649</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101272</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Bioterrorism: plague as a biological weapon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bioterrorism: Pest als biologische Waffe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bioterrorism : peste comme arme biologique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bioterrorism: praga como uma arma biológica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bioterrorism: peste come arma biologica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Bioterrorism: πανούκλα ως βιολογικό όπλο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Bioterrorism: plaga como arma biológica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Bioterrorism is the utilization of microorganisms or toxins in order to produce a disease and/or death in human beings, animals or plants. Different from conventional weaponry, relatively economic means are used that allow the elimination of living beings without destroying the surrounding atmosphere. The most probably method for spread of bioweapons is aerial transmission, continuing into water supplies and food. The CDC (US Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta) has subdivided into three categories the aggressiveness of "Bioweapons". Category A comprises: Plague, Anthrax, Smallpox, Botulism, Tularemia, viral hemorrhagic fevers (ebola, Marburg), the Plague.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bioterrorism ist die Anwendung der Mikroorganismen
oder der Giftstoffe, zwecks eine Krankheit und/oder einen Tod in den 
Menschen, in den Tieren oder in den Betrieben zu produzieren. 
Unterschiedlich zu herkömmlichen Kampfmittel, werden 
verhältnismäßig ökonomische Mittel verwendet, die die Beseitigung 
der lebenden Wesen erlauben, ohne die umgebende Atmosphäre zu 
zerstören. Die vermutlich Methode für Verbreitung von 
bioweapons ist Luftübertragung und fährt in Wasserversorgungen und 
in Nahrung fort. Die CDC (US Mitten zur Krankheit-Steuerung und 
zur Verhinderung, Atlanta) hat in drei Kategorien die aggressive 
Haltung von "Bioweapons" unterteilt. Kategorie A enthält: 
Pest, Anthrax, Pocken, Botulismus, Tularämie, hemorrhagic 
Virenfieber (ebola, Marburg), die Pest.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bioterrorism est l'utilisation des 
micro-organismes ou des toxines afin de produire une maladie et/ou une
mort aux êtres humains, aux animaux ou aux usines. Différent 
des armements conventionnels, on utilise des moyens relativement 
économiques qui permettent l'élimination des êtres vivants sans 
détruire l'atmosphère environnante. La méthode pour la 
diffusion des bioweapons est le plus probablement transmission 
aérienne, continuant dans les approvisionnements en eau et la 
nourriture. La CDC (centres des USA pour commande de maladie et 
empêchement, Atlanta) a subdivisé en trois catégories 
l'agressivité de "Bioweapons". La catégorie A comporte : 
Peste, anthrax, variole, botulisme, tularémie, fièvres 
hémorragiques virales (ebola, Marburg), la peste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bioterrorism é a utilização dos microorganisms 
ou dos toxins a fim produzir uma doença e/ou uma morte em seres 
humanos, em animais ou em plantas. Diferente do weaponry 
convencional, os meios relativamente econômicos são usados que 
permitem o elimination de seres vivos sem destruir a atmosfera 
circunvizinha. O mais provavelmente o método para a 
propagação dos bioweapons é transmissão aérea, continuando em 
fontes de água e em alimento. O CDC (centros dos E. U. para o 
controle de doença e a prevenção, Atlanta) subdividiu em três 
categorias o aggressiveness de "Bioweapons". A categoria A 
compreende: Praga, anthrax, smallpox, botulism, tularemia, 
febres hemorrágicas viral (ebola, Marburg), o praga.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bioterrorism è l'utilizzazione dei microorganismi
o delle tossine per produrre una malattia e/o una morte in esseri 
umani, in animali o in piante. Differente da armamento 
convenzionale, i mezzi relativamente economici sono usati che 
permettono l'eliminazione degli esseri viventi senza distruggere 
l'atmosfera circostante. Il più probabilmente il metodo per la 
diffusione degli armi biologica è trasmissione aerea, continuando nei 
rifornimenti idrici e nell'alimento. Il CDC (centri degli Stati 
Uniti per controllo di malattia e la prevenzione, Atlanta) ha 
suddiviso in tre categorie il aggressiveness "degli Armi biologica". 
La categoria A contiene: Peste, antrace, vaiolo, 
botulismo, tularemia, febbri hemorrhagic virali (ebola, Marburg), la 
peste.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Bioterrorism είναι η χρησιμοποίηση των 
μικροοργανισμών ή των τοξινών προκειμένου να παραχθούν μια 
ασθένεια ή/και ένας θάνατος στα ανθρώπινα οντα, τα ζώα ή τα 
φυτά. Διαφορετικά από το συμβατικό εξοπλισμό, τα σχετικά 
οικονομικά μέσα χρησιμοποιούνται που επιτρέπουν την αποβολή των 
ζωντανών οντων χωρίς καταστροφή της περιβάλλουσας ατμόσφαιρας. 
Η πιθανότατα μέθοδος για τη διάδοση των bioweapons είναι 
εναέρια μετάδοση, που συνεχίζεται στις παροχές νερού και τα 
τρόφιμα. Το CDC (αμερικανικά κέντρα για τον έλεγχο 
ασθενειών και την πρόληψη, Ατλάντα) έχει υποδιαιρέσει σε τρεις 
κατηγορίες την επιθετικότητα "Bioweapons". Η κατηγορία Α 
περιλαμβάνει: Πανούκλα, άνθρακας, ευλογιά, αλλαντίαση, 
tularemia, προερχόμενοι από ιό hemorrhagic πυρετοί 
(ebola, Marburg), η πανούκλα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Bioterrorism es la utilización de microorganismos
o de toxinas para producir una enfermedad y/o una muerte en seres 
humanos, animales o plantas. Diferente del armamento 
convencional, se utilizan los medios relativamente económicos que 
permiten la eliminación de seres vivos sin destruir la atmósfera 
circundante. El método para la extensión de bioweapons es lo 
más probablemente posible transmisión aérea, continuando en 
abastecimientos de agua y alimento. La CDC (centros de los 
E.E.U.U. para el control de enfermedad y la prevención, Atlanta) ha 
subdividido en tres categorías la agresividad de "Bioweapons". 
La categoría A abarca: Plaga, ántrax, viruela, 
botulismo, tularemia, fiebres hemorrágicas virales (ebola, Marburg), 
la plaga.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CAMDIC
FN:CAMDIC
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>20101272</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107649</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/bioterrorism-plague-as-a-biological-weapon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
