<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105389</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105389</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087230</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"When the Whistle Blows . . . I Come Home and Get Supper": Women and Work in the Interwar Years</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wenn Schläge pfeifen Sie. . . 
Ich komme Haus und erhalte das Abendessen ": Frauen und 
Arbeit in den Interwar Jahren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"quand sifflez les coups. . . Je
viens maison et obtiens le dîner ": Femmes et travail en 
années d'Entre-deux guerres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"quando assobie sopros. . . Eu 
venho HOME e começo o supper ": Mulheres e trabalho nos anos de
Interwar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"quando fischi i colpi. . . 
Vengo sede ed ottengo il supper ": Donne e lavoro durante 
gli anni di Interwar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Όταν ο συριγμός φυσά. .. Έρχομαι κατ' 
οίκον και παίρνω το βραδυνό ": Γυναίκες και εργασία στα 
έτη μεσοπολέμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"cuando silbe los soplos. . . 
Vengo hogar y consigo cena ": Mujeres y trabajo en los 
años de Interwar</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In August 1920, when Tennessee became the 36th state to ratify the 19th amendment to the U.S. constitution, assuring that it became law in time for women to vote in the presidential election, many feminists predicted great advances for women. "We are no longer petitioners," declared suffrage leader Carrie Chapman Catt, "we are not wards of the nation, but free and equal citizens." The promised gains proved elusive, however, especially in the crucial realm of employment. Among working women, all but a tiny number of well-paid professionals faced the burdens of a double shift of both paid jobs and unpaid household labor. In a 1929 story for the  Nation , Paul Blanshard recorded the daily routine of a South Carolina cotton mill worker. Her narrative intertwined her home duties with her work in the mill, as her long day at the mill was punctuated by equally burdensome domestic chores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im August 1920, als Tennessee der 36th Zustand 
wurde, zum der 19. Änderung zur VEREINIGTE STAATEN Beschaffenheit zu 
bestätigen, versichernd, daß es Gesetz rechtzeig zu den Frauen 
wurde, zum in der Präsidentenwahl zu wählen, sagten viele Feminist 
große Fortschritte für Frauen voraus. "wir sind nicht mehr 
Antragsteller," erklärten Stimmrechtführer Carrie ambulanten 
Händler Catt, "wir sind nicht Bezirke der Nation, aber freie und 
gleiche Bürger." Die versprochenen Gewinne prüften schwer 
bestimmbares jedoch besonders im entscheidenden Reich der 
Beschäftigung. Unter Funktion Frauen stellten alle aber eine 
kleine Anzahl von gut-zahlenden Fachleuten die Belastungen einer 
doppelten Schicht der gezahlten Jobs und der unbezahlten Haushalt 
Arbeit gegenüber. In einer Geschichte 1929 für die Nation, 
speicherte Paul Blanshard das tägliche Programm eines Südcarolina 
Baumwollspinnereiarbeiters. Ihre Darstellung griff ihre 
Hauptaufgaben mit ihrer Arbeit im Tausendstel ineinander, wie ihr 
langer Tag am Tausendstel durch gleichmäßig lästige inländische 
Chores interpunktiert wurde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En août 1920, quand le Tennessee est devenu le 
trente-sixième état pour ratifier le 19ème amendement à la 
constitution des ETATS-UNIS, s'assurant que c'est devenu loi pour des 
femmes à voter dans l'élection présidentielle, beaucoup de 
féministes ont prévu de grandes avances pour des femmes. "nous
ne sommes plus des pétitionnaires," ont déclaré le colporteur Catt 
de Carrie du Chef de suffrage, "nous ne sommes pas des salles de la 
nation, mais des citoyens libres et égaux." Les gains promis 
ont prouvé évasif, cependant, particulièrement dans le royaume 
crucial de l'emploi. Parmi des travailleuses actives, tout sauf 
un nombre minuscule de professionnels bien-payés ont fait face aux 
fardeaux d'un double décalage des travaux payés et de travail 
impayé de ménage. Dans une histoire 1929 pour la nation, Paul 
Blanshard a enregistré le sous-programme quotidien d'un ouvrier 
Du sud de filature de coton de la Caroline. Son récit a 
entrelacé ses fonctions à la maison avec son travail dans le moulin,
comme sa longue journée au moulin a été ponctuée par des corvées 
domestiques également onéreuses.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em agosto 1920, quando Tennessee se transformou o 
36th estado para ratificar a 19a emenda ao constitution de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS, assegurando que se transformou lei a tempo para mulheres votar
na eleição presidencial, muitas feministas predisseram avanços 
grandes para mulheres. "nós não somos nenhum petitioners mais 
longo," declararam o chapman Catt de Carrie do líder do suffrage, 
"nós não somos divisões da nação, mas os cidadãos livres e 
iguais." Os ganhos prometidos provaram elusive, entretanto, 
especial no reino crucial do emprego. Entre mulheres de 
funcionamento, todos mas um número minúsculo de profissionais 
bem-pagos enfrentaram os burdens de uma SHIFT dobro  de trabalhos 
pagos e de trabalho por pagar da casa. Em uma história 1929 
para a nação, Paul Blanshard gravou a rotina diária de um 
trabalhador do moinho de algodão de carolina sul. Sua narrativa
intertwined seus deveres home com seu trabalho no moinho, como seu dia
longo no moinho punctuated por chores domésticos ingualmente 
burdensome.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel mese di agosto del 1920, quando il Tennessee 
si è transformato in nel trentaseesimo dichiari per 
ratificare la diciannovesima correzione alla costituzione degli STATI 
UNITI, rassicurante che si è transformato in in legge in tempo per le
donne da votare nell'elezione presidenziale, molte femministe ha 
predetto gli avanzamenti grandi per le donne. "non siamo più 
istanti," hanno dichiarato il chapman Catt di Carrie del capo 
di suffrage, "noi non siamo quartieri della nazione, ma i cittadini 
liberi ed uguali." I guadagni promessi hanno dimostrato evasivo,
tuttavia, particolarmente nel regno cruciale di occupazione. Fra
le donne lavorarici, tutti ma un numero molto piccolo di 
professionisti bene-well-paid hanno affrontato le difficoltà di 
doppio spostamento sia dei lavori pagati che del lavoro non 
pagato della famiglia. In una storia 1929 per la nazione, Paul 
Blanshard ha registrato la procedura quotidiana di un operaio del 
cotonificio della Carolina del Sud. La sua descrizione 
intertwined le sue funzioni domestiche con il suo lavoro nel 
laminatoio, come il suo giorno lungo al laminatoio è stato 
punteggiato tramite i chores domestici ugualmente pesanti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τον Αύγουστο του 1920, όταν το Tennessee έγινε το
36$ο κράτος για να επικυρώσει τη 19$η τροποποίηση στο ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ 
σύνταγμα, βεβαιώνοντας ότι έγινε νόμος εγκαίρως για τις 
γυναίκες για να ψηφίσει στην προεδρική εκλογή, πολλές 
φεμινίστριες πρόβλεψαν τις μεγάλες προόδους για τις γυναίκες. 
"Δεν είμαστε πλέον ενάγοντες," δηλωμένος γυρολόγος Catt 
Carrie ηγετών ψήφου, "δεν είμαστε θάλαμοι του έθνους, αλλά 
ελεύθεροι και ίσοι πολίτες." Τα υποσχεμένα κέρδη 
αποδείχθηκαν αόριστα, εντούτοις, ειδικά στην κρίσιμη σφαίρα της 
απασχόλησης. Μεταξύ των εργαζόμενων γυναικών, όλος εκτός 
από ένας μικροσκοπικός αριθμός καλοπληρωμένων επαγγελματιών 
αντιμετώπισε τα φορτία μιας διπλής μετατόπισης και των πληρωμένων
εργασιών και της απλήρωτης οικιακής εργασίας. Σε μια 
ιστορία του 1929 για το έθνος, Paul Blanshard κατέγραψε 
την καθημερινή ρουτίνα ενός εργαζομένου μύλων βαμβακιού της 
νότιας Καρολίνας. Το αφήγημά της συνδύασε τα βασικά 
καθήκοντά της με την εργασία της στο μύλο, όπως τη μακριά ημέρα
της στο μύλο από οι εξίσου φορτικές εσωτερικές μικροδουλειές 
έβαλε σημεία στίξης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En agosto de 1920, cuando Tennessee se convirtió 
en el 36.o estado para ratificar la diecinueveavo enmienda a la 
constitución de ESTADOS UNIDOS, asegurando que se convirtió en ley 
en la hora para las mujeres de votar en la elección presidencial, 
muchas feministas predijeron los grandes avances para las mujeres. 
"no somos ningún solicitante más largo," declararon a chapman 
Catt de Carrie del arranque de cinta del sufragio, "nosotros no somos 
salas de la nación, sino los ciudadanos libres e iguales." Los 
aumentos prometidos probaron evasivo, sin embargo, especialmente en el
reino crucial del empleo. Entre mujeres de funcionamiento, todos
pero un número minúsculo de profesionales bien-pagados hicieron 
frente a las cargas de una rotación doble de trabajos pagados y del 
trabajo sin pagar de la casa. En una historia 1929 para la 
nación, Paul Blanshard registró la rutina diaria de un trabajador de
la fábrica de algodón de Carolina del Sur. Su narrativa 
intertwined sus deberes caseros con su trabajo en el molino, como su 
día largo en el molino fue puntuado por tareas domésticas igualmente
pesadas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087230</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105389</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/when-the-whistle-blows-i-come-home-and-get-supper-women-and-work-in-the-interwar-years</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
