<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107248</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107248</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212125</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Single-Celled Organisms</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einzelne-Celled Organismen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Organizations Simples-Celled</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Únicos-Celled Organismos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Singoli-Celled Organismi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενιαίος-κυτταρώδης οργανισμοί</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Solos-Celled Organismos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Project Oceanography lesson plan (PDF) explores the symbiotic relationships of single-celled organisms. In this activity, students will compare and contrast three types of symbiotic relationships, describe the relationship between zooxanthellae (a dinoflagellate) and coral, and explain the effects of nitrogen-fixing bacteria on their symbiotic partners. It begins with an introduction to symbiotic relationships, the dinoflagellate/coral system, and cyanobacteria, and then features an interactive activity called "Feeding Friends," in which students work in partners to act out symbiotic relationships.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Projekt-Ozeanographielektionplan (pdf) 
erforscht die symbiotischen Verhältnisse der einzelnen-celled 
organismen. In dieser Aktivität vergleichen Kursteilnehmer und 
kontrastieren drei Typen symbiotische Verhältnisse, beschreiben das 
Verhältnis zwischen zooxanthellae (ein dinoflagellate) und Koralle 
und erklären die Effekte des nitrogenfixierenden Bakteriums auf ihren
symbiotischen Partnern. Es fängt mit einer Einleitung zu den 
symbiotischen Verhältnissen, zum dinoflagellate/coral System und zum 
cyanobacteria an und kennzeichnet dann eine interaktive Aktivität, 
die "einziehende Freunde," genannt wird in, welchen Kursteilnehmern in
den Partnern arbeiten, um aus symbiotischen Verhältnissen zu 
fungieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce plan de leçon d'océanographie de projet (pdf)
explore les rapports symbiotiques des organizations simples-celled. 
Dans cette activité, les étudiants compareront et 
contrasteront trois types de rapports symbiotiques, décriront le 
rapport entre les zooxanthellae (un dinoflagellate) et le corail, et 
expliqueront les effets des bactéries de fixation d'azote sur leurs 
associés symbiotiques. Il commence par une introduction aux 
rapports symbiotiques, au système de dinoflagellate/coral, et au 
cyanobacteria, et puis comporte une activité interactive appelée 
"les amis d'alimentation," dans quels étudiants travaillent dans les 
associés pour agir hors des rapports symbiotiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta planta da lição do oceanography do projeto 
(pdf) explora os relacionamentos symbiotic de únicos-celled 
organismos. Nesta atividade, os estudantes compararão e 
contrastarão três tipos de relacionamentos symbiotic, descreverão o
relacionamento entre zooxanthellae (um dinoflagellate) e coral, e 
explicarão os efeitos das bactérias nitrogen-fixing em seus sócios 
symbiotic. Começa com uma introdução aos relacionamentos 
symbiotic, ao sistema de dinoflagellate/coral, e ao cyanobacteria, e 
caracteriza então uma atividade interativa chamada "amigos de 
alimentação," em que estudantes trabalham nos sócios para agir para
fora dos relacionamentos symbiotic.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo programma di lezione di oceanografia di 
progetto (pdf) esplora i rapporti simbiotici di singoli-celled 
organismi. In questa attività, gli allievi confronteranno e 
contrapporranno tre tipi di rapporti simbiotici, descriveranno il 
rapporto fra gli zooxanthellae (un dinoflagellate) ed il coral e 
spiegheranno gli effetti dei batteri che fissa l'azoto sui loro soci 
simbiotici. Comincia con un'introduzione ai rapporti simbiotici,
al sistema di dinoflagellate/coral ed al cyanobacteria ed allora 
caratterizza un'attività interattiva chiamata "amici 
d'alimentazione," in quali allievi lavorano in soci per comportarsi 
verso l'esterno i rapporti simbiotici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το σχέδιο μαθήματος ωκεανογραφίας προγράμματος 
(PDF) ερευνά τις συμβιοτικές σχέσεις των ενιαίος-κυτταρωδών 
οργανισμών. Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι σπουδαστές θα 
συγκρίνουν και θα αντιπαραβάλουν τρεις τύπους συμβιοτικών 
σχέσεων, θα περιγράψουν τη σχέση μεταξύ των zooxanthellae (ένα
dinoflagellate) και του κοραλλιού, και θα εξηγήσουν τα 
αποτελέσματα των nitrogen-fixing βακτηριδίων στους συμβιοτικούς 
συνεργάτες τους. Αρχίζει με μια εισαγωγή στις συμβιοτικές 
σχέσεις, το dinoflagellate/to σύστημα κοραλλιών, και το 
cyanobacteria, και χαρακτηρίζει έπειτα μια διαλογική 
δραστηριότητα αποκαλούμενη "ταϊ'ζοντας φίλους," σε ποιους 
σπουδαστές εργαστείτε στους συνεργάτες για να ενεργήσετε έξω 
συμβιοτικές σχέσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este plan de la lección de la oceanografía del 
proyecto (pdf) explora los lazos simbióticos de solos-celled 
organismos. En esta actividad, los estudiantes compararán y 
pondrán en contraste tres tipos de lazos simbióticos, describirán 
el lazo entre los zooxanthellae (un dinoflagellate) y el coral, y 
explicarán los efectos de bacterias nitrogen-fixing en sus socios 
simbióticos. Comienza con una introducción a los lazos 
simbióticos, al sistema de dinoflagellate/coral, y al cyanobacteria, 
y después ofrece una actividad interactiva llamada de "amigos 
alimentación," en qué estudiantes trabajan en socios para actuar 
fuera de lazos simbióticos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PROJECT OCEANOGRAPHY
FN:PROJECT OCEANOGRAPHY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH FLORIDA
FN:UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH FLORIDA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212125</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107248</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/single-celled-organisms-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
