<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106203</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106203</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974076</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Off the Map - Strangers from other Worlds.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Weg von der Karte - Fremde von anderen Welten.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Outre de la carte - étrangers d'autres mondes.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fora do mapa - desconhecido de outros mundos.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fuori del programma - sconosciuti da altri mondi.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από το χάρτη - ξένοι από άλλους κόσμους.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">De la correspondencia - extranjeros de otros 
mundos.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This activity focuses on the kind of worlds some visionary artists envision. Using the Off the Map Web site as a starting point, students are asked to create a new planet or world and include descriptions of the creatures and beings who live there. How do they live? How do they get along? What are their cities like? How are they different from human beings? What do they look like? Students will also evaluate the potential successes and predict the possible failures of their imagined society and compare them to our own earthly communities. Grades 7-9.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Aktivität konzentriert auf die Art der Welten, die 
einige visionäre Künstler sich vorstellen. Mit der weg Karte 
Web site als Ausgangspunkt, werden Kursteilnehmer gebeten, einen neuen
Planeten oder eine Welt herzustellen und Beschreibungen der Geschöpfe
und der Wesen einzuschließen, die dort leben. Wie leben sie? 
Wie erhalten sie entlang? Wie was sind ihre Städte? 
Wie sind sie zu Menschen unterschiedlich? Wie was sehen 
sie aus? Kursteilnehmer auch werten die möglichen Erfolge aus 
und sagen die möglichen Ausfälle ihrer vorgestellten Gesellschaft 
voraus und vergleichen sie mit unseren eigenen earthly Gemeinschaften.
Grade 7-9.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité se concentre sur le genre de mondes que 
quelques artistes visionnaires envisagent. En utilisant hors 
fonction le site de Web de carte comme point de départ, des 
étudiants sont invités à créer une nouvelle planète ou monde et 
à inclure des descriptions des créatures et des êtres qui vivent 
là. Comment vivent-ils ? Comment obtiennent-ils le long ?
À quoi ressemblent leurs villes ? Comment vont-elles 
différentes des êtres humains ? À quoi ressemblent-elles ? 
Les étudiants également évalueront les succès potentiels et 
prévoiront les pannes possibles de leur société imaginée et les 
compareront à nos propres communautés terrestres. Catégories 
7-9.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade focaliza no tipo dos mundos que alguns 
artistas visionary envision. Usando fora o Web site do mapa como
um ponto começar, os estudantes são pedidos para criar um planeta ou
um mundo novo e para incluir descrições das criaturas e dos seres 
que vivem lá. Como vivem? Como começam 
longitudinalmente? Que são suas cidades como? Como são 
diferente dos seres humanos? Que olham como? Os estudantes
também avaliarão os sucessos potenciais e predirão as falhas 
possíveis de sua sociedade imaginada e compará-las-ão a nossas 
próprias comunidades earthly. Classes 7-9.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività mette a fuoco sul genere di mondi che 
alcuni artisti visionary prevedono. Usando fuori il Web site del
programma come punto di partenza, gli allievi sono chiesti di creare 
un nuovo pianeta o mondo e di includere le descrizioni delle creature 
e degli esseri che vivono là. Come vivono? Come ottengono
avanti? Che cosa sono le loro città come? Come sono 
differenti dagli esseri umani? A che cosa assomigliano? 
Gli allievi egualmente valuteranno i successi potenziali e 
prediranno i guasti possibili della loro società immaginata e li 
confronteranno alle nostre proprie Comunità earthly. Gradi 7-9.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η δραστηριότητα εστιάζει στο είδος κόσμων που 
μερικοί παραισθησιακοί καλλιτέχνες προβλέπουν. 
Χρησιμοποιώντας το μακριά ιστοχώρο χαρτών ως αφετηρία, οι 
σπουδαστές καλούνται να δημιουργήσουν έναν νέο πλανήτη ή έναν 
κόσμο και να περιλάβουν τις περιγραφές των πλασμάτων και των οντων
που ζουν εκεί. Πώς ζουν; Πώς παρουσιάζουν πρόοδο; 
Ποιες είναι οι πόλεις τους όπως; Πώς είναι 
διαφορετικοί από τα ανθρώπινα οντα; Τι μοιάζουν με; Οι
σπουδαστές θα αξιολογήσουν επίσης τις πιθανές επιτυχίες και θα 
προβλέψουν τις πιθανές αποτυχίες της φαντασμένης κοινωνίας τους 
και θα τις συγκρίνουν με τις γείηνες κοινότητές μας. Βαθμοί
7-9.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad se centra en la clase de mundos que algunos
artistas visionarios preven. Usando apagado el sitio del 
Web de la correspondencia como punto de partida, piden los 
estudiantes crear un planeta o un mundo nuevo e incluir las 
descripciones de las criaturas y de los seres que viven allí. 
¿Cómo viven? ¿Cómo consiguen adelante? ¿Como cuál
son sus ciudades? ¿Cómo son diferentes de seres humanos? 
¿Qué parecen? Los estudiantes también evaluarán los 
éxitos potenciales y predirán los incidentes posibles de su sociedad
imaginada y los compararán a nuestras propias comunidades terrenales.
Grados 7-9.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974076</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106203</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/off-the-map-strangers-from-other-worlds</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
