<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104093</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104093</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206369</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Luso-Hispanic World In Maps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Luso-Luso-Hispanicwelt In den Karten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Monde de Luso-Hispanique Dans Les Cartes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Mundo Do Luso-Hispânico Nos Mapas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Mondo Di Luso-ispano In Programmi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο λuσο-ισπανικός κόσμος στους χάρτες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Mundo El Luso-Hispanico En Correspondencias</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">includes maps created back to the early 16th century, when exploration and new discoveries brought the need for improved information about the world. The maps, most of which are hand drawn, depict portions of five continents and were prepared by cartographers from Spain, Portugal, France, Great Britain, the Netherlands, Latin America countries, and the U.S., among others. The maps represent different national and political interests and perspectives, at various periods of time.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">enthält die Karten, die zurück zu dem frühen 
16. Jahrhundert hergestellt werden, als Erforschung und neue 
Entdeckungen die Notwendigkeit zu verbesserter Information über die 
Welt holten. Die Karten, denen die meisten die gezeichnete Hand 
sind, stellen Teile von fünf Kontinenten bildlich dar und wurden von 
den Kartenzeichnern von Spanien, von Portugal, von Frankreich, von 
Großbritannien, von den Ländern der Niederlande, lateinischen 
Amerikas und von den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN, unter anderen vorbereitet. 
Die Karten stellen unterschiedliche nationalen und politischen 
Interessen und die Perspektiven, an den verschiedenen Zeitabschnitten 
dar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">inclut des cartes créées de nouveau au 16ème 
siècle tôt, quand l'exploration et les nouvelles découvertes ont 
apporté le besoin d'information améliorée au sujet du monde. 
Les cartes, lesquelles sont main dessinée, dépeignent des 
parties de cinq continents et ont été préparées par des 
cartographes d'Espagne, du Portugal, de France, de Grande-Bretagne, 
les Pays Bas, des pays d'Amérique latine, et des ETATS-UNIS, 
entre d'autres. Les cartes représentent différents intérêts 
et perspectives nationaux et politiques, à de diverses périodes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">inclui os mapas criados para trás ao 1õ século 
adiantado, quando a exploração e as descobertas novas trouxeram a 
necessidade para a informação melhorada sobre o mundo. Os 
mapas, a maioria de que são mão desenhada, descrevem parcelas de 
cinco continentes e foram preparados por cartographers de Spain, de 
Portugal, de France, de Grâ Bretanha, dos países dos Países Baixos,
de América latin, e dos ESTADOS UNIDOS, entre outros. Os mapas 
representam interesses diferentes e perspectives nacionais e 
políticos, em vários períodos de tempo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">include i programmi creati di nuovo al sedicesimo 
secolo in anticipo, quando l'esplorazione e le nuove scoperte hanno 
portato il fabbisogno di informazioni migliorate circa il mondo. 
I programmi, la maggior parte di cui sono mano estratta, 
descrivono lle parti di cinque continenti e sono stati preparati dai 
cartographers dalla Spagna, dal Portogallo, dalla Francia, dalla Gran 
Bretagna, dai paesi di america latina, dei Paesi Bassi e dagli STATI 
UNITI, tra altri. I programmi rappresentano gli interessi 
differenti e le prospettive nazionali e politici, ai vari periodi di 
tempo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιλαμβάνει τους χάρτες που δημιουργούνται πίσω στον 
πρόωρο 16$ο αιώνα, όταν έφεραν η εξερεύνηση και οι νέες 
ανακαλύψεις την ανάγκη για τις βελτιωμένες πληροφορίες για τον 
κόσμο. Οι χάρτες, οι περισσότεροι από τους οποίους είναι 
χέρι που σύρεται, απεικονίζουν τις μερίδες πέντε ηπείρων και 
προετοιμάστηκαν από τους χαρτογράφους από την Ισπανία, την 
Πορτογαλία, τη Γαλλία, τη Μεγάλη Βρετανία, τις Κάτω Χώρες, τις 
χώρες της λατινικής Αμερικής, και τις ΗΠΑ, μεταξύ των άλλων. 
Οι χάρτες αντιπροσωπεύουν τα διαφορετικές εθνικές και 
πολιτικές ενδιαφέροντα και τις προοπτικές, στις διάφορες χρονικές
περιόδους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">incluye las correspondencias creadas de nuevo al 
décimosexto siglo temprano, cuando la exploración y los nuevos 
descubrimientos causaron la necesidad de la información mejorada el 
mundo. Las correspondencias, la mayoría de las cuales son mano 
trazada, representan las porciones de cinco continentes y fueron 
preparadas por los cartógrafos de España, de Portugal, de Francia, 
de Gran Bretaña, de los países de Países Bajos, de América latina,
y de los ESTADOS UNIDOS, entre otros. Las correspondencias 
representan diversos intereses y perspectivas nacionales y políticos,
en los varios períodos del tiempo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206369</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104093</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-luso-hispanic-world-in-maps</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
