<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106373</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106373</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206559</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Microscope Imaging Station</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mikroskop-Belichtung Station</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Station de Formation image de Microscope</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Estação Da Imagem latente Do Microscópio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Stazione Di Formazione immagine Del Microscopio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σταθμός απεικόνισης μικροσκοπίων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Estación De la Proyección de imagen Del 
Microscopio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">shows what blood is, what happens when the immune system goes awry, what are stem cells are, and more. See videos exploring cell structure and function, cell development and motility, plankton, plants, and protozoa. Learn how the sea urchin helps us understand genes, reproduction, and cancer.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zeigt was Blut ist, was geschieht, wenn das immune 
System schief geht, was sind, sind Stammzellen und mehr. 
Sehen Sie videos, Zelle Struktur zu erforschen und Funktion, 
Zelle Entwicklung und Motilität, Plankton, Betriebe und Protozoen. 
Erlernen Sie, wie der Seeigel uns hilft, Gene, Wiedergabe und 
Krebs zu verstehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">montre à ce qui le sang est, ce qui se produit 
quand le système immunitaire va de travers, ce qui est les cellules 
de tige sont, et plus. Voir les videos explorer la structure et 
la fonction de cellules, le développement et la motilité de 
cellules, le plancton, les plantes, et les protozoaires. 
Apprenez comment l'oursin nous aide à comprendre les gènes, la
reproduction, et le cancer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">mostra a o que o sangue é, o que acontece quando o
sistema imune vai awry, o que é as pilhas de haste são, e mais. 
Veja videos explorar a estrutura e a função da pilha, 
desenvolvimento e motility da pilha, plankton, plantas, e protozoa. 
Aprenda como o urchin de mar nos ajuda compreender genes, 
reprodução, e cancer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">mostra che cosa l'anima è, che cosa accade quando 
il sistema immune va awry, che cosa è le cellule formative sono e 
più. Veda i videos esplorare la struttura e funzione delle 
cellule, sviluppo e motilità delle cellule, plancton, piante ed i 
protozoi. Impari come il urchin di mare li aiuta a capire i 
geni, la riproduzione ed il cancro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εμφανίζει ποιο αίμα είναι, τι συμβαίνει πότε το 
ανοσοποιητικό σύστημα πηγαίνει λοξό, τι είναι κύτταρα μίσχων 
είναι, και περισσότεροι. Δείτε τα βίντεο τη δομή 
κυττάρων και λειτουργήστε, την ανάπτυξη και motility κυττάρων, 
το πλαγκτόν, τις εγκαταστάσεις, και τις πρωτόζωες. Μάθετε 
πώς το σκανταλιάρικο παιδί θάλασσας μας βοηθά να καταλάβουμε τα 
γονίδια, την αναπαραγωγή, και τον καρκίνο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">muestra a qué la sangre es, qué sucede cuando va 
el sistema inmune mal, cuál es las células de vástago son, y más. 
Vea los videos el explorar de la estructura y función de la 
célula, desarrollo y motility de la célula, plancton, las plantas, y
los protozoos. Aprenda cómo el pilluelo de mar nos ayuda a 
entender genes, la reproducción, y el cáncer.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206559</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106373</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/microscope-imaging-station</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
