<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108208</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108208</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087402</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Andrew Sherburne's Experiences on a Privateer During the Revolutionary War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Andrew Sherburnes Erfahrungen auf einem Privateer 
während des revolutionären Krieges</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Expériences d'Andrew Sherburne sur un Privateer 
pendant la guerre révolutionnaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Experiências de Andrew Sherburne em um Privateer 
durante a guerra revolucionária</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esperienze del Andrew Sherburne su un Privateer 
durante la guerra rivoluzionaria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εμπειρία του Andrew Sherburne's σε ένα 
Privateer κατά τη διάρκεια του επαναστατικού πολέμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Experiencias de Andrew Sherburne en un Privateer 
durante la guerra revolucionaria</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">General George Washington and the patriot leaders faced an enormous challenge in mounting a military campaign against the British forces during the revolutionary war. For soldiers, they drew upon existing state militias and also raised a Continental army. But no such source for a naval force existed. Instead, Washington's officers acquired the services of American captains and sailors by commissioning them as privateers, or private citizens authorized to attack a military enemy. Colonists had long experience serving as privateers for the British forces during numerous eighteenth-century wars against Spain, France, and the Netherlands. They now turned their skills against Great Britain. Andrew Sherburne's memoirs capture the youth's enthusiastic desire to participate in the military campaign against the British; many others were less enthusiastic about their military service due to its infrequent pay and poor living conditions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">General George Washington und die Patriotführer 
stellte eine enorme Herausforderung gegenüber, wenn er eine 
militärische Kampagne gegen die britischen Kräfte während des 
revolutionären Krieges einhing. Für Soldaten zeichneten sie 
nach vorhandenen Zustandmilizen und hoben auch eine kontinentale Armee
an. Aber keine solche Quelle für eine Marinekraft existierte. 
Stattdessen erwarben Offiziere Washingtons die Services der 
amerikanischen Kapitäne und der Seeleute, indem sie sie als 
privateers oder die privaten beauftrugen, Bürger, die autorisiert 
wurden, einen militärischen Feind anzugreifen. Kolonisten 
hatten lange Erfahrung Umhüllung als privateers für die britischen 
Kräfte während der zahlreichen Achtzehntjahrhundert Kriege gegen 
Spanien, Frankreich und die Niederlande. Sie drehten jetzt ihre 
Fähigkeiten gegen Großbritannien. Andrew Sherburnes 
Abhandlungen erfassen den enthusiastischen Wunsch der Jugend, an der 
militärischen Kampagne gegen die Briten teilzunehmen; viele 
andere waren über ihren militärischen Service wegen seiner seltenen 
Bezahlung und schlechten lebenden Bedingungen weniger enthusiastisch.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">George général Washington et les amorces de 
patriote a relevé un énorme défi en organisant une campagne 
militaire contre les forces britanniques pendant la guerre 
révolutionnaire. Pour des soldats, elles ont utilisé les 
milices existantes d'état et ont également élevé une armée 
continentale. Mais aucune une telle source une force navale n'a 
existé. Au lieu de cela, les officiers de Washington ont saisi 
les services des capitaines et des marins américains en les 
commissionnant comme privateers, ou les citoyens privés autorisés à
attaquer un ennemi militaire. Les colons ont eu la longue 
portion d'expérience comme privateers les forces britanniques pendant
de nombreuses guerres de dix-huitième-siècle contre l'Espagne, la 
France, et les Pays Bas. Ils ont maintenant tourné leurs 
qualifications contre la Grande-Bretagne. Les mémoires d'Andrew
Sherburne capturent le désir enthousiaste de la jeunesse de 
participer à la campagne militaire contre les Anglais ; 
beaucoup d'autres étaient moins enthousiastes au sujet de leur 
service militaire dû à son salaire peu fréquent et conditions 
vivantes faibles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O general George Washington e líderes do patriot 
enfrentou um desafio enorme em montar uma campanha militar de encontro
às forças britânicas durante a guerra revolucionária. Para 
soldados, desenharam em cima das milícias existentes do estado e 
levantaram também um exército continental. Mas nenhuma tal 
fonte para uma força naval existiu. Instead, os oficiais de 
Washington adquiriram os serviços de capitães e de sailors 
americanos comissão os como privateers, ou os cidadãos confidenciais
autorizados atacar um inimigo militar. Os colonos tiveram o 
serving longo da experiência como privateers para as forças 
britânicas durante guerras numerosas de décimo-século de encontro a
Spain, a France, e aos Países Baixos. Giraram agora suas 
habilidades de encontro a Grâ Bretanha. Os memoirs de Andrew 
Sherburne capturam o desejo entusiástico da juventude participar na 
campanha militar de encontro aos Ingleses; muito outro era mais 
menos entusiástico sobre seu serviço militar  devido a seus 
pagamento infrequënte e circunstâncias vivas deficientes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il General George Washington ed i capi del 
patriot ha affrontato una sfida enorme nell'organizzare una campagna 
militare contro le forze britanniche durante la guerra rivoluzionaria.
Per i soldati, hanno dissipato sull'esistere dichiarano le 
milizie ed egualmente hanno alzato un esercito continentale. Ma 
nessuna tale sorgente per una forza navale ha esistito. Invece, 
gli ufficiali de Washington hanno acquistato i servizi dei capitani e 
dei marinai americani incaricandoli come privateers, o i cittadini 
riservati autorizzati ad attacare un nemico militare. I 
colonizzatori hanno avuti serving lungo di esperienza come privateers 
per le forze britanniche durante le guerre numerose di 
diciottesimo-secolo contro la Spagna, la Francia ed i Paesi Bassi. 
Ora hanno girato le loro abilità contro la Gran Bretagna. 
Le memorie del Andrew Sherburne bloccano il desiderio 
entusiastico della gioventù partecipare alla campagna militare contro
i Britannici; molti altri erano meno entusiasti del loro 
servizio militare dovuto la relative paga rara e povere 
circostanze di vita.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στρατηγός George Ουάσιγκτον και οι ηγέτες 
πατριωτών αντιμετώπισαν μια τεράστια πρόκληση στην επικόλληση 
μιας στρατιωτικής εκστρατείας ενάντια στις βρετανικές δυνάμεις 
κατά τη διάρκεια του επαναστατικού πολέμου. Για τους 
στρατιώτες, βασίστηκαν στις υπάρχουσες κρατικές πολιτοφυλακές και
ανέθρεψαν επίσης έναν ηπειρωτικό στρατό. Αλλά καμία 
τέτοια πηγή για μια ναυτική δύναμη δεν υπήρξε. Αντ' αυτού,
οι ανώτεροι υπάλληλοι της Ουάσιγκτον απόκτησαν τις υπηρεσίες των 
αμερικανικών καπετάνιων και των ναυτικών με την ανάθεση τους ως 
privateers, ή τους απλούς πολίτες που εγκρίθηκαν για να 
επιτεθούν σε έναν στρατιωτικό εχθρό. Οι άποικοι είχαν τη 
μακροχρόνια εμπειρία που χρησιμεύει ως τα privateers για τις 
βρετανικές δυνάμεις κατά τη διάρκεια των πολυάριθμων πολέμων 
δέκατος-αιώνα ενάντια στην Ισπανία, τη Γαλλία, και τις Κάτω 
Χώρες. Γύρισαν τώρα τις δεξιότητές τους ενάντια στη 
Μεγάλη Βρετανία. Τα απομνημονεύματα του Andrew 
Sherburne's συλλαμβάνουν την ενθουσιώδη επιθυμία της νεολαίας 
να συμμετέχουν στη στρατιωτική εκστρατεία ενάντια στους Βρετανούς
πολλοί άλλοι ήταν λιγότερο ενθουσιώδεις για τη στρατιωτική
θητεία τους λόγω στη σπάνια αμοιβή και τις φτωχές συνθήκες 
διαβίωσής του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">General George Washington y los arranques de cinta
del patriota hizo frente a un desafío enorme en montar una campaña 
militar contra las fuerzas británicas durante la guerra 
revolucionaria. Para los soldados, trazaron sobre las milicias 
existentes del estado y también levantaron a ejército continental. 
Pero ninguna tal fuente para una fuerza naval existió. En
lugar, los oficiales de Washington adquirieron a los servicios de 
capitanes y de marineros americanos comisionándolos como privateers, 
o a ciudadanos privados autorizados a atacar a un enemigo militar. 
Los colonos tenían porción larga de la experiencia como 
privateers para las fuerzas británicas durante guerras numerosas del 
de'cimo octavo-siglo contra España, Francia, y los Países Bajos. 
Ahora dieron vuelta a sus habilidades contra Gran Bretaña. 
Las memorias de Andrew Sherburne capturan el deseo entusiástico
de la juventud de participar en la campaña militar contra los 
Británicos; muchos otros eran menos entusiásticos sobre su 
servicio militar  debido a su paga infrecuente y condiciones vivas 
pobres.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087402</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108208</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/andrew-sherburnes-experiences-on-a-privateer-during-the-revolutionary-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
