<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108693</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108693</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206491</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The E Pluribus Unum Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das E Pluribus Unum Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Projet de E Pluribus Unum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Projeto De E Pluribus Unum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progetto Di E Pluribus Unum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το πρόγραμμα ε Pluribus Unum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Proyecto De E Pluribus Unum</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines Americans' attempt to make one from many in three pivotal decades: the 1770s, 1850s, and 1920s. Each decade is framed by an introductory essay with links to key topics and primary documents, including the Declaration of Independence, newspapers, and the rhetoric of the Revolution; reform, cultures of the North and South, religion, and popular movements; and prohibition, Broadway, evangelical Protestantism, and the Roaring Twenties.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft Versuch der Amerikaner, ein von vielen
in drei Angeldekaden zu bilden: das 1770s, das 1850s und die 
zwanziger Jahre, die jede Dekade durch einen einleitenden Versuch mit 
Links zu den Schlüsselthemen und Primärdokumente gestaltet wird, 
einschließlich die Unabhängigkeitserklärung, Zeitungen und die 
Rhetorik der Umdrehung; Verbesserung, Kulturen des Nordens und 
Süd, Religion und populäre Bewegungen; und Verbot, Broadway, 
evangelisches Protestantism und die Brüllenzwanziger Jahre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine la tentative des Américains de faire un 
à partir de beaucoup dans trois décennies pivotales : le 
1770s, le 1850s, et les années 20. Chaque décennie est 
encadrée par un essai préliminaire avec des liens aux sujets 
principaux et les documents primaires, y compris la déclaration de 
l'indépendance, les journaux, et la rhétorique de la révolution ; 
réforme, cultures du nord et des Sud, religion, 
et mouvements populaires ; et prohibition, Broadway, 
Protestantisme évangélique, et les années '20 d'hurler.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina a tentativa dos americanos de fazer um de 
muitos em três décadas pivotal: o 1770s, o 1850s, e os 1920s. 
onde cada década é moldada por um essay introdutório com ligações
aos tópicos chaves e originais preliminares, including a declaração
de independência, jornais, e o rhetoric da volta; reforma, 
culturas do norte e sul, religião, e movimentos populares; e 
proibição, Broadway, Protestantism evangelical, e os twenties rujir.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina il tentativo degli Americani di fare uno 
da molti in tre decadi chiave: il 1770s, il 1850s e gli anni 20 
che ogni decade è incorniciata da un saggio introduttivo con i 
collegamenti ai temi principali e documenti primari, compreso la 
dichiarazione di indipendenza, giornali e retorica della rivoluzione; 
riforma, colture del nord e del sud, religione e movimenti 
popolari; e proibizione, Broadway, Protestantism evangelical e 
gli anni '20 ruggire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει την προσπάθεια Αμερικανών να κάνουν μιας από
πολλούς σε τρεις κεντρικές δεκαετίες: το 1770s, το 
1850s, και η δεκαετία του '20 Κάθε δεκαετία πλαισιώνεται 
από ένα εισαγωγικό δοκίμιο με τις συνδέσεις με τα βασικά θέματα
και τα αρχικά έγγραφα, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της Διακήρυξης της 
ανεξαρτησίας, τις εφημερίδες, και τη ρητορική της επανάστασης  
μεταρρύθμιση, πολιτισμοί του Βορρά και του νότου, της 
θρησκείας, και των δημοφιλών κινημάτων  και απαγόρευση, 
Broadway, εβαγγελικός Προτεσταντισμός, και οι δεκαετίες του '20 
βρυχηθμού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina la tentativa de los americanos de hacer 
uno de muchos en tres décadas giratorias: el 1770s, el 1850s, y
los años 20 que cada década es enmarcada por un ensayo introductorio
con conexiones a los asuntos dominantes y los documentos primarios, 
incluyendo el declaración de la independencia, periódicos, y el 
retórico de la revolución; reforma, culturas del norte y del 
sur, religión, y movimientos populares; y prohibición, 
Broadway, Protestantism evangélico, y los años 20 el rugir.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206491</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108693</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-e-pluribus-unum-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
