<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107670</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107670</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086287</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Hope to Fall With My Face to the Foe": Lewis Douglass Describes the Battle of Fort Wagner, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"I Hoffnung, mit meinem Gesicht zum Feind zu 
fallen": Lewis Douglass beschreibt die Schlacht des Forts 
Wagner, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"espoir de I de tomber avec mon visage à 
l'ennemi" : Lewis Douglass décrit la bataille du fort 
Wagner, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">de "esperança I cair com minha cara ao foe": 
Lewis Douglass descreve a batalha do fort Wagner, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"speranza di I cadere con la mia faccia al 
Nemico": Lewis Douglass descrive la battaglia di Wagner 
Forte, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"ελπίζω να πέσω με το πρόσωπό μου στον εχθρό": 
Το Lewis Douglass περιγράφει τη μάχη του οχυρού 
Wagner, 1863</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"esperanza de I de caer con mi cara al enemigo": 
Lewis Douglass describe la batalla de la fortaleza Wagner, 1863</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Lewis Douglass was a son of Frederick Douglass and a sergeant in the Union army's Fifty-fourth Massachusetts Infantry. The Fifty-fourth, led by its white colonel, Robert Gould Shaw, scion of a prominent Boston family, was an elite black regiment. On July 18, 1863, the Fifty-fourth mounted a brave but hopeless attack against Fort Wagner, which guarded Charleston Harbor. Shaw and almost half the regiment were killed. African Americans had already proven themselves in Civil War battles, but the battle at Fort Wagner turned the public's attention to the heroism of black soldiers. In this letter to the woman he later married, Douglass, still unaware of the dimensions of his regiment's losses, described the battle.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lewis Douglass war ein Sohn von Frederick Douglass
und ein Sergeant in der Fünfzig-vierten Infanterie 
Massachusetts der Anschlußarmee. Das Fünfzig-vierte, geführt 
durch seinen weißen Oberst, Robert Gould Shaw, scion einer 
vorstehenden Boston Familie, war ein Ausleseschwarzregiment. An 
Juli 18, 1863, hing das Fünfzig-vierte einen tapferen aber 
hoffnungslosen Angriff gegen Fort Wagner ein, das Charleston Hafen 
schützte. Shaw und fast Hälfte Regiment wurden beendet. 
Afrikanische Amerikaner hatten sich bereits in den 
Bürgerkriegschlachten geprüft, aber die Schlacht am Fort Wagner 
drehte die Aufmerksamkeit der Öffentlichkeit zum Heroism der 
schwarzen Soldaten. In diesem Zeichen zur Frau verband er 
später, Douglass, noch ahnungslos von den Maßen der Verluste seines 
Regiments, beschrieb die Schlacht.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lewis Douglass était un fils de Frederick 
Douglass et un sergent dans infanterie du Massachusetts d'armée 
des syndicats la Cinquante-quatrième. Le Cinquante-quatrième, 
mené par son colonel blanc, Robert Gould Shaw, scion d'une famille en
avant de Boston, était un régiment de noir d'élite. Juillet 
18, 1863, le Cinquante-quatrième a monté un braver mais 
l'attaque désespérée contre le fort Wagner, qui a gardé le 
port de Charleston. Shaw et presque moitié du régiment ont 
été détruits. Les Américains africains s'étaient déjà 
prouvés dans des batailles de guerre civile, mais la bataille au fort
Wagner a tourné l'attention du public au héroisme des soldats 
noirs. Dans cette lettre à la femme il plus tard s'est marié, 
Douglass, encore ignorant des dimensions des pertes de son régiment, 
a décrit la bataille.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lewis Douglass era um filho de Frederick Douglass 
e um sergeant infantaria de Massachusetts de exército de união na 
Cinqüênta-quarta. O Cinqüênta-quarto, conduzido por seu 
coronel branco, Robert Gould Shaw, scion de uma família proeminente 
de Boston, era um regiment do preto do elite. Julho em 18, 1863,
o Cinqüênta-quarto montou um ataque bravo mas impossível de 
encontro ao fort Wagner, que guardou o porto de Charleston. Shaw
e metade do regiment foi matado quase. Os americanos africanos 
tinham-se provado já em batalhas da guerra civil, mas a batalha no 
fort Wagner girou a atenção do público ao heroism de soldados 
pretos. Nesta letra à mulher casou-se mais tarde, Douglass, 
ainda inconsciente das dimensões de perdas do seu regiment, descreveu
a batalha.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lewis Douglass era un figlio di Frederick Douglass
e un sergeant nella fanteria di Fifty-quarto Massachusetts 
dell'esercito del sindacato. Il Fifty-quarto, condotto dal 
relativo colonnello bianco, Robert Gould Shaw, scion di una famiglia 
prominente de Boston, era un regiment di nero dell'elite. Il 18 
luglio 1863, il Fifty-quarto ha montato un attacco brave ma 
disperato contro Wagner Forte, che ha custodito il porto de 
Charleston. Shaw e quasi metà del regiment è stato ucciso. 
Gli Americani africani già si erano dimostrati nelle battaglie 
di guerra civile, ma la battaglia a Wagner Forte ha rivolto 
l'attenzione del pubblico al heroism dei soldati neri. In questa
lettera alla donna più successivamente si è sposato, Douglass, 
ancora ignaro delle dimensioni delle perdite del suo regiment, ha 
descritto la battaglia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το Lewis Douglass ήταν γιος Frederick 
Douglass και λοχίας στο ένωσης πεζικό της Μασαχουσέτης του 
στρατού πενήντα-τέταρτο. Το πενήντα-τέταρτο, που οδηγήθηκε
σύνταγμα από το λευκό συνταγματάρχη του, Robert Gould 
Shaw, scion μιας προεξέχουσας οικογένειας της Βοστώνης, ήταν
ένα ελίτ μαύρο. Στις 18 Ιουλίου ..1863, 
πενήντα-τέταρτο επικολλημένη μια γενναία αλλά μάταιη επίθεση 
ενάντια στο οχυρό Wagner, το οποίο φρούρησε το λιμάνι του 
Τσάρλεστον. Το Shaw και το σχεδόν μισό σύνταγμα 
σκοτώθηκαν. Αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί είχαν αποδειχθεί ήδη 
στις μάχες εμφύλιου πολέμου, αλλά η μάχη στο οχυρό Wagner 
έστρεψε την προσοχή του κοινού στον ηρωισμό των μαύρων 
στρατιωτών. Σε αυτήν την επιστολή στη γυναίκα που πάντρεψε 
αργότερα, Douglass, ακόμα απληροφόρητο των διαστάσεων των 
απωλειών του συντάγματός του, περιέγραψε τη μάχη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lewis Douglass era un hijo de Frederick Douglass y
sargento en infantería de Massachusetts del ejército de unión la 
Cincuenta-cuarta. El Cincuenta-cuarto, conducido por su coronel 
blanco, Roberto Gould Shaw, scion de una familia prominente de Boston,
era un regimiento del negro de la élite. 18 de julio de 
1863, el Cincuenta-cuarto montó un ataque valiente pero desesperado 
contra la fortaleza Wagner, que guardó el puerto de Charleston. 
Shaw y casi mitad del regimiento fue matado. Los 
americanos africanos se habían probado ya en batallas de la guerra 
civil, pero la batalla en la fortaleza Wagner dio vuelta a la 
atención del público al heroísmo de soldados negros. En esta 
carta a la mujer él casó más adelante, Douglass, aún inconsciente 
de las dimensiones de las pérdidas de su regimiento, describió la 
batalla.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086287</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107670</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-hope-to-fall-with-my-face-to-the-foe-lewis-douglass-describes-the-battle-of-fort-wagner-1863</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
