<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107629</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107629</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086880</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Telling Tales: Byington's Study of Homestead</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erklären Von von Geschichten: Studie 
Byingtons des Gehöfts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dire des Contes : L'étude de Byington de la
ferme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dizendo Tales: Estudo de Byington do 
homestead</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dire Ai Racconti: Studio del Byington della 
fattoria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστορίες αφήγησης: Μελέτη Byington του 
αγροτικού σπιτιού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Contar Cuentos: Estudio de Byington de la 
granja</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Homestead, Pennsylvania, was in many ways the prototypical early twentieth-century mill town. Located seven miles up the Monongahela River from Pittsburgh, the first steel mill was built in Homestead in 1881. In 1892, Homestead was the site of one of the most dramatic strikes in U.S. history. The Carnegie Steel Company's ultimate victory resulted in the destruction of a once-powerful union of skilled iron and steel workers. By 1907, almost 7,000 workers toiled at the Homestead plant for the U.S. Steel Corporation. In 1907-1908, the Russell Sage Foundation undertook an intensive study that attempted to understand the dramatic changes that had reshaped Homestead and other industrial communities. Written by progressive social reformers, the six-volume Pittsburgh Survey emphasized the devastating impact of industrial life on those who labored in the nation's factories. The following excerpt is from Margaret Byington's Pittsburgh Survey volume,  Homestead: The Households of a Mill Town , first published in 1910. In the spirit of the Progressive-era effort to scientifically document conditions, the book also included photographs (by the famous documentary photographer Lewis Hine) and detailed family budgets.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gehöft, Pennsylvania, war in vielen Methoden die 
prototypische frühe Zwanzigstjahrhundert Tausendstelstadt. 
Gefunden sieben Meilen herauf den Monongahela Fluß von 
Pittsburgh, wurde das erste Stahltausendstel im Gehöft 1881 
aufgebaut. 1892 war Gehöft die Site von einem der drastischsten
Schläge in der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Geschichte. Der Carnegie 
entscheidende Sieg des Stahlwerkes ergab die Zerstörung eines 
sobald-leistungsfähigen Anschlußes der erfahrenen Eisen- und 
Stahlarbeiter. Bis zum 1907 plagten fast 7.000 Arbeiter
am Gehöftbetrieb für die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN Steel Corporation ab. 
1907-1908 nahm sich die Russell Sage Grundlage eine intensive 
Studie auf, die versuchte, die drastischen Änderungen zu verstehen, 
die Gehöft und andere industrielle Gemeinschaften umgestaltet hatten.
Geschrieben durch progressive SozialReformer, hob die 
Sechsdatenträger Pittsburgh Übersicht die verheerende Auswirkung der
industriellen Lebensdauer auf die hervor, die in den Fabriken der 
Nation bearbeiteten. Das folgende Excerpt ist vom Margaret 
Byingtons Pittsburgh Übersicht Datenträger, Gehöft: Die 
Haushalte einer Tausendstel-Stadt, zuerst veröffentlicht 1910. 
Im Geist der Progressiv-Ära Bemühung, Bedingungen, die 
eingeschlossenen Fotographien des Buches auch (durch den berühmten 
dokumentarischen Photographen Lewis Hine) und die genau geschilderten 
Familie Etats wissenschaftlich zu dokumentieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La ferme, Pennsylvanie, était de beaucoup de 
voies la ville tôt prototypique de moulin de vingtième-siècle. 
Situé sept milles vers le haut du fleuve de Monongahela de 
Pittsburgh, la première aciérie a été construite dans la ferme en 
1881. En 1892, la ferme était le site d'une des grèves les 
plus excessives dans l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS. La victoire 
finale de l'aciérie de Carnegie a eu comme conséquence la 
destruction d'une union une fois-puissante de fer habile et des 
ouvriers en acier. D'ici 1907, presque 7.000 ouvriers 
travaillent fort à l'usine de ferme pour les ETATS-UNIS Steel 
Corporation. En 1907-1908, la base sage de Russell a entrepris 
une étude intensive qui a essayé de comprendre les changements 
excessifs qui avaient restructuré la ferme et d'autres communautés 
industrielles. Écrit par les réformateurs sociaux progressifs, 
l'enquête de Pittsburgh de six-volume a souligné l'impact 
dévastateur de la vie industrielle sur ceux qui ont travaillé dans 
les usines de la nation. L'extrait suivant est de volume 
d'enquête de Pittsburgh de Margaret Byington, ferme : Les 
ménages d'une ville de moulin, d'abord édités en 1910. Dans 
l'esprit de l'effort de Progressif-ère de documenter scientifiquement
des conditions, les photographies également incluses de livre (par le
photographe documentaire célèbre Lewis Hine) et les budgets 
détaillés de famille.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O homestead, Pensilvânia, era em muitas maneiras 
a cidade adiantada prototypical do moinho de vigésimo-século. 
Localizado sete milhas acima do rio de Monongahela de 
Pittsburgh, o primeiro moinho de aço foi construído no homestead em 
1881. Em 1892, o homestead era o local de uma das batidas as 
mais dramáticas no history de ESTADOS UNIDOS. A vitória final 
de companhia de aço de Carnegie resultou na destruição de uma 
união uma vez que-poderosa de ferro hábil e dos trabalhadores de 
aço. Por 1907, quase 7.000 trabalhadores labutam na planta do 
homestead para os ESTADOS UNIDOS Aço Corporation. Em 1907-1908,
a fundação prudente de Russell empreendeu um estudo intensive que 
tentasse compreender as mudanças dramáticas que reshaped o homestead
e outras comunidades industriais. Escrito por reformers sociais 
progressivos, o exame de Pittsburgh do seis-volume emfatizou o impacto
devastating da vida industrial naqueles que trabalharam nas fábricas 
da nação. O seguinte excerpt é do volume do exame de 
Pittsburgh de Margaret Byington, homestead: As casas de uma 
cidade do moinho, publicadas primeiramente em 1910. No espírito
do esforço da Progressivo-era documentar scientifically 
circunstâncias, as fotografias também incluídas do livro (pelo 
fotógrafo documentary famoso Lewis Hine) e orçamentos detalhados da 
família.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La fattoria, Pensilvania, era in molti modi la 
città in anticipo prototipa del laminatoio di ventesimo-secolo. 
Individuato sette miglia sul fiume di Monongahela da Pittsburgh,
la prima acciaieria è stata costruita in fattoria in 1881. In 
1892, la fattoria era il luogo di uno dei colpi più drammatici nella 
storia degli STATI UNITI. Vittoria dell'acciaieria di Carnegie 
l'ultima ha provocato la distruzione di un'unione una volta 
che-potente nei dei lavoratori dell'industria siderurgica esperti e 
del ferro. Entro 1907, quasi 7.000 operai lavorano duramente 
nella pianta della fattoria per gli STATI UNITI Steel Corporation. 
In 1907-1908, il fondamento prudente di Russell ha intrapreso 
uno studio intenso che ha tentato di capire i cambiamenti drammatici 
che avevano rimodellato la fattoria ed altre Comunità industriali. 
Scritto dai reformers sociali progressivi, l'indagine de 
Pittsburgh del sei-volume ha dato risalto all'effetto devastating di 
vita industriale su coloro che ha lavorato nelle fabbriche della 
nazione. Il seguente brano proviene dal volume di indagine de 
Pittsburgh di Margaret Byington, fattoria: Le famiglie di una 
città del laminatoio, in primo luogo pubblicate in 1910. Nello 
spirito dello sforzo di Progressivo-era documentare scientificamente 
le circostanze, le fotografie anche incluse del libro (dal 
photographer documentario famoso Lewis Hine) ed i preventivi 
dettagliati della famiglia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το αγροτικό σπίτι, Πενσυλβανία, ήταν από πολλές 
απόψεις η πρωτότυπη πρόωρη πόλη μύλων εικοστός-αιώνα. 
Τοποθετημένος επτά μίλια επάνω ο ποταμός Monongahela 
από το Πίτσμπουργκ, ο πρώτος μύλος χάλυβα χτίστηκε στο αγροτικό
σπίτι το 1881. Το 1892, το αγροτικό σπίτι ήταν η 
περιοχή μια από τις πιό δραματικές απεργίες στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ 
ιστορία. Η τελευταία νίκη της επιχείρησης χάλυβα 
Carnegie οδήγησε στην καταστροφή μιας μόλις-ισχυρής ένωσης των
ειδικευμένων εργαζομένων σιδήρου και χάλυβα. Μέχρι το 
1907, σχεδόν 7.000 εργαζόμενοι κοπίασαν στις εγκαταστάσεις 
αγροτικών σπιτιών για την εταιρία ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ χάλυβα. Το 
1907-1908, ο Russell Sage Foundation ανέλαβε μια 
εντατική μελέτη που προσπάθησε να καταλάβει τις δραματικές 
αλλαγές που είχαν αναδιαμορφώσει το αγροτικό σπίτι και άλλες 
βιομηχανικές κοινότητες. Γραπτή από τους προοδευτικούς 
κοινωνικούς μεταρρυθμιστές, η έρευνα του Πίτσμπουργκ έξι-έντασης
του ήχου υπογράμμισε τον καταστρεπτικό αντίκτυπο της βιομηχανικής
ζωής σε εκείνους που εργάστηκαν στα εργοστάσια του έθνους. 
Το ακόλουθο απόσπασμα είναι από την ένταση του ήχου 
ερευνών του Πίτσμπουργκ της Margaret Byington's, αγροτικό 
σπίτι: Οι οικογένειες μιας πόλης μύλων, δημοσίευσαν αρχικά
το 1910. Στο πνεύμα της προσπάθειας προοδευτικός-εποχής 
να τεκμηριωθούν επιστημονικά οι όροι, το βιβλίο περιέλαβε επίσης
τις φωτογραφίες (από το διάσημο αποδεικτικό φωτογράφο Lewis 
Hine) και απαρίθμησε τους οικογενειακούς προϋπολογισμούς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La granja, Pennsylvania, era de muchas maneras la 
ciudad temprana prototípica del molino del vige'simo-siglo. 
Localizado siete millas encima del río de Monongahela de 
Pittsburgh, el primer molino de acero fue construido en granja en 
1881. En 1892, la granja era el sitio de una de las huelgas más
dramáticas de la historia de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Victoria de la 
empresa siderúrgica de Carnegie la última dio lugar a la 
destrucción de una unión una vez que-de gran alcance del hierro 
experto y de los trabajadores de acero. Antes de 1907, casi 
7.000 trabajadores trabajan en la planta de la granja para los ESTADOS
UNIDOS Steel Corporation. En 1907-1908, la fundación sabia de 
Russell emprendió un estudio intensivo que procuró entender los 
cambios dramáticos que habían restructurado a la granja y a otras 
comunidades industriales. Escrito por los reformadores sociales 
progresivos, la encuesta sobre Pittsburgh del seis-volumen acentuó el
impacto devastador de la vida industrial en los que trabajaron en las 
fábricas de la nación. El extracto siguiente es de volumen de 
la encuesta sobre Pittsburgh de Margaret Byington, granja: Las 
casas de una ciudad del molino, primero publicadas en 1910. En 
el alcohol del esfuerzo de la Progresivo-era de documentar científico
condiciones, las fotografías también incluidas del libro (por el 
fotógrafo documental famoso Lewis Hine) y los presupuestos detallados
de la familia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086880</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107629</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/telling-tales-byingtons-study-of-homestead</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
