<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108727</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108727</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086953</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Harlem Renaissance: George Schuyler Argues against "Black Art"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Harlem Renaissance: George Schuyler 
argumentiert gegen "schwarze kunst"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Renaissance de Harlem : George 
Schuyler discute contre "l'art noir"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Renascimento De Harlem: George Schuyler 
discute de encontro "à arte preta"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Rinascita Di Harlem: George Schuyler parla
contro "l'arte nera"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η αναγέννηση Harlem: Θ*Γεοργε Schuyler 
Argues ενάντια στη "μαύρη τέχνη"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Renacimiento De Harlem: George Schuyler 
discute contra "arte negro"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Hundreds of writers and artists lived in Harlem in the 1920s and 1930s and were part of a vibrant, creative community that found its voice in what came to be called the "Harlem Renaissance." Vigorous debate also characterized the Harlem Renaissance. Rejecting stereotypical depictions of African-American life that had dominated all the arts, Alain Locke urged black artists to incorporate the themes and styles of African art into sophisticated, genteel, modern works. But journalist George Schuyler denied that there was such a thing as "black art" or a black sensibility. In this 1926 article ,  "The Negro Art Hokum," Schuyler argued that black artists in America were equally as diverse as white artists, and that to expect a uniform style or subject matter was as insulting as the stereotypes that were being rejected. In a scathing response, Langston Hughes argued that for black artists to paint anything but images of African Americans was tantamount to wanting to be white.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hunderte Verfasser und Künstler wohnten in Harlem
in den zwanziger Jahren und in den dreißiger Jahren und waren ein 
Teil einer vibrant, kreativen Gemeinschaft, die seine Stimme fand in, 
was kam, genannt zu werden die "Harlem Renaissance." Kräftige 
Debatte kennzeichnete auch die Harlem Renaissance. 
Stereotypische Beschreibungen der Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen 
Lebensdauer zurückweisend, die alle künste beherrscht hatten, 
drängte Alain Locke schwarze Künstler, die Themen und die Arten der 
afrikanischen kunst in die hoch entwickelten, genteel, modernen 
Arbeiten zu enthalten. Aber Journalist George Schuyler 
verweigerte, daß es eine solche Sache wie "schwarze kunst" oder eine 
schwarze Empfindlichkeit gab. In diesem Artikel 1926 "die 
Schwarze-kunst Hokum," Schuyler argumentierte, daß schwarze Künstler
in Amerika gleichmäßig so verschieden wie weiße Künstler waren, 
und der, zum einer konstanten Art oder des Themas zu erwarten war als 
Beleidigen als die Stereotypen, die zurückgewiesen wurden. In 
einer scathing Antwort argumentierte Langston Hughes, daß, damit 
schwarze Künstler alles außer Bilder der afrikanischen Amerikaner 
waren gleichwertig mit dem Wunsch, weiß zu sein malen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les centaines d'auteurs et artistes ont habité 
dans Harlem dans les années 20 et les années 30 et faisaient 
partie d'une communauté vibrante et créatrice qui a trouvé sa 
voix dans ce qui est venu pour s'appeler la "Renaissance de 
Harlem." La discussion vigoureuse a également caractérisé
la Renaissance de Harlem. Rejetant les descriptions 
stéréotypées de la vie afro-américaine qui avaient dominé tous les 
arts, Alain Locke a invité les artistes noirs à incorporer les 
thèmes et les modèles de l'art africain aux travaux sophistiqués, 
distingués, modernes. Mais le journaliste George Schuyler a
nié qu'il y avait une chose telle que "l'art noir" ou une 
sensibilité noire. En cet article 1926, "l'art Hokum de 
nègre," Schuyler a argué du fait que les artistes noirs en Amérique
étaient également aussi divers que les artistes blancs, et ce pour 
s'attendre un modèle uniforme ou à des thèmes était en tant 
qu'insulter comme stéréotypes qui étaient rejetés. Dans une 
réponse virulente, Langston Hughes a argué du fait que pour que 
les artistes noirs peignent n'importe quoi mais des images des 
Américains africains étaient équivalents à vouloir être blancs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As centenas dos escritores e dos artistas viveram 
em Harlem nos 1920s e nos 1930s e foram parte de uma comunidade 
vibrant, creativa que encontrasse sua voz em o que veio ser chamado de
"o renascimento Harlem." O debate vigoroso caracterizou também 
o renascimento de Harlem. Rejeitando os depictions stereotypical
da vida Africano-Americana que tinham dominado todas as artes, Alain 
Locke incitou artistas pretos incorporar os temas e os estilos da arte
africana em trabalhos sofisticados, genteel, modernos. Mas o 
journalist George Schuyler negou que havia uma coisa como "a arte 
preta" ou um sensibility preto. Neste artigo 1926, "a arte Hokum
do negro," Schuyler discutiu que os artistas pretos em América eram 
ingualmente tão diversos quanto os artistas brancos, e aquele para 
esperar um estilo uniforme ou uma matéria sujeita era como insultar 
como os stereotypes que eram rejeitados. Em uma resposta 
scathing, Langston Hughes discutiu que para que os artistas pretos 
pintem qualquer coisa mas imagens de americanos africanos eram 
tantamount a querer ser brancos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I centinaia dei produttori e degli artisti hanno 
vissuto in Harlem negli anni 20 e nei 1930s e facevano parte di una 
Comunità vibrant e creativa che ha trovato la relativa voce in che 
cosa è venuto essere chiamato "la rinascita di Harlem." Il 
dibattito vigoroso egualmente ha caratterizzato la rinascita di 
Harlem. Rifiutando i depictions stereotypical di vita 
Africano-Americana che avevano dominato tutte le arti, Alain Locke ha 
invitato gli artisti neri a comprendere i temi e gli stili dell'arte 
africana negli impianti specializzati, genteel, moderni. Ma il 
giornalista George Schuyler ha negato che ci era una cosa come "l'arte
nera" o sensibilità nera. In questo articolo 1926, "l'arte 
Hokum del negro," Schuyler ha sostenuto che gli artisti neri in 
America erano ugualmente vari quanto gli artisti bianchi e quello per 
prevedere uno stile o un tema dell'uniforme era come insultare come
gli stereotipi che stavano rifiutandi. In una risposta scathing,
Langston Hughes ha sostenuto che affinchè gli artisti neri 
verniciasse qualche cosa ma le immagini degli Americani africani era 
equivalente a desiderare essere bianca.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι εκατοντάδες των συγγραφέων και των καλλιτεχνών 
έζησαν σε Harlem στη δεκαετία του '20 και τη δεκαετία του '30 
και ήταν μέρος μιας δονούμενης, δημιουργικής κοινότητας που 
βρήκε τη φωνή της σε αυτό που ήρθε να κληθεί "αναγέννηση 
Harlem." Η σφριγηλή συζήτηση χαρακτήρισε επίσης την 
αναγέννηση Harlem. Απορρίπτοντας τα stereotypical 
depictions της αφρικανικός-αμερικανικής ζωής που είχε 
εξουσιάσει όλες τις τέχνες, ο Alain Locke ώθησε τους 
μαύρους καλλιτέχνες για να ενσωματώσει τα θέματα και τις μορφές 
της αφρικανικής τέχνης στις περίπλοκες, καλοαναθρεμένες, 
σύγχρονες εργασίες. Αλλά ο δημοσιογράφος George 
Schuyler αρνήθηκε ότι υπήρξε ένα τέτοιο πράγμα ως "μαύρη 
τέχνη" ή μαύρη ευαισθησία. Σε αυτό το άρθρο του 1926, 
"η τέχνη Hokum νέγρων," Schuyler υποστήριξε ότι οι μαύροι 
καλλιτέχνες στην Αμερική ήταν εξίσου τόσο διαφορετικοί όσο και 
τους λευκούς καλλιτέχνες, και ότι να αναμείνει ένα ομοιόμορφο 
ύφος ή ένα περιεχόμενο ήταν ως προσβολή ως στερεότυπα που 
απορρίπτονταν. Σε μια τραυματίζοντας απάντηση, Langston 
Hughes υποστήριξε αυτό για τους μαύρους καλλιτέχνες στο χρώμα 
τίποτα αλλά οι εικόνες αφρικανικών Αμερικανών ήταν ισοδύναμες 
προς την επιθυμία να είναι άσπρες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los centenares de programas de escritura y de 
artistas vivieron en Harlem en los años 20 y los años 30 y eran 
parte de una comunidad vibrante, creativa que encontró su voz en 
qué vino ser llamada el "renacimiento de Harlem." El discusión
vigoroso también caracterizó el renacimiento de Harlem. 
Rechazando las pinturas stereotypical de la vida 
Africano-Americana que habían dominado todos los artes, Alain Locke 
impulsó a artistas negros incorporar los temas y los estilos del arte
africano en trabajos sofisticados, genteel, modernos. Pero el 
periodista George Schuyler negó que había una cosa tal como "arte 
negro" o una sensibilidad negra. En este artículo 1926, "el 
arte Hokum del negro," Schuyler discutió que los artistas negros en 
América fueran igualmente tan diversos como los artistas blancos, y 
eso para contar con un estilo uniforme o un tema estaba como 
insultar como los estereotipos que eran rechazados. En una 
respuesta scathing, Langston Hughes discutió que para que los 
artistas negros pinten todo menos imágenes de americanos africanos 
eran equivalentes al deseo ser blancos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086953</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108727</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-harlem-renaissance-george-schuyler-argues-against-black-art</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
