<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/949563426</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>949563426</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203694</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lights Alive!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lichter Lebendig!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lumières Vivantes !</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Luzes Vivas!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Luci Vive!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φώτα ζωντανά!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Luces Vivas!</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This San Diego Natural History Museum interactive website, designed specifically for kids, explores living lights and the chemistry of bioluminescence. It includes links to informational pages and facts about bioluminescence, a quiz and word search game, detailed glossary, and links to related websites. Java is required to fully access the activities associated with this page.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese San Diego Naturgeschichte-Museum interaktive Web 
site, spezifisch konzipiert für Zicklein, erforscht lebende Lichter 
und die Chemie von bioluminescence. Sie schließt Links zu den 
informatorischen Seiten ein und Tatsachen über bioluminescence, einen
Quiz und Wort suchen Spiel, ausführliches Glossar und Links zu in 
Verbindung stehenden Web site. Java wird benoetigt, um auf die 
Aktivitäten völlig zuzugreifen, die mit dieser Seite verbunden sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web interactif de musée d'histoire naturelle de 
San Diego, conçu spécifiquement pour des gosses, explore les 
lumières vivantes et la chimie du bioluminescence. Il inclut 
des liens aux pages informationnelles et les faits sur le 
bioluminescence, un jeu et le mot recherchent le jeu, le glossaire 
détaillé, et les liens aux sites Web relatifs. Java est exigé
pour accéder entièrement aux activités liées à cette page.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site interativo do museu do history natural do 
San Diego, projetado especificamente para miúdos, explora luzes vivas
e o chemistry do bioluminescence. Inclui as ligações às 
páginas informativas e os fatos sobre o bioluminescence, um quiz e a 
palavra procuraram o jogo, glossário detalhado, e ligações aos Web 
site relacionados. Java é requerido para alcançar inteiramente
as atividades associadas com esta página.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site interattivo del museo di storia naturale 
de San Diego, progettato specificamente per i capretti, esplora le 
luci viventi e la chimica del bioluminescence. Include i 
collegamenti alle pagine informative ed i fatti circa il 
bioluminescence, un quiz e la parola cercano il gioco, il glossario 
dettagliato ed i collegamenti ai Web site relativi. Java è 
richiesto completamente per accedere alle attività connesse con 
questa pagina.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το μουσείο φυσικής ιστορίας του Σαν Ντιέγκο που 
ο διαλογικός ιστοχώρος, σχεδίασε συγκεκριμένα για τα κατσίκια, 
ερευνά τα φώτα διαβίωσης και τη χημεία της βιολογικής 
ακτινοβολίας. Περιλαμβάνει τις συνδέσεις με τις ενημερωτικά 
σελίδες και τα γεγονότα για τη βιολογική ακτινοβολία, ένα 
παιχνίδι αναζήτησης διαγωνισμοου γνώσεων και λέξης, το λεπτομερές
γλωσσάρι, και τις συνδέσεις με τους σχετικούς ιστοχώρους. Η 
Ιάβα πρέπει για να έχει πρόσβαση πλήρως στις δραστηριότητες που 
συνδέονται με αυτήν την σελίδα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site interactivo del museo de la historia natural
de San Diego, diseñado específicamente para los cabritos, explora 
luces vivas y la química del bioluminescence. Incluye 
conexiones a las paginaciones informativas y los hechos sobre 
bioluminescence, un concurso y palabra buscan el juego, el glosario 
detallado, y conexiones a los Web site relacionados. Java se 
requiere para tener acceso completamente a las actividades asociadas a
esta paginación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KIDS HABITAT
FN:KIDS HABITAT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SAN DIEGO NATURAL HISTORY MUSEUM
FN:SAN DIEGO NATURAL HISTORY MUSEUM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203694</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>949563426</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lights-alive</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
