<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106348</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106348</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086973</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The introduction of Caliban to Cadmus": John Swinton on Working-Class Literacy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Einleitung von Caliban zu Cadmus": John
Swinton auf Arbeiten-Kategorie Bildungsgrad</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"l'introduction de Caliban à Cadmus" : John
Swinton sur l'instruction de Travailler-Classe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a introdução de Caliban a Cadmus": John 
Swinton no literacy da Trabalh-Classe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"l'introduzione di Caliban a Cadmus": John 
Swinton su literacy del Funzion-Codice categoria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η εισαγωγή Caliban σε Cadmus": Θ*Ιοχν 
Swinton στη βασική εκπαίδευση εργατικής τάξης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la introducción de Caliban a Cadmus": Juan
Swinton en la instrucción de la Trabajar-Clase</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Not surprisingly, labor editors like John Swinton put great store in the liberating powers of the written word. Swinton had been an abolitionist before the Civil War; in the 1870s, he was an editor for the New York  Times  and  Sun ; and in the mid-1880s, he published  John Swinton's Paper. Swinton's Paper  was one of hundreds of labor newspapers that flourished in Gilded Age America. In this essay, Swinton argued that reading was the key to the prosperity and progress of the working classes. The essay, which appeared in  The Carpenter  in 1901, was itself a testimony to the extent of working-class literacy in this period. Swinton assumed that his readers would understand his references to Caliban (the slave in Shakespeare's  The Tempest)  and Cadmus (the figure in Greek mythology who brought the alphabet).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nicht überraschend, setzten Arbeitsherausgeber 
wie John Swinton großen Speicher in die befreienden Energien des 
schriftlichen Wortes ein. Swinton war ein abolitionist vor dem 
Bürgerkrieg gewesen; im 1870s war er ein Herausgeber für die 
New York Zeiten und die Sonne; und im mid-1880s, 
veröffentlichte er John Swintons Papier. Papier Swintons war 
eins von Hunderten der Arbeitszeitungen, die in vergoldetem Alter 
Amerika blühten. In diesem Versuch argumentierte Swinton, daß 
Messwert die Taste zum Wohlstand und zum Fortschritt der Funktion 
Kategorien war. Der Versuch, der im Tischler 1901 erschien, war 
selbst ein Zeugnis im Umfang eines Arbeiterklassebildungsgrades in 
dieser Periode. Swinton nahm an, daß seine Leser seine 
Referenzen auf Caliban (der Sklave Shakespeares im Tempest) und Cadmus
verstehen würden (die Abbildung in der griechischen Mythologie, die 
das Alphabet holte).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pas étonnamment, les éditeurs de travail comme 
John Swinton ont mis la grande mémoire dans les puissances de 
libération du mot écrit. Swinton avait été un abolitionniste 
avant la guerre civile ; dans le 1870s, il était un éditeur 
pendant les temps et le soleil de New York ; et dans le 
mid-1880s, il a édité le papier de John Swinton. Le papier de 
Swinton était l'une de centaines de journaux de travail qui se sont 
épanouis dans l'âge doré Amérique. Dans cet essai, Swinton a
argué du fait que la lecture était la clé à la prospérité et au 
progrès des classes ouvrières. L'essai, qui est apparu dans le
charpentier en 1901, était lui-même un témoignage jusqu'au degré 
de l'instruction de classe ouvrière dans cette période. 
Swinton a supposé que ses lecteurs comprendraient ses 
références à Caliban (le slave dans la tempête de 
Shakespeare) et à Cadmus (la figure en mythologie grecque qui a 
apporté l'alphabet).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Não surprisingly, os editores labor como John 
Swinton puseram a loja grande nas potências liberating da palavra 
escrita. Swinton tinha sido um abolitionist antes da guerra 
civil; no 1870s, era um editor para os tempos e o sol de New 
York; e no mid-1880s, publicou o papel de John Swinton. O 
papel de Swinton era uma das centenas dos jornais labor que 
floresceram na idade gilded América. Neste essay, Swinton 
discutiu que a leitura era a chave à prosperidade e ao progresso das 
classes de funcionamento. O essay, que apareceu no carpinteiro 
em 1901, era próprio um testimony à extensão do literacy do 
working-class neste período. Swinton supos que seus leitores 
compreenderiam suas referências a Caliban (o escravo na tempestade de
Shakespeare) e a Cadmus (a figura no mythology grego que trouxe o 
alfabeto).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Non sorprendentemente, gli editori di lavoro 
come John Swinton hanno messo il deposito grande nelle potenzi di 
liberazione della parola scritta. Swinton era stato un 
abolitionist prima della guerra civile; nel 1870s, era un 
editore per i tempi ed il sole de New York; e nel mid-1880s, ha 
pubblicato la relazione del John Swinton. La relazione dello 
Swinton era una delle centinaia dei giornali di lavoro che sono 
fiorito nell'età gilded America. In questo saggio, Swinton ha 
sostenuto che la lettura era il tasto alla prosperità ed al progresso
dei codici categoria di funzionamento. Il saggio, che è 
comparso nel carpentiere in 1901, era in se una testimonianza nella 
misura di literacy della classe operaia in questo periodo. 
Swinton ha supposto che i suoi lettori capirebbero i suoi 
riferimenti a Caliban (lo schiavo nella tempesta dello Shakespeare) ed
a Cadmus (la figura in mitologia greca che ha portato l'alfabeto).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όπως ήταν αναμενόμενο, οι επεξεργαστές εργασίας όπως
John Swinton βάζουν το μεγάλο κατάστημα στις δυνάμεις 
απελευθέρωσης της γραπτής λέξης. Το Swinton ήταν 
ρεφορμιστής πριν από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο  1870s, ήταν 
επεξεργαστής για τους New York Times και τον ήλιο  
και στα μέσα της 1880s, δημοσίευσε το έγγραφο John 
Swinton. Το έγγραφο του Swinton ήταν μια από τις 
εκατοντάδες των εφημερίδων εργασίας που άκμασαν στην επιχρυσωμένη
ηλικία Αμερική. Σε αυτό το δοκίμιο, Swinton υποστήριξε 
ότι η ανάγνωση ήταν το πλήκτρο στην ευημερία και την πρόοδο των 
εργατικών τάξεων. Το δοκίμιο, που εμφανίστηκε στον ξυλουργό
το 1901, ήταν ο ίδιος μια κατάθεση στην έκταση της βασικής 
εκπαίδευσης εργατικών τάξεων σε αυτήν την περίοδο. Το 
Swinton υπέθεσε ότι οι αναγνώστες του θα καταλάβαιναν τις 
αναφορές του σε Caliban (ο σκλάβος θύελλα Shakespeare στη) 
και Cadmus (ο αριθμός στην ελληνική μυθολογία που έφερε το 
αλφάβητο).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">No asombrosamente, los editores de trabajo como 
Juan Swinton pusieron el gran almacén en las potencias de liberación
de la palabra escrita. Swinton había sido un abolitionist antes
de la guerra civil; en el 1870s, él era editor por los tiempos 
y el sol de Nueva York; y en el mid-1880s, él publicó el papel
de Juan Swinton. El papel de Swinton era uno de centenares de 
los periódicos de trabajo que prosperaron en la edad dorada América.
En este ensayo, Swinton discutió que la lectura fuera el clave 
a la prosperidad y al progreso de las clases obreras. El ensayo,
que apareció en el carpintero en 1901, era sí mismo un testimonio al
fragmento de la instrucción de la clase obrera en este período. 
Swinton asumió que sus programas de lectura entenderían sus 
referencias a Caliban (el esclavo en la tempestad de Shakespeare) y a 
Cadmus (la figura en la mitología griega que trajo el alfabeto).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086973</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106348</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-introduction-of-caliban-to-cadmus-john-swinton-on-working-class-literacy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
