<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108705</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108705</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086908</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Bum as Con Artist: An Undercover Account of the Great Depression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Gammler als gegen Künstler: Ein 
Innenabdeckung Konto des großen Tiefstands</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le clochard en tant que contre artiste : Un 
compte de capot interne de la grande dépression</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O bum como con o artista: Um cliente da capa 
interna do depression grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il bum come con artista: Un cliente della 
copertura inferiore della depressione grande</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο άχρηστος ως καλλιτέχνη Con: Ένας μυστικός 
απολογισμός της μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Vago como con artista: Una cuenta de
la cubierta interior de la gran depresión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Middle-class observers reacted to hoboes and tramps of the Great Depression with an array of responses, viewing them with suspicion, empathy, concern, fear, sometimes even a twinge of envy. For some, stolidly holding onto traditional values of work and success, the "bum" was suspect, potentially a con artist. Tom Kromer's "Pity the Poor Panhandler: $2 An Hour Is All He Gets" exemplified this stance, urging readers to resist the appeals of panhandlers and refer them to relief agencies, where professionals could help the deserving and get rid of the rest. Ironically, the young journalist who went undercover to write this piece would find himself unemployed and on the road within a year of the publication of his condescending article.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Mittelklassebeobachter, die zu den hoboes und 
zu den Tramps des großen Tiefstands mit einer Reihe Antworten, sie 
ansehend mit dem Misstrauen, empathy, Interesse, Furcht reagiert 
werden, glätten manchmal einen Twinge des Neides. Für einiges 
stolidly anhalten auf traditionelle Werte der Arbeit und des Erfolges,
war der "Gammler", möglicherweise ein betrügerischer Künstler 
vermutlich defekt. Tom Kromers "Mitleid der arme Bettler: 
alle $2 ein Stunde ist, die er "illustrierte diese Position 
erhält und drängt Leser, den Anklänge der Bettler zu widerstehen 
und sie auf Entlastung Agenturen zu verweisen, in denen Fachleute dem 
Verdienen helfen konnten und loszuwerden den Rest. Ironisch 
würde der junge Journalist, der die Innenabdeckung ging, zum dieses 
Stückes zu schreiben, sich Arbeitslose und auf der Straße innerhalb 
eines Jahres der Publikation seines herablassenden Artikels finden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les observateurs de classe moyenne mis à réagir 
aux hoboes et aux bruits de la grande dépression avec un choix de 
réponses, les visualisant avec le soupçon, empathie, souci, 
crainte, égalisent parfois un élancement d'envie. Pour 
certains, stolidly se tenant sur des valeurs traditionnelles de 
travail et de succès, le "clochard" était suspect, potentiellement 
un artiste trompeur. Pitié de Tom Kromer "le pauvre 
clochard : $2 par heure est tous qu'il obtient "a exemplifié 
cette position, invitant des lecteurs à résister aux appels des 
clochards et à les renvoyer aux agences de soulagement, où les 
professionnels pourraient aider mériter et se débarasser du repos. 
Ironiquement, le jeune journaliste qui est allé capot interne 
pour écrire ce morceau se trouverait des chômeurs et sur la route 
dans une année de la publication de son article condescendant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os observadores do middle-class reagidos aos hoboes
e às caminhadas do depression grande com uma disposição das 
respostas, vendo as com a suspeita, empathy, interesse, medo, nivelam 
às vezes um twinge do envy. Para algum, stolidly prendendo em 
valores tradicionais do trabalho e do sucesso, o "bum" era suspeito, 
potencial um artista con. Piedade de Tom Kromer "o panhandler 
deficiente: $2 um a hora são todos que começa "exemplified 
este stance, incitando leitores resistir as apelações dos 
panhandlers e consultá-los às agências do relevo, onde os 
profissionais poderiam ajudar a merecer e começar livrou do descanso.
Ironically, o journalist novo que foi capa interna para escrever
esta parte encontrar-se-ia desempregados e na estrada dentro de um ano
da publicação de seu artigo condescending.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli osservatori della classe media reagiti ai 
hoboes ed ai vagabondi della depressione grande con un allineamento 
delle risposte, osservante lei con sospetto, empathy, la 
preoccupazione, timore, a volte livellano un twinge di invidia. 
Per alcuno, stolidly la tenuta sui valori tradizionali di 
lavoro ed il successo, "il bum" erano sospetti, potenzialmente un 
artista con. Pity di Tom Kromer "il Povero panhandler: 
$2 un l'ora sono tutti che ottenga "abbia esemplificato questa 
posizione, invitante i lettori a resistere agli appelli dei 
panhandlers ed a farli riferimento alle agenzie di rilievo, in cui i 
professionisti potrebbero aiutare meritarsi ed eliminare il resto. 
Ironicamente, il giornalista giovane che è andato copertura 
inferiore per scrivere questa parte si troverebbe disoccupati e sulla 
strada in un anno della pubblicazione del suo articolo condescending.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι παρατηρητές μεσαίας τάξης αντέδρασαν στα hoboes 
και τους αγύρτες της μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης με μια σειρά 
απαντήσεων, που εμφανίζουν τους με την υποψία, ενσυναίσθημα, 
ανησυχία, φόβος, μερικές φορές ακόμη και ένας πόνος του 
φθόνου. Για μερικούς, stolidly που κρατούν επάνω στις 
παραδοσιακές αξίες της εργασίας και της επιτυχίας, ο "άχρηστοσ" 
ήταν ύποπτος, ενδεχομένως ένας καλλιτέχνης con. Οίκτος 
του Tom Kromer's "το φτωχό Panhandler: $2 μια ώρα
είναι ό,τι παίρνει "εξηγημένος αυτήν την θέση, ωθώντας τους 
αναγνώστες για να αντισταθεί στις εκκλήσεις των panhandlers και 
να τις αναφέρει στις αντιπροσωπείες ανακούφισης, όπου οι 
επαγγελματίες μπόρεσαν να βοηθήσουν να αξίζουν και να ξεφορτωθούν
το υπόλοιπο. Ειρωνικά, ο νέος δημοσιογράφος που πήγε 
μυστικός για να γράψει αυτό το κομμάτι θα βρισκόταν άνεργοι και 
στο δρόμο μέσα σε ένα έτος από τη δημοσίευση του 
condescending άρθρου του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los observadores de la clase media reaccionados a 
los hoboes y a los vagabundos de la gran depresión con un arsenal de 
respuestas, viéndolas con la suspicacia, empathy, preocupación, 
miedo, igualan a veces una punzada de la envidia. Para alguno, 
stolidly sosteniendo sobre valores tradicionales del trabajo y del 
éxito, el "vago" era sospechado, potencialmente un artista con.
Compasión de Tom Kromer "el panhandler pobre: $2 por hora
es todos lo que él consigue "ejemplificó esta postura, impulsando a 
programas de lectura resistir las súplicas de panhandlers y 
referirlos a las agencias de la relevación, donde los profesionales 
podrían ayudar a merecer y conseguir libró del resto. 
Irónico, el periodista joven que fue cubierta interior para 
escribir este pedazo se encontraría los parados y en el camino dentro
de un año de la publicación de su artículo condescending.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086908</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108705</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-bum-as-con-artist-an-undercover-account-of-the-great-depression</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
