<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104141</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104141</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206686</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Salem Witchcraft Papers: Transcription and Archival Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Salem Witchcraft-Papiere: Übertragung und 
archivalisches Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Papiers de Sorcellerie de Salem : 
Transcription et projet archivistique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Papéis Do Witchcraft De Salem: 
Transcrição e projeto archival</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Carte Da Witchcraft De Salem: Trascrizione e
progetto archivistico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Witchcraft του Σάλεμ έγγραφα: Μεταγραφή και 
αρχειακό πρόγραμμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Papeles De la Brujería De Salem: 
Transcripción y proyecto archival</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Salem Witchcraft Papers: Transcription and Archival Project introduces the infamous Salem Witch Trials of 1692 and presents information on other aspects of the history of Danvers (formerly Salem Village), Massachusetts. The website features rare documents including the complete 1692 Salem Witchcraft Papers, narratives of witchcraft cases, historical maps, and answers to frequently asked questions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Salem Witchcraft-Papiere: Übertragung und 
archivalisches Projekt stellt die unbeliebten Salem Hexe-Versuche von 
1692 vor und stellt Informationen über andere Aspekte der Geschichte 
von Danvers (früher Salem Dorf), Massachusetts dar. Die Web 
site kennzeichnet seltene Dokumente einschließlich die kompletten 
Salem Witchcraft-Papiere 1692, die Darstellungen der Witchcraftfälle,
die historischen Karten und die Antworten zu häufig gestellten 
Fragen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Papiers de Sorcellerie de Salem : La 
transcription et le projet archivistique présente les épreuves 
infâmes de sorcière de Salem de 1692 et présente l'information sur 
d'autres aspects de l'histoire de Danvers (autrefois village de 
Salem), le Massachusetts. Le site Web comporte les documents 
rares comprenant les papiers 1692 complets de sorcellerie de Salem, 
des récits des cas de sorcellerie, des cartes historiques, et des 
réponses aux questions fréquemment posées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Papéis Do Witchcraft De Salem: A 
transcrição e o projeto archival introduzem as experimentações 
infamous da bruxa de Salem de 1692 e apresentam a informação em 
outros aspectos do history de Danvers (anteriormente vila) de Salem, 
Massachusetts. O Web site caracteriza originais raros including 
os papéis 1692 completos do witchcraft de Salem, narrativas de casos 
do witchcraft, mapas históricos, e respostas às perguntas 
freqüentemente feitas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Carte Da Witchcraft De Salem: La 
trascrizione ed il progetto archivistico introduce le prove malfamate 
della strega de Salem di 1692 e presenta le informazioni su altre 
funzioni della storia di Danvers (precedentemente villaggio) de Salem,
Massachusetts. Il Web site caratterizza i documenti rari 
compreso le carte complete 1692 da witchcraft de Salem, le descrizioni
dei casi di witchcraft, i programmi storici e le risposte alle domande
frequentemente fatte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Witchcraft του Σάλεμ έγγραφα: Η μεταγραφή και
το αρχειακό πρόγραμμα εισάγουν τις κακόφημες δοκιμές μαγισσών 
του Σάλεμ 1692 και παρουσιάζουν τις πληροφορίες για άλλες 
πτυχές της ιστορίας Danvers (στο παρελθόν χωριό του Σάλεμ), 
Μασαχουσέτη. Ο ιστοχώρος χαρακτηρίζει τα σπάνια έγγραφα 
συμπεριλαμβανομένων των πλήρων 1692 witchcraft του Σάλεμ 
εγγράφων, των αφηγημάτων witchcraft των περιπτώσεων, των 
ιστορικών χαρτών, και των απαντήσεων στις συχνά ερωτήσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Papeles De la Brujería De Salem: La 
transcripción y el proyecto archival introduce los ensayos infames de
la bruja de Salem de 1692 y presenta la información sobre otros 
aspectos de la historia de Danvers (antes aldea) de Salem, 
Massachusetts. El Web site ofrece documentos raros incluyendo 
los papeles completos 1692 de la brujería de Salem, las narrativas de
los casos de la brujería, las correspondencias históricas, y las 
respuestas a preguntas con frecuencia hechas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206686</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104141</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/salem-witchcraft-papers-transcription-and-archival-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
