<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103753</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103753</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200457</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Animation of Wave Motion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Animation der Welle Bewegung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Animation de mouvement de vague</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Animation do movimento da onda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Animazione di movimento dell'onda</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ζωτικότητα της κίνησης κυμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Animación del movimiento de la onda</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Flash animation illustrates wave motion, or the movement of energy through water. Users can stop, play, fast forward and rewind the animation at any time. This visualization is one of several animations in a series developed as a component of Exploring Earth, a website that supports the textbook Earth Science.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese grelle Animation veranschaulicht Welle 
Bewegung oder die Bewegung von Energie durch Wasser. Benutzer 
können stoppen, spielen, schnelles Vorwärts und die Animation 
jederzeit rückspulen. Diese Sichtbarmachung ist eine einiger 
Animationen in einer Serie, die als Bestandteil der erforschenden 
Masse, eine Web site entwickelt wird, die die Lehrbuch Geowissenschaft
unterstützt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette animation instantanée illustre le mouvement
de vague, ou le mouvement de l'énergie par l'eau. Les 
utilisateurs peuvent s'arrêter, jouer, vers l'avant rapide et 
rebobiner l'animation à tout moment. Cette visualisation est 
l'une de plusieurs animations d'une série développée comme 
composant de la terre l'explorant, un site Web qui supporte la science
de la terre de manuel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este animation flash ilustra o movimento da onda, 
ou o movimento da energia através da água. Os usuários podem 
parar, jogar, para diante rápido e rebobinar o animation em em 
qualquer altura que. Este visualization é um de diversos 
animations em uma série desenvolvida como um componente da terra 
explorando, um Web site que suporte a ciência de terra do textbook.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa animazione istantanea illustra il movimento
dell'onda, o il movimento di energia attraverso acqua. Gli 
utenti possono arrestarsi, giocare, di andata veloce e riavvolgere in 
qualunque momento la animazione. Questa visualizzazione è una 
di parecchie animazioni in serie sviluppata come componente di terra 
d'esplorazione, un Web site che sostiene le scienze della terra del 
manuale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ζωτικότητα λάμψης επεξηγεί την κίνηση 
κυμάτων, ή τη μετακίνηση της ενέργειας μέσω του ύδατος. Οι
χρήστες μπορούν να σταματήσουν, να παίξουν, να διαβιβάζουν 
γρήγορα και να ξανατυλίξουν τη ζωτικότητα οποιαδήποτε στιγμή. 
Αυτή η απεικόνιση είναι μια από διάφορες ζωτικότητες σε 
μια σειρά που αναπτύσσεται ως συστατικό τη γη, ένας ιστοχώρος που
υποστηρίζει τη γήινη επιστήμη εγχειριδίων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta animación de destello ilustra el movimiento 
de la onda, o el movimiento de la energía a través del agua. 
Los utilizadores pueden parar, jugar, delantero rápido y 
rebobinar la animación en cualquier momento. Esta 
visualización es una de varias animaciones en una serie desarrollada 
como componente de la tierra que explora, un Web site que utilice la 
geología del libro de textos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200457</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103753</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/animation-of-wave-motion</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
