<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103317</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103317</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206917</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">First Battle of Manassas: An End to Innocence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erste Schlacht von Manassas: Ein Ende zur 
Unschuld</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Première bataille de Manassas : Une fin à 
l'innocence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Primeira batalha de Manassas: Um fim ao 
innocence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prima battaglia di Manassas: Una conclusione
a innocence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρώτη μάχη Manassas: Ένα τέλος στην αθωότητα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Primera batalla de Manassas: Un final a la 
inocencia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at the first conflict of the Civil War, the battle of Bull Run. More than 5,000 people perished -- Northern and Southern troops, as well as private citizens who came from Washington, D.C., to watch. Personal stories, maps, and photos show how this battle shocked the nation into realizing that the conflict was not some romantic adventure and that it would be longer and more costly than anyone had imagined.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf die erste $überschneidung des 
Bürgerkrieges, die Schlacht des Bull Durchlaufes mehr als 5.000 Leute
umgekommen -- Nord- und südliche Truppen, sowie private Bürger, die 
aus Washington, Gleichstrom kamen, zu überwachen. Persönliche 
Geschichten, Karten und Fotoerscheinen, wie diese Schlacht die Nation 
in das Feststellen entsetzte, daß die $überschneidung nicht 
irgendein romantisches Abenteuer war und daß es länger und teurer 
als sein würde, jedermann hatten sich vorgestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regards au premier conflit de la guerre civile, la
bataille du passage de Bull. Plus de 5.000 personnes péries -- 
troupes nordiques et méridionales, aussi bien que les citoyens 
privés qui sont venus de Washington, C.C, pour observer. Les 
histoires personnelles, les cartes, et l'exposition de photos comment 
cette bataille a choqué la nation dans se rendre compte que le 
conflit n'était pas une certaine aventure romantique et qu'elle 
serait plus longue et plus coûteuse que n'importe qui avaient 
imaginé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olhares no primeiro conflito da guerra civil, a 
batalha do funcionamento de Bull mais de 5.000 povos perished -- 
tropas do norte e do sul, as.well.as os cidadãos confidenciais que 
vieram de Washington, C.C., prestar atenção. As histórias 
pessoais, os mapas, e a mostra das fotos como esta batalha chocou a 
nação em realizar que o conflito não era alguma aventura romântica
e que seria mais longa e mais cara do que qualquer um tinham 
imaginado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sguardi al primo conflitto della guerra civile, la
battaglia del funzionamento di Bull più di 5.000 genti perite -- 
truppe nordiche e del sud, così come i cittadini riservati che sono 
venuto da Washington, DC, guardare. Le storia personali, i 
programmi e l'esposizione delle foto come questa battaglia ha scosso 
la nazione nel rendersi conto che il conflitto non era una certa 
avventura romantica e che sarebbe più lunga e più costosa di 
chiunque avevano immaginato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει την πρώτη σύγκρουση του εμφύλιου πολέμου, η 
μάχη του τρεξίματος του Bull. Περισσότεροι από 5.000 
άνθρωποι χάθηκαν -- βόρεια και νότια στρατεύματα, καθώς επίσης 
και απλοί πολίτες που προήλθαν από την Ουάσιγκτον, ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ 
ΡΕΎΜΑ, να προσέξουν. Οι προσωπικές ιστορίες, οι χάρτες, και
οι φωτογραφίες επιδεικνύουν πώς αυτή η μάχη συγκλόνισε το έθνος
στη συνειδητοποίηση ότι η σύγκρουση δεν ήταν κάποια ρομαντική 
περιπέτεια και ότι θα ήταν μακρύτερη και δαπανηρότερη από 
καθένα είχε φανταστεί.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">miradas en el primer conflicto de la guerra civil,
la batalla del funcionamiento de Bull más de 5.000 personas 
fallecidas -- tropas norteñas y meridionales, así como los 
ciudadanos privados que vinieron de Washington, C.C., mirar. Las
historias personales, las correspondencias, y la demostración de las 
fotos cómo esta batalla dio una sacudida eléctrica la nación en 
realizar que el conflicto no era una cierta aventura romántica y que 
sería más larga y más costosa que cualquier persona se habían 
imaginado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206917</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103317</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/first-battle-of-manassas-an-end-to-innocence</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
