<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103229</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103229</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201361</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Exploration Toolbook Chapter: Analyzing Wetlands</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Erforschung Toolbook Kapitel: 
Analysieren von von Sumpfgebieten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chapitre de Toolbook d'Exploration de la Terre : 
Analyse des Marécages</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capítulo De Toolbook Da Exploração Da Terra: 
Analisando Wetlands</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitolo Di Toolbook Di Esplorazione Della Terra: 
Analizzare Wetlands</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεφάλαιο Toolbook γήινης εξερεύνησης: Ανάλυση
των υγρότοπων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capítulo De Toolbook De la Exploración De la 
Tierra: Analizar Wetlands</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Ramsar Wetlands Data Gateway is a database containing information on protected international wetlands. In this activity, users search the database to find a wetland that they are interested in helping to protect. Using the database search capabilities, users select various wetland characteristics and generate a report on the sites that meet their search criteria. Then, they access an interactive map to view the locations and nearby features of the identified wetland sites. Next, they narrow the choices down to a single wetland that they would like to protect and gather further information about it. Finally, users prepare a brief report to persuade others of the value of protecting the site.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Ramsar Sumpfgebiet-Daten-Gateway ist eine 
Datenbank, die Informationen über geschützte internationale 
Sumpfgebiete enthält. In dieser Aktivität suchen Benutzer 
die Datenbank, um ein Sumpfgebiet zu finden, daß sie interessiert 
sind, an zu helfen sich zu schützen. Mit den 
Datenbanksuchfähigkeiten wählen Benutzer verschiedene 
Sumpfgebieteigenschaften aus und legen einen Report auf den Sites fest,
die ihre Suchkriterien treffen. Dann greifen sie auf eine 
interaktive Karte zu, um die Standorte und die nahe gelegenen Merkmale
der gekennzeichneten Sumpfgebietsites anzusehen. Zunächst 
verengen sie die Wahlen unten zu einem einzelnen Sumpfgebiet, das 
sie möchten, weitere Informationen über es schützen und erfaßt. 
Schließlich bereiten Benutzer einen kurzen Report vor, um 
andere des Wertes des Schützens der Sites zu überzeugen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Gateway de données de Marécages de Ramsar est
une base de données contenant l'information sur les marécages 
internationaux protégés. Dans cette activité, les 
utilisateurs recherchent la base de données pour trouver un 
marécage qu'ils sont intéressés à aider à se protéger. En
utilisant les capacités de recherche de base de données, les 
utilisateurs choisissent de diverses caractéristiques de marécage 
et produisent d'un état sur les sites qui rencontrent leurs 
critères de recherche. Puis, ils accèdent à une carte 
interactive pour visualiser les emplacements et les dispositifs 
voisins des sites identifiés de marécage. Ensuite, ils 
rétrécissent les choix vers le bas à un marécage simple qui ils 
voudraient que protège et recueille d'autres informations sur lui. 
En conclusion, les utilisateurs disposent un bref état pour 
persuader d'autres de la valeur de protéger le site.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Gateway dos dados de Ramsar Wetlands é uma base 
de dados que contem a informação em wetlands internacionais 
protegidos. Nesta atividade, os usuários procuraram a base de 
dados para encontrar um wetland que estão interessados na ajuda 
proteger. Usando as potencialidades da busca da base de dados, 
os usuários selecionam várias características do wetland e geram um
relatório nos locais que se encontram com seus critérios da busca. 
Então, alcançam um mapa interativo para ver as posições e as
características próximas dos locais identificados do wetland. 
Em seguida, estreitam as escolhas para baixo a um único wetland
de que gostem de proteger e recolher uma informação mais adicional 
sobre ele. Finalmente, os usuários preparam um relatório breve
para persuadir outro do valor de proteger o local.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Gateway di dati di Ramsar Wetlands è una base 
di dati che contiene le informazioni sui wetlands internazionali 
protetti. In questa attività, gli utenti cercano la base di 
dati per trovare un wetland che sono interessati nel contribuire a 
proteggere. Usando le possibilità di ricerca della base di 
dati, gli utenti selezionano le varie caratteristiche del wetland e 
generano un rapporto sui luoghi che rispondono ai loro test di 
verifica di ricerca. Allora, accedono ad un programma 
interattivo per osservare le posizioni ed ai le caratteristiche vicine
dei luoghi identificati del wetland. Dopo, limitano le scelte 
giù ad un singolo wetland che vorrebbero per proteggergli e 
riunireli ulteriori informazioni. Per concludere, gli 
utenti preparano un breve rapporto per persaudere altri del valore di 
protezione del luogo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η πύλη στοιχείων υγρότοπων Ramsar είναι μια βάση 
δεδομένων που περιέχει τις πληροφορίες για τους προστατευμένους 
διεθνείς υγρότοπους. Σε αυτήν την δραστηριότητα, οι χρήστες
ψάχνουν τη βάση δεδομένων για να βρούν έναν υγρότοπο ότι 
ενδιαφέρονται για τη βοήθεια να προστατεύσουν. 
Χρησιμοποιώντας τις ικανότητες αναζήτησης βάσεων δεδομένων,
οι χρήστες επιλέγουν τα διάφορα χαρακτηριστικά υγρότοπου και 
παράγουν μια έκθεση σχετικά με τις περιοχές που ικανοποιούν τα 
κριτήρια αναζήτησής τους. Κατόπιν, έχουν πρόσβαση σε έναν
διαλογικό χάρτη για να εμφανίσουν τις θέσεις και τα κοντινά 
χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα των προσδιορισμένων περιοχών υγρότοπου.
Έπειτα, στενεύουν τις επιλογές κάτω σε έναν ενιαίο 
υγρότοπο που θα επιθυμούσαν να προστατεύσουν και να συγκεντρώσουν 
τις συμπληρωματικές πληροφορίες για το. Τέλος, οι χρήστες 
προετοιμάζουν μια συνοπτική έκθεση για να πείσουν άλλων της 
αξίας της προστασίας της περιοχής.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Gateway de los datos de Ramsar Wetlands es una 
base de datos que contiene la información sobre wetlands 
internacionales protegidos. En esta actividad, los utilizadores 
buscan la base de datos para encontrar un wetland que están 
interesados en ayudar a proteger. Usando las capacidades de la 
búsqueda de la base de datos, los utilizadores seleccionan varias 
características del wetland y generan un informe en los sitios que 
resuelven sus criterios de la búsqueda. Entonces, tienen acceso
a una correspondencia interactiva para visión las localizaciones y 
las características próximas de los sitios identificados del 
wetland. Después, enangostan las opciones abajo a un solo 
wetland que quisieran que protegiera y recopilara la información 
adicional sobre él. Finalmente, los utilizadores preparan un 
informe abreviado para persuadir otros del valor de proteger el sitio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ROBERT DOWNS
FN:ROBERT DOWNS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201361</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103229</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-exploration-toolbook-chapter-analyzing-wetlands</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
