<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106491</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106491</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087314</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Letter Home From Massachusetts Bay in 1631</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Zeichen Haupt von der Massachusetts Bucht 
1631</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une lettre à la maison du compartiment du 
Massachusetts en 1631</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma letra home da baía de Massachusetts em 1631</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una lettera domestica dalla baia del Massachusetts
in 1631</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια "Οικία" επιστολών από τον κόλπο της Μασαχουσέτης 
το 1631</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una carta casera de la bahía de Massachusetts en 
1631</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Over 20,000 migrants from England crossed the Atlantic to the new colony of Massachusetts Bay in the decade of the 1630s. This sudden influx of settlers became known to historians as the "Great Migration." Once in New England, they quickly dispersed to various towns. About forty families followed Sir Richard Saltonstall and the Reverend George Phillips four miles up the Charles River to found the community of Watertown in July 1630. Many had relocated from the East Anglian region of England, where William Pond, the correspondent's father, lived. These families attempted to set up a familiar farm economy based on grain and livestock, but early dreams of an easy trade with the Indians proved elusive. Their concerns focused on feeding themselves and achieving economic sufficiency.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Über 20.000 Wanderern von England kreuzte den 
Atlantik zur neuen Kolonie der Massachusetts Bucht in der Dekade des 
1630s. Dieser plötzliche Zufluß der Siedleren wurde bekannt zu
den Historikern als die "große Migration." Einmal in 
Neu-England, zerstreuten sie schnell zu den verschiedenen Städten. 
Ungefähr vierzig Familien folgten Sir Richard Saltonstall und 
die Reverend George Kreuzkopfvier Meilen herauf den Charles Fluß zu 
fanden die Gemeinschaft von Watertown im Juli 1630. Viele von 
der Ostanglian Region von England, in dem William Teich, der Vater des
Korrespondenten verlagert hatten, gelebt. Diese Familien 
versuchten, ein vertrautes landwirtschaftliches aufzustellen basiert 
auf Korn und Vieh, aber frühe Träume eines einfachen Handels mit den
Indern prüften schwer bestimmbares. Ihre Interessen 
konzentrierten auf das Einziehen und das Erzielen der ökonomischen 
Hinlänglichkeit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plus de 20.000 migrants d'Angleterre a croisé 
l'Océan atlantique à la nouvelle colonie du compartiment du 
Massachusetts dans la décennie du 1630s. Cet afflux soudain des
colons est devenu notoire aux historiens comme "grand transfert." 
Une fois en Nouvelle Angleterre, ils ont rapidement dispersé à
de diverses villes. Environ quarante familles ont suivi monsieur
Richard Saltonstall et milles Phillips de George de Révérend 
les quatre vers le haut du fleuve de Charles à ont trouvé la 
communauté de Watertown en juillet 1630. Beaucoup avaient 
replacé de la région est d'Anglian de l'Angleterre, où étang de 
William, le père du correspondant, vécu. Ces familles ont 
essayé d'installer une économie familière de ferme basée sur le 
grain et le bétail, mais les premiers rêves d'un commerce facile 
avec les Indiens ont prouvé évasif. Leurs soucis se sont 
concentrés sur s'alimenter et réaliser la suffisance économique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sobre 20.000 emigrantes de Inglaterra cruzou o 
Atlântico à colônia nova da baía de Massachusetts na década do 
1630s. Este influx repentino dos settlers tornou-se sabido aos 
historians como "a migração grande." Uma vez em Nova 
Inglaterra, dispersaram-se rapidamente às várias cidades. 
Aproximadamente quarenta famílias seguiram o senhor Richard 
Saltonstall e milhas Phillips de Reverend George as quatro acima do 
rio de Charles a encontraram a comunidade de Watertown em julho 1630. 
Muitos relocated da região do leste de Anglian de Inglaterra, 
onde lagoa de William, pai do correspondente, vivido. Estas 
famílias tentaram ajustar acima uma economia de fazenda familiar 
baseada na grão e nos animais domésticos, mas os sonhos adiantados 
de um comércio fácil com os indians provaram elusive. Seus 
interesses focalizaram em alimentar-se e em conseguir o sufficiency 
econômico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Oltre 20.000 migranti dall'Inghilterra ha 
attraversato l'Atlantico alla nuova colonia della baia del 
Massachusetts nella decade del 1630s. Questo afflusso improvviso
dei settlers è stato conosciuto agli storici come "l'espansione 
grande." Una volta in Nuova Inghilterra, si sono dispersi 
rapidamente alle varie città. Circa quaranta famiglie hanno 
seguito il sir Richard Saltonstall e miglia "phillips" di Reverend 
George le quattro sul fiume del Charles a hanno trovato la Comunità 
di Watertown nel mese di luglio del 1630. Molti avevano 
riassegnato dalla regione orientale di Anglian dell'Inghilterra, in 
cui stagno del William, il padre del corrispondente, vivo. 
Queste famiglie hanno tentato di installare un'economia esperta 
dell'azienda agricola basata su grano e su bestiame, ma i sogni 
iniziali di un commercio facile con gli indiani hanno dimostrato 
evasivo. Le loro preoccupazioni hanno messo a fuoco 
sull'alimentazione e sul realizzare la sufficienza economica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πάνω από 20.000 μετανάστες από την Αγγλία 
διέσχισαν τον Ατλαντικό στη νέα αποικία του κόλπου της 
Μασαχουσέτης στη δεκαετία του 1630s. Αυτή η ξαφνική 
εισροή των αποίκων έγινε γνωστή στους ιστορικούς ως "μεγάλη 
μετανάστευση." Μιά φορά στη Νέα Αγγλία, διασκόρπισαν 
γρήγορα στις διάφορες πόλεις. Περίπου σαράντα οικογένειες 
ακολούθησαν το Sir Richard Saltonstall και ο Αιδεσιμότατος 
George Phillips τέσσερα μίλια επάνω ο Charles River 
βρήκε την κοινότητα watertown τις 1630, Ιουλίου Πολλοί
είχαν επανεντοπίσει από την περιοχή ανατολικού Anglian της 
Αγγλίας, όπου William Pond, ο πατέρας του ανταποκριτή, 
έζησε. Αυτές οι οικογένειες προσπάθησαν να οργανώσουν μια 
γνωστή αγροτική οικονομία βασισμένη στο σιτάρι και το ζωικό 
κεφάλαιο, αλλά τα πρόωρα όνειρα ενός εύκολου εμπορίου με τους 
Ινδούς αποδείχθηκαν αόριστα. Οι ανησυχίες τους εστίασαν στη
σίτιση και την επίτευξη της οικονομικής επάρκειας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sobre 20.000 nómadas de Inglaterra cruzó el 
Atlántico a la nueva colonia de la bahía de Massachusetts en la 
década del 1630s. Esta afluencia repentina de colonos se sabía
a los historiadores como la "gran migración." Una vez en Nueva 
Inglaterra, se dispersaron rápidamente a las varias ciudades. 
Cerca de cuarenta familias siguieron a sir Richard Saltonstall y
millas Phillips de Reverend George las cuatro encima del río de 
Charles a encontraron a comunidad de Watertown en julio de 1630. 
Muchos habían vuelto a poner de la región del este de Anglian 
de Inglaterra, en donde charca de Guillermo, el padre del 
correspondiente, vivido. Estas familias procuraron instalar una 
economía de granja familiar basada en grano y ganado, pero los 
sueños tempranos de un comercio fácil con los indios probaron 
evasivo. Sus preocupaciones se centraron en la alimentación y 
la realización de desahogo económico.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087314</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106491</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-letter-home-from-massachusetts-bay-in-1631</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
