<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106559</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106559</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086938</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The First Freedom Ride:" Bayard Rustin On His Work With CORE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Erste Freiheit Fahrt:" Bayard Rustin 
Auf Seiner Arbeit Mit KERN</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Le Premier Tour de Liberté :" Bayard 
Rustin Sur Son Travail Avec le NOYAU</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O Primeiro Passeio Da Liberdade:" Bayard 
Rustin Em Seu Trabalho Com NÚCLEO</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Primo Giro Di Libertà:" Bayard Rustin 
Sul Suo Lavoro Con il NUCLEO</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ο πρώτος γύρος ελευθερίας:" Bayard Rustin
στην εργασία του με τον ΠΥΡΗΝΑ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"El Primer Paseo De la Libertad:" Bayard 
Rustin En Su Trabajo Con BASE</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">World War II was a period of economic and social advance for African Americans, and many who served overseas in the military, worked in defense industries, and listened to wartime propaganda about freedom became more assertive in their demands for equal rights. In 1942, Bayard Rustin, a pacifist whose expertise in non-violent protest would have a deep impact on the Civil Rights movement, helped found the Congress of Racial Equality (CORE). The group, dedicated to non-violent direct action, was one of many rights groups that came to life during and immediately after the war. In 1947 Rustin led a group of whites and blacks on a "Journey of Reconciliation" to challenge racial segregation on inter-state buses. The willingness of Rustin and his companions to undergo arrest _ at one point serving 30 days on a North Carolina chaingang _ provided an important example for the more famous Freedom Rides of 1960.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Zweite Weltkrieg war eine Periode des 
ökonomischen und Sozialfortschritts für afrikanische Amerikaner, und
viele, die übersee im Militär dienten, bearbeitet in den 
Verteidigungindustrien, und zur Kriegpropaganda über Freiheit 
gehört, wurden in ihren Nachfragen nach gleichen Rechten assertive. 
1942 Bayard Rustin, ein pacifist dessen Sachkenntnis im 
nicht-heftigen Protest eine tiefe Auswirkung auf die Zivilrechte 
Bewegung haben würde, geholfen gefunden dem Kongreß der rassischen 
Gleichheit (KERN). Die Gruppe, die zur nicht-heftigen direkten 
Tätigkeit engagiert ist, war eine vieler Rechtgruppen, deren zum 
Leben während und sofort nach dem Krieg kam. Rustin 1947 
geführt eine Gruppe Weiß und Schwarze auf einer "Reise der 
Versöhnung", zum der rassischen Abtrennung auf zwischenstaatlichen 
Bussen herauszufordern. Die Bereitwilligkeit von Rustin und von 
seinen Begleitern, Anhalten _ bei einem Punkt durchzumachen, der 30 
Tage auf einem Nord-Carolina chaingang _ dient, stellte ein wichtiges 
Beispiel für die berühmteren Freiheit Fahrten von 1960 zur 
Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La deuxième guerre mondiale était une période 
de l'avance économique et sociale pour les Américains africains, et 
beaucoup qui a servi outre-mer dans les militaires, travaillés dans 
des industries de la défense, et écoutés la propagande de temps de 
guerre au sujet de la liberté sont devenues plus autoritaires dans 
leurs demandes d'égalité des droits. En 1942, Bayard Rustin, 
un pacifiste dont l'expertise dans la protestation non-violente 
aurait un impact profond sur les droits civiques mouvement, aidé 
trouvé le congrès de l'égalité raciale (NOYAU). Le groupe, 
dédié à l'action directe non-violente, était l'un de beaucoup de 
groupes de droites pendant lesquels est venu à la vie et juste après
la guerre. En Rustin 1947 mené un groupe de blancs et de noirs 
sur un "voyage de la réconciliation" pour défier la ségrégation 
raciale sur les bus d'un état à un autre. La bonne volonté de
Rustin et de ses compagnons de subir l'arrestation _ à un point 
servant 30 jours sur un chaingang du nord de la Caroline _ a 
fourni un exemple important pour les tours plus célèbres de liberté
de 1960.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A segunda guerra mundial era um período do 
avanço econômico e social para americanos africanos, e muitas que 
serviram no ultramar nas forças armadas, trabalhadas em indústrias 
da defesa, e escutadas o propaganda do wartime sobre a liberdade 
tornaram-se mais assertive em suas demandas para direitas iguais. 
Em 1942, Bayard Rustin, um pacifist cuja a perícia no protesto 
non-violento tivesse um impacto profundo nas direitas civis movimento,
ajudado encontrado o congress da igualdade racial (NÚCLEO). O 
grupo, dedicado à ação direta non-violenta, era um de muitos grupos
das direitas que veio à vida durante e imediatamente depois da 
guerra. Em Rustin 1947 conduzido um grupo dos brancos e dos 
pretos em uma "viagem do reconciliation" para desafiar o segregation 
racial em barras-ônibus inter-state. O voluntariedade de Rustin
e de seus companheiros submeter-se à apreensão _ em um ponto que 
serve a 30 dias em um chaingang de North.carolina _ forneceu um 
exemplo importante para os passeios mais famosos da liberdade de 1960.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La seconda guerra mondiale era un periodo di 
avanzamento economico e sociale per gli Americani africani e molte che
servissero oltremare nei militari, lavorati nelle industrie della 
difesa ed ascoltati la propaganda di wartime circa la libertà sono 
diventato più assertive nelle loro domande dei diritti uguali. 
In 1942, Bayard Rustin, un pacifist di cui la perizia nella 
protesta non-violenta avrebbe un effetto profondo sui diritti civili 
movimento, aiutato trovato il congresso di uguaglianza razziale 
(NUCLEO). Il gruppo, dedicato ad azione diretta non-violenta, 
era uno di molti gruppi di diritti che è venuto a vita durante e 
subito dopo della guerra. In Rustin 1947 condotto un gruppo dei 
bianchi e dei neri "su un viaggio di riconciliazione" per sfidare 
segregazione razziale sui bus di inter-dichiarare. La compiacenza
di Rustin e dei suoi compagni subire l'arresto _ ad un punto che serve
30 giorni su un chaingang del North.carolina _ ha fornito un esempio 
importante per i giri più famosi di libertà di 1960.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο παγκόσμιος πόλεμος ΙΙ ήταν μια περίοδος οικονομικής
και κοινωνικής προόδου για αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς, και πολλές 
που εξυπηρέτησαν στο εξωτερικό στο στρατιωτικό, εργασμένος στις 
αμυντικές βιομηχανίες, και ακουσμένος την εν καιρώ πολέμου 
προπαγάνδα για την ελευθερία έγινε πιό κατηγορηματικός στις 
απαιτήσεις τους για τα ίσα δικαιώματα. Το 1942, Bayard 
Rustin, ένας ειρηνόφιλος η ο οποίος πείρα στη μη βίαια 
διαμαρτυρία θα ασκούσε βαθιά επίδραση στη μετακίνηση αστικών 
δικαιωμάτων, βοήθησε να βρεί το συνέδριο της φυλετικής ισότητας 
(ΠΥΡΗΝΑΣ). Η ομάδα, που αφιερώθηκε στη μη βίαια άμεση 
ενέργεια, ήταν μια από πολλές ομάδες δικαιωμάτων που ήρθαν στη 
ζωή κατά τη διάρκεια και αμέσως μετά από του πολέμου. Το 
1947 Rustin οδήγησε μια ομάδα λευκών και Μαύρων σε ένα 
"ταξίδι της συμφιλίωσησ" στο φυλετικό διαχωρισμό πρόκλησης στους 
διακρατικούς διαδρόμους. Η προθυμία Rustin και των 
συντρόφων του για να υποβληθεί στη σύλληψη _ σε ένα σημείο που 
εξυπηρετεί 30 ημέρες σε μια βόρεια Καρολίνα chaingang _ 
παρείχε ένα σημαντικό παράδειγμα για τους διασημότερους γύρους 
ελευθερίας του 1960.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Segunda Guerra Mundial era un período del 
avance económico y social para los americanos africanos, y muchas que
sirvieron en ultramar en los militares, trabajados en industrias de la
defensa, y escuchados la propaganda del tiempo de guerra sobre la 
libertad llegaron a ser más asertivas en sus demandas para las 
derechas iguales. En 1942, Bayard Rustin, un pacifist que 
maestría en protesta no-violenta tendría un impacto profundo en las 
derechas civiles movimiento, ayudado encontrado el congreso de la 
igualdad racial (BASE). El grupo, dedicado a la acción directa 
no-violenta, era uno de muchos grupos de las derechas durante quienes 
vino a la vida e inmediatamente después de la guerra. En Rustin
1947 conducido un grupo de blancos y de negros en un "viaje de la 
reconciliación" para desafiar la segregación racial en los megabuses
de un estado a otro. La buena voluntad de Rustin y de sus 
compañeros de experimentar la detención _ en una punta que servía 
30 días en un chaingang de Carolina del Norte _ proporcionó a un 
ejemplo importante para los paseos más famosos de la libertad de 
1960.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086938</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106559</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-first-freedom-ride-bayard-rustin-on-his-work-with-core</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
