<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108402</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108402</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086305</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Will Kill Frick": Emma Goldman Recounts the Attempt to Assassinate the Chairman of the Carnegie Steel Company During the: Homestead Strike in 1892</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ich Beende Frick": Emma Goldman zählt den 
Versuch nach, den Vorsitzenden Carnegie Steel Company zu ermorden 
während: Gehöft-Schlag 1892</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Je Détruirai Frick" : Emma Goldman raconte
la tentative d'assassiner le Président de Carnegie Steel Company 
pendant : Grève de ferme en 1892</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Eu Matarei Frick": Emma Goldman recounts a 
tentativa de assassinate o presidente do Carnegie Aço Companhia 
durante: Batida do homestead em 1892</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Ucciderò Frick": Emma Goldman racconta il 
tentativo di assassinare il presidente del Carnegie Steel Company 
durante: Colpo della fattoria in 1892</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"θα σκοτώσω Frick": Θ*Εμμα Goldman 
Recounts η προσπάθεια να δολοφονηθεί ο πρόεδρος της επιχείρησης
χάλυβα Carnegie κατά τη διάρκεια: Απεργία αγροτικών 
σπιτιών το 1892</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Mataré A Frick": Emma Goldman contó de 
nuevo la tentativa de asesinar al presidente del Carnegie Steel 
Company durante: Huelga de la granja en 1892</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Henry Clay Frick, chairman of the Carnegie Steel Company, was demonized by labor for his role in the violent Homestead strike in 1892 in which a pitched battle was fought between strikers and company-hired Pinkerton detectives. Known for his uncompromising and cruel tactics, Frick became an obvious target for labor activists looking to make a statement during the protracted strike. In this excerpt from her autobiography,  Living my Life , radical Emma Goldman described how fellow radical Alexander Berkman decided to murder Frick during the Homestead strike.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Henry-Lehm Frick, Vorsitzender Carnegie Steel 
Company, war demonized durch Arbeit für seine Rolle im heftigen 
Gehöftschlag 1892, in dem eine geworfene Schlacht zwischen 
Schlaggeräten gekämpft wurde und Firma-anstellte Pinkerton 
Detektive. Gewußt für seine kompromisslosen und grausamen 
Taktiken, wurde Frick ein offensichtliches Ziel für die 
Arbeitsaktivisten, die schauen, um eine Anweisung während des 
langwierigen Schlages abzugeben. In diesem Excerpt von ihrer 
Autobiographie, beschrieb leben meine Lebensdauer, radikales Emma 
Goldman, wie Gefährte radikaler Alexander Berkman entschied, Frick 
während des Gehöftschlages zu ermorden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'argile Frick, Président d'Henry de Carnegie 
Steel Company, était demonized par le travail pour son rôle dans la 
grève violente de ferme en 1892 l'où une bataille lancée a été 
combattue entre les butées et compagnie-a loué des détectives de 
Pinkerton. Connu pour son tactique intransigeante et cruelle, 
Frick est devenu une cible évidente pour les activistes de travail 
regardant pour faire un rapport pendant la grève prolongée. 
Dans cet extrait de son autobiographie, la vie ma vie, Emma 
radical Goldman a décrit comment le camarade Alexandre radical 
Berkman a décidé d'assassiner Frick pendant la grève de ferme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A argila Frick do Henry, presidente do Carnegie 
Aço Companhia, era demonized pelo trabalho para seu papel na batida 
violenta do homestead em 1892 em que uma batalha lançada foi lutada 
entre grevistas e companhia-empregou detetives de Pinkerton. 
Sabido para suas táticas uncompromising e cruéis, Frick 
transformou-se um alvo óbvio para as activistas labor que olham para 
fazer uma indicação durante a batida protracted. Neste excerpt
de seu autobiography, viver minha vida, Emma radical Goldman descreveu
como o companheiro Alexander radical Berkman se decidiu assassinar 
Frick durante a batida do homestead.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'argilla Frick, presidente di henry del Carnegie 
Steel Company, era demonized dal lavoro per il suo ruolo nel 
colpo violento della fattoria in 1892 in où una battaglia lanciata è
stata combattuta fra i percussori ed azienda-ha assunto i detectivi di
Pinkerton. Saputo per le sue tattiche intransigenti e crudeli, 
Frick si è transformato in in un obiettivo evidente per gli 
attivisti di lavoro che osservano per rilasciare un'istruzione 
durante il colpo prolungato. In questo brano dal suo 
autobiography, vivere la mia vita, Emma radicale Goldman ha descritto 
come il collega Alexander radicale Berkman ha deciso assassinare Frick
durante il colpo della fattoria.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Χενρυ Clay Frick, πρόεδρος της επιχείρησης 
χάλυβα Carnegie, ήταν από την εργασία για το ρόλο του στη 
βίαια απεργία αγροτικών σπιτιών το 1892 στην οποία μια 
ριγμένη μάχη πάλεψαν μεταξύ των απεργών και των 
επιχείρηση-μισθωμένων ιδιωτικών αστυνομικών Pinkerton. 
Γνωστό για την ασυμβίβαστη και σκληρή τακτική του, Frick 
έγινε ένας προφανής στόχος για τα ενεργά στελέχη εργασίας που 
κοιτάζουν για να κάνει μια δήλωση κατά τη διάρκεια της 
παρατεταμένης απεργίας. Σε αυτό το απόσπασμα από την 
αυτοβιογραφία της, που ζει η ζωή μου, η ριζική Emma Goldman 
περιέγραψε πώς ο συντροφικός ριζικός Αλέξανδρος Berkman 
αποφάσισε να δολοφονήσει Frick κατά τη διάρκεια της απεργίας 
αγροτικών σπιτιών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La arcilla Frick, presidente del Henrio del 
Carnegie Steel Company, era demonized por el trabajo para su papel en 
la huelga violenta de la granja en 1892 en el cual una batalla echada 
fue luchada entre los huelguistas y compañi'a-empleo' a detectives de
Pinkerton. Sabido para sus táctica inflexibles y crueles, Frick
se convirtió en una blanco obvia para los activistas de trabajo que 
miraban para hacer una declaración durante la huelga prolongada. 
En este extracto de su autobiografía, el vivir mi vida, Emma 
radical Goldman describió cómo el compañero Alexander radical 
Berkman decidía asesinar Frick durante la huelga de la granja.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086305</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108402</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-will-kill-frick-emma-goldman-recounts-the-attempt-to-assassinate-the-chairman-of-the-carnegie-steel-company-during-the-homestead-strike-in-1892</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
