<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107861</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107861</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087257</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"You are Like Women, Bare and Open, without any Fortifications": Hendrick Criticizes the British for Inaction at the Albany Congress, 1754</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Sie sind wie die Frauen, bloß und öffnen sich, 
ohne irgendwelche Verstärkungen": Hendrick kritisiert die 
Briten für Untätigkeit auf dem Albanien Kongreß, 1754</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"vous êtes comme des femmes, nues et ne vous 
ouvrez, sans aucune fortification" : Hendrick critique les 
Anglais pour l'inaction au congrès d'Albany, 1754</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"você é como as mulheres, desencapadas e abre, 
sem nenhuns fortifications": Hendrick critica os Ingleses para o
inaction no congress de Albany, 1754</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"siete come le donne, nude e vi aprite, senza 
alcune fortificazioni": Hendrick critica i Britannici per 
l'inerzia al congresso de Albany, 1754</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Είστε όπως τις γυναίκες, γυμνός και ανοικτός, χωρίς
οποιεσδήποτε οχυρώσεισ": Θ*Χενδρηθκ Criticizes οι Βρετανοί
για την απραξία στο συνέδριο του Αλμπανυ, 1754</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"usted es como las mujeres, descubiertas y se abre,
sin ningunos fortalecimientos": Hendrick critica a Británicos 
para la inacción en el congreso de Albany, 1754</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">When the British colonial administration called a conference in Albany in the summer of 1754, the British Empire was in the midst of great change. Britain's grip on the colonies appeared to have broken down: French troops had occupied the Ohio valley while the Indians in New York had declared the Covenant chain alliance broken. Hendrick, a Mohawk leader among the Iroquois Confederation, sought to renew diplomatic alliances between the Iroquois and the colonists. However, his speech at the meeting also criticized the British officials and colonial politicians for the weakness of their response in the face of French activities. Soon the Seven Year's War would engulf all three parties: British, colonists, and Native Americans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als die britische Kolonialleitung eine Konferenz in
Albanien am Sommer von 1754 benannte, war das britische Reich in der 
Mitte der großen Änderung. Griff Großbritanniens auf den 
Kolonien schien, unten gebrochen zu haben: Französische Truppen
hatten die Ohio Senke besetzt, während die Inder in New York das 
gebrochene Vereinbarungkette Bündnis erklärt hatten. Hendrick,
ein mohikanischer Führer unter dem Irokese-Bündnis, gesucht, um 
diplomatische Bündnisse zwischen dem Irokesen und den Kolonisten zu 
erneuern. Jedoch kritisierte seine Rede bei der Sitzung auch die
britischen Beamten und die Kolonialpolitiker für die Schwäche ihrer 
Antwort angesichts der französischen Aktivitäten. Bald würde 
der sieben Krieg des Jahres alle drei Parteien versenken: 
Briten, Kolonisten und gebürtige Amerikaner.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quand la gestion coloniale britannique a appelé 
une conférence à Albany en été de 1754, l'empire britannique 
était au milieu du grand changement. La poignée de la 
Grande-Bretagne sur les colonies a semblé avoir décomposé : 
Les troupes françaises avaient occupé la vallée de l'Ohio 
tandis que les Indiens à New York avaient déclaré l'alliance de 
chaîne d'engagement cassée. Hendrick, une amorce mohicanne 
parmi la confédération de Iroquois, recherchée pour remplacer des 
alliances diplomatiques entre le Iroquois et les colons. 
Cependant, son discours lors de la réunion a également 
critiqué les fonctionnaires britanniques et les politiciens coloniaux
pour la faiblesse de leur réponse face aux activités françaises. 
Bientôt des sept la guerre ans engloutirait chacune des trois 
parties : Les Anglais, colons, et Américains indigènes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando a administração colonial britânica chamou
uma conferência em Albany no verão de 1754, o império britânico 
estava no meio da mudança grande. O aperto de Grâ Bretanha nas
colônias pareceu ter quebrado para baixo: As tropas francesas 
tinham ocupado o vale de Ohio quando os indians em New York tinham 
declarado o alliance da corrente do convénio quebrado. 
Hendrick, um líder mohawk entre o confederation do iroquois, 
procurado renovar alliances diplomatic entre o iroquois e os colonos. 
Entretanto, seu discurso na reunião criticou também os 
oficiais britânicos e os políticos coloniais para a fraqueza de sua 
resposta na cara de atividades francesas. Logo a guerra dos sete
anos engulf todos os três partidos: Ingleses, colonos, e 
americanos nativos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quando la gestione coloniale britannica ha chiamato
un congresso a Albany di estate di 1754, l'impero britannico era 
cambiamento in mezzo a grande. La presa della Gran-Bretagna 
sulle colonie è sembrato analizzare: Le truppe francesi avevano
occupato la valle dell'Ohio mentre gli indiani a New York avevano 
dichiarato l'alleanza della catena del patto rotta. Hendrick, un
capo mohawk fra la confederazione del iroquois, cercata per 
rinnovare le alleanze diplomatiche fra il iroquois ed i colonizzatori.
Tuttavia, il suo discorso alla riunione egualmente ha criticato 
i funzionari britannici ed i politici coloniali per la debolezza della
loro risposta di fronte alle attività francesi. Presto la 
guerra dei sette anni inghiottirebbe tutti e tre i partiti: 
Britannici, colonizzatori ed Americani natali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Όταν η βρετανική αποικιακή κυβέρνηση κάλεσε μια 
διάσκεψη στο Αλμπανυ το καλοκαίρι 1754, η βρετανική 
αυτοκρατορία ήταν στη μέση της μεγάλης αλλαγής. Το πιάσιμο
της Μεγάλης Βρετανίας στις αποικίες εμφανίστηκε να χωρίζει: 
Τα γαλλικά στρατεύματα είχαν καταλάβει την κοιλάδα του 
Οχάιου ενώ οι Ινδοί στη Νέα Υόρκη είχαν κηρύξει τη συμμαχία 
αλυσίδων συμβολαίων σπασμένη. Ο Hendrick, ένας ηγέτης 
Mohawk μεταξύ της iroquois συνομοσπονδίας, επιδίωξε να 
ανανεώσει τις διπλωματικές συμμαχίες μεταξύ iroquois και των 
αποίκων. Εντούτοις, η ομιλία του στη συνεδρίαση επέκρινε 
επίσης τους βρετανικούς ανώτερους υπαλλήλους και τους αποικιακούς
πολιτικούς για την αδυναμία της απάντησής τους παρά τις γαλλικές
δραστηριότητες. Σύντομα ο επτά πόλεμος του έτους θα 
κατάπινε και τα τρία συμβαλλόμενα μέρη: Βρετανοί, άποικοι,
και εγγενείς Αμερικανοί.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuando la administración colonial británica 
llamó una conferencia en Albany en el verano de 1754, el imperio 
británico estaba en el medio del gran cambio. El apretón de 
Gran Bretaña en las colonias aparecía haber analizado: Las 
tropas francesas habían ocupado el valle de Ohio mientras que los 
indios en Nueva York habían declarado la alianza del encadenamiento 
del convenio rota. Hendrick, arranque de cinta mohawk entre la 
confederación del iroquois, intentada para renovar alianzas 
diplomáticas entre el iroquois y los colonos. Sin embargo, su 
discurso en la reunión también criticó a los funcionarios 
británicos y a políticos coloniales para la debilidad de su 
respuesta en la cara de actividades francesas. Pronto la guerra 
de los siete años engulliría los tres partidos: Británicos, 
colonos, y americanos nativos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087257</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107861</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/you-are-like-women-bare-and-open-without-any-fortifications-hendrick-criticizes-the-british-for-inaction-at-the-albany-congress-1754</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
