<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107922</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107922</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201681</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Faults</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Störungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Défauts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Falhas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Difetti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βλάβες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Incidentes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site, which accompanies an introductory structural geology class at the University of Leeds, UK, contains information on faults. Topics include normal faults, thrust faults, strike-slip faults, faults and stress, and soft-linked fault systems. The site features explanations of the three basic types of faults with informative diagrams and a photo gallery.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site, die eine einleitende strukturelle 
Geologiekategorie an der Universität von Leeds begleitet, 
Großbritannien, enthält Informationen über Störungen. Themen
schließen normale Störungen ein, stoßen Störungen, 
anschlagen-gleiten Störungen, Störungen und Druck und 
weich-gebundene Störung Systeme. Die 
Situationsmerkmalerklärungen der drei grundlegenden Typen der 
Störungen mit informativen Diagrammen und einer Fotogalerie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site, qui accompagne une classe structurale 
préliminaire de géologie à l'université de Leeds, le R-U, contient
l'information sur des défauts. Les sujets incluent les défauts
normaux, poussent des défauts, frapper-glissent des défauts, des 
défauts et effort, et des systèmes doux-joints de défaut. Les
explications de dispositifs de site des trois types de base de 
défauts avec des diagrammes instructifs et une galerie de photo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local, que acompanha uma classe estrutural 
introdutória da geologia na universidade de Leeds, Reino Unido, 
contem a informação em falhas. Os tópicos incluem falhas 
normais, empurram falhas, golpe-deslizam falhas, falhas e stress, e 
sistemas macio-ligados da falha. As explanações das 
características de local dos três tipos básicos de falhas com 
diagramas informative e uma galeria da foto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo, che accompagna un codice categoria 
strutturale introduttivo di geologia all'università di Leeds, il 
Regno Unito, contiene le informazioni sui difetti. I soggetti 
includono i difetti normali, spingono i difetti, colpire-slittano i 
difetti, difetti e sforzo e sistemi morbido-collegati del difetto. 
Le spiegazioni delle caratteristiche di luogo dei tre tipi di 
base di difetti con gli schemi informativi e una galleria della foto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή, που συνοδεύει μια εισαγωγική δομική 
κλάση γεωλογίας στο πανεπιστήμιο του Λιντς, UK, περιέχει τις 
πληροφορίες για τις βλάβες. Τα θέματα περιλαμβάνουν τις 
κανονικές βλάβες, τις βλάβες ώθησης, τις βλάβες 
απεργία-ολίσθησης, τις βλάβες και την πίεση, και τα 
μαλακός-συνδεμένα συστήματα βλαβών. Η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει
τις εξηγήσεις των τριών βασικών τύπων βλαβών με τα πληροφοριακά 
διαγράμματα και μια στοά φωτογραφιών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio, que acompaña una clase estructural 
introductoria de la geología en la universidad de Leeds, Reino Unido,
contiene la información sobre incidentes. Los asuntos incluyen 
incidentes normales, empujan incidentes, pulso-deslizan 
incidentes, los incidentes y tensión, y los sistemas suave-conectados
del incidente. Las explicaciones de las características de 
sitio de los tres tipos básicos de incidentes con diagramas 
informativos y una galería de la foto.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201681</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107922</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/faults</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
