<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105688</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105688</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211220</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Nanobacteria: Are They or Aren't They Alive?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nanobacteria: Sind sie, oder nicht sind sie 
lebendig?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nanobacteria : Sont-elles ou ne sont-elles 
pas vivantes ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nanobacteria: São ou não estão viva?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nanobacteria: Sono o non sono vive?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Nanobacteria: Είναι ή δεν είναι αυτοί 
ζωντανοί;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Nanobacteria: ¿Son o no están vivas?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This California State University lesson plan contains materials for a five-part activity regarding whether or not nanobacteria are alive. The case-study based activities include: What does it mean to be alive?; What evidence is there that nanobacteria are alive?; More evidence of life; Corroborating evidence (?); and The final chapter (or is it?). The website contains pertinent general information articles and resource lists for students as well as homework assignments based on readings. An answer key is provided, but may require registration to the Case Study in Science Program.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Kalifornien Landesuniversität-Lektionplan enthält
Materialien für eine fünfteilige Aktivität betreffend ist, ob oder 
nicht nanobacteria lebendig sind. Schachtel-studieren Sie 
gegründete Aktivitäten einschließen: Was es bedeutet, 
lebendig zu sein?; Welcher Beweis dort dieses nanobacteria ist, 
seien Sie? lebendig; Mehr Beweis des Lebens; Beweis (?); 
und das abschließende Kapitel (oder bekräftigt es?). Die Web 
site enthält passende allgemeine Informationen Artikel und 
Hilfsmittellisten für Kursteilnehmer sowie die Heimarbeit 
Anweisungen, die auf Messwerten basieren. Eine Antworttaste wird
zur Verfügung gestellt, aber kann Registrierung zur Fallstudie im 
Wissenschaft Programm benötigen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce plan de leçon d'université de l'Etat de la Californie
contient des matériaux pour une activité de cinq parties concernant 
si le nanobacteria sont vivant. Cas-étudiez les activités 
basées incluent : Ce qui il signifie pour être vivant ? ; 
Quelle évidence est là ce nanobacteria soyez vivant ? ; 
Plus d'évidence de la vie ; Évidence corrobore (?) ; et 
le chapitre final (ou il ?). Le site Web contient les articles 
d'informations générales et les listes convenables de ressource pour
des étudiants aussi bien que des affectations de travail basées sur 
des lectures. Une clé de réponse est fournie, mais peut exiger
l'enregistrement à l'étude de cas dans le programme de la Science.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta planta da lição da universidade de estado de 
Califórnia contem materiais para uma atividade five-part a respeito 
de se ou não o nanobacteria está vivo. Caixa-estude atividades
baseadas incluem: O que ele significa estar vivo?; Que 
evidência está lá esse nanobacteria esteja vivo?; Mais 
evidência da vida; Evidência corroborating (?); e o capítulo 
final (ou?). O Web site contem artigos da informação geral e 
listas pertinentes do recurso para estudantes as.well.as as 
atribuições do homework baseadas em leituras. Uma chave da 
resposta é fornecida, mas pode reque o registo ao estudo de caso no 
programa da ciência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa California Dichiara il programma di lezione 
dell'università contiene i materiali per un'attività five-part per 
quanto riguarda se o non il nanobacteria è vivo. 
Contenitore-studi le attività basate includono: Che cosa 
esso significa essere vivo?; Che prova è là quel nanobacteria 
sia vivo?; Più prova di vita; Prova sta confermando (?); 
ed il capitolo finale (o?). Il Web site contiene gli articoli di
generalità e le liste pertinenti delle risorse per gli allievi così 
come le assegnazioni di lavoro basate sulle letture. Un tasto di
risposta è fornito, ma può richiedere il registro all'inchiesta nel 
programma di scienza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το σχέδιο μαθήματος κρατικού πανεπιστημίου 
Καλιφόρνιας περιέχει τα υλικά για μια δραστηριότητα πέντε-μερών 
σχετικά με εάν το nanobacteria είναι ή όχι ζωντανό. Οι 
βασισμένες στην περιπτωσιολογία δραστηριότητες περιλαμβάνουν: 
Αυτό που αυτό σημαίνει να είναι ζωντανό;  Ποια 
στοιχεία είναι εκεί ότι το nanobacteria είναι ζωντανό;  
Περισσότερα στοιχεία της ζωής  Επιβεβαιώνοντας 
στοιχεία (?) και το τελευταίο κεφάλαιο (ή είναι αυτό;). 
Ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει τα σχετικούς άρθρα γενικών 
πληροφοριών και τους καταλόγους των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς για 
τους σπουδαστές καθώς επίσης και τις αναθέσεις εργασίας 
βασισμένους στις αναγνώσεις. Ένα πλήκτρο απάντησης 
παρέχεται, αλλά μπορεί να απαιτήσει την εγγραφή στην 
περιπτωσιολογική μελέτη στο πρόγραμμα επιστήμης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este plan de la lección de la universidad de estado de 
California contiene los materiales para una actividad five-part en 
relac'ion con a si o no el nanobacteria está vivo. Caso-estudie
las actividades basadas incluyen: Qué él significa estar 
vivo?; Qué evidencia está allí ese nanobacteria esté vivo?; 
Más evidencia de la vida; Evidencia está corroborando 
(?); y el capítulo final (o?). El Web site contiene los 
artículos de la información de carácter general y las listas 
pertinentes del recurso para los estudiantes así como las 
asignaciones de la preparación basadas en lecturas. Un clave de
la respuesta se proporciona, pero puede requerir el registro al 
estudio de caso en programa de la ciencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:MERRI LYNN CASEM
FN:MERRI LYNN CASEM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NATIONAL CENTER FOR CASE STUDY TEACHING IN SCIENCE
FN:NATIONAL CENTER FOR CASE STUDY TEACHING IN SCIENCE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211220</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105688</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nanobacteria-are-they-or-arent-they-alive</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
