<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104899</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104899</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086873</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Sweatshop.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fabrik mit schlechten Arbeitsbedingungen.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bagne.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sweatshop.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Azienda che sfrutta la manodopera.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σκλαβοπάζαρο.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fábrica de explotación.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the 1970s and 1980s, Asian and Latino immigrants flocked to the United States, rivaling in sheer numbers the trans-Atlantic immigration of a century earlier. Many came because even minimum wage work in the United States paid five to ten times more than they could earn in their homelands. These Asian workers, photographed in 1991 as they labored in a garment shop in lower Manhattan, typified the work experience of many immigrants: monotonous, low wage work in conditions reminiscent of clothing industry sweatshops from earlier in the twentieth century.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den siebziger Jahren und in den achtziger Jahren 
scharten sich Asiat- und Latinoimmigranten in die Vereinigten Staaten 
und früh rivalisierten in den blossen Zahlen mit der trans-Atlantic 
Immigration von ein Jahrhundert. Viele kamen, weil 
gleichmäßige Arbeit des minimalen Lohnes in den Vereinigten Staaten 
fünf bis 10mal mehr zahlte, als sie konnten in ihren Heimaten 
erwerben. Diese asiatischen Arbeiter, fotografiert in 1991, wie 
sie in einem Kleidsystem in untererem Manhattan bearbeiteten, 
verkörpert der Arbeit Erfahrung vieler Immigranten: monotone, 
niedrige Lohnarbeit in den Bedingungen erinnernd von den 
Bekleidungsindustriefabriken mit schlechten Arbeitsbedingungen früh 
innen vom zwanzigsten Jahrhundert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans les années 70 et les années 80, l'Asiatique et les 
immigrés de Latino se sont assemblés aux Etats-Unis, rivalisant
dans des nombres fins l'immigration transatlantique un siècle de plus
tôt. Beaucoup sont venus parce que le même travail de salaire 
minimum aux Etats-Unis a payé cinq à dix fois plus qu'elles 
pourraient gagner dans leurs patries. Ces ouvriers asiatiques, 
photographiés dans 1991 comme ils ont travaillé dans un système de 
vêtement à Manhattan inférieure, caractérisé l'expérience 
professionnelle de beaucoup d'immigrés : travail monotone et 
bas de salaire en conditions réminiscentes des bagnes d'industrie de 
la confection plus tôt dedans du vingtième siècle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nos 1970s e nos 1980s, os immigrants do asian e do Latino 
reuniram-se aos estados unidos, rivalizando em números sheer o 
immigration trans-Atlantic um século de mais cedo. Muitos 
vieram porque o trabalho uniforme do salário mínimo nos estados 
unidos pagou cinco a dez vezes mais do que eles poderiam ganhar em 
seus homelands. Estes trabalhadores asian, fotografados em 1991 
como trabalharam em uma loja do garment em um Manhattan mais baixo, 
typified a experiência de trabalho de muitos immigrants: 
trabalho monotonous, baixo do salário nas circunstâncias 
reminiscent de sweatshops da indústria de roupa mais cedo dentro do 
vigésimo século.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Negli anni 70 e negli anni 80, gli immigranti di Latino e 
dell'asiatico affollati al unito Dichiara, rivaleggiando con 
nei numeri puri l'immigrazione transatlantica un secolo di più 
presto. Molti sono venuto perché il persino lavoro dello 
stipendio minimo in unito Dichiara cinque - dieci volte paid 
più di potrebbero guadagnare nelle loro patrie. Questi 
operai asiatici, fotografati in 1991 come hanno lavorato in un negozio
dell'indumento a Manhattan più basso, caratterizzato l'esperienza di 
lavoro in molti immigranti: lavoro monotono e basso dello 
stipendio nelle circostanze rievocative delle azienda che sfrutta la 
manodopera di industria del abbigliamento più presto dentro dal 
ventesimo secolo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη δεκαετία του '70 και τη δεκαετία του '80, τους 
ασιατικούς και λατίνους μετανάστες που συγκεντρώνονται στις 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες, που συναγωνίζονται στους καθαρούς αριθμούς 
υπερατλαντική μετανάστευση ενός αιώνα νωρίτερα. Πολλοί 
ήρθαν επειδή ακόμη και η εργασία βασικών μισθών στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες πλήρωσε πέντε έως δέκα φορές περισσότερο από θα 
μπορούσαν κερδίζω στις πατρίδες τους. Αυτοί οι ασιατικοί 
εργαζόμενοι, που φωτογραφίστηκαν το 1991 όπως εργάστηκαν σε 
ένα κατάστημα ενδυμάτων στο χαμηλότερο Μανχάτταν, απεικόνισαν 
την επαγγελματική εμπειρία πολλών μεταναστών: μονότονη, 
χαμηλόμισθη εργασία στις συνθήκες ενθυμίζουσες των σκλαβοπάζαρο
βιομηχανίας ιματισμού από νωρίτερα στον εικοστό αιώνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los años 70 y los años 80, los inmigrantes del 
asiático y de Latino se reunieron a los Estados Unidos, rivalizando 
en números escarpados la inmigración transatlántica un siglo de 
anterior. Muchos vinieron porque el trabajo uniforme del salario
mínimo en los Estados Unidos pagó cinco a diez veces más que ellos 
podrían ganar en sus patrias. Estos trabajadores asiáticos, 
fotografiados en 1991 como trabajaron en un departamento de la ropa en
Manhattan más baja, caracterizado la experiencia profesional de 
muchos inmigrantes: trabajo monótono, bajo del salario en las 
condiciones evocadoras de fábricas de explotación de la industria de
la confección a partir anterior adentro del vigésimo siglo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086873</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104899</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/sweatshop</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
