<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/27890</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>27890</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
    <entry>skolverket_8256</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_8256</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_8256</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">SP.784 Wheelchair Design in Developing Countries, Spring 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Design des Rollstuhl-SP.784 in 
Entwicklungsländern, Frühling 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Conception du fauteuil roulant SP.784 dans les 
pays en voie de développement, le printemps 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Projeto em países tornando-se, mola 2007 do 
wheelchair SP.784 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Disegno in pæsi in via di sviluppo, primavera 2007
(MIT) della sedia a rotelle SP.784</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">SP.784 σχέδιο αναπηρικών καρεκλών στις 
αναπτυσσόμενες χώρες, άνοιξη του 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Diseño en países en vías de desarrollo, resorte
2007 (MIT) del sillón de ruedas SP.784</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An online course from the MIT OpenCourseWare website (http://ocw.mit.edu) operated by Massachusetts Institute of Technology. This course material is free for anyone to use who accept the terms and conditions of use. The description of this course, published on the MIT OpenCourseWare website, is: "This class will give students the chance to better the lives of others by improving wheelchairs and tricycles made in the developing world. According to the United States Agency for International Development, 20 million people in developing countries require wheelchairs, and the United Nations Development Programme estimates below 1% of the need in Africa is being met by local production. Lectures will focus on understanding local factors, such as operating environments, social stigmas against the disabled, and manufacturing constraints, then applying sound scientific/engineering knowledge to develop appropriate technical solutions. Multidisciplinary student teams will conduct term-long projects on topics such as hardware design, manufacturing optimization, biomechanics modeling, and business plan development. Theory will further be connected to real-world implementation during guest lectures by MIT faculty, Third World community partners, and U.S. wheelchair organizations. Funded summer fellowships to implement class projects into African wheelchair workshops will be offered to at least six students.  This class is made possible by an MIT Alumni Sponsored Funding Opportunities grant with additional support from the MIT Public Service Center and the Edgerton Center. "</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Special Programs</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Onlinekurs von der MIT OpenCourseWare Web site
(http://ocw.mit.edu) funktionierte durch Massachusetts Institute of 
Technology. Dieses Kursmaterial ist frei, damit jedermann 
verwendet, wem die Bedingungen des Gebrauches annehmen. Die 
Beschreibung dieses Kurses, veröffentlicht auf der MIT OpenCourseWare
Web site, ist: "diese Kategorie gibt Kursteilnehmern die 
Wahrscheinlichkeit, die Lebensdauern von anderen zu verbessern, indem 
sie die Rollstühle und Dreiräder verbessert, die in der sich 
entwickelnden Welt gebildet werden. Entsprechend der Vereinigte 
Staaten Agentur für internationale Entwicklung, benötigen 20 Million
Leute in Entwicklungsländern Rollstühle, und die Nationen 
Entwicklungsprogrammschätzungen unter 1% der Notwendigkeit in Afrika 
wird durch lokale Produktion getroffen. Vorträge konzentrieren 
auf das Verstehen der lokalen Faktoren, wie Betriebsumgebungen, der 
SozialSchanden gegen die untauglichen und herstellenbegrenzungen
und dann wenden stichhaltiges wissenschaftlich/technisches Wissen an, 
um passende technische Lösungen zu entwickeln. 
Multidisziplinäre Kursteilnehmerteams leiten Bezeichnung-lange 
Projekte auf Themen wie Hardwaredesign, herstellenoptimierung, die 
formende und Unternehmensplanentwicklung Biomechanik. Theorie 
wird weiter an realistische Implementierung während der Gastvorträge
durch Partner der MIT Lehrkörpers, der dritte Weltgemeinschaft und 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Rollstuhl Organisationen angeschlossen. Die 
finanzierten Sommerstipenien, zum von von Kategorie Projekten in 
afrikanische Rollstuhlwerkstätten einzuführen werden mindestens 
sechs Kursteilnehmern angeboten. Diese Kategorie wird durch eine
MIT Schüler geförderte finanzierengelegenheiten Bewilligung mit 
zusätzlichem Support von der MIT allgemeiner Service-Mitte und von 
der Edgerton Mitte "ermöglicht</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un cours en ligne du site Web de MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) a fonctionné par 
massachusetts.institute.of.technology. Ce matériel de cours est
libre pour que n'importe qui utilise qui reçoivent les modalités et 
les conditions de l'utilisation. La description de ce cours, 
éditée sur le site Web de MIT OpenCourseWare, est : "cette 
classe donnera à des étudiants la chance d'améliorer les vies de 
d'autres en améliorant des fauteuils roulants et des tricycles faits 
dans le monde en voie de développement. Selon l'agence des 
Etats-Unis pour le développement international, 20 millions de 
personnes dans les pays en voie de développement ont besoin des 
fauteuils roulants, et les évaluations de Programme des Nations Unies
pour le développement En-dessous de 1% du besoin en Afrique est 
rencontrées par production locale. Les conférences se 
concentreront sur des facteurs locaux d'arrangement, tels que des 
environnements de fonctionnement, des stigmates sociaux contre les 
contraintes handicapées et et fabriquantes, appliquant alors la 
connaissance scientifique/technique saine pour développer les 
solutions techniques appropriées. Les équipes 
multidisciplinaires d'étudiant conduiront de limite-longs projets sur
des sujets tels que la conception de matériel, l'optimisation de 
fabrication, modeler de biomécanique, et le développement de plan 
d'affaires. La théorie sera plus loin reliée à la mise en 
place réelle pendant les conférences d'invité des organismes par 
les associés de corps enseignant de MIT, de communauté du tiers 
monde, et des ETATS-UNIS fauteuil roulant. Des camaraderies 
placées d'été pour mettre en application des projets de classe dans
les ateliers africains de fauteuil roulant seront offertes à à 
moindres six étudiants. Cette classe est rendue possible par 
une concession de placement d'occasions commanditée par anciennes 
élèves de MIT avec le support supplémentaire à partir du centre de
service public de MIT et du centre d'Edgerton "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um curso em linha do Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) operou-se por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material do curso está livre
para que qualquer um use-se quem aceitam os termos e as condições do
uso. A descrição deste curso, publicada no Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare, é: "esta classe dará a estudantes a 
possibilidade melhorar as vidas de outras melhorando os wheelchairs e 
os triciclos feitos no mundo tornando-se. De acordo com a 
agência unida dos estados para o desenvolvimento internacional, 20 
milhão povos em países tornando-se requerem wheelchairs, e as 
estimativas unidas do programa de desenvolvimento das nações abaixo 
de 1% da necessidade em África estão sendo encontradas com pela 
produção local. Os lectures focalizarão em compreender 
fatores locais, tais como ambientes operando-se, os stigmas sociais de
encontro aos confinamentes disabled, e manufaturando, aplicando então
o conhecimento scientific/engineering sadio para desenvolver 
soluções técnicas apropriadas. As equipes multidisciplinary 
do estudante conduzirão projetos termo-longos em tópicos tais como o
projeto da ferragem, o optimization manufaturando, modelar do 
biomechanics, e o desenvolvimento da planta de negócio. A 
teoria será conectada mais mais à execução real-world durante 
lectures do convidado por sócios da faculdade de MIT, da comunidade 
do terceiro mundo, e de wheelchair de ESTADOS UNIDOS organizações. 
Os fellowships financiados do verão para executar projetos da 
classe em oficinas africanas do wheelchair serão oferecidos ao menos 
a seis estudantes. Esta classe é feita possível por uma 
concessão financiando patrocinada alunos das oportunidades do MIT com
sustentação adicional do centro de serviço público do MIT e do 
centro de Edgerton "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un corso in linea dal Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) ha funzionato da Massachusetts 
Institute of Technology. Questo materiale di corso è libero 
affinchè chiunque usi chi accettano i termini e le condizioni di uso.
La descrizione di questo corso, pubblicata sul Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare, è: "questo codice categoria darà ad allievi la
probabilità migliorare le durate di altre migliorando le sedie a 
rotelle ed i tricicli fatti nel mondo di sviluppo. Secondo unito
Dichiara l'agenzia per sviluppo internazionale, 20 milione di 
persone in pæsi in via di sviluppo richiedono le sedie a rotelle e le 
valutazioni di programma di sviluppo di Nazioni Unite inferiore a 1% 
del bisogno in Africa sta venenda a contatto di da produzione locale. 
Le conferenze metteranno a fuoco sul capire i fattori locali, 
quali le condizioni di funzionamento, gli stigmas sociali contro i 
vincoli disabled e e di produzioni, allora applicanti la conoscenza 
scientifica/d'ingegneria sana per sviluppare le soluzioni tecniche 
adatte. Le squadre pluridisciplinari dell'allievo condurranno i 
progetti termine-lunghi sui soggetti quali il disegno del hardware, 
l'ottimizzazione di produzione, la modellistica di biomeccanica e lo 
sviluppo di programma di affari. La teoria più ulteriormente 
sarà collegata all'implementazione nell'ambiente durante le 
conferenze dell'ospite dai soci della facoltà del MIT, della 
Comunità del terzo mondo ed organizzazioni dalla sedia a rotelle 
degli STATI UNITI. I fellowships costituiti un fondo per di 
estate per effettuare i progetti del codice categoria nei workshop 
africani della sedia a rotelle saranno offerti almeno a sei allievi. 
Questo codice categoria è permesso da una concessione 
costituente un fondo per di occasioni patrocinata alunni del MIT con 
supporto supplementare dal centro di servizio pubblico del MIT e dal 
centro di Edgerton "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρά μαθημάτων από τον 
ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) που 
χρησιμοποιείται από το ίδρυμα της Μασαχουσέτης τεχνολογίας. 
Αυτό το υλικό σειράς μαθημάτων είναι ελεύθερο για καθένα 
να χρησιμοποιήσει ποιοι αποδέχονται τους όρους και τους όρους 
χρησιμοποίησης. Η περιγραφή αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων, που
δημοσιεύεται στον ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare, είναι: 
"Αυτή η κλάση θα δώσει στους σπουδαστές την πιθανότητα 
καλύτερα οι ζωές άλλες με τη βελτίωση των αναπηρικών καρεκλών 
και των τρίκυκλων που γίνονται στον αναπτυσσόμενο κόσμο. 
Σύμφωνα με την Ηνωμένη αντιπροσωπεία για τη διεθνή 
ανάπτυξη, 20 εκατομμύριο άνθρωποι στις αναπτυσσόμενες χώρες 
απαιτούν τις αναπηρικές καρέκλες, και οι εκτιμήσεις προγράμματος 
ανάπτυξης Ηνωμένων Εθνών κάτω από 1% της ανάγκης στην Αφρική
καλύπτομαι από την τοπική παραγωγή. Οι διαλέξεις θα 
εστιάσουν στην κατανόηση των τοπικών παραγόντων, όπως τα 
λειτουργικά περιβάλλοντα, κοινωνικά στίγματα ενάντια στα άτομα 
με ειδικές ανάγκες, και περιορισμοί κατασκευής, κατόπιν 
εφαρμόζοντας την καλή επιστημονική/γνώση εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής 
να αναπτύξουν τις κατάλληλες τεχνικές λύσεις. Οι πολλαπλών 
ειδικοτήτων ομάδες σπουδαστών θα διευθύνουν τα όρος-μακριά 
προγράμματα για τα θέματα όπως το σχέδιο υλικού, η 
βελτιστοποίηση κατασκευής, η διαμόρφωση βιομηχανικής, και η 
ανάπτυξη επιχειρησιακών σχεδίων. Η θεωρία θα συνδεθεί 
περαιτέρω με την πραγματική εφαρμογή κατά τη διάρκεια των 
διαλέξεων φιλοξενουμένων με MIT την ικανότητα, τους κοινοτικούς
συνεργάτες τρίτων κόσμων, και τις οργανώσεις ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΩΝ 
αναπηρικών καρεκλών. Οι χρηματοδοτημένες θερινές υποτροφίες
για να εφαρμόσουν τα προγράμματα κλάσης στα αφρικανικά εργαστήρια
αναπηρικών καρεκλών θα προσφερθούν σε τουλάχιστον έξι 
σπουδαστές. Αυτή η κλάση πραγματοποιείται από μια 
υποστηριγμένη απόφοιτοι κολλεγίου επιχορήγηση ευκαιριών 
χρηματοδότησης MIT με την πρόσθετη υποστήριξη από το κέντρο 
δημόσιων υπηρεσιών MIT και το κέντρο Edgerton. 
"</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un curso en línea del Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) funcionó por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material del curso está 
libre para que cualquier persona utilice quiénes validan los 
términos y las condiciones del uso. La descripción de este 
curso, publicada en el Web site del MIT OpenCourseWare, es: 
"esta clase dará a estudiantes la ocasión de mejorar las vidas
de otras mejorando los sillones de ruedas y los triciclos hechos en el
mundo que se convierte. Según la agencia de Estados Unidos para
el desarrollo internacional, 20 millones de personas de en países en 
vías de desarrollo requieren los sillones de ruedas, y las 
estimaciones del programa de desarrollo de Naciones Unidas debajo del 
1% de la necesidad en África están siendo resueltas por la 
producción local. Las conferencias se centrarán en entender 
factores locales, tales como ambientes de funcionamiento, los estigmas
sociales contra los apremios lisiados, y de fabricaciones, entonces 
aplicando conocimiento científico y de ingeniería sano para 
desarrollar soluciones técnicas apropiadas. Los equipos 
multidisciplinarios del estudiante conducirán proyectos 
te'rmino-largos sobre asuntos tales como diseño de la dotación 
física, optimización de fabricación, modelar de la biomecánica, y 
desarrollo del plan de negocio. La teoría será conectada más 
lejos con la puesta en práctica del mundo real durante conferencias 
de la huésped por los socios de la facultad de MIT, de la comunidad 
del tercer mundo, y las organizaciones del sillón de ruedas de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS. Las becas financiadas del verano para poner 
proyectos de la clase en ejecucio'n en talleres africanos del sillón 
de ruedas serán ofrecidas por lo menos a seis estudiantes. Esta
clase es hecha posible por una concesión de financiamiento 
patrocinada los alumnos de las oportunidades del MIT con la ayuda 
adicional del centro de servicio público del MIT y del centro de 
Edgerton "</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spezielle Programme</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Programmes Spéciaux</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Programas Especiais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Programmi Speciali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ειδικά προγράμματα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Programas Especiales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>587</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">higher education</string>
                <string language="sv">högre utbildning</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_8256-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_8256-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-03-15T20:00:00.0Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
N:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
ORG:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T06:17:20.30Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
      <entry>skolverket_8256</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://ocw.mit.edu/OcwWeb/Special-Programs/SP-784Spring-2007/CourseHome/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
