<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/26487</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>26487</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
    <entry>skolverket_8025</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_8025</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_8025</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">STS.069 Technology in a  Dangerous World, Fall 2002 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">STS.069 Technologie in einer gefährlichen Welt, 
Fall 2002 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">STS.069 technologie dans un monde dangereux, 
automne 2002 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">STS.069 tecnologia em um mundo perigoso, queda 
2002 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">STS.069 tecnologia in un mondo pericoloso, caduta 
2002 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">STS.069 τεχνολογία σε έναν επικίνδυνο κόσμο, 
πτώση του 2002 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">STS.069 tecnología en un mundo peligroso, caída 
2002 (MIT)</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An online course from the MIT OpenCourseWare website (http://ocw.mit.edu) operated by Massachusetts Institute of Technology. This course material is free for anyone to use who accept the terms and conditions of use. The description of this course, published on the MIT OpenCourseWare website, is: "Aim is to analyze important current events for what they reveal about the nature and working of our technological world. Starting point is connection between technology and terrorism. Subject also explores how a human-built world can foster insecurity and danger, and how human beings respond. Many invited guests help develop a strong interdisciplinary approach (science, engineering, social science, humanities). Topics include technological risk and remediation, sociotechnical systems, imagination of disaster, technology and identity, technology and religion, technology and education, and technology and trust. Written and oral assignments and a final project required. Service-learning proposals and web-based presentations, in addition to written work, may be considered for the final project by the instructor."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science  Technology  and Society</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">religion</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">remediation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">identity</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">terrorism</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">sociotechnical systems</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">danger</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">technological risk</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">current events</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">imagination of disaster</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">education</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science  Technology and Society.</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Onlinekurs von der MIT OpenCourseWare Web site
(http://ocw.mit.edu) funktionierte durch Massachusetts Institute of 
Technology. Dieses Kursmaterial ist frei, damit jedermann 
verwendet, wem die Bedingungen des Gebrauches annehmen. Die 
Beschreibung dieses Kurses, veröffentlicht auf der MIT OpenCourseWare
Web site, ist: "Ziel ist, zu analysieren wichtige aktuelle 
Fälle für, was sie über die Natur und das Arbeiten unserer 
technologischen Welt aufdecken. Ausgangspunkt ist Anschluß 
zwischen Technologie und Terrorismus. Thema erforscht auch, wie 
eine menschlich-aufgebaute Welt Unsicherheit und Gefahr fördern kann 
und wie Menschen reagieren. Viele eingeladene Gäste helfen, 
eine starke interdisziplinäre Annäherung (Wissenschaft, Technik, 
Sozialwissenschaft, Menschlichkeit) zu entwickeln. Themen 
schließen technologische Gefahr und Remediation, sociotechnical 
Systeme, Phantasie des Unfalles, Technologie und Identität, 
Technologie und Religion, Technologie und Ausbildung und Technologie 
und Vertrauen ein. Geschriebene und Mundanweisungen und 
abschließendes ein Projekt benötigt. Service-erlernenanträge 
und Web-gegründete Darstellungen, zusätzlich zu schriftlicher 
Arbeit, können für das abschließende Projekt vom Ausbilder 
betrachtet werden."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un cours en ligne du site Web de MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) a fonctionné par 
massachusetts.institute.of.technology. Ce matériel de cours est
libre pour que n'importe qui utilise qui reçoivent les modalités et 
les conditions de l'utilisation. La description de ce cours, 
éditée sur le site Web de MIT OpenCourseWare, est : le "but 
est d'analyser des événements actuels importants pour ce qu'elles 
indiquent au sujet de la nature et de travailler de notre monde 
technologique. Le point de départ est connexion entre la 
technologie et le terrorisme. Le sujet explore également 
comment un monde humain-construit peut stimuler l'insécurité et le 
danger, et comment les êtres humains répondent. Beaucoup 
d'invités invités aident à développer une approche 
interdisciplinaire forte (la science, ingénierie, science sociale, 
sciences humaines). Les sujets incluent le risque et la 
remédiation technologique, les systèmes sociotechnical, 
l'imagination du désastre, la technologie et l'identité, la 
technologie et la religion, la technologie et l'éducation, et la 
technologie et la confiance. Affectations écrites et orales et 
un projet final requis. des propositions d'Service-étude et les
présentations Web-basées, en plus du travail écrit, peuvent être 
considérées pour le projet final par l'instructeur."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um curso em linha do Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) operou-se por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material do curso está livre
para que qualquer um use-se quem aceitam os termos e as condições do
uso. A descrição deste curso, publicada no Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare, é: o "alvo é analisar eventos atuais 
importantes para o que revela sobre a natureza e trabalhar de nosso 
mundo technological. O ponto começar é conexão entre a 
tecnologia e o terrorismo. O assunto explora também como um 
mundo humano-construído pode promover o insecurity e o perigo, e como
os seres humanos respondem. Muitos convidados convidados ajudam 
desenvolver uma aproximação interdisciplinary forte (ciência, 
engenharia, ciência social, humanities). Os tópicos incluem o 
risco e remediação technological, sistemas sociotechnical, 
imaginação do disastre, tecnologia e identidade, tecnologia e 
religião, tecnologia e instrução, e tecnologia e confiança. 
Atribuições escritas e orais e um projeto final requerido. 
as propostas deaprendizagem e as apresentações Web-baseadas, 
além ao trabalho escrito, podem ser consideradas para o projeto final
pelo instrutor."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un corso in linea dal Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) ha funzionato da Massachusetts 
Institute of Technology. Questo materiale di corso è libero 
affinchè chiunque usi chi accettano i termini e le condizioni di uso.
La descrizione di questo corso, pubblicata sul Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare, è: "lo scopo è analizzare gli eventi correnti 
importanti per che cosa rivelano circa la natura ed il funzionamento 
del nostro mondo tecnologico. Il punto di partenza è 
collegamento fra tecnologia e terrorismo. L'oggetto egualmente 
esplora come un mondo umano-costruito può promuovere l'insicurezza ed
il pericolo e come gli esseri umani rispondono. Molti ospiti 
invitati contribuiscono a sviluppare un metodo interdisciplinare forte
(scienza, ingegneria, scienza sociale, studi umanistici). I 
soggetti includono il rischio e remediation tecnologico, sistemi 
sociotechnical, l'immaginazione di disastro, tecnologia ed identità, 
tecnologia e religione, tecnologia e formazione e tecnologia e 
fiducia. Assegnazioni scritte ed orali e un progetto finale 
richiesto. le proposte Servizio-imparanti e le presentazioni 
Web-basate, oltre che lavoro scritto, possono essere considerate per 
il progetto finale dall'istruttore."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρά μαθημάτων από τον 
ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) που 
χρησιμοποιείται από το ίδρυμα της Μασαχουσέτης τεχνολογίας. 
Αυτό το υλικό σειράς μαθημάτων είναι ελεύθερο για καθένα 
να χρησιμοποιήσει ποιοι αποδέχονται τους όρους και τους όρους 
χρησιμοποίησης. Η περιγραφή αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων, που
δημοσιεύεται στον ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare, είναι: 
"Ο στόχος είναι να αναλυθούν τα σημαντικά παρόντα γεγονότα
για αυτό που αποκαλύπτουν για τη φύση και την εργασία του 
τεχνολογικού κόσμου μας. Η αφετηρία είναι σύνδεση μεταξύ 
της τεχνολογίας και της τρομοκρατίας. Το θέμα εξερευνά 
επίσης πώς ένας ανθρώπινος-χτισμένος κόσμος μπορεί να 
ενθαρρύνει την αβεβαιότητα και τον κίνδυνο, και πώς τα ανθρώπινα 
οντα αποκρίνονται. Οδηγίες πολλών οι προσκεκλημένες 
φιλοξενουμένων αναπτύσσουν μια ισχυρή διεπιστημονική προσέγγιση 
(επιστήμη, εφαρμοσμένη μηχανική, κοινωνικές επιστήμες, 
ανθρωπότητες). Τα θέματα περιλαμβάνουν τον τεχνολογική 
κίνδυνο και την επανόρθωση, τα sociotechnical συστήματα, τη 
φαντασία της καταστροφής, την τεχνολογία και την ταυτότητα, την 
τεχνολογία και τη θρησκεία, την τεχνολογία και την εκπαίδευση, και
την τεχνολογία και την εμπιστοσύνη. Γραπτές και προφορικές 
αναθέσεις και ένα τελικό πρόγραμμα που απαιτείται. Οι 
προτάσεις υπηρεσία-εκμάθησης και οι βασισμένες στο WEB 
παρουσιάσεις, εκτός από τη γραπτή εργασία, μπορούν να 
εξεταστούν για το τελικό πρόγραμμα από τον εκπαιδευτικό."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un curso en línea del Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) funcionó por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material del curso está 
libre para que cualquier persona utilice quiénes validan los 
términos y las condiciones del uso. La descripción de este 
curso, publicada en el Web site del MIT OpenCourseWare, es: la 
"puntería es analizar los sucesos actuales importantes para lo que 
él revela sobre la naturaleza y el trabajo de nuestro mundo 
tecnológico. El punto de partida es conexión entre la 
tecnología y el terrorismo. El tema también explora cómo un 
mundo humano-construido puede fomentar inseguridad y peligro, y cómo 
responden los seres humanos. Muchas huéspedes invitadas ayudan 
a desarrollar un acercamiento interdisciplinario fuerte (ciencia, 
ingeniería, ciencia social, humanidad). Los asuntos incluyen 
riesgo y remediación tecnológica, los sistemas sociotechnical, 
imaginación del desastre, tecnología e identidad, tecnología y 
religión, tecnología y educación, y tecnología y confianza. 
Asignaciones escritas y orales y un proyecto final requerido. 
las ofertas Servicio-que aprenden y las presentaciones 
Web-basadas, además del trabajo escrito, se pueden considerar para el
proyecto final por el instructor."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft Technologie und Gesellschaft</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Religion</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Remediation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Identität</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Terrorismus</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">sociotechnical Systeme</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gefahr</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">technologische Gefahr</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">aktuelle Fälle</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Phantasie des Unfalles</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ausbildung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft Technologie und Gesellschaft.</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Technologie et société de la Science</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">religion</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">remédiation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">identité</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">terrorisme</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">systèmes sociotechnical</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">danger</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">risque technologique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">événements actuels</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">imagination de désastre</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">éducation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Technologie et société de la Science.</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tecnologia e sociedade da ciência</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">religião</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">remediação</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">identidade</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">terrorismo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">sistemas sociotechnical</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">perigo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">risco technological</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">eventos atuais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">imaginação do disastre</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">instrução</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tecnologia e sociedade da ciência.</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tecnologia e società di scienza</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">religione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">remediation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">identità</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">terrorismo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sistemi sociotechnical</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">pericolo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">rischio tecnologico</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">eventi correnti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">immaginazione del disastro</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">formazione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tecnologia e società di scienza.</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τεχνολογία και κοινωνία επιστήμης</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">θρησκεία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">επανόρθωση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ταυτότητα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τρομοκρατία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">sociotechnical συστήματα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">κίνδυνος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τεχνολογικός κίνδυνος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρόντα γεγονότα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">φαντασία της καταστροφής</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εκπαίδευση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τεχνολογία και κοινωνία επιστήμης.</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tecnología y sociedad de la ciencia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">religión</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">remediación</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">identidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">terrorismo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">sistemas sociotechnical</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">peligro</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">riesgo tecnológico</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">sucesos actuales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">imaginación del desastre</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">educación</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tecnología y sociedad de la ciencia.</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1141</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">science education</string>
                <string language="sv">undervisning i naturvetenskap och matematik</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1292</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">technology</string>
                <string language="sv">teknologi</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1204</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">social sciences</string>
                <string language="sv">samhällsvetenskap</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_8025-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_8025-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-03-15T19:57:41.0Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
N:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
ORG:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T05:58:31.95Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
      <entry>skolverket_8025</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://ocw.mit.edu/OcwWeb/Science--Technology--and-Society/STS-069Technology-in-a--Dangerous-WorldFall2002/CourseHome/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
