<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/28516</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>28516</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
    <entry>SK195_4</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM       http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:openlearn.open.ac.uk:SK195_4</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>LearningSpace</catalog>
            <entry>SK195_4</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en-gb">Gene testing</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Genprüfung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Test de gène</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Testar do gene</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prova del gene</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δοκιμή γονιδίων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Prueba del gene</string>
          </title>
          <language>en-gb</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">This Unit looks at three different uses of genetic testing: pre-natal diagnosis, childhood testing and adult testing. Such tests provide genetic information in the form of a predictive diagnosis, and as such are described as predictive tests. Pre-natal diagnosis uses techniques such as amniocentesis to test fetuses in the womb. For example, it is commonly offered to women over 35 to test for Down's syndrome. Childhood testing involves testing children for genetic diseases that may not become a problem until they grow up, and adult testing is aimed at people at risk of late-onset disorders, which do not appear until middle age. In addition, we address some of the issues involved in carrier testing, another predictive test. This involves the testing of people from families with a history of genetic disease, to find out who carries the gene, and who therefore might pass the disease onto their children even though they themselves are unaffected. Here the aim is to enable couples to make informed choices about whether or not to have children, and if so whether they might have a genetic disease studies 'proteins'. Starting with a simple analysis of the molecular make up, the Unit moves on to look at the importance of protein and how they are digested and absorbed.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Science and Nature</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Child_development</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Ethics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Genes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Genetic_counselling</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Genetic_disease</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Genetics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Health</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Predictive_tests</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Screening</string>
          </keyword>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>linear</value>
          </structure>
          <aggregationLevel>
            <source>aggregationLevelValues</source>
            <value>2</value>
          </aggregationLevel>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Maßeinheit betrachtet drei 
unterschiedliche Gebräuche von genetischer Prüfung: prenatale 
Diagnose, prüfende und Erwachsenprüfung Kindheit. Solche Tests
stellen genetische Informationen in Form einer vorbestimmten Diagnose 
zur Verfügung und während so als vorbestimmte Tests beschrieben 
werden. Prenatale Diagnose verwendet Techniken wie 
Amniocentesis, um Fötusse in der Geb5rmutter zu prüfen. Z.B. 
wird sie geläufig Frauen über 35 zum Test für unten Syndrom 
angeboten. Die Kindheitprüfung bezieht mit ein, Kinder auf 
genetische Krankheiten zu prüfen, die möglicherweise nicht ein 
Problem werden können, bis sie aufwachsen, und die Erwachsenprüfung 
ist angestrebte Leute an der Gefahr der Spätangriff Störungen, die 
nicht bis mittleres Alter erscheinen. In der Hinzufügung 
sprechen wir einige der Punkte an, die in die prüfende 
Fördermaschine, ein anderer vorbestimmter Test mit einbezogen werden.
Dieses bezieht die Prüfung der Leute von den Familien in eine 
Geschichte der genetischen Krankheit mit ein, um herauszufinden, wem 
das Gen trägt und wem die Krankheit auf ihre Kinder folglich führen 
konnte, obwohl sie selbst unberührt sind. Hier ist das Ziel, 
Paare zu aktivieren, informierte Wahlen ungefähr zu treffen ob oder 
Kinder nicht zu haben und wenn so, ob sie haben konnten, eine 
genetische Krankheit ' der Proteine studiert. Beginnend mit 
einer einfachen Analyse vom molekularen bilden Sie, die Maßeinheit 
Bewegungen, den Wert des Proteins an zu betrachten und wie sie verdaut
und aufgesogen werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette unité regarde trois utilisations 
différentes du test génétique : diagnostic prénatal, enfance
testant et test d'adulte. De tels essais fournissent des 
informations génétiques sous forme de diagnostic prédictif, et 
pendant que tels sont décrits en tant qu'essais prédictifs. Le
diagnostic prénatal emploie des techniques telles que l'amniocentèse 
pour examiner des foetus dans l'utérus. Par exemple, il est 
généralement offert aux femmes plus de 35 à l'essai pour vers le 
bas le syndrome. Le test d'enfance implique d'examiner des 
enfants pour les maladies génétiques qui peuvent ne pas devenir un 
problème jusqu'à ce qu'ils grandissent, et le test d'adulte est les 
personnes visées en danger des désordres de tard-début, qui 
n'apparaissent pas jusqu'à l'âge moyen. En outre, nous 
abordons certaines des questions impliquées dans le porteur testant, 
un autre essai prédictif. Ceci comporte le test des personnes 
des familles d'une histoire de la maladie génétique, pour découvrir
qui porte le gène, et qui pourrait donc passer la maladie sur leurs 
enfants quoiqu'elles elles-mêmes soient inchangées. Ici le but
est de permettre à des couples de faire des choix au courant environ 
si de ne pas avoir des enfants, et si ainsi s'ils pourraient avoir une
maladie génétique étudie les 'protéines. Commençant par une
analyse simple du moléculaire composez, les mouvements d'unité de 
regarder en fonction l'importance de la protéine et comment elles 
sont assimilées et absorbées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta unidade olha três usos diferentes de testar 
genetic: diagnóstico pre-natal, infância que testa e testar do
adulto. Tais testes fornecem a informação genetic no 
formulário de um diagnóstico predictive, e enquanto tais estão 
descritos como testes predictive. O diagnóstico pre-natal usa 
técnicas tais como o amniocentesis testar fetuses no womb. Para
o exemplo, é oferecido geralmente às mulheres sobre 35 ao teste para
para baixo o syndrome. Testar da infância envolve testar 
crianças para as doenças genetic que não podem se transformar um 
problema até que cresçam acima, e testar do adulto é pessoa visado 
no risco dos disorders do tarde-início, que não aparecem até a 
idade média. Além, nós dirigimo-nos a algumas das edições 
envolvidas no portador que testa, um outro teste predictive. 
Isto envolve testar dos povos das famílias com um history da 
doença genetic, para encontrar para fora quem carregam o gene, e quem
pôde conseqüentemente passar a doença em suas crianças mesmo que 
ela mesma sejam não afetada. Aqui o alvo é permitir pares de 
fazer aproximadamente escolhas informed se ou de não ter crianças, e
se assim se puderam ter uma doença genetic estudar ' proteínas. 
Começando com uma análise simples do molecular faça acima, os
movimentos da unidade olhar sobre a importância da proteína e como 
são digeridos e absorvidos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa unità guarda tre usi differenti di prova 
genetica: diagnosi prenatale, infanzia che esamina e prova 
dell'adulto. Tali prove forniscono le informazioni genetiche 
sotto forma d'una diagnosi preventiva e mentre tali sono descritti 
come prove preventive. La diagnosi prenatale usa le tecniche 
quale l'amniocentesi per esaminare i feti nel womb. Per esempio,
è offerta comunemente alle donne oltre 35 alla prova per giù la 
sindrome. La prova di infanzia coinvolge esaminare i bambini a 
malattie genetiche che non possono transformarsi in in un problema 
fino a che non si sviluppino in su e la prova dell'adulto è gente 
puntata su al rischio di disordini di in ritardo-inizio, che non 
compaiono fino all'età centrale. In più, richiamiamo alcune 
delle edizioni coinvolgere in elemento portante che esamina, un'altra 
prova preventiva. Ciò coinvolge la prova della gente dalle 
famiglie con una storia della malattia genetica, per scoprire chi 
trasporta il gene e chi quindi potrebbe passare la malattia sui loro 
bambini anche se essi stessi sono inalterate. Qui lo scopo è 
permettere alle coppie di fare le scelte informed circa se o di non 
avere bambini ed in caso affermativo se potrebbero avere una malattia 
genetica studia 'le proteine. Cominciando da un'analisi semplice
del molecolare componga, i movimenti dell'unità sopra guardare 
l'importanza di proteina e come sono digerite ed assorbite.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η μονάδα εξετάζει τρεις διαφορετικές χρήσεις της
γενετικής δοκιμής: προγενέθλια διάγνωση, δοκιμή παιδικής 
ηλικίας και ενήλικη δοκιμή. Τέτοιες δοκιμές παρέχουν τις 
γενετικές πληροφορίες υπό μορφή προφητικής διάγνωσης, και υπό 
αυτήν τη μορφή περιγράφονται ως προφητικές δοκιμές. Η 
προγενέθλια διάγνωση χρησιμοποιεί τις τεχνικές όπως η 
αμνιοκέντηση για να εξεταστούν τα έμβρυα στη μήτρα. 
Παραδείγματος χάριν, προσφέρεται συνήθως στις γυναίκες άνω
των 35 στη δοκιμή για το κάτω σύνδρομο. Η δοκιμή 
παιδικής ηλικίας περιλαμβάνει τα εξεταστικά παιδιά για τις 
γενετικές ασθένειες που μπορούν να μην γίνουν ένα πρόβλημα έως 
ότου μεγαλώνουν, και την ενήλικη δοκιμή στοχεύουν στους 
ανθρώπους σε κίνδυνο αναταραχών πρόσφατος-αρχής, οι οποίες δεν 
εμφανίζονται μέχρι τη μέση ηλικία. Επιπλέον, 
αντιμετωπίζουμε μερικά από τα ζητήματα που περιλαμβάνονται στη 
δοκιμή μεταφορέων, μια άλλη προφητική δοκιμή. Αυτό 
περιλαμβάνει τη δοκιμή των ανθρώπων από τις οικογένειες με μια 
ιστορία της γενετικής ασθένειας, για να ανακαλύψει ποιος φέρνει 
το γονίδιο, και ποιος επομένως να περάσει την ασθένεια επάνω στα 
παιδιά τους ακόμα κι αν οι ίδιοι είναι απρόσβλητοι. Εδώ ο 
στόχος είναι να επιτραπούν τα ζεύγη για να κάνει τις 
ενημερωμένες επιλογές για εαν πρέπει να υπάρξουν τα παιδιά, και 
σε αυτή την περίπτωση εάν να έχουν μελέτες "πρωτεϊ'νεσ" τις 
γενετικές ασθενειών. Αρχίζοντας από μια απλή ανάλυση του 
μοριακού τύπου επάνω, η μονάδα κινείται για να εξετάσει τη 
σημασία της πρωτεϊ'νης και πώς αφομοιώνονται και απορροφώνται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta unidad mira tres diversas aplicaciones de la 
prueba genética: diagnosis prenatal, niñez que prueba y prueba
del adulto. Tales pruebas proporcionan a la información 
genética en la forma de una diagnosis profética, y mientras que 
tales se describen como pruebas proféticas. La diagnosis 
prenatal utiliza técnicas tales como amniocentesis para probar fetos 
en la matriz. Por ejemplo, se ofrece comúnmente a las mujeres 
sobre 35 a la prueba para abajo el síndrome. La prueba de la 
niñez implica el probar de los niños para las enfermedades 
genéticas que pueden no convertirse en un problema hasta que crecen 
para arriba, y la prueba del adulto es gente dirigida en el riesgo de 
los desórdenes del tarde-inicio, que no aparecen hasta edad media. 
Además, tratamos algunas de las ediciones implicadas en el 
portador que prueba, otra prueba profética. Esto implica la 
prueba de la gente de las familias con una historia de la enfermedad 
genética, para descubrir quién lleva el gene, y quién por lo tanto 
pudo pasar la enfermedad sobre sus niños aunque ellos mismos son 
inafectados. Aquí la puntería es permitir a pares hacer 
opciones informadas alrededor si o no tener niños, y si si puede ser 
que tengan una enfermedad genética estudia tan las ' proteínas. 
Comenzando con un análisis simple del molecular haga para 
arriba, los movimientos de la unidad encendido de mirar la importancia
de la proteína y cómo se digieren y se absorben.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Natur</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Child_development</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ethik</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gene</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Genetic_counselling</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Genetic_disease</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Genetik</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gesundheit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Predictive_tests</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Siebung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et nature</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Child_development</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Éthique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Gènes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Genetic_counselling</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Genetic_disease</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La génétique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Santé</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Predictive_tests</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Criblage</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e natureza</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Child_development</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ethics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Genes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Genetic_counselling</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Genetic_disease</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Genetics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Saúde</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Predictive_tests</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Seleção</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e natura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Child_development</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Etica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Geni</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Genetic_counselling</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Genetic_disease</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La genetica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Salute</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Predictive_tests</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Selezione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και φύση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Child_development</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ηθική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γονίδια</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Genetic_counselling</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Genetic_disease</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γενετική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υγεία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Predictive_tests</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαλογή</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y naturaleza</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Child_development</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El ética</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Genes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Genetic_counselling</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Genetic_disease</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Genética</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Salud</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Predictive_tests</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Investigación</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <version>
            <string>1.0</string>
          </version>
          <status>
            <source>statusValues</source>
            <value>final</value>
          </status>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:openlearn.open.ac.uk:SK195_4</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>LearningSpace</catalog>
            <entry>SK195_4</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <language>en-gb</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:OpenLearn
N:OpenLearn
ORG:OpenLearn
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T17:18:09.56Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <technical>
          <format>text/html</format>
          <location>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/SK195_4</location>
        </technical>
        <educational>
          <interactivityType>
            <source>interactivityTypeValues</source>
            <value>mixed</value>
          </interactivityType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>text</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <interactivityLevel>
            <source>interactivityLevelValues</source>
            <value>low</value>
          </interactivityLevel>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="en-gb">18+</string>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <difficulty>
            <source>difficultyValues</source>
            <value>easy</value>
          </difficulty>
          <typicalLearningTime>
            <duration>PT4H</duration>
          </typicalLearningTime>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">Independent self-study</string>
          </description>
          <language>en-gb</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution - NonCommercial-ShareAlike 2.0 Licence - see http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/uk/ - Original copyright The Open University</string>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/uk/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>references</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">An OU course on this topic</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>URL</catalog>
              <entry>http://www3.open.ac.uk/courses/bin/p12.dll?C01SK195</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>references</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">Study this topic at the OU</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>URL</catalog>
              <entry>http://www3.open.ac.uk/courses/classifications/science.shtm</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>references</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">open2.net: Science &amp; Nature</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>URL</catalog>
              <entry>http://www.open2.net/sciencetechnologynature</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>isbasedon</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">This is the title and course code of the source course material</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>Open University course</catalog>
              <entry>Human genetics and health issues - SK195</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>SK195_4 - web site</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>SK195_4 - web site</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/SK195_4</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>SK195_4 - Common Cartridge 1.0</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>package in</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.packageInValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>imscc_v1p0</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>SK195_4 - Common Cartridge 1.0</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/blocks/formats/logrequest.php?url=/file.php/2480/downloads/SK195_4_ims_cc.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>SK195_4 - Content Package</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>package in</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.packageInValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>imscp_v1p1p4</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>SK195_4 - Content Package</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/blocks/formats/logrequest.php?url=/file.php/2480/downloads/SK195_4_ims_cp.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
