<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/26226</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>26226</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
    <entry>U212_1</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM       http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:openlearn.open.ac.uk:U212_1</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>LearningSpace</catalog>
            <entry>U212_1</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en-gb">Children and violence: an introductory, international and interdisciplinary approach</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kinder und Gewalttätigkeit: eine 
einleitende, internationale und interdisziplinäre Annäherung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enfants et violence : une approche 
préliminaire, internationale et interdisciplinaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Crianças e violência: uma aproximação 
introdutória, internacional e interdisciplinary</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bambini e violenza: un metodo introduttivo, 
internazionale ed interdisciplinare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιδιά και βία: μια εισαγωγική, διεθνής και 
διεπιστημονική προσέγγιση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Niños y violencia: un acercamiento 
introductorio, internacional e interdisciplinario</string>
          </title>
          <language>en-gb</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">Children are subject to many forms of adversity, for example, poverty or ill health. However, a significant form of adversity experienced by children in many different regions of the world is violence. The form of violence against children varies widely and is hugely disparate. In this unit, the focus is on three different environments where children experience violence: at home, among peers at school and in the wider society (in the context of armed conflicts). The text considers the experiences of children both locally and globally. For this reason, violence against children should not be considered a phenomenon that is remote. Sadly, children may experience violence in their families and among their peers, and may also become involved in armed conflict. The unit considers in detail the daily experiences of violence which can have negative impacts on the physical or emotional health of children and moves from ideas about children and violence in very localized contexts – within families and with peers at school – through to the broader community and on to the international perspective. It also analyses the different roles that children take on in relation to violence, such as victim, perpetrator, witness, colluder and peacemaker.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Education</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Bullying</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Children</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Child_soldier</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Families</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Globally</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Locally</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">School</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Violence</string>
          </keyword>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>linear</value>
          </structure>
          <aggregationLevel>
            <source>aggregationLevelValues</source>
            <value>2</value>
          </aggregationLevel>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kinder sind abhängig von vielen Formularen des 
Missgeschicks, der z.B., Armut oder der kranken Gesundheit. 
Jedoch ist ein bedeutendes Formular des Missgeschicks erfahren 
von den Kindern in vielen unterschiedlichen Regionen der Welt 
Gewalttätigkeit. Das Formular der Gewalttätigkeit gegen Kinder
verändert sich weit und ist sehr groß unvereinbar. In dieser 
Maßeinheit ist der Fokus auf drei unterschiedlichen Umgebungen, in 
denen Kinder Gewalttätigkeit erfahren: zu Hause unter Gleichen 
an der Schule und in der breiteren Gesellschaft (im Kontext der 
bewaffneten $überschneidungen). Der Text betrachtet die 
Erfahrungen der Kinder lokal und global. Aus diesem Grund sollte
Gewalttätigkeit gegen Kinder nicht gelten als ein Phänomen, das 
entfernt ist. Traurig können Kinder Gewalttätigkeit in ihren 
Familien und unter ihren Gleichen erfahren, und können in bewaffneter
$überschneidung beteiligt auch werden. Die Maßeinheit 
betrachtet im Detail die täglichen Erfahrungen der Gewalttätigkeit, 
die negative Auswirkungen auf die körperliche oder emotionale 
Gesundheit der Kinder und der Bewegungen von den Ideen über Kinder 
und Gewalttätigkeit in sehr beschränkten Kontexten haben können? 
innerhalb der Familien und mit Gleichen an der Schule? 
durch zu die ausgedehntere Gemeinschaft und an zur 
internationalen Perspektive. Sie analysiert auch die 
unterschiedlichen Rollen, die Kinder an in bezug auf eine 
Gewalttätigkeit, wie Opfer, Täter, Zeuge, colluder und 
Friedensstifter nehmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les enfants sont sujets à des beaucoup de formes 
d'adversité, par exemple, de pauvreté ou de santé mauvaise. 
Cependant, une forme significative d'adversité éprouvée par 
des enfants dans beaucoup de différentes régions du monde est 
violence. La forme de la violence contre des enfants change 
considérablement et est énormement disparate. Dans cette 
unité, le foyer est sur trois environnements différents où les 
enfants éprouvent la violence : à la maison, parmi des pairs 
à l'école et dans la société plus large (dans le contexte des 
conflits armés). Le texte considère les expériences des 
enfants localement et globalement. Pour cette raison, la 
violence contre des enfants ne devrait pas être considérée un 
phénomène qui est à distance. Tristement, les enfants peuvent
éprouver la violence dans leurs familles et parmi leurs pairs, et 
peuvent également devenir impliqués dans le conflit armé. 
L'unité considère en détail les expériences quotidiennes de 
la violence qui peuvent avoir des impacts négatifs sur la santé 
physique ou émotive des enfants et les mouvements des idées au sujet
des enfants et la violence dans des contextes très localisés ? 
chez des familles et avec des pairs à l'école ? par à 
la communauté plus large et en fonction à la perspective 
internationale. Elle analyse également les différents rôles 
que les enfants prennent en fonction par rapport à la violence, telle
que la victime, le malfaiteur, le témoin, le colluder et le 
conciliateur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As crianças são sujeitas a muitos formulários 
do adversity, para o exemplo, a pobreza ou a saúde doente. 
Entretanto, um formulário significativo do adversity 
experimentado por crianças em muitas regiões diferentes do mundo é 
violência. O formulário da violência de encontro às 
crianças varia extensamente e é enorme disparate. Nesta 
unidade, o foco é em três ambientes diferentes onde as crianças 
experimentam a violência: na HOME, entre pares na escola e na 
sociedade mais larga (no contexto de conflitos armados). O texto
considera as experiências das crianças  localmente e global. 
Para esta razão, a violência de encontro às crianças não 
deve ser considerada um fenômeno que seja remoto. Sadly, as 
crianças podem experimentar a violência em suas famílias e entre 
seus pares, e podem também tornar-se involvidas em conflito armado. 
A unidade considera em detalhe as experiências diárias da 
violência que podem ter impactos negativos na saúde física ou 
emocional das crianças e os movimentos das idéias sobre crianças e 
na violência em contextos muito localizados? dentro das 
famílias e com os pares na escola? através à comunidade mais 
larga e sobre ao perspective internacional. Analisa também os 
papéis diferentes de que as crianças fazem exame sobre com relação
à violência, tal como a vítima, o perpetrator, a testemunha, o 
colluder e o peacemaker.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I bambini sono conforme a molte forme di 
adversity, per esempio, di povertà o di affezione. Tuttavia, 
una forma significativa di adversity sperimentata dai bambini in molte
regioni differenti del mondo è violenza. La forma della 
violenza contro i bambini varia ampiamente ed è enorme disparata. 
In questa unità, il fuoco è su tre ambienti differenti in cui 
i bambini avvertono la violenza: nel paese, fra i pari alla 
scuola e nella società più larga (nel contesto dei conflitti 
muniti). Il testo considera le esperienze nei bambini sia 
localmente che globalmente. Per questo motivo, la violenza 
contro i bambini non dovrebbe essere considerata un fenomeno che è a 
distanza. Tristemente, i bambini possono avvertire la violenza 
nelle loro famiglie e fra i loro pari e possono anche essere implicati
in conflitto munito. L'unità considera dettagliatamente le 
esperienze quotidiane nella violenza che possono avere effetti 
negativi sulla salute fisica o impressionabile dei bambini e movimenti
dalle idee circa i bambini e sulla violenza nei contesti molto 
localizzati? presso le famiglie e con i pari alla scuola? 
attraverso alla più vasta Comunità e sopra alla prospettiva 
internazionale. Egualmente analizza i ruoli differenti che i 
bambini prendono sopra rispetto alla violenza, quali la vittima, il 
perpetrator, il testimone, il colluder ed il peacemaker.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα παιδιά υπόκεινται σε πολλές μορφές της 
αντιπαλότητας, παραδείγματος χάριν, της ένδειας ή της κακής 
υγείας. Εντούτοις, μια σημαντική μορφή της αντιπαλότητας 
που βιώνεται από τα παιδιά σε πολλές διαφορετικές περιοχές του 
κόσμου είναι βία. Η μορφή της βίας κατά των παιδιών 
ποικίλλει ευρέως και είναι σημαντικά ανόμοια. Σε αυτήν την
μονάδα, η εστίαση είναι σε τρία διαφορετικά περιβάλλοντα όπου 
τα παιδιά δοκιμάζουν τη βία: στο σπίτι, μεταξύ των λόρδων 
στο σχολείο και στην ευρύτερη κοινωνία (στα πλαίσια των ένοπλων 
συγκρούσεων). Το κείμενο εξετάζει την εμπειρία των παιδιών 
και τοπικά και συνολικά. Για αυτόν τον λόγο, η βία κατά 
των παιδιών δεν πρέπει να θεωρηθεί φαινόμενο που είναι 
απομακρυσμένο. Δυστυχώς, τα παιδιά μπορούν να δοκιμάσουν τη
βία στις οικογένειές τους και μεταξύ των λόρδων τους, και 
μπορούν επίσης να αναμιχθούν στην ένοπλη σύγκρουση. Η 
μονάδα εξετάζει λεπτομερώς την καθημερινή εμπειρία της βίας που 
μπορεί να ασκήσει αρνητικές επιδράσεις στη φυσική ή 
συναισθηματική υγεία των παιδιών και των κινήσεων από τις ιδέες 
για τα παιδιά και τη βία στα πολύ εντοπισμένα πλαίσια; 
μέσα στις οικογένειες και με τους λόρδους στο σχολείο; 
μέσω στην ευρύτερη κοινότητα και προς τη διεθνή προοπτική. 
Αναλύει επίσης τους διαφορετικούς ρόλους ότι τα παιδιά 
παίρνουν σε σχέση με τη βία, όπως το θύμα, το δράστη, το 
μάρτυρα, colluder και τον ειρηνοποιό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los niños están conforme a muchas formas de 
adversidad, por ejemplo, de pobreza o de mala salud. Sin 
embargo, una forma significativa de adversidad experimentada por los 
niños en muchas diversas regiones del mundo es violencia. La 
forma de violencia contra niños varía extensamente y es enorme 
dispar. En esta unidad, el foco es en tres diversos ambientes 
donde los niños experimentan violencia: en el país, entre 
pares en la escuela y en la sociedad más ancha (en el contexto de 
conflictos armados). El texto considera las experiencias de 
niños localmente y global. Por esta razón, la violencia contra
niños no se debe considerar un fenómeno que esté alejado. 
Tristemente, los niños pueden experimentar violencia en sus 
familias y entre sus pares, y pueden también llegar a estar 
implicados en conflicto armado. ¿La unidad considera 
detalladamente las experiencias diarias de la violencia que pueden 
tener impactos negativos en la salud física o emocional de niños y 
los movimientos de ideas sobre niños y la violencia en contextos muy 
localizados? ¿dentro de las familias y con los pares en la 
escuela? a través a la comunidad más amplia y encendido a la 
perspectiva internacional. También analiza los diversos papeles
que los niños toman encendido en lo referente a violencia, tal como 
víctima, autor, testigo, colluder y pacificador.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ausbildung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tyrannisieren</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kinder</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Child_soldier</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Familien</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Global</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lokal</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schule</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gewalttätigkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Éducation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Intimider</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enfants</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Child_soldier</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Familles</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Globalement</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Localement</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">École</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Violence</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Instrução</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bullying</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Crianças</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Child_soldier</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Famílias</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Global</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Localmente</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Escola</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Violência</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Formazione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bullying</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bambini</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Child_soldier</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Famiglie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Globalmente</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Localmente</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scuola</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Violenza</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκπαίδευση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φοβέρα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιδιά</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Child_soldier</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οικογένειες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συνολικά</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τοπικά</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σχολείο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Educación</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El bullying</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Niños</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Child_soldier</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Familias</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Global</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Localmente</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Escuela</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Violencia</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <version>
            <string>1.0</string>
          </version>
          <status>
            <source>statusValues</source>
            <value>final</value>
          </status>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:openlearn.open.ac.uk:U212_1</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>LearningSpace</catalog>
            <entry>U212_1</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <language>en-gb</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:OpenLearn
N:OpenLearn
ORG:OpenLearn
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T17:14:10.77Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <technical>
          <format>text/html</format>
          <location>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/U212_1</location>
        </technical>
        <educational>
          <interactivityType>
            <source>interactivityTypeValues</source>
            <value>mixed</value>
          </interactivityType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>text</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <interactivityLevel>
            <source>interactivityLevelValues</source>
            <value>low</value>
          </interactivityLevel>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="en-gb">18+</string>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <difficulty>
            <source>difficultyValues</source>
            <value>medium</value>
          </difficulty>
          <typicalLearningTime>
            <duration>PT20H</duration>
          </typicalLearningTime>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">Independent self-study</string>
          </description>
          <language>en-gb</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution - NonCommercial-ShareAlike 2.0 Licence - see http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/uk/ - Original copyright The Open University</string>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/uk/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>references</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">An OU course on this topic</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>URL</catalog>
              <entry>http://www3.open.ac.uk/courses/bin/p12.dll?C01U212</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>references</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">Studying this topic at the OU</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>URL</catalog>
              <entry>http://www3.open.ac.uk/courses/classifications/education_and_teacher_training.shtm</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>references</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">open2.net: Society</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>URL</catalog>
              <entry>http://www.open2.net/society/</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>isbasedon</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">This is the title and course code of the source course material</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>Open University course</catalog>
              <entry>Children and violence: an introductory, international and interdisciplinary approach - U212</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>U212_1 - web site</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>U212_1 - web site</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/U212_1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>U212_1 - Common Cartridge 1.0</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>package in</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.packageInValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>imscc_v1p0</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>U212_1 - Common Cartridge 1.0</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/blocks/formats/logrequest.php?url=/file.php/1649/downloads/U212_1_ims_cc.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>U212_1 - Content Package</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>package in</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.packageInValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>imscp_v1p1p4</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>U212_1 - Content Package</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/blocks/formats/logrequest.php?url=/file.php/1649/downloads/U212_1_ims_cp.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
