<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/26899</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>26899</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
    <entry>A207_5</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM       http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:openlearn.open.ac.uk:A207_5</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>LearningSpace</catalog>
            <entry>A207_5</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en-gb">French Revolution</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Französische Revolution</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Révolution Française</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Volta Francesa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giro Francese</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γαλλική επανάσταση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Revolución Francesa</string>
          </title>
          <language>en-gb</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">This unit provides basic historical background to the French Revolution. It will show that the Revolution accelerated intellectual, cultural and psychological change, and opened up new horizons and possibilities. In fact, while much controversy and scepticism remain as to the real extent of underlying change in the social and economic structure of France, it is generally agreed by scholars that the Revolution stimulated a widening of expectations and imaginative awareness: a belief, inherited from the Enlightenment, in the possibility of progress, as well as a conviction that state and society could be reconstituted with a view to realizing social and individual aspirations and human happiness generally. As it degenerated into violence and bloodshed, however, the Revolution also provoked scepticism and pessimism about progress and human nature. The two basic types of modern political outlook, progressive and conservative, date from this experience. Which, if any, of these sets of beliefs was true is not at issue here. What matters is that the Revolution gave rise to them and gave them lasting life</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Arts and History</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">French_revolution</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">History</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en-gb">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>linear</value>
          </structure>
          <aggregationLevel>
            <source>aggregationLevelValues</source>
            <value>2</value>
          </aggregationLevel>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Maßeinheit stellt grundlegenden 
historischen Hintergrund zur Französischen Revolution zur Verfügung.
Sie zeigt, daß die Umdrehung intellektuelle, kulturelle und 
psychologische Änderung beschleunigte und neue Horizonte und 
Möglichkeiten erschloß. Tatsächlich während viel Kontroverse
und Skepsis hinsichtlich des realen Umfangs einer zugrundeliegenden 
Änderung in der Sozial- und Wirtschaftsstruktur von Frankreich 
bleiben, wird es im Allgemeinen von den Gelehrten vereinbart, daß die
Umdrehung ein Verbreitern von Erwartungen und von phantasiereichem 
Bewußtsein anregte: ein Glaube, übernommen von der 
Aufklärung, in der Möglichkeit des Fortschritts, sowie eine 
Überzeugung, daß Zustand und Gesellschaft angesichts die Sozial- und
einzelnen Aspirationen und menschliches Glück im Allgemeinen 
verwirklichen wieder hergestellt werden konnten. Wie sie in 
Gewalttätigkeit degenerierte und Blutvergießen jedoch erregte die 
Umdrehung auch Skepsis und Pessimismus über Fortschritt und 
menschliche Natur. Die zwei grundlegenden Typen der modernen 
politischen Aussicht, progressiv und konservativ, Datum von dieser 
Erfahrung. Welches, wenn irgendwelche, dieser Sets Glaubens 
zutreffend war, ist nicht an der Ausgabe hier. Was ausmacht, 
ist, daß die Umdrehung sie verursachte und ihnen dauerhafte 
Lebensdauer gab</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette unité fournit l'historique de base à la 
révolution française. Elle prouvera que la révolution a 
accéléré le changement intellectuel, culturel et psychologique, et 
a ouvert de nouveaux horizons et possibilités. En fait, alors 
que beaucoup de polémique et de scepticisme demeurent quant à la 
vraie ampleur du changement fondamental de la structure sociale et 
économique de la France, des disciples convient généralement le que
la révolution a stimulé un élargissement des espérances et de la 
conscience imaginative : une croyance, héritée de 
l'éclaircissement, dans la possibilité de progrès, aussi bien 
qu'une conviction que l'état et la société pourraient être 
reconstitués en vue de réaliser des aspirations sociales et 
différentes et le bonheur humain généralement. Comme elle 
s'est dégénérée dans la violence et carnage, cependant, la 
révolution a également provoqué le scepticisme et le pessimisme au 
sujet du progrès et de la nature humaine. Les deux types de 
base de perspectives politiques modernes, progressif et conservateur, 
date de cette expérience. Quel, le cas échéant, de ces 
ensembles de croyance était vrai n'est pas à l'issue ici. Ce 
qui importe est que la révolution les a provoqués et leur a donné 
la vie durable</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta unidade fornece o fundo histórico básico à
volta francesa. Mostrará que a volta acelerou a mudança 
intelectual, cultural e psicológica, e a abriu acima dos horizontes e
das possibilidades novos. No fato, quando muitos controvérsia e
scepticism remanescerem a respeito da extensão real de mudança 
subjacente na estrutura social e econômica de France, concorda-se 
geralmente por scholars que a volta estimulou se alargar das 
expectativas e da consciência imaginative: uma opinião, 
herdada do enlightenment, na possibilidade de progresso, as.well.as 
uma convicção que o estado e a sociedade poderiam reconstituted com 
uma vista a realizar aspirations sociais e individuais e a felicidade 
humana geralmente. Como degenerated na violência e bloodshed, 
entretanto, a volta provocou também o scepticism e o pessimism sobre 
o progresso e a natureza humana. Os dois tipos básicos de 
outlook político moderno, progressivo e conservador, data desta 
experiência. Qual, se exister, destes jogos da opinião forem 
verdadeiros não está na edição aqui. O que importa é que a 
volta lhes deu a ascensão e lhes deu vida durável</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa unità fornisce i precedenti di base alla 
rivoluzione francese. Indicherà che la rivoluzione ha 
accelerato il cambiamento intellettuale, culturale e psicologico ed ha
aperto i nuovi orizzonti e possibilità. Infatti, mentre molti 
polemica e scetticismo rimangono quanto al limite reale di cambiamento
di fondo nella struttura sociale ed economica della Francia, è 
accosentito generalmente dagli eruditi che la rivoluzione ha 
stimolato un allargamento delle aspettative e della consapevolezza 
immaginativa: una credenza, ereditata dal chiarimento, nella 
possibilità di progresso, così come una convinzione che 
dichiara e società potrebbe essere ricostituita con vista a 
realizzare le aspirazioni sociali e diverse e la felicità umana 
generalmente. Come ha degenerato nella violenza e massacro, 
tuttavia, la rivoluzione egualmente ha provocato lo scetticismo ed il 
pessimismo circa progresso e la natura umana. I due tipi di base
di prospettive politiche moderne, progressive e conservatore, data da 
questa esperienza. Quale, all'occorrenza, di questi insiemi di 
credenza fosse allineare non è all'edizione qui. Che cosa 
importa è che la rivoluzione li ha provocati ed ha dato loro la vita 
durevole</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η μονάδα παρέχει το βασικό ιστορικό υπόβαθρο 
στη γαλλική επανάσταση. Θα δείξει ότι η επανάσταση 
επιτάχυνε τη διανοητική, πολιτιστική και ψυχολογική αλλαγή, και 
άνοιξε τους νέους ορίζοντες και τις δυνατότητες. Στην 
πραγματικότητα, ενώ πολλοί διαμάχη και σκεπτικισμός παραμένουν 
ως προς την πραγματική έκταση της ελλοχεύουσας αλλαγής στην 
κοινωνική και οικονομική δομή της Γαλλίας, συμφωνείται γενικά 
από τους μελετητές ότι η επανάσταση υποκίνησε μια διεύρυνση των 
προσδοκιών και της επινοητικής συνειδητοποίησης: μια 
πεποίθηση, που κληρονομούνται από το Διαφωτισμό, στη δυνατότητα 
της προόδου, καθώς επίσης και μια πεποίθηση ότι το κράτος και η 
κοινωνία θα μπορούσαν να ανασυγκροτηθούν με σκοπό να 
πραγματοποιήσουν τις κοινωνικές και μεμονωμένες φιλοδοξίες και την
ανθρώπινη ευτυχία γενικά. Δεδομένου ότι εκφυλίστηκε στη 
βία και την αιματοχυσία, εντούτοις, η επανάσταση προκάλεσε 
επίσης το σκεπτικισμό και την απαισιοδοξία για την πρόοδο και την 
ανθρώπινη φύση. Οι δύο βασικοί τύποι σύγχρονων πολιτικών 
προοπτικών, προοδευτικός και συντηρητικός, ημερομηνία από αυτήν 
την εμπειρία. Όποιος, ενδεχομένως, αυτών των συνόλων 
πεποιθήσεων ήταν αληθινός δεν είναι στο ζήτημα εδώ. Αυτό 
που πειράζει είναι ότι η επανάσταση τους προκάλεσε και τους 
έδωσε μόνιμη ζωή</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta unidad proporciona al fondo histórico 
básico a la revolución francesa. Mostrará que la revolución 
aceleró el cambio intelectual, cultural y psicologico, y abrió 
nuevos horizontes y posibilidades. En hecho, mientras que sigue 
habiendo mucha controversia y escepticismo en cuanto a el fragmento 
verdadero del cambio subyacente en la estructura social y económica 
de Francia, es convenido generalmente por los eruditos que la 
revolución estimuló ensanchar de expectativas y de conocimiento 
imaginativo: una creencia, heredada de la aclaración, en la 
posibilidad de progreso, así como una convicción que el estado y la 
sociedad se podrían reconstituir con objeto de realizar aspiraciones 
sociales e individuales y felicidad humana generalmente. Como 
degeneró en violencia y matanza, sin embargo, la revolución también
provocó escepticismo y pesimismo sobre progreso y la naturaleza 
humana. Los dos tipos básicos de perspectiva política moderna,
progresivo y conservador, fecha de esta experiencia. Cuál, si 
los hay, de estos conjuntos de creencia era verdad no está en la 
edición aquí. Qué importa es que la revolución les dio lugar
y les dio vida duradera</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste und Geschichte</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">French_revolution</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschichte</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts et histoire</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">French_revolution</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Histoire</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes e history</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">French_revolution</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">History</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti e storia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">French_revolution</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Storia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες και ιστορία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">French_revolution</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστορία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes e historia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">French_revolution</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Historia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <version>
            <string>1.0</string>
          </version>
          <status>
            <source>statusValues</source>
            <value>final</value>
          </status>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:openlearn.open.ac.uk:A207_5</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>LearningSpace</catalog>
            <entry>A207_5</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Open University
N:Open University
ORG:Open University
ADR:Walton Hall, Milton Keynes, Buckinghamshire, MK7 6AA, United Kingdom
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <language>en-gb</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:OpenLearn
N:OpenLearn
ORG:OpenLearn
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T17:13:51.89Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <technical>
          <format>text/html</format>
          <location>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/A207_5</location>
        </technical>
        <educational>
          <interactivityType>
            <source>interactivityTypeValues</source>
            <value>mixed</value>
          </interactivityType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>text</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <interactivityLevel>
            <source>interactivityLevelValues</source>
            <value>low</value>
          </interactivityLevel>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="en-gb">18+</string>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <difficulty>
            <source>difficultyValues</source>
            <value>medium</value>
          </difficulty>
          <typicalLearningTime>
            <duration>PT16H</duration>
          </typicalLearningTime>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">Independent self-study</string>
          </description>
          <language>en-gb</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en-gb">Licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution - NonCommercial-ShareAlike 2.0 Licence - see http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/uk/ - Original copyright The Open University</string>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/uk/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>references</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">An OU course on this topic</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>URL</catalog>
              <entry>http://www3.open.ac.uk/courses/bin/p12.dll?C01REPLACE</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>references</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">Study this topic at the OU</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>URL</catalog>
              <entry>http://www3.open.ac.uk/courses/classifications/humanities__arts__languages__history.shtm</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>references</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">open2.net: History &amp; The Arts</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>URL</catalog>
              <entry>http://www.open2.net/historyandthearts/index.html</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
        <relation>
          <kind>
            <source>LRE.kindValues</source>
            <value>isbasedon</value>
          </kind>
          <resource>
            <description>
              <string language="en-gb">This is the title and course code of the source course material</string>
            </description>
            <identifier>
              <catalog>Open University course</catalog>
              <entry>From Enlightenment to Romanticism - A207</entry>
            </identifier>
          </resource>
        </relation>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>A207_5 - web site</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>A207_5 - web site</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/A207_5</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>A207_5 - Common Cartridge 1.0</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>package in</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.packageInValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>imscc_v1p0</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>A207_5 - Common Cartridge 1.0</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/blocks/formats/logrequest.php?url=/file.php/1515/downloads/A207_5_ims_cc.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
      <entry>A207_5 - Content Package</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>package in</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.packageInValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>imscp_v1p1p4</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <identifier>
        <catalog>OpenLearn</catalog>
        <entry>A207_5 - Content Package</entry>
      </identifier>
      <location>
        <uri>http://openlearn.open.ac.uk/blocks/formats/logrequest.php?url=/file.php/1515/downloads/A207_5_ims_cp.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
