<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/29570</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>29570</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
    <entry>skolverket_7634</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_7634</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_7634</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">2.993 Special Topics in Mechanical Engineering: The Art and Science of Boat Design, January (IAP) 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">2.993 Spezielle Themen im Maschinenbauwesen:
Die kunst und die Wissenschaft des Boot Designs, Januar (IAP) 
2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">2.993 Sujets spéciaux en construction 
mécanique : L'art et la Science de la conception de bateau, 
janvier (IAP) 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">2.993 Tópicos especiais na engenharia 
mecânica: A arte e a ciência do projeto do barco, janeiro 
(IAP) 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">2.993 Soggetti speciali in ingegneria 
meccanica: Arte e scienza del disegno della barca, gennaio 
(pressione i.a.) 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">2.993 Ειδικά θέματα στη μηχανική εφαρμοσμένη 
μηχανική: Η τέχνη και η επιστήμη του σχεδίου βαρκών, 
Ιανουάριος (IAP) 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">2.993 Asuntos especiales en la ingeniería 
industrial: El arte y la ciencia del diseño del barco, enero 
(IAP) 2007 (MIT)</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An online course from the MIT OpenCourseWare website (http://ocw.mit.edu) operated by Massachusetts Institute of Technology. This course material is free for anyone to use who accept the terms and conditions of use. The description of this course, published on the MIT OpenCourseWare website, is: "This class is jointly sponsored by the MIT Museum, Massachusetts Bay Maritime Artisans, the Department of Mechanical Engineering s Center for Ocean Engineering, and the Department of Architecture. The course teaches the fundamental steps in traditional boat design and demonstrates connections between craft and modern methods. Instructors provide vessel design orientation and then students carve their own shape ideas in the form of a wooden half-hull model. Experts teach the traditional skills of visualizing and carving your model in this phase of the class. After the models are completed, a practicing naval architect guides students in translating shape from models into a lines plan. The final phase of the class is a comparative analysis of the designs generated by the group. "</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mechanical Engineering</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Onlinekurs von der MIT OpenCourseWare Web site
(http://ocw.mit.edu) funktionierte durch Massachusetts Institute of 
Technology. Dieses Kursmaterial ist frei, damit jedermann 
verwendet, wem die Bedingungen des Gebrauches annehmen. Die 
Beschreibung dieses Kurses, veröffentlicht auf der MIT OpenCourseWare
Web site, ist: "diese Kategorie wird gemeinsam durch das MIT 
Museum, die Massachusetts Bucht-Seehandwerker, die Abteilung der Mitte
des Maschinenbauwesen-s für Ozean-Technik und die Abteilung der 
Architektur gefördert. Der Kurs unterrichtet die grundlegenden 
Jobsteps im traditionellen Boot Design und zeigt Anschlüsse zwischen 
Fertigkeit und modernen Methoden. Ausbilder stellen 
Behälterdesignlagebestimmung zur Verfügung und dann schnitzen 
Kursteilnehmer ihre eigenen Formideen in Form eines hölzernen 
Hälfte-Rumpf Modells. Experten unterrichten die traditionellen 
Fähigkeiten des Sichtbar machens und des Schnitzens Ihres Modells in 
dieser Phase der Kategorie. Nachdem die Modelle durchgeführt 
sind, führen ein übender Marinearchitekt Kursteilnehmer, wenn er 
Form von den Modellen in Zeilen Plan übersetzt. Die 
abschließende Phase der Kategorie ist eine Analyse mit 
Vergleichswerten der Designs, die von der Gruppe "festgelegt werden</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un cours en ligne du site Web de MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) actionné par 
massachusetts.institute.of.technology. Ce matériel de cours est
libre pour que n'importe qui utilise qui reçoivent les modalités et 
les conditions de l'utilisation. La description de ce cours, 
éditée sur le site Web de MIT OpenCourseWare, est : "cette 
classe est conjointement commanditée par le musée de MIT, les 
artisans maritimes de compartiment du Massachusetts, le service du 
centre de la construction mécanique s pour l'ingénierie d'océan, et
le service de l'architecture. Le cours enseigne les étapes 
fondamentales dans la conception traditionnelle de bateau et démontre
des connexions entre le métier et les méthodes modernes. Les 
instructeurs fournissent l'orientation de conception de navire et 
alors les étudiants découpent leurs propres idées de forme sous 
forme de modèle en bois de moitié-coque. Les experts 
enseignent les techniques traditionnelles de visualiser et de 
découper votre modèle dans cette phase de la classe. Après 
que les modèles soient terminés, un architecte naval de pratique 
guident des étudiants en traduisant la forme des modèles dans des 
lignes plan. La phase finale de la classe est une analyse 
comparative des conceptions produites par le groupe "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um curso em linha do Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) operou-se por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material do curso está livre
para que qualquer um use-se quem aceitam os termos e as condições do
uso. A descrição deste curso, publicada no Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare, é: "esta classe é patrocinada conjuntamente 
pelo museu do MIT, pelos artisans marítimos da baía de 
Massachusetts, pelo departamento do centro da engenharia mecânica s 
para a engenharia do oceano, e pelo departamento da arquitetura. 
O curso ensina as etapas fundamentais no projeto tradicional do 
barco e demonstra conexões entre o ofício e métodos modernos. 
Os instrutores fornecem a orientação do projeto da 
embarcação e então os estudantes carve suas próprias idéias da 
forma no formulário de um modelo de madeira do metade-half-hull. 
Os peritos ensinam as habilidades tradicionais de visualizar e 
de carving seu modelo nesta fase da classe. Depois que os 
modelos são terminados, um arquiteto naval praticando guia estudantes
em traduzir a forma dos modelos no linhas planta. A fase final 
da classe é uma análise comparativa dos projetos gerados pelo grupo 
"</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un corso in linea dal Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) ha funzionato da Massachusetts 
Institute of Technology. Questo materiale di corso è libero 
affinchè chiunque usi chi accettano i termini e le condizioni di uso.
La descrizione di questo corso, pubblicata sul Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare, è: "questo codice categoria è patrocinato 
insieme dal museo del MIT, dagli artigianale marittimi della baia del 
Massachusetts, dal reparto del centro di ingegneria meccanica s per 
ingegneria dell'oceano e dal reparto di architettura. Il corso 
insegna i punti basilari nel disegno tradizionale della barca e 
dimostra i collegamenti fra il mestiere ed i metodi moderni. Gli
istruttori forniscono l'orientamento di disegno del vaso ed allora gli
allievi intagliano le loro proprie idee di figura sotto forma d'un 
modello di legno del metà-guscio. Gli esperti insegnano le 
tecniche tradizionali di prevedere e di scultura del vostro modello in
questa fase del codice categoria. Dopo che i modelli siano 
completati, un architetto navale esercitantesi guida gli allievi nella
traduzione della figura dai modelli nell'righe programma. La 
fase finale del codice categoria è un'analisi comparativa dei disegni
generati dal gruppo "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρά μαθημάτων από τον 
ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) που 
χρησιμοποιείται από το ίδρυμα της Μασαχουσέτης τεχνολογίας. 
Αυτό το υλικό σειράς μαθημάτων είναι ελεύθερο για καθένα 
να χρησιμοποιήσει ποιοι αποδέχονται τους όρους και τους όρους 
χρησιμοποίησης. Η περιγραφή αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων, που
δημοσιεύεται στον ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare, είναι: 
"Αυτή η κλάση υποστηρίζεται από κοινού από το μουσείο 
MIT, τον κόλπο θαλάσσιο Artisans της Μασαχουσέτης, το τμήμα 
κέντρου μηχανικής εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής s για την ωκεάνια 
εφαρμοσμένη μηχανική, και το τμήμα αρχιτεκτονικής. Η σειρά 
μαθημάτων διδάσκει τα θεμελιώδη βήματα στο παραδοσιακό σχέδιο 
βαρκών και καταδεικνύει τις συνδέσεις μεταξύ της τέχνης και των 
σύγχρονων μεθόδων. Οι εκπαιδευτικοί παρέχουν τον 
προσανατολισμό σχεδίου σκαφών και έπειτα οι σπουδαστές χαράζουν 
τις ιδέες μορφής τους υπό μορφή ξύλινου μοντέλου μισό-φλουδών.
Οι εμπειρογνώμονες διδάσκουν τις παραδοσιακές δεξιότητες της
απεικόνισης και της χάραξης του μοντέλου σας σε αυτήν την φάση 
της κλάσης. Αφότου ολοκληρώνονται τα μοντέλα, ένας εν 
ενεργεία ναυτικός αρχιτέκτονας καθοδηγεί τους σπουδαστές στη 
μετάφραση της μορφής από τα μοντέλα σε ένα σχέδιο γραμμών. 
Η τελική φάση της κλάσης είναι μια συγκριτική ανάλυση των 
σχεδίων που παράγονται από την ομάδα. "</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un curso en línea del Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) funcionado por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material del curso está 
libre para que cualquier persona utilice quiénes validan los 
términos y las condiciones del uso. La descripción de este 
curso, publicada en el Web site del MIT OpenCourseWare, es: 
"esta clase es patrocinada en común por el museo del MIT, los 
artesanos marítimos de la bahía de Massachusetts, el departamento 
del centro de la ingeniería industrial s para la ingeniería del 
océano, y el departamento de la configuración. El curso 
enseña los pasos de progresión fundamentales en diseño tradicional 
del barco y demuestra conexiones entre el arte y los métodos 
modernos. Los instructores proporcionan a la orientación del 
diseño del recipiente y entonces los estudiantes tallan sus propias 
ideas de la dimensión de una variable en la forma de un modelo de 
madera del mitad-casco. Los expertos enseñan las habilidades 
tradicionales de visualizar y de tallar su modelo en esta fase de la 
clase. Después de que se terminen los modelos, un arquitecto 
naval practicante dirige a estudiantes en traducir dimensión de una 
variable de modelos en las líneas plan. La fase final de la 
clase es un análisis comparativo de los diseños generados por el 
grupo "</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Maschinenbauwesen</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Construction Mécanique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Engenharia Mecânica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ingegneria Meccanica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μηχανική εφαρμοσμένη μηχανική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ingeniería Industrial</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>795</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">mechanical engineering</string>
                <string language="sv">maskinteknik</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_7634-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_7634-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-03-15T19:54:09.0Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
N:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
ORG:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T05:58:40.22Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
      <entry>skolverket_7634</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://ocw.mit.edu/OcwWeb/Mechanical-Engineering/2-993January--IAP--2007/CourseHome/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
