<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104872</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104872</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203161</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">How does the temperature of the Great Lakes change over time?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wie ändert die Temperatur der Great Lakes 
Überzeit?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comment la température des Great Lakes 
change-t-elle le temps fini ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Como a temperatura dos Great Lakes muda o tempo 
excedente?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Come la temperatura dei Great Lakes cambia col 
tempo?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πώς η θερμοκρασία των μεγάλων λιμνών αλλάζει κατά τη
διάρκεια του χρόνου;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Cómo la temperatura de los Great Lakes cambia en 
un cierto plazo?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This classroom activity allows students to use water surface temperature, bathymetric data and weather data to look at trends in the water temperature of the Great Lakes. The exercise asks students to make predictions, and then use the data to answer questions. The site contains everything that is needed for the exercise, including student handouts, maps, links to data sources, and background information and questions for discussion.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Klassenzimmeraktivität erlaubt Kursteilnehmern, 
Wasseroberflächentemperatur, Tiefendaten und Wetterdaten zu 
verwenden, um Tendenzen in der Wassertemperatur der Great Lakes zu 
betrachten. Die Übung bittet Kursteilnehmer, Vorhersagen zu 
bilden und verwendet dann die Daten, um Fragen zu beantworten. 
Die Site enthält alles, das für die Übung, einschließlich 
Handbücher, Karten, Links zu den Datenquellen und 
Hintergrundinformationen und Fragen für Diskussion erforderlich ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité de salle de classe permet à des 
étudiants d'utiliser la température de surface de l'eau, données 
bathymétriques et de survivre à à des données pour regarder 
des tendances dans la température de l'eau des Great Lakes. 
L'exercice demande à des étudiants de faire des prévisions, 
et puis emploie les données pour répondre à des questions. Le
site contient tout qui est nécessaire pour l'exercice, y compris des 
aumônes d'étudiant, les cartes, liens aux points d'émission de 
données, et l'information de fond et les questions pour la 
discussion.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade da sala de aula permite que os estudantes 
usem a temperatura de superfície da água, dados bathymetric e dados 
do tempo olhar tendências na temperatura de água dos Great Lakes. 
O exercício pede que os estudantes façam predições, e usa 
então os dados responder a perguntas. O local contem tudo que 
é needed para o exercício, including handouts de estudante, os 
mapas, ligações às origens dos dados de, e a informação e as 
perguntas de fundo para a discussão.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività dell'aula permette che gli allievi usino 
la temperatura in superficie dell'acqua, i dati batimetrici ed i dati 
del tempo per guardare le tendenze nella temperatura dell'acqua dei 
Great Lakes. L'esercitazione chiede agli allievi di fare le 
previsioni ed allora usa i dati per rispondere alle domande. Il 
luogo contiene tutto che sia necessario per l'esercitazione, compreso 
le dispense di allievo, programmi, collegamenti alle sorgenti di dati 
ed informazioni di base e domande per la discussione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η δραστηριότητα τάξεων επιτρέπει στους 
σπουδαστές για να χρησιμοποιήσει τη θερμοκρασία επιφάνειας 
ύδατος, τα βαθυμετρικά στοιχεία και τα καιρικά στοιχεία για να 
εξετάσει τις τάσεις στη θερμοκρασία ύδατος των μεγάλων λιμνών. 
Η άσκηση ζητά από τους σπουδαστές για να κάνει τις 
προβλέψεις, και να χρησιμοποιήσει έπειτα τα στοιχεία για να 
απαντήσει στις ερωτήσεις. Η περιοχή περιέχει όλα που 
απαιτούνται για την άσκηση, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των φυλλάδιων 
σπουδαστών, των χαρτών, των συνδέσεων με τις πηγές στοιχείων, και
των βασικών πληροφοριών και των ερωτήσεων για τη συζήτηση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad de la sala de clase permite que los 
estudiantes utilicen la temperatura superficial del agua, datos 
bathymetric y datos del tiempo para mirar tendencias en la temperatura
del agua de los Great Lakes. El ejercicio pide que los 
estudiantes hagan predicciones, y después utiliza los datos para 
contestar a preguntas. El sitio contiene todo que sea necesario 
para el ejercicio, incluyendo los folletos de estudiante, las 
correspondencias, conexiones a las fuentes de datos, e información y 
las preguntas de fondo para la discusión.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203161</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104872</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/how-does-the-temperature-of-the-great-lakes-change-over-time</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
