<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103059</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103059</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202612</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">English Historical Newsletter Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Englisches Historisches Rundschreiben-Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Projet Historique Anglais de Bulletin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Projeto Histórico Inglês Do Boletim de 
notícias</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progetto Storico Inglese Del Bollettino</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αγγλικό ιστορικό πρόγραμμα ενημερωτικών δελτίων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Proyecto Histórico Inglés Del Boletín de 
noticias</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is the major research activity for my senior English students enrolled in MHS average English. It is a term-long project that coincides with their ongoing thematic portfolios in British literature. These portfolios with other class ingredients (including this research activity) culminate in a final showcase portfolio which is their final exam. Students pick (first come, first served) from a list of decades and become an English subject of that decade. In this role, they are to publish a documented newsletter reflecting a week (covering 10 areas) of their life in the decade. They must also generate an annotated bibliography to document their multiple types of sources (20). Students must report on 3 required items (popular writer's latest effort, a new invention from the decade and a new clothing fashion). The remaining 7 areas come from a supplied list: a concert they attended, a new medical discovery, etc.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist die Hauptforschung Aktivität für 
meine älteren englischen Kursteilnehmer, die auf MHS 
durchschnittliches Englisch eingeschrieben werden. Es ist ein 
Bezeichnung-langes Projekt, das mit ihren fortwährenden thematischen 
Mappen in der britischen Literatur übereinstimmt. Diese Mappen 
mit anderen Kategorie Bestandteilen (einschließlich diese Forschung 
Aktivität) kulminieren in einer abschließenden Schaukastenmappe, die
ihre abschließende Prüfung ist. Kursteilnehmer wählen (zuerst
gekommen, zuerst gedient) von einer Liste von Dekaden und ein 
englisches Thema dieser Dekade geworden aus. In dieser Rolle 
sollen sie ein dokumentiertes Rundschreiben veröffentlichen, das eine
Woche (Bedeckung 10 Bereiche) reflektiert ihrer Lebensdauer in der 
Dekade. Sie müssen eine angemerkte Bibliographie auch 
festlegen, um ihre mehrfachen Typen der Quellen (20) zu dokumentieren.
Kursteilnehmer müssen über 3 benötigte Einzelteile (neueste 
Bemühung des populären Verfassers, eine neue Erfindung von der 
Dekade und eine neue Kleidung Art und Weise) berichten. Die 
restlichen 7 Bereiche kommen von einer angegebenen Liste: ein 
Konzert, das sie bedienten, eine neue medizinische Entdeckung, ein 
usw..</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est l'activité principale de recherches pour 
mes étudiants anglais aînés inscrits dans l'anglais moyen de MHS. 
C'est un limite-long projet qui coïncide avec leurs brochures 
thématiques continues en littérature britannique. Ces 
brochures avec d'autres ingrédients de classe (cette activité y 
compris de recherches) aboutissent à une brochure finale d'étalage 
qui est leur examen final. Les étudiants sélectionnent 
(d'abord venu, d'abord servi) d'une liste de décennies et devenue un 
sujet anglais de cette décennie. Dans ce rôle, ils doivent 
éditer un bulletin documenté reflétant une semaine (bâche 10 
zones) de leur vie dans la décennie. Ils doivent également 
produire d'une bibliographie annotée pour documenter leurs types 
multiples de sources (20). Les étudiants doivent rendre compte 
de 3 éléments priés (le dernier effort de l'auteur populaire, une 
nouvelle invention de la décennie et une nouvelle mode 
d'habillement). Les 7 zones restantes viennent d'une liste 
fournie : un concert qu'elles se sont occupé, une nouveaux 
découverte, etc.. médicaux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta é a atividade principal da pesquisa para 
meus estudantes ingleses sênior registrados no inglês médio do MHS.
É um projeto termo-longo que coincida com seus portfolios 
thematic ongoing na literatura britânica. Estes portfolios com 
outros ingredientes da classe (esta atividade including da pesquisa) 
culminam em um portfolio final do showcase que seja seu exam final. 
Os estudantes escolhem (vindo primeiramente, servido 
primeiramente) de uma lista das décadas e transformada um assunto 
inglês dessa década. Neste papel, devem publicar um boletim de
notícias documentado que reflete uma semana (covering 10 áreas) de 
sua vida na década. Devem também gerar uma bibliografia 
anotada para documentar seus tipos múltiplos das fontes (20). 
Os estudantes devem relatar em 3 artigos requeridos (o esforço 
o mais atrasado do escritor popular, uma invenção nova da década e 
uma forma nova da roupa). As 7 áreas restantes vêm de uma 
lista fornecida: um concert que atenderam, uma descoberta, etc. 
médicos novos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è l'attività principale di ricerca per i 
miei allievi inglesi maggiori iscritti all'inglese medio di MHS. 
È un progetto termine-lungo che coincide con le loro cartelle 
tematiche continue in letteratura britannica. Queste cartelle 
con altri ingredienti del codice categoria (questa attività compresa 
di ricerca) culminano in un finale montrano la cartella che è 
il loro exam finale. Gli allievi selezionano (in primo luogo 
venuto, in primo luogo servito) da una lista delle decadi e diventata 
un argomento inglese di quella decade. In questo ruolo, devono 
pubblicare un bollettino documentato che riflette una settimana 
(covering 10 zone) della loro vita nella decade. Devono anche 
generare una bibliografia critica per documentare i loro tipi multipli
di sorgenti (20). Gli allievi devono segnalare su 3 articoli 
richiesti (ultimo sforzo del produttore popolare, una nuova invenzione
dalla decade e un nuovo modo dei vestiti). Le 7 zone restanti 
vengono da una lista fornita: un concerto che hanno assistito a,
una nuovi scoperta, ecc medici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι η σημαντικότερη ερευνητική δραστηριότητα 
για τους ανώτερους αγγλικούς σπουδαστές μου που εγγράφονται στο 
MHS τα μέσα αγγλικά. Είναι ένα όρος-μακρύ πρόγραμμα 
που συμπίπτει με τα τρέχοντα θεματικά χαρτοφυλάκιά τους στη 
βρετανική λογοτεχνία. Αυτά τα χαρτοφυλάκια με άλλα 
συστατικά κλάσης (συμπεριλαμβανομένης αυτής της ερευνητικής 
δραστηριότητας) καταλήγουν σε ένα τελικό χαρτοφυλάκιο προθηκών 
που είναι ο τελικός διαγωνισμός τους. Οι σπουδαστές 
επιλέγουν ('αυτός που έρχεται πρώτος, εξυπηρετείται πρώτοσ') 
από έναν κατάλογο δεκαετιών και γίνονται ένας αγγλικός υπήκοος
εκείνης της δεκαετίας. Σε αυτόν τον ρόλο, πρόκειται να 
δημοσιεύσουν ένα τεκμηριωμένο ενημερωτικό δελτίο απεικονίζοντας 
μια εβδομάδα (που καλύπτει 10 περιοχές) της ζωής τους στη 
δεκαετία. Πρέπει επίσης να παραγάγουν μια σχολιασμένη 
βιβλιογραφία πιό πρόσφατη προσπάθεια για να τεκμηριώσουν τους 
πολλαπλάσιους τύπους τους σπουδαστών πηγών (20). πρέπει να 
υποβάλουν έκθεση σχετικά με 3 απαραίτητα αντικείμενα (του 
δημοφιλούς συγγραφέα, μια νέα εφεύρεση από τη δεκαετία και μια 
νέα μόδα ιματισμού). Οι υπόλοιπες 7 περιοχές προέρχονται 
από έναν παρεχόμενο κατάλογο: μια συναυλία που 
παρευρέθηκαν, μια νέα ιατρική ανακάλυψη, κ.λπ....</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ésta es la actividad principal de la 
investigación para mis estudiantes ingleses mayores alistados en 
inglés medio del MHS. Es un proyecto te'rmino-largo que 
coincide con sus listas temáticas en curso en literatura británica. 
Estas listas con otros ingredientes de la clase (esta actividad 
incluyendo de la investigación) culminan en una lista final del 
escaparate que sea su examen final. Los estudiantes escogen 
(primero venido, primero servido) de una lista de décadas y hecha un 
tema inglés de esa década. En este papel, deben publicar un 
boletín de noticias documentado que refleja una semana (cubierta 10 
áreas) de su vida en la década. Deben también generar una 
bibliografía anotada para documentar sus tipos múltiples de las 
fuentes (20). Los estudiantes deben señalar sobre 3 items 
requeridos (el esfuerzo más último del programa de escritura 
popular, una nueva invención a partir de la década y una nueva 
manera de la ropa). Las 7 áreas restantes vienen de una lista 
provista: un concierto que atendieron, un nuevos descubrimiento,
etc médicos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JOE HUDDLESTON
FN:JOE HUDDLESTON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202612</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103059</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/english-historical-newsletter-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
