<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106907</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106907</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203785</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Marine Bioluminescence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Marinebioluminescence</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bioluminescence Marin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Bioluminescence Marinho</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bioluminescence Marino</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θαλάσσια βιολογική ακτινοβολία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Bioluminescence Marina</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This classroom activity is part of the Smithsonian's Giant Squid Curriculum. It uses flashlights to teach students about luminescence, counterillumination, and photophores. In the scope of this activity, students will identify luminescence and brainstorm possible reasons for its biological purpose and function. The activity includes a detailed procedure accompanied with questions teachers can ask in order to promote inquiry and classroom discussion. A link directs teachers to background content about the Giant Squid.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Klassenzimmeraktivität ist ein Teil des 
Smithsonian riesigen Kalmar-Lehrplans. Sie benutzt 
Taschenlampen, um Kursteilnehmer über Lumineszenz, 
counterillumination und photophores zu unterrichten. Im Bereich 
dieser Aktivität, kennzeichnen Kursteilnehmer Lumineszenz und lösen 
mögliche Gründe zu seinem biologischen Zweck und zu Funktion 
gedanklich. Die Aktivität schließt eine ausführliche Prozedur
ein, die mit Fragen begleitet wird, die Lehrer stellen können, um 
Anfrage und Klassenzimmerdiskussion zu fördern. Ein Link 
verweist Lehrer auf Hintergrundinhalt über den riesigen Kalmar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité de salle de classe fait partie du 
programme d'études géant Smithsonien de calmar. Elle utilise 
des lampes-torches pour enseigner des étudiants au sujet de 
luminescence, de counterillumination, et de photophores. Dans la
portée de cette activité, les étudiants identifieront la 
luminescence et feront un brainstorm des raisons possibles de son but 
et fonction biologiques. L'activité inclut un procédé 
détaillé accompagné avec des questions que les professeurs peuvent 
poser afin de favoriser l'enquête et la discussion de salle de 
classe. Un lien dirige des professeurs vers le contenu de fond 
au sujet du calmar géant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade da sala de aula é parte do 
curriculum gigante smithsonian do calamar. Usa lanternas 
elétricas ensinar estudantes sobre o luminescence, o 
counterillumination, e os photophores. No espaço desta 
atividade, os estudantes identificarão o luminescence e brainstorm 
razões possíveis para suas finalidade e função biológicas. 
A atividade inclui um procedimento detalhado acompanhado com 
perguntas que os professores podem fazer a fim promover o inquérito e
a discussão da sala de aula. Uma ligação dirige professores 
ao índice do fundo sobre o calamar gigante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività dell'aula fa parte del programma 
di studi gigante smithsonian del calamaro. Utilizza le pile per 
insegnare gli allievi circa luminescenza, il counterillumination ed i 
photophores. Nella portata di questa attività, gli allievi 
identificheranno la luminescenza e brainstorm motivi possibili per il 
relativi scopo e funzione biologici. L'attività include una 
procedura dettagliata accompagnata con le domande che gli insegnanti 
possono fare per promuovere l'inchiesta e la discussione dell'aula. 
Un collegamento dirige gli insegnanti verso il soddisfare della 
priorità bassa circa il calamaro gigante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η δραστηριότητα τάξεων είναι μέρος του 
σμιθσονιτικού γιγαντιαίου προγράμματος σπουδών καλαμαριών. 
Χρησιμοποιεί τους φακούς για να διδάξει τους σπουδαστές για 
luminescence, counterillumination, και photophores. Στο
πεδίο αυτής της δραστηριότητας, οι σπουδαστές θα προσδιορίσουν 
luminescence και καταιγισμού ιδεών τους πιθανούς λόγους για το 
βιολογικούς σκοπό και τη λειτουργία του. Η δραστηριότητα 
περιλαμβάνει μια λεπτομερή διαδικασία που συνοδεύεται με τους 
δασκάλους ερωτήσεων μπορεί να ζητήσει προκειμένου να προωθηθούν 
η έρευνα και η συζήτηση τάξεων. Μια σύνδεση κατευθύνει τους
δασκάλους στο περιεχόμενο υποβάθρου για το γιγαντιαίο καλαμάρι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad de la sala de clase es parte del 
plan de estudios gigante smithsonian del calamar. Utiliza las 
linternas para enseñar a estudiantes sobre luminescencia, el 
counterillumination, y photophores. En el alcance de esta 
actividad, los estudiantes identificarán luminescencia y se 
inspirarán las razones posibles de su propósito y función 
biológicos. La actividad incluye un procedimiento detallado 
acompañado con preguntas que los profesores pueden hacer para 
promover pregunta y la discusión de la sala de clase. Una 
conexión dirige a profesores al contenido del fondo sobre el calamar 
gigante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GIANT SQUID CURRICULUM MODULE
FN:GIANT SQUID CURRICULUM MODULE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SMITHSONIAN INSTITUTE'S NATIONAL MUSEUM OF NATURAL HISTORY
FN:SMITHSONIAN INSTITUTE'S NATIONAL MUSEUM OF NATURAL HISTORY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203785</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106907</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/marine-bioluminescence</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
