<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103313</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103313</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209946</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Triangle Incenter </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dreieck Incenter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Triangle Incenter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Triângulo Incenter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Triangolo Incenter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τρίγωνο Incenter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Triángulo Incenter</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A web page and interactive applet demonstrating the concept of the incenter of a triangle. The applet shows a triangle where the user can drag the vertices around. The incenter and the angle bisector lines that generate it are continuously moved as the user drags the vertices. By experimentation the user can observe that the incenter always remains inside the triangle. The page text explains the definition of the incenter and how to find it. It describes how the incenter is also the center of the incircle of the triangle with a link to that page http://www.mathopenref.com/triangleincenter.html Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Webseite und ein interaktiver applet, die das
Konzept des incenter eines Dreiecks zeigen. Der applet zeigt 
einem Dreieck, wo der Benutzer die Gipfel herum schleppen kann. 
Das incenter und die Winkel bisector Zeilen, die es festlegen, 
werden ununterbrochen verschoben, während der Benutzer die Gipfel 
schleppt. Durch Experimentieren kann der Benutzer beobachten, 
daß das incenter immer innerhalb des Dreiecks bleibt. Der Seite
Text beschreibt die Definition des incenter und wie man es findet. 
Er beschreibt, wie das incenter auch die Mitte des incircle des 
Dreiecks mit einem Link zu diesem Seite 
http://www.mathopenref.com/triangleincenter.html applet kann zum 
vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor 
vergrößert werden ist. Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, 
Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause 
oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. 
Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes 
Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une page Web et un applet interactif démontrant
le concept de l'incenter d'une triangle. L'applet montre à une 
triangle où l'utilisateur peut traîner les sommets autour. 
L'incenter et les lignes de bisector d'angle qui produisent de 
lui sont sans interruption déplacés pendant que l'utilisateur 
traîne les sommets. Par expérimentation l'utilisateur peut 
observer que l'incenter demeure toujours à l'intérieur de la 
triangle. Le texte de page explique la définition de l'incenter
et comment le trouver. Il décrit comment l'incenter est 
également le centre de l'incircle de la triangle avec un lien à cet 
applet de la page http://www.mathopenref.com/triangleincenter.html 
peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour l'usage avec un 
projecteur de salle de classe. Le après utilisation dans la 
salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder encore de n'importe quel 
navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la bibliothèque sans la 
procédure de connexion exigée. Cette ressource est un 
composant du projet interactif de manuel de la géométrie de 
référence ouverte de maths à http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um Web page e um applet interativo que demonstram 
o conceito do incenter de um triângulo. O applet mostra a um 
triângulo onde o usuário pode arrastar os vertices ao redor. O
incenter e as linhas do bisector do ângulo que o geram são movidos 
continuamente enquanto o usuário arrasta os vertices. Pela 
experimentação o usuário pode observar que o incenter remanesce 
sempre dentro do triângulo. O texto da página explica a 
definição do incenter e como encontrá-lo. Descreve como o 
incenter é também o centro do incircle do triângulo com uma 
ligação a esse applet da página 
http://www.mathopenref.com/triangleincenter.html pode ser ampliado ao 
tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. 
O depois de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la 
outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum 
início de uma sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente 
do projeto interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta 
do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Web page e un applet interattivo che dimostrano
il concetto del incenter di un triangolo. Il applet mostra ad un
triangolo dove l'utente può trascinare i vertici intorno. Il 
incenter e le righe di bisector di angolo che lo generano sono 
spostati continuamente mentre l'utente trascina i vertici. Da 
esperimento l'utente può osservare che il incenter rimane sempre 
all'interno del triangolo. Il testo della pagina spiega la 
definizione del incenter e come trovarlo. Descrive come il 
incenter è anche il centro del incircle del triangolo con un 
collegamento a quel applet della pagina 
http://www.mathopenref.com/triangleincenter.html può essere 
ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore 
dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può 
accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria 
senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un 
componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστοσελίδας και διαλογικό ένα applet που 
καταδεικνύουν την έννοια του incenter ενός τριγώνου. Το 
applet εμφανίζει ένα τρίγωνο όπου ο χρήστης μπορεί να σέρει 
vertices γύρω. Το incenter και οι διαχωριστικές γραμμές
γωνίας που παράγουν αυτό κινούνται συνεχώς δεδομένου ότι ο 
χρήστης σέρνει vertices. Από τον πειραματισμό ο χρήστης 
μπορεί να παρατηρήσει ότι το incenter παραμένει πάντα μέσα 
στο τρίγωνο. Το κείμενο σελίδων εξηγεί τον καθορισμό του 
incenter και πώς να τον βρεί. Περιγράφει πώς το 
incenter είναι επίσης το κέντρο του incircle του τριγώνου με
μια σύνδεση με εκείνη την σελίδα 
http://www.mathopenref.com/triangleincenter.html Applet μπορεί 
να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν 
προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε 
ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια 
εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων 
γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un Web page y un applet interactivo que demuestran
el concepto del incenter de un triángulo. El applet muestra a 
triángulo donde el utilizador puede arrastrar las cimas alrededor. 
El incenter y las líneas del bisector del ángulo que lo 
generan se mueven continuamente mientras que el utilizador arrastra 
las cimas. Por la experimentación el utilizador puede observar 
que sigue habiendo el incenter siempre dentro del triángulo. El
texto de la paginación explica la definición del incenter y cómo 
encontrarlo. Describe cómo el incenter es también el centro 
del incircle del triángulo con una conexión a ese applet de la 
paginación http://www.mathopenref.com/triangleincenter.html se puede 
agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209946</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103313</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/triangle-incenter</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
