<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106909</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106909</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087454</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Burned at the Stake: A Black Man Pays for a Town's Outrage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gebrannt an der Stange: Ein schwarzer Mann 
zahlt für das Verbrechen einer Stadt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Brûlé au pieu : Un homme noir paye 
l'outrage d'une ville</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Queimado na estaca: Um homem preto paga pelo 
ultraje de uma cidade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Bruciato al palo: Un uomo nero paga 
l'oltraggio della città</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μμένος στον πάσσαλο: Ένα μαύρο άτομο πληρώνει 
για την προσβολή μιας πόλης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Quemado en la estaca: Un hombre negro paga el
ultraje de una ciudad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">From the eighteenth to the mid-nineteenth centuries, the term "lynching" did not have any racial implications. Targets included Tories, horse thieves, gamblers, and abolitionists. But starting in the 1880s, mob violence was increasingly directed at African Americans. Between 1882 and 1964, nearly five thousand people died from lynching, the majority African-American. The 1890s witnessed the worst period of lynching in U.S. history. The grim statistical record almost certainly understates the story. Many lynchings were not recorded outside their immediate locality, and pure numbers do not convey the brutality of lynching. In early 1893, a white reporter, writing in the New York  Sun , offered a grisly account of the burning at the stake in Paris, Texas, of a black man accused of molesting a white girl.As press accounts like this make clear, to witness a lynching--or even just glimpse its aftermath--could be a searing experience for those who were the most likely victims of the lynch mob--young African-American males. That, indeed, was the intention--the threat of lynching was a powerful mechanism for keeping black Southerners in line.   In response to the rising tide of lynchings of African-Americans across the South during the 1890s, Memphis, Tennessee, newspaper editor Ida Wells-Barnett launched a national anti-lynching crusade.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Von den achtzehnten bis mittler-19.jahrhunderten 
hatte die "lynchende" Bezeichnung keine rassischen Implikationen. 
Ziele enthielten Tories, Pferd Diebe, Spieler und abolitionists.
Aber, beginnend im 1880s, wurde Pöbelgewalttätigkeit in 
zunehmendem Maße an den afrikanischen Amerikanern verwiesen. 
Zwischen 1882 und 1964 starben fast fünf tausend Leute am 
Lynchen, die Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Majorität. Das 1890s 
zeugte die falschste Periode des Lynchens in der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Geschichte. Der grimmige statistische Satz understates fast 
zweifellos die Geschichte. Viele lynchings wurden nicht 
außerhalb ihrer sofortigen Stelle gespeichert, und reine Zahlen 
übermitteln nicht die Brutalitäten des Lynchens. Frühem 1893
bot ein weißer Reporter, schreibend in die New York Sonne, ein grisly
Konto des Brennens an der Stange in Paris, Texas, eines schwarzen 
Mannes an, der belästigenRechnungsprüfungen einer weiße girl.As 
Presse wie diesen Marke freien Raum beschuldigt wurde, um ein Lynchen 
zu zeugen -- oder sogar gerechter Blick seine Nachmahd -- könnte eine
verwelkende Erfahrung für die sein, die die wahrscheinlichsten Opfer 
des lynchenpöbels -- junge Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Männer waren. 
Daß in der Tat die Absicht -- die Drohung des Lynchens war, war
eine leistungsfähige Einheit für das Halten von von schwarzem 
Southerners in der Zeile. In Erwiderung auf die steigenden 
Gezeiten von lynchings der Afrikanisch-Amerikaner über dem 
Süden während des 1890s, stieß Memphis, Tennessee, Zeitungsverleger
Ida Vertiefungen-Barnett einen nationalen Anti-lynchenden Kreuzzug 
aus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des dix-huitième à mi-dix-neuvième siècles, le 
terme "lynchant" n'a eu aucune implication raciale. Les cibles 
ont inclus des Conservateurs, des voleurs de cheval, des joueurs, et des
abolitionnistes. Mais commençant dans le 1880s, la violence de 
foule a été de plus en plus dirigée aux Américains africains. 
Entre 1882 et 1964, presque cinq mille personnes sont mortes de 
lyncher, l'Afro-Américain de majorité. Le 1890s était témoin de 
la plus mauvaise période de lyncher dans l'histoire des ETATS-UNIS. 
L'enregistrement statistique sinistre minimise presque 
certainement l'histoire. Beaucoup de lynchings n'ont pas été 
enregistrés en dehors de leur localité immédiate, et les nombres 
purs ne donnent pas la brutalité de lyncher. Début 1893, un 
journaliste blanc, écrivant dans le soleil de New York, a offert un 
compte effroyable de la brûlure au pieu à Paris, le Texas, d'un 
homme noir accusé des comptes blancs molestants d'une presse de 
girl.As comme cet espace libre de marque, pour être témoin de 
lyncher aperçu -- ou même juste sa conséquence -- pourrait être 
une expérience desséchante pour telles qui étaient les victimes le 
plus susceptibles de la foule de lyncher -- jeunes mâles 
afro-américains. Que, en effet, était l'intention -- la menace de 
lyncher était un mécanisme puissant pour maintenir les Habitants du sud 
noirs dans la ligne. En réponse à la marée se levante des 
lynchings des Afro-Américains à travers les Sud pendant le 
1890s, Memphis, Tennessee, Puits-Barnett d'Ida d'éditeur de journal a
lancé une croisade anti-lynchante nationale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dos décimos oitavos a mid-décimos nonos séculos,
o termo "que lynching" não teve nenhumas implicações raciais. 
Os alvos incluíram tories, ladrões do cavalo, gamblers, e 
abolitionists. Mas começando no 1880s, a violência do mob foi 
dirigida cada vez mais em americanos africanos. Entre 1882 e 
1964, quase cinco mil povos morreram de lynching, maioria 
Africano-Americana. O 1890s testemunhou o período o mais mau de
lynching no history de ESTADOS UNIDOS. O registro estatístico 
grim suaviza quase certamente a história. Muitos lynchings não
foram gravados fora de seu locality imediato, e os números puros não
fazem saber ao brutality de lynching. Em 1893 adiantado, um 
repórter branco, escrevendo no sol de New York, ofereceu um cliente 
grisly da queimadura na estaca em Paris, Texas, de um homem preto 
acusado de clientes brancos molestando de uma imprensa de girl.As como
este espaço livre do make, para testemunhar lynching -- ou para 
nivelar o glimpse justo seu aftermath -- poderia ser uma experiência 
searing para aqueles que eram as vítimas mais prováveis do mob do 
lynch -- machos Africano-Americanos novos. Que, certamente, era 
a intenção -- a ameaça de lynching era um mecanismo poderoso para 
manter Southerners preto na linha. Em resposta à maré 
levantando-se dos lynchings dos Africano-Americanos através do sul 
durante o 1890s, Memphis, Tennessee, Poços-Barnett de Ida do editor 
de jornal lançou um crusade anti-anti-lynching nacional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dai diciottesimi - metà di-diciannovesimi secoli, 
il termine "che lynching" non ha avuto alcune implicazioni razziali. 
Gli obiettivi hanno incluso i tories, i ladri del cavallo, i 
gamblers ed i abolitionists. Ma cominciando nel 1880s, la 
violenza del mob sempre più è stata diretta agli Americani africani.
Fra 1882 e 1964, quasi cinque mila genti sono morto dal 
lynching, la maggioranza Africano-Americana. Il 1890s ha 
testimoniato il periodo più difettoso di lynching nella storia degli 
STATI UNITI. Il record statistico torvo quasi certamente 
minimizza la storia. Molti lynchings non sono stati registrati 
fuori della loro località immediata ed i numeri puri non trasportano 
il brutality di lynching. All'inizio di 1893, un reporter 
bianco, scrivente nel sole de New York, ha offerto un cliente grisly 
del bruciarsi al palo a Parigi, il Texas, di un uomo nero accusato dei
clienti bianchi molestanti della pressa di girl.As come questa radura 
di marca, per testimoniare lynching -- o persino glimpse giusto il 
relativo guaime -- potrebbe essere un'esperienza searing per coloro 
che era le vittime più probabili del mob di lynch -- maschi 
Africano-Americani giovani. Che, effettivamente, era 
l'intenzione -- la minaccia di lynching era un meccanismo potente per 
mantenere Southerners nero nella riga. In risposta alla marea 
aumentante dei lynchings degli Africano-Americani attraverso il sud 
durante il 1890s, Memphis, Tennessee, Pozzi-Barnett di Ida 
dell'editore di giornale ha lanciato un crusade anti-anti-lynching 
nazionale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από το δέκατο όγδοο στους μέσος-δέκατους έννατους 
αιώνες, ο όρος "που λυντσάρει" δεν είχε οποιεσδήποτε φυλετικές 
επιπτώσεις. Οι στόχοι περιέλαβαν tories, τους κλέφτες 
αλόγων, τους παίκτες, και τους ρεφορμιστές. Αλλά αρχικός 
στο 1880s, η βία όχλου κατευθύνθηκε όλο και περισσότερο σε 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς. Μεταξύ 1882 και 1964, σχεδόν
πέντε χιλιάες άνθρωποι πέθαναν από το λυντσάρισμα, η πλειοψηφία
αφρικανικός-Αμερικανός. Το 1890s βεβαίωσε τη χειρότερη 
περίοδο λυντσαρίσματος στην ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΉ ιστορία. Το απαίσιο
στατιστικό αρχείο σχεδόν βεβαίως μειώνει την ιστορία. 
Πολλά λυντσαρίσματα δεν καταγράφηκαν έξω από την άμεση 
τοποθεσία τους, και οι καθαροί αριθμοί δεν μεταβιβάζουν τη 
βιαιότητα του λυντσαρίσματος. Σε πρόωρα 1893, ένας 
λευκός δημοσιογράφος, που γράφει στον ήλιο της Νέας Υόρκης, 
πρόσφερε έναν φρικιαστικό απολογισμό του καψίματος στον πάσσαλο 
στο Παρίσι, Τέξας, ενός μαύρου ατόμου που κατηγορήθηκε για την 
κακοποίηση ενός λευκού κοριτσιού Δεδομένου ότι οι 
απολογισμοί Τύπου όπως αυτό καθιστούν σαφές, να βεβαιώσει ένα 
λυντσάρισμα -- ή ακόμα και ακριβώς την αναλαμπή η συνέπειά του 
-- θα μπορούσε να είναι μια searing εμπειρία για εκείνους που 
ήταν τα πλέον πιθανά θύματα λυντσάρουν τον όχλο -- νέα 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά αρσενικά. Ότι, πράγματι, ήταν η 
πρόθεση -- η απειλή του λυντσαρίσματος ήταν ένας ισχυρός 
μηχανισμός για τους μαύρους νοτίους στη γραμμή. Σε απάντηση
στην αυξανόμενη παλίρροια των λυντσαρισμάτων 
αφρικανικός-Αμερικανών πέρα από το νότο κατά τη διάρκεια του 
1890s, Μέμφιδα, Tennessee, ο επεξεργαστής IDA φρεάτιο- 
Barnett εφημερίδων προώθησε μια εθνική σταυροφορία 
αντι-λυντσαρίσματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">A partir de los décimo octavos a mediados 
de-diecinueveavo siglos, el término "lynching" no tenía ninguna 
implicaciones racial. Las blancos incluyeron tories, ladrones 
del caballo, jugadores, y abolitionists. Pero comenzando en el 
1880s, la violencia de la multitud fue dirigida cada vez más en los 
americanos africanos. Entre 1882 y 1964, casi cinco mil personas
murieron de lynching, la mayoría Africano-Americana. El 1890s 
atestiguó el período peor de lynching en la historia de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS. El expediente estadístico severo minimisa casi 
ciertamente la historia. Muchos lynchings no fueron registrados 
fuera de su lugar inmediato, y los números puros no transportan la 
brutalidad de lynching. A principios de 1893, un reportero 
blanco, escribiendo en el sol de Nueva York, ofreció una cuenta 
espantosa de quemarse en la estaca en París, Tejas, de un hombre 
negro acusado de cuentas blancas de una prensa de girl.As que 
molestaban como este claro de la marca, para atestiguar lynching -- o 
aún justa ojeada sus consecuencias -- podría ser una experiencia que
se chamuscaba para los que eran las víctimas más probable de la 
multitud del lynch -- varones Africano-Americanos jóvenes. Que,
estaba de hecho la intención -- la amenaza de lynching era un 
mecanismo de gran alcance para mantener Southerners negro línea. 
En respuesta a la marea de levantamiento de lynchings de 
Africano-Americanos a través del sur durante el 1890s, Memphis, 
Tennessee, Receptores de papel-Barnett de Ida del redactor lanzó una 
cruzada contra-anti-lynching nacional.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087454</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106909</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/burned-at-the-stake-a-black-man-pays-for-a-towns-outrage</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
