<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107997</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107997</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203055</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hands-on Experiments To Test for Acid Mine Drainage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blindeinschub Experimente zum Test für saure 
Grube Entwässerung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Expériences à commande manuelle à l'essai pour 
le drainage acide de mine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Experiências hands-on ao teste para a drenagem 
ácida da mina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esperimenti hands-on alla prova per drenaggio 
acido della miniera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εμπράγματα πειράματα στη δοκιμή για την όξινη 
αποξήρανση ορυχείου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Experimentos con manos a la prueba para el drenaje
ácido de la mina</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is an on-line prototype for a book aimed at teaching kids the effects of acid mine drainage on our environment through experimentation and observation. Experiments introduce litmus paper, pH testing, neutralization, identification of aquatic organisms and their use as water quality indicators, acid mine drainage, organisms in acidic environments (including plants, bacteria, and algae), oxidation-reduction reactions, the manganese cycle, the water cycle, and treatments for acid mine drainage. The entire document is also available in a downloadable Adobe PDF format.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist ein Onlineprototyp für ein Buch, das 
Zicklein die Effekte der sauren Grube Entwässerung auf unserer 
Umgebung durch Experimentieren und Beobachtung beibringend angestrebt 
wird. Experimente stellen Lackmuspapier vor, prüfenden pH, 
Neutralisation, Kennzeichen der Wasserorganismen und ihres Gebrauches 
während Wasserqualitätanzeigen, saure Grube Entwässerung, 
organismen in den säurehaltigen Umgebungen (einschließlich Betriebe,
Bakterium und Algen), Oxidation-Reduktionreaktionen, die 
Manganschleife, die Wasserschleife und die Behandlungen auf saure 
Grube Entwässerung. Das gesamte Dokument ist auch in einem 
downloadableluftgetrockneter Ziegelstein pdf Format vorhanden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est un prototype en ligne pour un livre visé 
enseignant à des gosses les effets du drainage acide de mine sur 
notre environnement par l'expérimentation et l'observation. Les
expériences présentent le papier tournesol, le pH déterminant, la 
neutralisation, l'identification des organizations aquatiques et de 
leur utilisation pendant que des indicateurs de qualité de l'eau, le 
drainage acide de mine, les organizations dans les environnements 
acides (usines y compris, bactéries, et algues), les réactions 
d'oxydation/réduction, le cycle de manganèse, le cycle de l'eau, et 
des traitements le drainage acide de mine. Le document entier 
est également disponible dans un format downloadable de pdf d'adobe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este é um protótipo em linha para um livro 
visado ensinando a miúdos os efeitos da drenagem ácida da mina em 
nosso ambiente com a experimentação e a observação. As 
experiências introduzem o papel de litmus, o pH que testam, a 
neutralização, a identificação de organismos aquáticos e de seu 
uso enquanto indicadores da qualidade de água, a drenagem ácida da 
mina, os organismos em ambientes acidic (plantas including, 
bactérias, e algas), as reações do oxidation-reduction, o ciclo do 
manganês, o ciclo da água, e tratamentos para a drenagem ácida da 
mina. O original inteiro está também disponível em um formato
downloadable do pdf do adôbe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è un prototipo in linea per un libro puntato
su insegnando a capretti gli effetti di drenaggio acido della miniera 
sul nostro ambiente con l'esperimento e l'osservazione. Gli 
esperimenti introducono la carta da tornasole, il pH che esaminano, la
neutralizzazione, l'identificazione degli organismi acquatici e del 
loro uso mentre indicatori di qualità dell'acqua, il drenaggio acido 
della miniera, gli organismi negli ambienti silicei (piante comprese, 
batteri ed alghe), le reazioni di ossidazione/riduzione, il ciclo del 
manganese, il ciclo dell'acqua ed i trattamenti a drenaggio acido 
della miniera. L'intero documento è egualmente disponibile in 
un formato downloadable del pdf dell'adobe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι ένα σε απευθείας σύνδεση πρωτότυπο για 
ένα βιβλίο που στοχεύει στα κατσίκια διδασκαλίας τα αποτελέσματα
της όξινης αποξήρανσης ορυχείων στο περιβάλλον μας μέσω του 
πειραματισμού και της παρατήρησης. Τα πειράματα εισάγουν 
litmus το έγγραφο, τη δοκιμή pH, την ουδετεροποίηση, τον 
προσδιορισμό των υδρόβιων οργανισμών και της χρήσης τους ως 
δείκτες ποιότητας νερού, την όξινη αποξήρανση ορυχείων, τους 
οργανισμούς στα όξινα περιβάλλοντα (συμπεριλαμβανομένων των 
εγκαταστάσεων, των βακτηριδίων, και των αλγών), τις 
oxidation-reduction αντιδράσεις, τον κύκλο μαγγάνιου, τον κύκλο
ύδατος, και τις επεξεργασίες για την όξινη αποξήρανση ορυχείων. 
Το ολόκληρο έγγραφο είναι επίσης διαθέσιμο με μια 
τηλεκατεγραφόμενη μορφή πλίθας PDF.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esto es un prototipo en línea para un libro 
dirigido enseñando a cabritos los efectos del drenaje ácido de la 
mina en nuestro ambiente con la experimentación y la observación. 
Los experimentos introducen el papel de tornasol, el pH que 
prueba, la neutralización, la identificación de organismos 
acuáticos y de su uso mientras que los indicadores de la calidad del 
agua, el drenaje ácido de la mina, organismos en ambientes ácidos 
(plantas incluyendo, las bacterias, y las algas), las reacciones del 
oxidation-reduction, el ciclo del manganeso, el ciclo del agua, y los 
tratamientos para el drenaje ácido de la mina. El documento 
entero está también disponible en un formato downloadable del pdf 
del adobe.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ELEANORA ROBBINS
FN:ELEANORA ROBBINS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SANDRA MCSURDY
FN:SANDRA MCSURDY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:TIMOTHY CRADDOCK
FN:TIMOTHY CRADDOCK
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:UNITED STATES GEOLOGICAL SURVEY (USGS)
FN:UNITED STATES GEOLOGICAL SURVEY (USGS)
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203055</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107997</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/hands-on-experiments-to-test-for-acid-mine-drainage</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
