<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104170</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104170</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205593</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mars Exploration Rover Mission</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mars Erforschung-Vagabund-Mission</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mission de Vagabond d'Exploration de Mars</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Missão Do Vagabundo Da Exploração De Marte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Missione Del Vagabondo Di Esplorazione Del Marte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αποστολή πλανών εξερεύνησης του Αρη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Misión Del Rover De la Exploración De Marte</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site provides images and updates on the two Mars rovers, Spirit and Opportunity, which landed on Mars in 2004. Videos and text depict the challenges of getting to Mars: testing the rovers on Martian terrain, launching the rovers, navigating their flights, bringing them into the Martian atmosphere, landing them, and getting them out of the lander cocoon.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site stellt Bilder und 
Aktualisierungsvorgänge auf den zwei Mars Vagabunden, Geist und 
Gelegenheit zur Verfügung, die auf Mars 2004 landeten. Videos 
und Text stellen die Herausforderungen des Gelangens an Mars bildlich 
dar: Prüfung die Vagabunden auf Martian Gelände, die 
Vagabunden ausstoßend und steuern ihre Flüge und holen sie in 
die Martian Atmosphäre und landen sie und das Erhalten sie aus dem 
lander Kokon heraus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site fournit des images et des mises à jour 
sur les deux vagabonds, esprits et occasions de Mars, qui ont 
débarqué sur Mars en 2004. Videos et texte dépeignent les 
défis d'obtenir à Mars : testant les vagabonds sur le terrain 
de Martian, lançant les vagabonds, dirigeant leurs vols, les 
introduisant dans l'atmosphère de Martian, débarquant eux, et les 
obtenir hors du cocon de lander.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local fornece imagens e updates nos dois 
vagabundos, espíritos e oportunidades de Marte, que aterraram em 
Marte em 2004. Videos e o texto descrevem os desafios de 
começar a Marte: testando os vagabundos no terreno de Martian, 
lançando os vagabundos, navigating seus vôos, trazendo os na 
atmosfera de Martian, aterrando os, e começá-los fora do casulo do 
lander.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo fornisce le immagini e gli 
aggiornamenti sui due vagabondi, spirito ed occasioni del Marte, che 
hanno atterrato su Marte in 2004. Videos ed il testo descrivono 
le sfide di ottenere a Marte: esaminando i vagabondi sul terreno
del Martian, lanciando i vagabondi, traversando i loro voli, 
introducendoli nell'atmosfera del Martian, atterrando loro ed 
ottenerli dal bozzolo del lander.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει τις εικόνες και τις 
αναπροσαρμογές στους δύο πλάνες, το πνεύμα και την ευκαιρία του 
Αρη, οι οποίες προσγειώθηκαν στον Αρη σε 2004, βίντεο και το 
κείμενο απεικονίζει τις προκλήσεις να πάρει στον Αρη: 
δοκιμή των πλανών στην Αριανή έκταση, προώθηση των πλανών,
πλοήγηση των πτήσεών τους, να φέρει τις στην Αριανή ατμόσφαιρα, 
προσγείωση τους, και να πάρει τις από το κουκούλι lander.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio proporciona a imágenes y a 
actualizaciones en los dos rovers, alcoholes y oportunidades de Marte,
que aterrizaron en Marte en 2004. Videos y el texto representan 
los desafíos de conseguir a Marte: probando los rovers en el 
terreno de Martian, lanzando los rovers, navegando sus vuelos, 
trayéndolos en la atmósfera de Martian, aterrizando los, y 
conseguirlos del capullo del lander.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205593</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104170</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mars-exploration-rover-mission</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
