<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103758</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103758</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205850</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Quilt Index</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Steppdecke-Index</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Incrément de Édredon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Deslocamento predeterminado Do Quilt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'Indice Della Trapunta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ευρετήριο παπλωμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Índice Del Edredón</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a hub of information on American quilts and quilt-making. It now features images and documentation for hundreds of quilts from Kentucky, Tennessee, Michigan, and Illinois. An online discussion is open to anyone interested in the documentation or study of quilts, quilters, and quilting history.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Nabe der Informationen über 
amerikanische Steppdecken und das Steppdecke-Bilden. Sie 
kennzeichnet jetzt Bilder und Unterlagen für Hunderte Steppdecken von
Kentucky, von Tennessee, von Michigan und von Illinois. Eine 
Onlinediskussion ist zu jedermann interessiert an den Unterlagen oder 
der Studie der Steppdecken, der quilters und der quilting Geschichte 
geöffnet.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un pivot d'information sur les édredons 
américains et l'édredon-fabrication. Il comporte maintenant 
les images et la documentation pour des centaines d'édredons du 
Kentucky, du Tennessee, du Michigan, et l'Illinois. Une 
discussion en ligne est ouverte à n'importe qui intéressée à la 
documentation ou à l'étude des édredons, des quilters, et de 
l'histoire piquante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um cubo da informação nos quilts americanos e
em quilt-fazer. Caracteriza agora imagens e documentação para 
centenas dos quilts de Kentucky, de Tennessee, de Michigan, e de 
Illinois. Uma discussão em linha está aberta a qualquer um 
interessada na documentação ou no estudo dos quilts, dos quilters, e
do history quilting.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un mozzo delle informazioni sulle trapunte 
americane e sul trapunta-fare. Ora caratterizza le immagini e la
documentazione per le centinaia delle trapunte dal Kentucky, dal 
Tennessee, dal Michigan e dall'Illinois. Una discussione in 
linea è aperta a chiunque interessata alla documentazione o allo 
studio sulle trapunte, sui quilters e sulla storia quilting.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια πλήμνη των πληροφοριών για τα αμερικανικά 
παπλώματα και την πάπλωμα-παραγωγή. Χαρακτηρίζει τώρα τις 
εικόνες και την τεκμηρίωση για τις εκατοντάδες των παπλωμάτων από
το Κεντάκυ, το Tennessee, το Μίτσιγκαν, και το Ιλλινόις. 
Μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση συζήτηση είναι ανοικτή σε καθεμία
ενδιαφερόμενη στην τεκμηρίωση ή τη μελέτη των παπλωμάτων, των 
quilters, και να γεμίσει της ιστορίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un cubo de la información sobre los edredones 
americanos y la edredo'n-fabricacio'n. Ahora ofrece imágenes y 
la documentación para los centenares de edredones de Kentucky, de 
Tennessee, de Michigan, y de Illinois. Una discusión en línea 
está abierta a cualquier persona interesada en la documentación o el
estudio de edredones, de quilters, y de la historia que acolcha.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205850</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103758</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-quilt-index</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
