<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106451</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106451</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086245</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Home Sweet Home: Building and Loan Associations Lend a Hand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Süsses Haupthaus: Bausparkassen verleihen 
eine Hand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Maison Douce À la maison : Le bâtiment et 
les associations de prêt prêtent une main</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">HOME Doce Home: O edifício e as 
associações de empréstimo emprestam uma mão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sede Dolce Domestica: Di organismo per la 
formazione del risparmio destinato alla costruzione di abitazioni 
prestano una mano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γλυκιά "Οικία" "Οικιαών: Οι ενώσεις κτηρίου και
δανείου δανείζουν ένα χέρι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hogar Dulce Casero: El edificio y las 
asociaciones de préstamo prestan una mano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many working people responded to industrial capitalism with strategies that were neither purely individualistic nor collective. On the one hand, the quest for home ownership, which absorbed so many working-class families, was an individual--or family-based--effort. On the other hand, working people often employed their own community-based institutions such as savings and loan associations to achieve the goal of owning their own homes. Outsiders, like the authors of this 1889 Pennsylvania government report on building and loans associations, might celebrate the ways that these associations served as an "antidote against anarchism." But for working people themselves, the building and loan associations were simply vehicles for attaining independence and security.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele Arbeitsleute reagierten auf industriellen 
Kapitalismus mit Strategien, die weder lediglich individualistisch 
noch zusammen waren. Einerseits war die Suche nach 
Eigenheimbesitze, der so viele Arbeiterklassefamilien aufsog, eine 
Einzelperson -- oder Familie-gegründet -- Bemühung. 
Andererseits beschäftigten Arbeitsleute häufig ihre eigenen 
Gemeinschaft-gegründeten Anstalten wie Spar- und 
Darlehensgesellschaften, um das Ziel des Besitzens ihrer eigenen 
Häuser zu erzielen. Außenseiter, wie die Autoren dieses 
Pennsylvania Regierung Berichtes 1889 über Bausparkassen, konnten die
Methoden feiern, denen diese Verbindungen dienten als "Antidot gegen 
Anarchie." Aber für Arbeitsleute selbst, waren die 
Bausparkassen einfach Träger für das Erreichen von von 
Unabhängigkeit und von von Sicherheit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Beaucoup les personnes travaillantes ont répondu 
au capitalisme industriel avec les stratégies qui n'étaient ni 
purement individualistes ni collectives. D'une part, la 
recherche pour le propriétaire de logement, qui a absorbé tant de 
familles de classe ouvrière, était un individu -- ou famille-basé 
-- effort. D'autre part, les personnes travaillantes ont souvent
employé leurs propres établissements communauté-basés tels que des
sociétés d'investissement et de crédit immobilier pour réaliser le
but de posséder leurs propres maisons. Les étrangers, comme 
les auteurs de cet état 1889 de gouvernement de la Pennsylvanie sur 
le bâtiment et les associations de prêts, pourraient célébrer les 
manières dont ces associations ont servi d'"antidote contre 
l'anarchisme." Mais pour les personnes travaillantes 
elles-mêmes, le bâtiment et les associations de prêt étaient 
simplement des véhicules pour atteindre l'indépendance et la 
sécurité.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muitos povos trabalhando responderam ao 
capitalismo industrial com estratégias que eram nem puramente 
individualistic nem coletivas. Na uma mão, o quest para a posse
home, que absorveu assim muitas famílias do working-class, era um 
indivíduo -- ou família-baseado -- esforço. Na outra mão, os
povos trabalhando empregaram frequentemente seus próprios 
instituições comunidade-baseadas tais como economias e associações
de empréstimo para conseguir o objetivo de possuir suas próprias 
HOME. Os outsiders, como os autores deste relatório 1889 do 
governo de Pensilvânia no edifício e nas associações de 
empréstimos, puderam comemorar as maneiras a que estas associações 
serviram como um "antidote de encontro ao anarchism." Mas para 
os povos trabalhando eles mesmos, o edifício e as associações de 
empréstimo eram simplesmente veículos para alcançar a 
independência e a segurança.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molti gente lavorante hanno risposto al 
capitalismo industriale con le strategie che erano nè puramente 
individualistic nè collettive. Sull'una mano, la ricerca per la
proprietà domestica, che ha assorbito tante famiglie della classe 
operaia, era un individuo -- o famiglia-basato -- sforzo. 
D'altra parte, la gente lavorante ha impiegato spesso il loro 
propri istituzioni Comunità-basate quali il risparmio e le 
associazioni di prestito per realizzare l'obiettivo di possedere le 
loro proprie sedi. Gli stranieri, come gli autori di questo 
rapporto 1889 di governo della Pensilvania su di organismi per la 
formazione del risparmio destinato alla costruzione di abitazioni, 
potrebbero celebrare i modi che queste associazioni hanno servito da 
"antidoto contro l'anarchismo." Ma per la gente lavorante essi 
stessi, di organismo per la formazione del risparmio destinato alla 
costruzione di abitazioni erano semplicemente veicoli per il 
raggiungimento l'indipendenza e della sicurezza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλοί εργαζόμενοι άνθρωποι αποκρίθηκαν στη 
βιομηχανική κεφαλαιοκρατία με τις στρατηγικές που δεν ήταν ούτε 
καθαρώς ατομικιστικές ούτε συλλογικές. Αφ' ενός, η 
αναζήτηση για τη βασική ιδιοκτησία, που απορρόφησε τόσες πολλές 
οικογένειες εργατικών τάξεων, ήταν άτομο -- ή 
οικογένεια-βασισμένος στην -- προσπάθεια. Αφ' ετέρου, τα 
εργαζόμενα άτομα απασχόλησαν συχνά τα σε κοινοτικό επίπεδο 
όργανα τους όπως η αποταμίευση και τις ενώσεις δανείου 
για να επιτύχουν το στόχο των σπιτιών τους. Οι ξένοι, όπως 
τους συντάκτες αυτής της κυβερνητικής έκθεσης 1889 Πενσυλβανία
σχετικά με τις ενώσεις κτηρίου και δανείων, να γιορτάσουν τους 
τρόπους που αυτές οι ενώσεις εχρησίμευσαν ως ένα "αντίδοτο 
ενάντια στον αναρχισμό." Αλλά για τους εργαζόμενους 
ανθρώπους οι ίδιοι, οι ενώσεις κτηρίου και δανείου ήταν απλά 
φορείς για την ανεξαρτησία και την ασφάλεια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Muchos gente de trabajo respondieron al 
capitalismo industrial con las estrategias que eran ni puramente 
individualistas ni colectivas. En la una mano, la búsqueda para
la propiedad casera, que absorbió a tan muchas familias de la clase 
obrera, era un individuo -- o familia-basado -- esfuerzo. Por 
otra parte, la gente de trabajo empleó a menudo sus el propios las 
instituciones comunidad-basadas tales como ahorros y asociaciones de 
préstamo para alcanzar la meta de poseer sus propios hogares. 
Los forasteros, como los autores de este informe 1889 del 
gobierno de Pennsylvania sobre el edificio y asociaciones de 
préstamos, pudieron celebrar las maneras que estas asociaciones 
sirvieron como "antídoto contra el anarquismo." Pero para la 
gente de trabajo ellos mismos, el edificio y las asociaciones de 
préstamo eran simplemente vehículos para lograr independencia y 
seguridad.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086245</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106451</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/home-sweet-home-building-and-loan-associations-lend-a-hand</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
