<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107458</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107458</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202703</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Highlighting Revisions, Glossing Changes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Markieren Von von Änderungen, Polierende 
Änderungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mettre en valeur des Révisions, Changements 
d'Annotation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Destacando Revisões, Mudanças Anotando</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Messa in evidenza Delle Revisioni, Cambiamenti Di 
Lucentezza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δίνοντας έμφαση στις αναθεωρήσεις, σχολιάζοντας τις 
αλλαγές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Destacar Revisiones, Cambios Que lustran</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">By highlighting their revisions and explaining (i.e., glossing) the changes they have made to a draft of their work, students will not only become more proficient writers but will also become more conscious of the process of revision and thus more reflective writers. Further, teachers will find it easier to monitor and evaluate student revisions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Durch das Markieren ihrer Änderungen und das 
Erklären (, d.h. polierend), der Änderungen, die sie zu einem 
Entwurf ihrer Arbeit vorgenommen haben, werden Kursteilnehmer nicht 
nur, tüchtigere Verfasser aber werden auch des Prozesses der 
Änderung und folglich der reflektierenderen Verfasser bewußter. 
Weiter finden Lehrer es einfacher, Kursteilnehmeränderungen zu 
überwachen und auszuwerten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En mettant en valeur leurs révisions et en 
expliquant (c.-à-d., annotant) les changements qu'ils ont faits à 
une ébauche de leur travail, les étudiants deviendront non seulement
des auteurs plus compétents mais deviendront également plus 
conscients du processus de la révision et ainsi des auteurs plus 
r3fléchissants. De plus, les professeurs le trouveront plus 
facile de surveiller et évaluer des révisions d'étudiant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Destacando suas revisões e explicando (isto é, 
anotando) as mudanças que fizeram a um esboço de seu trabalho, os 
estudantes transformar-se-ão não somente uns escritores mais 
proficientes mas tornar-se-ão também mais conscious do processo da 
revisão e assim de uns escritores mais reflexivos. Mais mais, 
os professores encontrarão mais fácil de monitorar e avaliar 
revisões do estudante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Evidenziando le loro revisioni e spiegando (cioè,
lucidando) i cambiamenti che hanno fatto ad una brutta copia del loro 
lavoro, gli allievi diventeranno non soltanto produttori più 
competenti ma egualmente diventeranno più coscienti del processo 
della revisione e così dei produttori più riflettenti. Più 
ulteriormente, gli insegnanti lo troveranno più facile controllare e 
valutare le revisioni dell'allievo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Με να δώσουν έμφαση στις αναθεωρήσεις τους και την 
εξήγηση (δηλ., που σχολιάζει) των αλλαγών έχουν κάνει σε ένα 
σχέδιο της εργασίας τους, οι σπουδαστές όχι μόνο θα γίνουν 
ικανότεροι συγγραφείς αλλά θα γίνουν επίσης πιό συνειδητοί της 
διαδικασίας της αναθεώρησης και έτσι περισσότερων αντανακλαστικών
συγγραφέων. Περαιτέρω, οι δάσκαλοι θα το βρούν ευκολότερο 
να ελέγξουν και να αξιολογήσουν τις αναθεωρήσεις σπουδαστών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Destacando sus revisiones y explicando (es decir, 
lustrando) los cambios que han realizado a un bosquejo de su trabajo, 
los estudiantes harán no sólo programas de escritura más peritos 
sino también harán más conscientes del proceso de la revisión y 
así de programas de escritura más reflexivos. Además, los 
profesores encontrarán más fácil vigilar y evaluar revisiones del 
estudiante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PETER BOBBE
FN:PETER BOBBE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202703</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107458</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/highlighting-revisions-glossing-changes</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
