<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103708</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103708</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086796</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Russell Conwell Explains Why Diamonds Are a Man's Best Friend</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Russell Conwell erklärt, warum Diamanten der beste
Freund eines Mannes sind</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Russell Conwell explique pourquoi les diamants 
sont le meilleur ami d'un homme</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Russell Conwell explica porque os diamantes são o
mais melhor amigo de um homem</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Russell Conwell spiega perchè i diamanti sono 
amico migliore dell'uomo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Ρuσσελλ Conwell Explains Why Diamonds είναι
ανθρώπινος καλύτερος φίλος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Russell Conwell explica porqué los diamantes son 
el mejor amigo de un hombre</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The ideology of success--the notion that anyone could make it with enough hard work--was widely promoted in Gilded Age America. An aggressive proponent of the success ideology was Russell Conwell, a former minister who helped found Temple University. His lecture "Acres of Diamonds," parts of which are excerpted here as text, was his own route to riches. He delivered this pep talk on the joys of instant material success on the national lecture circuit more than 6,000 times, most often during the 1890s. By the time of his death in 1925, this speech had reportedly earned him $8 million. (Click here for an audio version of a different portion of the speech.)</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Ideologie des Erfolges -- der Begriff, die 
jedermann bilden könnte es mit genügender harten Arbeit -- wurde 
weit in vergoldetem Alter Amerika gefördert. Ein 
konkurrenzfähiger Antragsteller der Erfolgideologie war Russell 
Conwell, ein ehemaliger Minister, der gefundener Bügel-Universität 
half. Sein Vortrag "Morgen Diamanten," dessen die Teile hier als
Text excerptiert werden, waren sein eigener Weg zu den riches. 
Er lieferte dieses Pepgespräch auf den Freuden am sofortigen 
materiellen Erfolg auf dem nationalen Vortragstromkreis mehr als 
6.000mal, häufig während des 1890s. Bis von seinem Tod 1925, 
diese Rede ihm $8 Million angeblich erworben hatte. (klicken Sie
hier für eine Audioversion eines anderen Teils der Rede.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'idéologie du succès -- la notion que n'importe
qui pourrait lui faire avec assez de travail dur -- a été largement 
favorisée dans l'âge doré Amérique. Un partisan agressif de 
l'idéologie de succès était Russell Conwell, un ancien ministre qui
a aidé l'université trouvée de temple. Acres de sa 
conférence les "de diamants," dont des parties sont extraites ici 
comme texte, étaient son propre itinéraire à la richesse. 
Il a fourni cet entretien de dynamisme sur les joies du succès 
matériel instantané sur le circuit national de conférence plus de 
6.000 fois, le plus souvent pendant le 1890s. Avant que de sa 
mort en 1925, ce discours lui ait censément gagné $8 millions. 
(Clic ici pour une version sonore d'une partie 
différente du discours.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ideology do sucesso -- a noção que qualquer um
poderia lhe fazer com bastante trabalho duro -- foi promovido 
extensamente na idade gilded América. Um proponent aggressive 
do ideology do sucesso era Russell Conwell, um ministro anterior que 
ajudasse à universidade encontrada do temple. Acres do seu 
lecture os "dos diamantes," as partes de que excerpted aqui como o 
texto, eram sua própria rota aos riches. Entregou esta conversa
do pep nas alegrias do sucesso material imediato no circuito nacional 
do lecture mais de 6.000 vezes, o mais frequentemente durante o 1890s.
Pela época de sua morte em 1925, este discurso tinha-lhe 
ganhado reportedly $8 milhões. (estale aqui para uma versão 
audio de uma parcela diferente do discurso.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'ideologia di successo -- la nozione che chiunque
potrebbe rendergli con abbastanza lavoro duro -- ampiamente è stata 
promossa nell'età gilded America. Un fautore aggressivo 
dell'ideologia di successo era Russell Conwell, un ex ministro che
ha aiutato l'università trovata del tempiale. Gli acri della 
sua conferenza "di diamanti," le parti di cui sono stralciate qui come
testo, erano il suo proprio itinerario ai riches. Ha trasportato
il più spesso questo colloquio di pep sulle gioie di successo 
materiale istante sul circuito nazionale di conferenza più di 6.000 
volte, durante il 1890s. Per il momento in cui della sua morte 
in 1925, questo discorso secondo come riferito gli guadagni $8 
milioni. (scattisi qui per una versione audio di una parte 
differente del discorso.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιδεολογία της επιτυχίας -- η έννοια ότι καθεμία θα 
μπορούσε να την κάνει με αρκετή σκληρή εργασία -- προωθήθηκε 
ευρέως στην επιχρυσωμένη ηλικία Αμερική. Ένας επιθετικός 
υπερασπιστής της ιδεολογίας επιτυχίας ήταν ο Russell 
Conwell, ένας προηγούμενος υπουργός που βοήθησε να βρεί το 
πανεπιστήμιο ναών. Στρέμματα της διάλεξής του τα "των 
διαμαντιών," τα μέρη των οποίων είναι εδώ δεδομένου ότι το 
κείμενο, ήταν η διαδρομή του στους πλούτους. Παρέδωσε 
αυτήν την συζήτηση pep στις χαρές της στιγμιαίας υλικής 
επιτυχίας στο εθνικό κύκλωμα διάλεξης περισσότερες από 6.000 
φορές, ο συχνότερα κατά τη διάρκεια του 1890s. Μέχρι την
ώρα του θανάτου του το 1925, αυτή η ομιλία τον είχε κερδίσει 
σύμφωνα με τις υπάρχουσες πληροφορίες $8 εκατομμύρια. 
(Στιγμιαίο πάτημα εδώ για μια ηχητική έκδοση μιας 
διαφορετικής μερίδας της ομιλίας.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La ideología del éxito -- la noción que 
cualquier persona podría hacerle con bastante trabajo duro -- fue 
promovida extensamente en la edad dorada América. Un autor 
agresivo de la ideología del éxito era Russell Conwell, ministro 
anterior que ayudó a la universidad encontrada del templo. 
Acres de su conferencia los "de los diamantes," las partes de 
los cuales se extractan aquí como texto, eran su propia ruta a las 
riquezas. Él entregó esta charla del pep sobre las 
alegrías del éxito material inmediato en el circuito nacional de la 
conferencia más de 6.000 veces, lo más a menudo posible durante el 
1890s. Para el momento en que de su muerte en 1925, este 
discurso según se informa le hubiera ganado $8 millones. (haga 
clic aquí para una versión audio de una diversa porción del 
discurso.)</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086796</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103708</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/russell-conwell-explains-why-diamonds-are-a-mans-best-friend</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
