<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103637</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103637</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206722</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Nutrition and Physical Activity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nahrung und körperliche Aktivität</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nutrition et activité physique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nutrition e atividade física</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nutrizione ed attività fisica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διατροφή και σωματική δραστηριότητα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Nutrición y actividad física</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">focuses on physical activity and good nutrition. Explore the new food pyramid. Learn about body mass, bone health, cancer, dietary guidelines, fruits and vegetables and weight management, healthy eating tips, heart disease, intensity levels of various activities, obesity, physical activity statistics and recommendations, stairwells, tips for parents, and weight management ideas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Foki auf körperlicher Aktivität und guter 
Nahrung. Erforschen Sie die neue Nahrungsmittelpyramide. 
Erlernen Sie über Körpermasse, Knochengesundheit, Krebs, 
diätetische Korrekturlinien, Obst und Gemüse und Gewichtmanagement, 
gesunde Essenspitze-, Innerekrankheit, Intensität Stufen der 
verschiedenen Aktivitäten, Korpulenz, körperliche Aktivität 
Statistiken und Empfehlungen, stairwells, Spitzen für Eltern und 
Gewichtmanagementideen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">foyers sur l'activité physique et la bonne 
nutrition. Explorez la nouvelle pyramide de nourriture. 
Renseignez-vous sur la masse de corps, santé d'os, cancer, 
directives diététiques, fruits et légumes et gestion de poids, 
extrémités saines de manger, maladie de coeur, niveaux d'intensité 
de diverses activités, obésité, statistiques et recommandations 
physiques d'activité, stairwells, extrémités pour des parents, et 
idées de gestion de poids.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">focos na atividade física e no nutrition bom. 
Explore a pirâmide nova do alimento. Aprenda sobre a 
massa do corpo, a saúde do osso, o cancer, guidelines dietéticos, 
frutas e vegetais e gerência do peso, pontas saudáveis comer, 
doença de coração, níveis da intensidade de várias atividades, 
obesity, statistics e recomendações físicas da atividade, 
stairwells, pontas para pais, e idéias da gerência do peso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fuochi su attività fisica e su buona nutrizione. 
Esplori la nuova piramide dell'alimento. Impari circa la 
massa del corpo, salute dell'osso, cancro, guida di riferimento 
dietetica, frutta e verdure e gestione del peso, punte sane di 
consumo, malattia di cuore, livelli di intensità di varie attività, 
l'obesità, le statistiche e raccomandazioni fisiche di attività, 
stairwells, punte per i genitori ed idee della gestione del peso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εστίαση στη σωματική δραστηριότητα και την καλή 
διατροφή. Εξερευνήστε τη νέα πυραμίδα τροφίμων. 
Μάθετε για τη μάζα σωμάτων, την υγεία κόκκαλων, τον 
καρκίνο, τις διαιτητικές οδηγίες, τα φρούτα και τα λαχανικά και 
τη διαχείριση βάρους, τις υγιείς άκρες κατανάλωσης, τις 
καρδιακές παθήσεις, τα επίπεδα έντασης διάφορων δραστηριοτήτων, 
την παχυσαρκία, τις στατιστικές και τις συστάσεις σωματικής 
δραστηριότητας, stairwells, τις άκρες για τους γονείς, και τις 
διοικητικές ιδέες βάρους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">focos en actividad física y la buena nutrición. 
Explore la pirámide nueva del alimento. Aprenda sobre 
masa del cuerpo, salud del hueso, cáncer, las guías de consulta 
dietéticas, las frutas y los vehículos y gerencia del peso, las 
extremidades sanas el comer, enfermedad cardíaca, los niveles de la 
intensidad de varias actividades, obesidad, estadística y las 
recomendaciones físicas de la actividad, los stairwells, las 
extremidades para los padres, y las ideas de la gerencia del peso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206722</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103637</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nutrition-and-physical-activity</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
