<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106415</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106415</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087341</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Square Deal?": The Michigan CIO Debates the No-Strike Pledge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Eine Ehrliche Abmachung?": Das Michigan CIO
debattiert den Nr.schlag Versprechen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Une Affaire Carrée?" : Le Michigan CIO 
discute l'engagement de grève de non</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Um Negócio Quadrado?": O Michigan CIO 
debate o pledge da batida do No.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Un Affare Quadrato?": Il Michigan CIO 
dibatte l'impegno di colpo di no</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια τετραγωνική διαπραγμάτευση;": Το Μίτσιγκαν 
CIO συζητά την υποχρέωση κανένας-απεργίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Un Reparto Cuadrado?": El Michigan CIO 
discute el compromiso de la huelga de no</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In a total war like World War II, the question "Was everyone doing his or her 'part'?" inevitably arose. Immediately following Pearl Harbor, the labor movement made an "unconditional no-strike pledge" to help win the war. In turn, labor won some important concessions from the federal government. Some who believed that labor had given up too much responded with "wildcat" (unauthorized) strikes. Others moved to reconsider the no-strike pledge. In 1942 members of the Michigan CIO endorsed the no-strike pledge, but employer attacks on wages the following year caused them to reevaluate. At the 1943 annual meeting, CIO delegates debated and passed a resolution recommending that "unless the assurances that were made to labor at the time we gave up our right to strike" were honored, the pledge should be nullified. This debate provided a sense of the varying positions that workers took on this difficult issue, including the intensity of feeling that the no-strike pledge aroused.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In einem Gesamtkrieg mögen Sie den Zweiten 
Weltkrieg, die Frage "war jeder, das tut sein oder ' Teil '?" 
entstand unvermeidlich. Direkt nach Pearl Harbor 
versprechen die Arbeiterbewegung, die ein "unbedingtes keinen 
Schlag gebildet wird,", um zu helfen, den Krieg zu gewinnen. Der
Reihe nach bearbeiten Sie gewonnen einigen wichtigen Zugeständnissen 
von der Bundesregierung. Einiges, das glaubte, daß Arbeit 
herauf zuviel reagiert mit "wildem" gegeben hatte (nicht autorisiert) 
schlägt an. Andere, die verschoben werden, um den Nr.schlag 
nachzuprüfen, versprechen. In 1942 Bauteilen des Michigans 
indossierte CIO den Nr.schlag versprechen, aber 
Arbeitgeberangriffe auf Löhnen das folgende Jahr veranließen sie neu
zu bewerten. Bei der jährlichen Sitzung 1943 beaufträgt CIO 
debattiert und überschritten eine Zerlegung, die die "empfiehlt, es 
sei denn die Versicherungen, die gebildet wurden, um uns zu der Zeit 
zu bearbeiten, oben unser Recht zum Schlag" wurden geehrt, versprochene 
annulliert geben. Diese Debatte lieferte eine Richtung der 
unterschiedlichen Positionen, die Arbeiter auf diesem schwierigen 
Problem nahmen, einschließlich die Intensität des Gefühls, die der 
Nr.schlag geweckt versprechen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans une guerre totale aimez la deuxième guerre 
mondiale, la question "était chacun qui fait sa 'partie '?" a 
inévitablement surgi. Juste après le port de perle, le 
mouvement de travail n'a rendu un "sans conditions aucun engagement de
grève" à la victoire d'aide la guerre. Alternativement, 
travaillez gagné quelques concessions importantes du gouvernement 
fédéral. Une partie qui a cru que le travail avait donné vers
le haut de trop répondu avec "sauvage" (non autorisé) frappe. 
D'autres se sont déplacés pour reconsidérer l'engagement de 
grève de non. Dans 1942 membres du Michigan CIO a approuvé 
l'engagement de grève de non, mais les attaques d'employeur sur des 
salaires l'année suivante les ont faits réévaluer. Lors de la
réunion 1943 annuelle, CIO délègue discuté et passé une 
résolution recommandant cela "à moins que les assurances qui ont 
été faites pour nous travailler alors donnent vers le haut notre 
droit de grève" aient été honorées, l'engagement soient annulées.
Cette discussion a fourni un sens des positions variables que 
les ouvriers ont prises sur ce facteur difficile, y compris 
l'intensité du sentiment que l'engagement de grève de non a 
réveillée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em uma guerra total goste da segunda guerra 
mundial, a pergunta "era todos que faz sua ou sua ' parte '?" 
levantou-se inevitàvel. Imediatamente depois do porto de 
pérola, o movimento labor não fêz a um "incondicional nenhum pledge
da batida" à vitória da ajuda a guerra. Por sua vez, trabalhe 
ganhado algumas concessões importantes do governo federal. 
Algum que acreditou que o trabalho tinha dado acima de demasiado
respondido com o "desorganizado" (desautorizado) golpeia. Outros
moveram-se para reconsider o pledge da batida do No.. Em 1942 
membros do Michigan CIO endossou o pledge da batida do No., mas os 
ataques do empregador em salários o seguinte ano fizeram com que 
reavaliassem. Na reunião 1943 anual, CIO delega debatido e 
passado uma definição que recomenda aquela "a menos que as garantias
que estiveram feitas para nos trabalhar naquele tempo derem nossa 
direita à batida" forem honradas acima, o pledge forem anuladas. 
Este debate forneceu um sentido das posições variando de que 
os trabalhadores fizeram exame nesta edição difícil, including a 
intensidade do sentimento que o pledge da batida do No. despertou.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In una guerra totale gradisca la seconda guerra 
mondiale, la domanda "era tutto che fa la sua 'parte '?" ha 
presentato inevitabilmente. Subito dopo del porto di perla, il 
movimento di lavoro non ha reso "un incondizionato impegno di colpo"
alla vittoria di aiuto la guerra. A sua volta, il lavoro 
ha vinto alcune concessioni importanti dal governo federale. 
Alcuno che abbia creduto che il lavoro abbia dato su 
troppo risposto con "selvaggio" (non autorizzato) colpisce. 
Altri si sono mossi per riconsiderare l'impegno di colpo di no. 
In 1942 membri del Michigan CIO ha firmato l'impegno di colpo di
no, ma gli attacchi del datore di lavoro agli stipendi il seguente 
anno li hanno indotti a rivalutare. Alla riunione annuale 1943, 
CIO delega dibattuto e passato ad una risoluzione che suggerisce 
quella "a meno che le assicurazioni che sono state fatte allora al 
lavoro noi diano in su il nostro diritto di sciopero" honored, 
l'impegno sono annullate. Questo dibattito ha fornito un senso 
delle posizioni di variazione che gli operai hanno preso su questo 
fattore difficile, compreso l'intensità della sensibilità che 
l'impegno di colpo di no ha destato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε έναν συνολικό πόλεμο όπως τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο 
ΙΙ, η ερώτηση "ήταν η καθεμία που κάνει" το μέρος του/της ";" 
αναπόφευκτα προέκυψε. Αμέσως μετά από το λιμάνι 
μαργαριταριών, η μετακίνηση εργασίας έκανε μια "απεριόριστη 
υποχρέωση κανένας-απεργίασ" για να βοηθήσει να κερδίσει τον 
πόλεμο. Στη συνέχεια, η εργασία κέρδισε μερικές σημαντικές
παραχωρήσεις από την ομοσπονδιακή κυβέρνηση. Μερικοί που 
εθεώρησαν ότι η εργασία είχε σταματήσει πάρα πολύ αποκριμένος 
με τις "παράτολμεσ" (αναρμόδιες) απεργίες. Αλλοι κινήθηκαν 
για να επανεξετάσουν την υποχρέωση κανένας-απεργίας. Στα 
μέλη του 1942 του Μίτσιγκαν CIO επικύρωσε την υποχρέωση 
κανένας-απεργίας, αλλά τις επιθέσεις εργοδοτών στις αμοιβές που 
το επόμενο έτος τις ανάγκασε για να επαναξιολογήσει. Στην 
ετήσια συνεδρίαση του 1943, οι εκπρόσωποι CIO συζήτησαν και 
ενέκριναν ένα ψήφισμα συστήνοντας ότι "εκτός αν οι 
διαβεβαιώσεις που έγιναν στην εργασία στο χρόνο σταματήσαμε το 
δικαίωμά μας στην απεργία" ήμαστε τιμημένοι, η υποχρέωση πρέπει
να ακυρωθεί. Αυτή η συζήτηση παρείχε μια αίσθηση των 
ποικίλων θέσεων ότι οι εργαζόμενοι πήραν αυτό το δύσκολο θέμα,
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της έντασης της πίστης ότι η υποχρέωση 
κανένας-απεργίας που ξύπνησαν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En una guerra total tenga gusto de la Segunda 
Guerra Mundial, la pregunta "era cada una que hacía su o su ' parte 
'?" se presentó inevitable. Inmediatamente después de 
puerto de perla, el movimiento de trabajo no hizo un "incondicional 
ningún compromiso de la huelga" al triunfo de la ayuda la guerra. 
Alternadamente, trabaje ganado algunas concesiones importantes 
del gobierno federal. Algo que creyó que el trabajo había dado
encima de demasiado respondido con "salvaje" (desautorizado) pulso. 
Otros se movieron para reconsiderar el compromiso de la huelga 
de no. En 1942 miembros del Michigan CIO endosó el compromiso 
de la huelga de no, pero los ataques del patrón contra salarios el 
año siguiente los hicieron reevaluar. En la reunión anual 
1943, CIO delega discutido y pasado una resolución que recomienda eso
"a menos que se anulen los aseguramientos que fueron hechos para 
trabajarnos en ese entonces den para arriba la nuestra derecha a la 
huelga" fueran honrados, el compromiso. Este discusión 
proporcionó a un sentido de las posiciones que variaban que los 
trabajadores adquirieron este asunto difícil, incluyendo la 
intensidad de la sensación que el compromiso de la huelga de no 
despertó.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087341</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106415</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-square-deal-the-michigan-cio-debates-the-no-strike-pledge</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
