<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108558</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108558</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203111</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">History of Evolutionary Thought</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschichte des Entwicklungsgedankens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Histoire de pensée évolutionnaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">History do pensamento evolucionário</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Storia di pensiero evolutivo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστορία της εξελικτικής σκέψης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Historia del pensamiento evolutivo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This subsite of the University of California's Museum of Paleontology Evolution site for teachers, discusses the development of the modern understanding of evolution from the late Renaissance to the present. The website contains useful information regarding evolutionary thought that is accessed through a clickable timeline. The website allows users to explore the four disciplinary areas that have contributed to the current understanding of evolution: Earth's history, life's history, mechanisms of evolution and genetics.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses subsite der Universität des Museums 
Kaliforniens der Paläontologie-Entwicklung Sites für Lehrer, 
behandelt die Entwicklung des modernen Verständnisses der Entwicklung
von der späten Renaissance zum Geschenk. Die Web site enthält 
die nützlichen Informationen betreffend sind Entwicklungsgedanken, 
die durch ein clickable timeline erreicht wird. Die Web site 
erlaubt Benutzern, die vier disziplinären Bereiche zu erforschen, die
zum aktuellen Verständnis der Entwicklung beigetragen haben: 
Bedeckten Geschichte, Geschichte des Lebens, Einheiten der 
Entwicklung und Genetik mit Erde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce subsite de l'université du musée de la 
Californie du site d'évolution de paléontologie pour des 
professeurs, discute le développement de l'arrangement moderne de 
l'évolution de la défunte Renaissance au présent. Le site Web
contient l'information utile concernant la pensée évolutionnaire qui
est consultée par une chronologie clickable. Le site Web permet
à des utilisateurs d'explorer les quatre zones disciplinaires qui ont
contribué à l'arrangement actuel de l'évolution : Ont mis à
la terre l'histoire, l'histoire de la vie, les mécanismes de 
l'évolution et la génétique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este subsite da universidade do museu de 
Califórnia do local da evolução do paleontology para professores, 
discute o desenvolvimento da compreensão moderna da evolução do 
renascimento atrasado ao presente. O Web site contem a 
informação útil a respeito do pensamento evolucionário que é 
alcançada com um timeline clickable. O Web site permite que os 
usuários explorem as quatro áreas disciplinary que contribuíram à 
compreensão atual da evolução: Ligaram à terra o history, o 
history da vida, os mecanismos da evolução e o genetics.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo subsite dell'università di museo della 
California del luogo di sviluppo di paleontologia per gli insegnanti, 
discute lo sviluppo della comprensione moderna dello sviluppo dalla 
rinascita ritardata al presente. Il Web site contiene le 
informazioni utili per quanto riguarda pensiero evolutivo che sono 
raggiunte con un timeline clickable. Il Web site permette che 
gli utenti esplorino le quattro zone disciplinari che hanno 
contribuito alla comprensione corrente dello sviluppo: Hanno 
interrato la storia, la storia della vita, i meccanismi di sviluppo e 
la genetica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το subsite του πανεπιστημίου του μουσείου 
Καλιφόρνιας της περιοχής εξέλιξης παλαιοντολογίας για τους 
δασκάλους, συζητά την ανάπτυξη της σύγχρονης κατανόησης της 
εξέλιξης από την πρόσφατη αναγέννηση στο παρόν. Ο 
ιστοχώρος περιέχει τις χρήσιμες πληροφορίες σχετικά με την 
εξελικτική σκέψη που προσεγγίζεται μέσω μιας clickable 
υπόδειξης ως προς το χρόνο. Ο ιστοχώρος επιτρέπει στους 
χρήστες για να ερευνήσει τις τέσσερις πειθαρχικές περιοχές που 
έχουν συμβάλει στην παρούσα κατανόηση της εξέλιξης: Γήινη 
ιστορία, ιστορία της ζωής, μηχανισμοί της εξέλιξης και γενετική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este subsite de la universidad del museo de 
California del sitio de la evolución de la paleontología para los 
profesores, discute el desarrollo de la comprensión moderna de la 
evolución del último renacimiento al presente. El Web site 
contiene la información útil con respecto a pensamiento evolutivo 
que está alcanzada con un timeline clickable. El Web site 
permite que los utilizadores exploren las cuatro áreas disciplinarias
que han contribuido a la comprensión actual de la evolución: 
Conectaron a tierra historia, la historia de la vida, mecanismos
de la evolución y genética.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203111</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108558</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/history-of-evolutionary-thought</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
