<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103376</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103376</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206456</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Curiosity Creates Cures: The Value and Impact of Basic Research</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Neugier Erstellt Heilungen: Der Wert und die
Auswirkung der Grundlagenforschung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Curiosité Crée des Traitements : La 
valeur et l'impact de la recherche fondamentale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Curiosidade Cría Curas: O valor e o 
impacto da pesquisa básica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Curiosità Crea Le Cure: Il valore e 
l'effetto di ricerca di base</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η περιέργεια δημιουργεί τις θεραπείες: Η αξία 
και ο αντίκτυπος της βασικής έρευνας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Curiosidad Crea Las Curaciones: El valor 
y el impacto de la investigación básica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">introduces the work of basic biomedical scientists -- scientists who seek answers to key biological questions like how cells talk to each other, how biological machines fold into their active shapes, and how genes are regulated. Topics include Alzheimer's disease, anthrax, flu vaccines, Nobel Prize winners, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt die Arbeit der grundlegenden 
biomedizinischen Wissenschaftler -- Wissenschaftler vor, die Antworten
suchen, um zu befestigen biologische Fragen wie, wie Zellen 
miteinander sprechen, wie biologische Maschinen in ihre aktiven Formen
sich falten und wie Gene geregelt werden. Themen enthalten 
Krankheit Alzheimers, Anthrax, Grippeimpfstoffe, Nobelpreissieger und 
mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente le travail des savants en biomédecine 
de base -- les scientifiques qui recherchent des réponses pour 
introduire des questions biologiques comme la façon dont les cellules
parlent entre eux, la façon dont les machines biologiques se plient 
dans leurs formes actives, et comment des gènes sont réglés. 
Les sujets incluent la maladie d'Alzheimer, l'anthrax, les 
vaccins de grippe, les gagnants de prix Nobel, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">introduz o trabalho de cientistas biomedical 
básicos -- os cientistas que procuram respostas fechar à chave 
perguntas biológicas como como as pilhas se falam, como as máquinas 
biológicas se dobram em suas formas ativas, e como os genes são 
regulados. Os tópicos incluem a doença de Alzheimer, o 
anthrax, as vacinas do flu, os vencedores do prêmio de nobel, e o 
mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">introduce il lavoro degli scienziati biomedici di 
base -- scienziati che cercano le risposte per impostare le domande 
biologiche come come le cellule comunicano l'un l'altro, come le 
macchine biologiche si piegano nelle loro figure attive e come i geni 
sono regolati. I soggetti includono la malattia del Alzheimer, 
l'antrace, i vaccini di flu, i vincitori del premio Nobel e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εισάγει την εργασία των βασικών βιοϊατρικών 
επιστημόνων -- επιστήμονες που επιδιώκουν τις απαντήσεις για να 
κλειδώσουν τις βιολογικές ερωτήσεις όπως το πώς τα κύτταρα 
μιλούν το ένα στο άλλο, το πώς οι βιολογικές μηχανές διπλώνουν 
στις ενεργές μορφές τους, και πώς τα γονίδια είναι ρυθμισμένα. 
Τα θέματα περιλαμβάνουν την ασθένεια του Alzheimer, τον 
άνθρακα, τα εμβόλια γρίπης, τους νικητές βραβείων Νόμπελ, και 
περισσότεροι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">introduce el trabajo de los científicos 
biomédicos básicos -- los científicos que intentan respuestas para 
afinar preguntas biológicas como cómo las células hablan el uno al 
otro, cómo las máquinas biológicas plegable en sus dimensiones de 
una variable activas, y cómo se regulan los genes. Los asuntos 
incluyen la enfermedad de Alzheimer, el ántrax, vacunas de la gripe, 
ganadores del premio Nobel, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206456</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103376</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/curiosity-creates-cures-the-value-and-impact-of-basic-research</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
