<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107422</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107422</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205329</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">You Decide: Should we all be vegetarians?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sie Entscheiden: Sollten alle wir Vegetarier
sein?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vous Décidez : Au cas où nous tous être 
des végétariens ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Você Decide-se: Devemos nós todos ser 
vegetarianos?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Decidete: Dovremmo tutti essere vegetariani?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αποφασίζετε: Θα έπρεπε όλοι να είμαστε 
χορτοφάγοι;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usted Decide: ¿Debemos todos ser 
vegetarianos?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This educational guide focuses on both sides of the vegetarianism debate. Students are invited to examine the nutritional, environmental, health and lifestyle issues, developing critical thinking skills as they work through the activities. Students will learn how to support their arguments with evidence and reason. It is expected that at the end of this guide students will determine where they stand on this controversial issue.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese pädagogische Anleitung konzentriert auf beide 
Seiten der vegetarianism Debatte. Kursteilnehmer werden 
eingeladen, die Ernährungs-, Klima-, Gesundheit und Lebensstil 
Ausgaben zu überprüfen und entwickeln kritische denkende 
Fähigkeiten, während sie durch die Aktivitäten arbeiten. 
Kursteilnehmer erlernen, wie man ihre Argumente mit Beweis und 
Grund unterstützt. Es wird erwartet, daß am Ende dieser 
Anleitung Kursteilnehmer feststellen, wo sie zu diesem umstrittenen 
Punkt stehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce guide éducatif se concentre sur les deux côtés de la
discussion de végétarisme. Des étudiants sont invités à 
examiner les issues alimentaires, environnementales, de santé et de 
style de vie, développant des qualifications de pensée critiques 
pendant qu'ils travaillent par les activités. Les étudiants 
apprendront comment supporter leurs arguments avec l'évidence et la 
raison. On s'attend à ce qu'à l'extrémité de ce guide les 
étudiants déterminent où ils se tiennent sur cette question 
controversée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta guia educacional focaliza em ambos os lados do debate
do vegetarianism. Os estudantes estão convidados examinar as 
edições nutritivas, ambientais, da saúde e do lifestyle, 
desenvolvendo habilidades pensando críticas enquanto trabalham com as
atividades. Os estudantes aprenderão como suportar seus 
argumentos com evidência e razão. Espera-se que na extremidade
desta guia os estudantes determinarão onde estão nesta edição 
controversa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa guida educativa mette a fuoco da entrambi i lati 
del dibattito di vegetarianism. Gli allievi sono invitati ad 
esaminare le edizioni nutrizionali, ambientali, di salute e di 
lifestyle, sviluppanti le abilità pensanti critiche mentre lavorano 
con le attività. Gli allievi impareranno come sostenere i loro 
argomenti con prova e motivo. È previsto che all'estremità di 
questa guida allievi determinino dove si levano in piedi su questa 
edizione discutibile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο εκπαιδευτικός οδηγός εστιάζει και στις δύο 
πλευρές της συζήτησης χορτοφαγίας. Οι σπουδαστές καλούνται 
για να εξετάσουν τα θρεπτικά, περιβαλλοντικά, ζητήματα υγείας και
τρόπου ζωής, που αναπτύσσουν τις κρίσιμες δεξιότητες σκέψης 
όπως λειτουργούν μέσω των δραστηριοτήτων. Οι σπουδαστές θα 
μάθουν πώς να υποστηρίξουν τα ορίσματά τους με τα στοιχεία και 
το λόγο. Αναμένεται ότι στο τέλος αυτού του οδηγού οι 
σπουδαστές θα καθορίσουν όπου στέκονται σε αυτό το 
αμφισβητούμενο ζήτημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta guía educativa se centra en ambas caras del 
discusión del vegetarianism. Se invita a los estudiantes que 
examinen las ediciones alimenticias, ambientales, de la salud y de la 
forma de vida, desarrollando habilidades de pensamiento críticas 
mientras que trabajan con las actividades. Los estudiantes 
aprenderán cómo utilizar sus argumentos con evidencia y razón. 
Se espera que en el extremo de esta guía los estudiantes se 
determinen dónde están parados en esta edición polémica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205329</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107422</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/you-decide-should-we-all-be-vegetarians</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
