<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104511</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104511</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087068</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Utopian Promise of the Peacetime Atom": Predictions and Hopes for Atomic Energy</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die utopische Versprechung des Friedensatoms": 
Vorhersagen und Hoffnungen für Atomenergie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la promesse utopique de l'atome en temps de paix"
: Prévisions et espoirs pour l'énergie atomique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a promessa utópica do átomo pacífico": 
Predições e esperanças para a energia atômica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la promessa utopian dell'atomo pacifico": 
Previsioni e speranze per energia atomica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η ουτοπιστική υπόσχεση του εν καιρώ ειρήνης ατόμου":
Προβλέψεις και ελπίδες για την ατομική ενέργεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la promesa utópica del átomo pacífico": 
Predicciones y esperanzas de la energía atómica</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Atomic Energy Act of 1946, known informally as the McMahon Act, established the Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) as a federal institution to have total control of developments in the field of atomic energy. To replace the predominate image of atomic weapons as destructive, the AEC began a public relations campaign to show the atom's positive side. Hopes for a utopian society with atomic-powered cars and airplanes had died down by the late 1940s. But the promise of atomic energy for medical research, diagnosis, and treatment and for preventing starvation through duplicating photosynthesis remained. In 1954, President Dwight D. Eisenhower signed a revision to the McMahon Act opening development to private industry. In the following article from the popular magazine  Look  published a year later, David O. Woodbury reprised the "utopian promise" rhetoric of the late 1940s, as he discussed the potential of radioisotopes for health, food production, and industry, as well as the production of electric power through atomic energy. The first nuclear power plant began operation in 1957 and facilities proliferated during the next two decades. Due to a drop in demand for electricity, a strong grassroots antinuclear movement concerned about safety and the disposal of nuclear waste, and national anxiety after the Three Mile Island accident in 1979, no new facilities were built after 1979 and many have been shut down.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Atomenergie-Tat von 1946, formlos bekannt als 
die McMahon Tat, hergestellt der Atomenergie-Kommission (AEC) wie eine
Bundesanstalt, um Gesamtsteuerung von Entwicklungen in auffangene 
der Atomenergie zu haben. Um das vorherrschenbild der Atomwaffen
zu ersetzen an wie zerstörend, fing das AEC eine 
Öffentlichkeitsarbeitkampagne um die positive Seite des Atoms zu 
zeigen. Hoffnungen für eine utopische Gesellschaft mit 
Atom-angeschalteten Autos und Flugzeugen waren unten bis zum den 
späten vierziger Jahren gestorben. Aber die Versprechung der 
Atomenergie für medizinische Forschung, Diagnose und Behandlung und 
für das Verhindern des Verhungerns durch kopierende Fotosynthese 
blieb. 1954 unterzeichnete Präsident Dwight D. Eisenhower eine 
Änderung zur McMahon Tat Öffnung Entwicklung zur privaten Industrie.
Im folgenden Artikel vom populären veröffentlichten 
Zeitschrift Blick ein Jahr später, reprised David O. Woodbury die 
"utopische Versprechung" Rhetorik der späten vierziger Jahre, 
während er das Potential der Radioisotope für Gesundheit, 
Nahrungsmittelproduktion und Industrie behandelte, sowie die 
Produktion der elektrischer Leistung durch Atomenergie. Das 
erste Atomkraftwerk fing Operation 1957 und die Teildienste, die 
während der folgenden zwei Dekaden stark vermehrt wurden an. 
Wegen eines Tropfens der Nachfrage nach Elektrizität, einer 
antinuclear Bewegung der starken Basis, die über Sicherheit 
und der Beseitigung des Atommülls und nationale Angst nach dem drei 
Meile Inselunfall 1979 betroffen wurden, wurden keine neuen 
Teildienste nach 1979 aufgebaut und viele sind abgeschaltet worden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Loi d'énergie atomique de 1946, connue 
officieusement comme acte de McMahon, établi la Commission d'énergie
atomique (AEC) en tant qu'établissement fédéral pour avoir la 
commande totale des développements dans le domaine de l'énergie 
atomique. Pour substituer l'image de prédominance des armes 
atomiques comme destructive, l'AEC a commencé une campagne de 
relations publiques pour montrer le côté positif de l'atome. 
Les espoirs pour une société utopique avec les voitures et les
avions atomique-actionnés étaient morts vers le bas par les années 
40 en retard. Mais la promesse de l'énergie atomique pour la 
recherche médicale, le diagnostic, et le traitement et pour empêcher
la famine par la photosynthèse reproduisante est demeurée. En 
1954, le Président Dwight D. Eisenhower a signé une révision au 
développement d'ouverture de Loi de McMahon à l'industrie privée. 
Dans l'article suivant du sembler populaire de magasin édité 
un an après, David O. Woodbury reprised la rhétorique "de promesse 
utopique" des années 40 en retard, pendant qu'il discutait le 
potentiel des radio-isotopes pour la santé, la production de 
nourriture, et l'industrie, aussi bien que la production de l'énergie
électrique par l'énergie atomique. La première centrale 
nucléaire a commencé l'exécution en 1957 et les équipements 
proliférés pendant les deux décennies suivantes. En raison 
d'une baisse dans la demande de l'électricité, un mouvement 
antinucléaire de bases fortes préoccupé par la sûreté et 
l'élimination de la perte nucléaire, et inquiétude nationale après
l'accident d'île de trois milles en 1979, aucun nouvel équipement 
n'a été établi après 1979 et beaucoup ont été arrêtés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ato da energia atômica de 1946, sabido informal
como o ato de McMahon, estabelecido o commission de energia atômica 
(AEC) como uma instituição federal para ter o controle total dos 
desenvolvimentos no campo da energia atômica. Para substituir a
imagem do predominate de armas atômicas como destrutiva, o AEC 
começou uma campanha das relações públicas a mostrar o lado 
positivo do átomo. As esperanças para uma sociedade utópica 
com carros e os aviões atômico-atomic-powered tinham morrido para 
baixo pelos 1940s atrasados. Mas a promessa da energia atômica 
para a pesquisa médica, o diagnóstico, e o tratamento e para impedir
o starvation com a fotossíntese duplicando remanesceu. Em 1954,
o presidente Dwight D. Eisenhower assinou uma revisão ao 
desenvolvimento da abertura do ato de McMahon à indústria 
confidencial. No seguinte artigo do olhar popular do 
compartimento publicado um ano mais tarde, David O. Woodbury reprised 
"o rhetoric da promessa utópica" dos 1940s atrasados, enquanto 
discutiu o potencial dos radioisotopes para a saúde, a produção do 
alimento, e a indústria, as.well.as a produção da potência 
elétrica com a energia atômica. A primeira planta de potência
nuclear começou a operação em 1957 e as facilidades proliferated 
durante as duas décadas seguintes. devido a uma gota na 
demanda para a eletricidade, em um movimento antinuclear dos 
grassroots fortes concernido sobre a segurança e na eliminação do 
desperdício nuclear, e ansiedade nacional após o acidente do console
de três milhas em 1979, nenhuma facilidade nova foi construída após
1979 e muitos foram fechados para baixo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Legge di energia atomica di 1946, conosciuta 
senza formalità come la Legge di McMahon, stabilita la Commissione di
energia atomica (AEC) come istituzione federale per avere controllo 
totale degli sviluppi nel campo di energia atomica. Per 
sostituire l'immagine di predominanza delle armi atomiche come 
distruttiva, il AEC ha cominciato una campagna di pubbliche relazioni 
per mostrare il lato positivo dell'atomo. Le speranze per una 
società utopian con gli automobili e gli aeroplani atomico-alimentati
erano morto giù entro i 1940s tardi. Ma la promessa di energia 
atomica per ricerca medica, la diagnosi ed il trattamento e per 
impedire l'inedia con la fotosintesi duplicante è rimasto. In 
1954, il presidente Dwight D. Eisenhower ha firmato una revisione allo
sviluppo di apertura di Legge di McMahon ad industria riservata. 
Nel seguente articolo dal sembr popolare dello scomparto 
pubblicato un anno più successivamente, David O. Woodbury reprised 
"la retorica di promessa utopian" dei 1940s tardi, mentre ha discusso 
il potenziale dei radioisotopi per salute, produzione dell'alimento ed
industria, così come la produzione di energia elettrica con energia 
atomica. La prima pianta di energia nucleare ha cominciato il 
funzionamento in 1957 e le attrezzature proliferate durante le due 
decadi prossime. dovuto un calo nella richiesta di 
elettricità, in un movimento antinucleare dei grassroots forti 
interessato circa sicurezza e nell'eliminazione dei rifiuti nucleari 
ed ansia nazionale dopo l'incidente dell'isola da tre miglia in 1979, 
nessun'nuova attrezzatura è stata sviluppata dopo 1979 e molti si 
sono interrotti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο νόμος ατομικής ενέργειας του 1946, γνωστός 
ανεπίσημα ως νόμος McMahon, καθιέρωσε την Επιτροπή ατομικής 
ενέργειας (AEC) ως ομοσπονδιακό όργανο για να έχει το 
συνολικό έλεγχο των εξελίξεων στον τομέα της ατομικής ενέργειας.
Για να αντικαταστήσετε υπερισχύστε εικόνα των ατομικών 
όπλων όπως καταστρεπτική, το AEC άρχισε τις δημόσιες σχέσεις 
κάνει εκστρατεία να εμφανίσει θετική πλευρά του ατόμου. Οι
ελπίδες για μια ουτοπιστική κοινωνία με τα με ατομική ενέργεια 
αυτοκίνητα και τα αεροπλάνα είχαν πεθάνει κάτω μέχρι την 
πρόσφατη δεκαετία του '40. Αλλά η υπόσχεση της ατομικής 
ενέργειας για την ιατρική έρευνα, τη διάγνωση, και τη θεραπεία 
και για την παρεμπόδιση του λιμού μέσω της αναπαραγωγής της 
φωτοσύνθεσης παρέμεινε. Το 1954, ο Πρόεδρος Dwight 
D. Eisenhower υπέγραψε μια αναθεώρηση στην ανοίγοντας 
ανάπτυξη νόμων McMahon στην ιδιωτική βιομηχανία. Στο 
ακόλουθο άρθρο από το δημοφιλές περιοδικό φανείτε δημοσιευμένος
ένα έτος αργότερα, ο Δαβίδ O. Woodbury η ρητορική 
"ουτοπιστικής υπόσχεσησ" της πρόσφατης δεκαετίας του '40, 
δεδομένου ότι συζήτησε τη δυνατότητα των ραδιοϊσοτόπων για την 
υγεία, την παραγωγή τροφίμων, και τη βιομηχανία, καθώς επίσης 
και την παραγωγή της ηλεκτρικής ενέργειας μέσω της ατομικής 
ενέργειας. Οι πρώτες εγκαταστάσεις πυρηνικής ενέργειας 
άρχισαν τη λειτουργία το 1957 και οι εγκαταστάσεις 
πολλαπλασιάστηκαν κατά τη διάρκεια των επόμενων δύο δεκαετιών. 
Λόγω σε μια απελευθέρωση σε ζήτηση για την ηλεκτρική 
ενέργεια, μια ισχυρή αντιπυρηνική μετακίνηση σε επίπεδο βάσης 
ενδιαφερόμενη για την ασφάλεια και τη διάθεση των πυρηνικών 
αποβλήτων, και εθνική ανησυχία μετά από το ατύχημα νησιών 
τριών μιλίου το 1979, καμία νέα εγκατάσταση δεν χτίστηκε 
μετά από το 1979 και πολλές έχουν διακοπεί.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El acto de la energía atómica de 1946, conocido 
informal como el acto de McMahon, establecido la Comisión de energía
atómica (AEC) como institución federal para tener control total de 
progresos en el campo de la energía atómica. Para substituir 
la imagen del predominio de armas atómicas como destructiva, el AEC 
comenzó una campaña de las relaciones públicas para mostrar la cara
positiva del átomo. Las esperanzas de una sociedad utópica con
los coches y los aeroplanos ato'mico-accionados habían muerto abajo 
por los últimos años 40. Pero seguía habiendo la promesa de 
la energía atómica para la investigación médica, la diagnosis, y 
el tratamiento y para prevenir el hambre con fotosíntesis que 
duplicaba. En 1954, presidente Dwight D. Eisenhower firmó una 
revisión al desarrollo de la apertura del acto de McMahon a la 
industria privada. En el artículo siguiente de la mirada 
popular del compartimiento publicada un año más tarde, David O. 
Woodbury reprised el retórico de la "promesa utópica" de los 
últimos años 40, mientras que él discutió el potencial de los 
radioisótopos para la salud, la producción del alimento, y la 
industria, así como la producción de la energía eléctrica con 
energía atómica. La primera planta de energía atómica 
comenzó la operación en 1957 y los recursos proliferados durante las
dos décadas próximas. debido a una gota en la demanda para la
electricidad, un movimiento antinuclear de los pueblos fuertes 
referido sobre seguridad y la disposición de la basura nuclear, y 
ansiedad nacional después del accidente de la isla de tres millas en 
1979, no se construyó ningunos nuevos recursos después de 1979 y se 
han cerrado muchos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087068</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104511</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-utopian-promise-of-the-peacetime-atom-predictions-and-hopes-for-atomic-energy</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
