<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103725</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103725</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086458</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Manager N. B. Gordon Tends to the Union Cotton and Woolen Manufactory in Mansfield, Massachusetts, 1829</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Manager Notiz: Gordon neigt zur 
Anschluß-Baumwolle und zur Woolen Manufaktur in Mansfield, 
Massachusetts, 1829</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le gestionnaire NOTA: Gordon tend au coton des
syndicats et à l'usine de laine à Mansfield, le Massachusetts, 1829</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Gerente N. B. Gordon Tender ao algodão da união 
e manufactory de lã em Mansfield, Massachusetts, 1829</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il gestore N.B.: Gordon tende al cotone del 
sindacato ed al manufactory di lana a Mansfield, Massachusetts, 1829</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Manager Ν. Β. Gordon τείνει στο βαμβάκι ένωσης 
και το μάλλινο Manufactory στο Μάνσφιλντ, Μασαχουσέτη, 1829</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El encargado NOTA Gordon tiende al algodón de la 
unión y al manufactory de lana en Mansfield, Massachusetts, 1829</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Large factories such as the Lowell textile mills, with their thousands of employees and imposing structures, were the exception in the United States' early industrial development. More commonly, small manufactories sprang up throughout the northeastern United States wherever a fast moving stream was available to provide water power. N. B. Gordon was the general manager as well as the chief mechanic and mill agent at the Union Cotton and Woolen Manufactory, a small textile company in the southeastern Massachusetts town of Mansfield. His work diary chronicled the everyday difficulties he faced in keeping the mill operating, including such problems as broken machines and too little water to power the mill. Highly independent employees caused him headaches, too.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Große Fabriken wie die Lowell Textiltausendstel, 
mit ihren Tausenden Angestellten und imposing Strukturen, waren die 
Ausnahme in der der Vereinigten Staaten frühen industriellen 
Entwicklung. Häufiger entstanden kleine Manufakturen in den 
nordöstlichen Vereinigten Staaten, wohin ein schneller beweglicher 
Strom vorhanden war, Wasserenergie zur Verfügung zu stellen. 
Notiz: Gordon war der Generaldirektor sowie den Hauptmechaniker 
und das Tausendstelmittel an der Anschluß-Baumwolle und die Woolen 
Manufaktur, eine kleine Textilfirma in der südöstlichen 
Massachusetts Stadt von Mansfield. Sein Arbeit Tagebuch 
zeichnete die täglichen Schwierigkeiten, die er gegenüberstellte, 
wenn er das Tausendstel hielt zu funktionieren, einschließlich solche
Probleme wie unterbrochene Maschinen und zu wenig Wasser, um das 
Tausendstel anzuschalten auf. In hohem Grade unabhängige 
Angestellte verursachten ihm Kopfschmerzen, auch.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les grandes usines telles que les moulins de 
textile de Lowell, avec des leurs milliers d'employés et de 
structures imposantes, étaient l'exception dans le développement 
industriel précoce des Etats-Unis. Généralement, les petites 
usines ont pris naissance dans l'ensemble des Etats-Unis du nord-est 
partout où un jet mobile rapide était disponible pour fournir la 
puissance de l'eau. NOTA: Gordon était le directeur 
général aussi bien que le mécanicien et l'agent en chef de moulin 
au coton des syndicats et l'usine de laine, une petite compagnie de 
textile dans la ville du sud-est du Massachusetts de Mansfield. 
Son agenda de travail a fait la chronique des difficultés 
journalières qu'il a faites face en continuant le moulin opérer, y 
compris des problèmes tels que les machines cassées et trop peu 
d'eau pour actionner le moulin. Les employés fortement 
indépendants lui ont causé des maux de tête, aussi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As fábricas grandes tais como os moinhos de 
textile de Lowell, com seus milhares dos empregados e de estruturas 
imponentes, eram a exceção no desenvolvimento industrial adiantado 
dos estados unidos. Mais geralmente, os manufactories pequenos 
saltaram acima durante todo os estados unidos do nordeste onde quer 
que um córrego movente rápido estava disponível para fornecer a 
potência da água. N. B. Gordon era o gerente geral as.well.as 
o mecânico e o agente principal do moinho no algodão da união e o 
manufactory de lã, uma companhia pequena de textile na cidade do 
sudeste de Massachusetts de Mansfield. Seu diário do trabalho 
chronicled as dificuldades que diárias enfrentou em manter o moinho 
se operar, including problemas como máquinas quebradas e demasiado 
pouca água para power o moinho. Os empregados altamente 
independentes causaram-lhe headaches, demasiado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le grandi fabbriche quali i laminatoi della 
tessile de Lowell, con i loro migliaia degli impiegati e delle 
strutture imponenti, erano l'eccezione in unito Dichiara 'lo 
sviluppo industriale iniziale. Più conunemente, i piccoli 
manufactories si sono generati durante il di nordest unito 
Dichiara dovunque un flusso commovente veloce fosse a 
disposizione per fornire l'potenza dell'acqua. La N.B.: Gordon 
era il direttore generale così come il meccanico e l'agente 
principale del laminatoio al cotone del sindacato ed il manufactory di
lana, una piccola azienda della tessile nella città del sud-est del 
Massachusetts di Mansfield. Il suo diario del lavoro chronicled 
le difficoltà che giornalieri ha affrontato nel mantenere il 
laminatoio funzionare, compreso tali problemi come le macchine rotte e
troppo poca acqua per alimentare il laminatoio. Gli impiegati 
altamente indipendenti gli hanno causato le emicranie, anche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα μεγάλα εργοστάσια όπως οι υφαντικοί μύλοι του 
Lowell, με χιλιάδες τους υπάλληλοι και επιβολή των δομών, ήταν
εξαίρεση στην Ηνωμένη πρόωρη βιομηχανική ανάπτυξη. 
Συχνότερα, τα μικρά manufactories αναπήδησαν επάνω σε 
όλες τις βορειοανατολικές Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες οπουδήποτε ένα 
γρήγορα κινούμενο ρεύμα ήταν διαθέσιμο για να παρέχει την 
υδραυλική ισχύ. Ν. Β. Gordon ήταν ο γενικός διευθυντής 
καθώς επίσης και ο προϊστάμενος πράκτορας μηχανικών και μύλων στο 
βαμβάκι ένωσης και μάλλινο Manufactory, μια μικρή υφαντική 
επιχείρηση στη νοτιοανατολική πόλη της Μασαχουσέτης του 
Μάνσφιλντ. Το ημερολόγιο εργασίας του ηξιστόρησε κατά 
γράμμα τις καθημερινές δυσκολίες που αντιμετώπισε στην κράτηση 
του μύλου, συμπεριλαμβανομένων τέτοιων προβλημάτων όπως 
σπασμένες μηχανές και επίσης λίγο ύδωρ για να τροφοδοτήσει τα 
εκατομμύρια Οι ιδιαίτερα ανεξάρτητοι υπάλληλοι του 
προκάλεσαν τους πονοκέφαλους, επίσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las fábricas grandes tales como los molinos del 
textil de Lowell, con sus millares de empleados y de estructuras 
imponentes, eran la anomalía en el desarrollo industrial temprano de 
los Estados Unidos. Más comunmente, los manufactories pequeños
se originaron a través de los Estados Unidos del noreste dondequiera 
que una secuencia móvil rápida estuviera disponible para 
proporcionar a potencia del agua. La NOTA Gordon era el director
general así como el principal mecánico y agente del molino en el 
algodón de la unión y el manufactory de lana, compañía pequeña 
del textil en la ciudad del sudeste de Massachusetts de Mansfield. 
Su diario del trabajo chronicled las dificultades diarias que 
él hizo frente en guardar el molino el funcionar, incluyendo los 
problemas tales como las máquinas quebradas y demasiado poca agua 
para accionar el molino. Los empleados altamente independientes le
causaron dolores de cabeza, también.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086458</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103725</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/manager-n-b-gordon-tends-to-the-union-cotton-and-woolen-manufactory-in-mansfield-massachusetts-1829</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
