<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103014</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103014</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211777</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Public Lands for the People</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Allgemeine Länder für die Leute</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Terres publiques pour le peuple</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Terras públicas para os povos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Terre pubbliche per la gente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δημόσια εδάφη για τους ανθρώπους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pistas públicas para la gente</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Public Lands for the People is non-profit organization 'dedicated to preserving the rights of the public to access and use of public lands'. The site's purpose is to educate people and government agencies about their rights and the laws that apply to them, with a focus on the use of unappropriated public lands. It includes a legal resource page, with links to everything from the Federalist papers to the UN Declaration of Human Rights. There is also a suggested challenge page highlighting the procedure for addressing a legality challenge while pursuing outdoor activities. Also available is a discussion forum for submitting questions and opinions regarding public land use issues.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Allgemeine Länder für die Leute ist die 
gemeinnützige Organisation ', die dem Konservieren der Rechte der 
Öffentlichkeit zum Zugriff und zum Gebrauch der allgemeinen Länder 
eingesetzt wird. Der Zweck der Sites ist, Leute und 
Regierungsagenturen über ihre Rechte und die Gesetze, die auf sie 
zutreffen, mit einem Fokus auf dem Gebrauch der ungeeigneten 
allgemeinen Länder zu erziehen. Er enthält eine zugelassene 
Hilfsmittelseite, mit Links zu alles von den Föderalistpapieren zur 
UNO Erklärung der menschlichen Rechte. Es gibt auch eine 
vorgeschlagene Herausforderung Seite, welche die Prozedur für das 
Adressieren einer Legalitätherausforderung beim Ausüben von von im 
Freienaktivitäten markiert. Auch ist ein Diskussion Forum für 
das Eingeben von von Fragen und von von Meinungen betreffend sind 
allgemeine Flächennutzungausgaben vorhanden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les terres publiques pour le peuple est 
organisation à but non lucratif 'consacrée à préserver les droites
du public à l'accès et à l'utilisation des terres publiques. 
Le but du site est d'instruire des personnes et des organismes 
gouvernementaux au sujet de leurs droites et des lois qui s'appliquent
à elles, avec un foyer sur l'utilisation des terres publiques non 
distribuées. Il inclut une page légale de ressource, avec des 
liens à tout des articles de fédéraliste à la déclaration de 
l'ONU des droits de l'homme. Il y a également une page 
suggérée de défi mettant en valeur la procédure pour adresser un 
défi de légalité tout en exerçant des activités en plein air. 
En outre disponible est un forum de discussion pour soumettre 
des questions et des avis concernant les issues publiques 
d'utilisation de la terre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As terras públicas para os povos são 
organização non-profit ' dedicada a preservar as direitas do 
público ao acesso e ao uso de terras públicas. A finalidade do
local é educar povos e agências de governo sobre suas direitas e as 
leis que se aplicam lhes, com um foco no uso de terras públicas 
unappropriated. Inclui uma página legal do recurso, com 
ligações a tudo dos papéis do federalista à declaração dos UN de
direitas humanas. Há também uma página sugerida do desafio 
que destaca o procedimento para dirigir-se a um desafio do legality ao
perseguir atividades ao ar livre. Também disponível está um 
forum da discussão para submeter perguntas e opiniões a respeito das
edições públicas do uso de terra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le terre pubbliche per la gente è organizzazione 
senza scopo di lucro 'dedicata a conservare i diritti del pubblico ad 
accesso e ad uso delle terre pubbliche. Lo scopo del luogo è 
istruire la gente e gli enti governativi circa i loro diritti e le 
leggi che si applicano a loro, con un fuoco sull'uso delle terre 
pubbliche non stanziate. Include una pagina legale delle 
risorse, con i collegamenti a tutto dalle carte dal federalista alla 
dichiarazione di NU dei diritti dell'uomo. Ci è 
egualmente una pagina suggerita di sfida che evidenzia la procedura 
per il richiamo della sfida di legalità mentre persegue le attività 
esterne. Egualmente disponibile è una tribuna di discussione 
per la presentazione le domande e delle opinioni per quanto riguarda 
le edizioni pubbliche di utilizzazione delle terre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα δημόσια εδάφη για τους ανθρώπους είναι μη 
κερδοσκοπική οργάνωση "που αφιερώνεται στη συντήρηση των 
δικαιωμάτων του κοινού στην πρόσβαση και τη χρήση των δημόσιων 
εδαφών". Ο σκοπός της περιοχής είναι να εκπαιδευτούν οι 
άνθρωποι και οι κυβερνητικές αντιπροσωπείες για τα δικαιώματά 
τους και τους νόμους που ισχύουν για τους, με μια εστίαση στη 
χρήση των unappropriated δημόσιων εδαφών. Περιλαμβάνει 
μια νομική σελίδα των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς, με τις συνδέσεις με
όλα από τα ομοσπονδιακά έγγραφα στη Διακήρυξη των Η.Ε των 
ανθρώπινων δικαιωμάτων. Υπάρχει επίσης μια προτεινόμενη 
σελίδα πρόκλησης που δίνει έμφαση στη διαδικασία για μια 
πρόκληση νομιμότητας ασκώντας τις υπαίθριες δραστηριότητες. 
Επίσης διαθέσιμο είναι ένα φόρουμ συζήτησης για την 
υποβολή των ερωτήσεων και των απόψεων σχετικά με τα δημόσια 
ζητήματα χρήσης εδάφους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las pistas públicas para la gente son 
organización no lucrativa ' dedicada a preservar las derechas del 
público al acceso y al uso de las pistas públicas. El 
propósito del sitio es educar la gente y las agencias de estatal 
sobre las sus derechas y los leyes que se aplican a ellos, con un foco
en el uso de pistas públicas no asignadas. Incluye una 
paginación legal del recurso, con conexiones a todo de los papeles 
del federalista al declaración de la O.N.U de derechos humanos. 
Hay también una paginación sugerida del desafío que destaca 
el procedimiento para tratar un desafío de la legalidad mientras que 
persigue actividades al aire libre. También disponible está un
foro de la discusión para someter preguntas y opiniones con respecto 
a ediciones públicas de la utilización del suelo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GERALD HOBBS
FN:GERALD HOBBS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211777</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103014</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/public-lands-for-the-people</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
