<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106513</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106513</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206876</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Affidavit and Flyers from the Chinese Boycott Case</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Affidavit und Flieger vom chinesischen 
Boykott-Fall</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Déclaration sous serment et insectes du cas 
chinois de boycott</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Affidavit e insectos do exemplo chinês do 
boycott</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Affidavit ed alette di filatoio dal caso 
cinese di boicottaggio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένορκη κατάθεση και ιπτάμενα από την κινεζική 
περίπτωση μποϊκοταρίσματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Declaración jurada y aviadores del caso chino del
boicoteo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">introduces students to one instance in which immigrants overcame the ramifications of the Chinese Exclusion Act of 1882 through the U.S. judicial system. This lesson correlates to the National History Standards and National Standards for Civics and Social Sciences. It also has cross-curricular connections with history, government, language arts, and math.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Kursteilnehmer zu einem Fall vor, in dem 
Immigranten die Verzweigungen der chinesischen Ausschluss-Tat von 1882
durch das VEREINIGTE STAATEN Gerichtssystem überwanden. Diese 
Lektion bezieht mit den nationalen Geschichte Standards und den 
nationalen Standards für Gemeinschaftskunde und Sozialwissenschaften 
aufeinander. Sie hat auch Kreuzlehrplananschlüsse mit 
Geschichte, Regierung, Sprachenkünsten und Mathe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente des étudiants à un exemple dans lequel
les immigrés ont surmonté les ramifications de la Loi chinoise 
d'exclusion de 1882 par le système juridique des ETATS-UNIS. 
Cette leçon se corrèle avec les normes nationales d'histoire 
et des normes nationales pour l'éducation civique et les sciences 
sociales. Elle a également les connexions croix-curriculaires 
avec l'histoire, le gouvernement, les arts de langage, et les maths.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">introduz estudantes a um exemplo em que os 
immigrants superaram os ramifications do ato chinês da exclusão de 
1882 através do sistema judicial de ESTADOS UNIDOS. Esta 
lição correlaciona aos padrões nacionais do history e aos padrões 
nacionais para o civics e ciências sociais. Tem também 
conexões cruz-cross-curricular com o history, o governo, as artes da 
língua, e o math.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">introduce gli allievi ad un caso in cui gli 
immigranti hanno sormontato le ramificazioni della Legge cinese di
esclusione di 1882 attraverso il sistema giudiziario degli STATI 
UNITI. Questa lezione correla agli standard nazionali di storia 
ed agli standard nazionali per civics e le scienze sociali. 
Egualmente ha collegamenti traversa-d'insegnamento con storia, 
il governo, le arti di linguaggio ed il per la matematica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εισάγει τους σπουδαστές σε μια περίπτωση στην οποία οι
μετανάστες υπερνίκησαν τις διακλαδώσεις του κινεζικού νόμου 
αποκλεισμού 1882 μέσω του ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΥ δικαστικού συστήματος. 
Αυτό το μάθημα συσχετίζει στα εθνικά πρότυπα ιστορίας και 
τα εθνικά πρότυπα για Civics και τις κοινωνικές επιστήμες. 
Έχει επίσης τις διαγώνιος-διδακτικές συνδέσεις με την 
ιστορία, κυβέρνηση, γλωσσικές τέχνες, και math.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">introduce a estudiantes a un caso en el cual los 
inmigrantes superaron las ramificaciones del acto chino de la 
exclusión de 1882 a través del sistema judicial de ESTADOS UNIDOS. 
Esta lección correlaciona a los estándares nacionales de la 
historia y a los estándares nacionales para el civics y las ciencias 
sociales. También tiene conexiones cruz-del plan de estudios 
con historia, el gobierno, artes del lenguaje, y matemáticas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206876</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106513</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/affidavit-and-flyers-from-the-chinese-boycott-case</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
