<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/201105240</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>201105240</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212165</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Soil Erosion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Boden-Abnutzung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Érosion de Sol</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Erosão Do Solo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Erosione Del Terreno</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εδαφολογική διάβρωση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Erosión Del Suelo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site provides a collection of audio, visual, and informational resources about soil erosion. Animations and MPG movies cover topics including the migration of African dust across the Atlantic, bank erosion, rain splash erosion, dune sand saltation, and the physical and cultural effects of erosion in Haiti. The site also features audio and visual files about the Dust Bowl during the 1930's as well as links to galleries of soil erosion images.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site liefert eine Ansammlung Audio-, Sicht- 
und informatorische Betriebsmittel über Bodenabnutzung. 
Animationen und MPG Filme umfassen Themen einschließlich die 
Migration des afrikanischen Staubes über dem Atlantik, Bankabnutzung,
Regenspritzenabnutzung, Dünesand saltation und den körperlichen und 
kulturellen Effekten der Abnutzung in Haiti. Die Site 
kennzeichnet auch die Audio- und Sichtdateien über das Trockengebiet 
während der dreißiger Jahre sowie Links zu den Galerien der 
Bodenabnutzungbilder.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site fournit une collection de ressources 
sonores, visuelles, et informationnelles au sujet d'érosion de sol. 
Les animations et les films de MPG couvrent des sujets 
comprenant le transfert de la poussière africaine à travers l'Océan
atlantique, l'érosion de banque, l'érosion d'éclaboussure de pluie,
le saltation dunaire de sable, et les effets physiques et culturels
de l'érosion au Haïti. Le site comporte également les 
fichiers sonores et visuels au sujet de la cuvette de poussière 
pendant les années 30 aussi bien que des liens aux galeries des 
images d'érosion de sol.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local fornece uma coleção de recursos 
audio, visuais, e informativos sobre a erosão do solo. Os 
animations e os filmes de MPG cobrem tópicos including a migração 
da poeira africana através do Atlântico, da erosão do banco, da 
erosão do respingo da chuva, do saltation da areia da duna, e dos 
efeitos físicos e cultural da erosão em Haiti. O local 
caracteriza também limas audio e visuais sobre a bacia de poeira 
durante os 1930's as.well.as as ligações às galerias de imagens da 
erosão do solo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo fornisce una collezione di risorse 
audio, visive ed informative circa erosione del terreno. Le 
animazioni ed i film di MPG riguardano i soggetti compreso 
l'espansione di polvere africana attraverso l'Atlantico, l'erosione 
della banca, l'erosione della spruzzata della pioggia, il 
saltation della sabbia della duna e gli effetti fisici e culturali di 
erosione in Haiti. Il luogo egualmente caratterizza gli archivi 
audio e visivi circa la ciotola di polvere durante i 1930's così come
i collegamenti alle gallerie delle immagini di erosione del terreno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρέχει μια συλλογή των ηχητικών, 
οπτικών, και ενημερωτικών στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς για την 
εδαφολογική διάβρωση. Οι ζωτικότητες και οι κινηματογράφοι 
MPG καλύπτουν τα θέματα συμπεριλαμβανομένης της μετανάστευσης 
της αφρικανικής σκόνης πέρα από τον Ατλαντικό, τη διάβρωση 
τραπεζών, τη διάβρωση παφλασμών βροχής, το saltation άμμου 
αμμόλοφων, και τα φυσικά και πολιτιστικά αποτελέσματα της 
διάβρωσης στην Αϊτή. Η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει επίσης τα 
ηχητικά και οπτικά αρχεία για το κύπελλο σκόνης κατά τη 
διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '30 καθώς επίσης και των συνδέσεων με 
τις στοές των εικόνων εδαφολογικής διάβρωσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio proporciona a una colección de 
recursos audio, visuales, e informativos sobre la erosión del suelo. 
Las animaciones y las películas de MPG cubren asuntos 
incluyendo la migración del polvo africano a través del Atlántico, 
de la erosión de la batería, de la erosión del chapoteo de la 
lluvia, del saltation de la arena de la duna, y de los efectos 
físicos y culturales de la erosión en Haití. El sitio 
también ofrece ficheros audio y visuales sobre el tazón de fuente de
polvo durante los años 30 así como conexiones a las galerías de las
imágenes de la erosión del suelo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212165</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>201105240</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/soil-erosion</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
