<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104820</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104820</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973929</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Medicine Games: Incredible Megacell Game</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Medizin-Spiele: Unglaubliches Megacell 
Spiel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Médecine : Jeu Incroyable de 
Megacell</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Da Medicina: Jogo Incredible De 
Megacell</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Della Medicina: Gioco Incredibile Di 
Megacell</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια ιατρικής: Απίστευτο παιχνίδι 
Megacell</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Medicina: Juego Increíble De 
Megacell</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! The compartments of the cell, the organelles, are so small that it was impossible to study their structure until the electron microscope became available in 1938. Albert Claude, Christian de Duve and George E. Palade were awarded the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine in 1974 for developing methods making it possible to take a closer look at the organelles and for discovering some of them.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
Die Fächer der Zelle, die Organellen, sind so klein, daß es 
unmöglich war, ihre Struktur zu studieren, bis das 
Elektronenmikroskop 1938 vorhanden wurde. Albert Claude, 
Christian de Duve und George E. Palade wurden den Nobelpreis in der 
Physiologie oder Medizin 1974 für sich entwickelnden Methoden 
zugesprochen, die es möglich, die Organellen genau zu betrachten 
machen und für das Entdecken einige von ihnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! Les 
compartiments de la cellule, les organelles, sont si petits qu'il ait 
été impossible d'étudier leur structure jusqu'à ce que le 
microscope électronique soit devenu disponible en 1938. Albert 
Claude, Christian de Duve et George E. Palade ont été 
attribués le prix Nobel en physiologie ou la médecine en 1974 pour 
des méthodes se développantes permettant pour jeter un coup d'oeil 
plus étroit aux organelles et pour découvrir certains d'entre eux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! Os 
compartimentos da pilha, os organelles, foram assim pequenos que era 
impossível estudar sua estrutura até que o microscópio de elétron 
se tornou disponível em 1938. Albert Claude, Cristão de Duve e
George E. Palade foram concedidos o prêmio de nobel no physiology ou 
a medicina em 1974 para os métodos tornando-se que fazem a possível 
fazer exame de um olhar mais próximo nos organelles e para descobrir 
alguma deles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! Gli scompartimenti della 
cellula, gli organelli, sono così piccoli che era impossible da 
studiare la loro struttura fino a che il microscopio elettronico non 
sia diventato disponibile in 1938. Albert Claude, Christian de 
Duve e George E. Palade hanno ricevuto il premio Nobel in fisiologia o
la medicina in 1974 per i metodi di sviluppo che permettono di dare 
un'occhiata più vicina agli organelli e per la scoperta delle alcune 
di loro.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! _ ο 
διαμέρισμα ο κύτταρο, ο οργανελλες, είμαι τόσο μικρός που αυτός 
είμαι αδύνατος να μελετώ τους δομή έως ότου ο ηλεκτρονικός 
μικροσκόπιο διατίθεμαι διαθέσιμος 1938, Αλβέρτος Θ*Θλαuδε, 
Χριστιανός de Δuβε και George Ε. Παλαδε είμαι απο:νέμω ο 
Νόμπελ βραβείο φυσιολογία ή ιατρική 1974 για ανα:πτύσσω μέθοδος
καθ:ιστώ αυτός πιθανός να ρίχνω ένας στενός ματιά ο οργανελλες 
και για ανακαλύπτω μερικός αυτός.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! Los 
compartimientos de la célula, los organelles, son tan pequeños que 
era imposible estudiar su estructura hasta que el microscopio 
electrónico llegó a estar disponible en 1938. Concedieron 
Albert Claude, Christian de Duve y George E. Palade el premio Nobel en
fisiología o la medicina en 1974 para los métodos que se convertían
que permitían hechar una ojeada más cercano los organelles y para 
descubrir a algunos de ellos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973929</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104820</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/medicine-games-incredible-megacell-game</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
