<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106226</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106226</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207145</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Eisenhower Home Virtual Tour</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eisenhower Nach Hause Virtuelle Tour</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Excursion À la maison Virtuelle d'Eisenhower</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Excursão Para casa Virtual De Eisenhower</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giro A casa Virtuale Di Eisenhower</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εικονικός γύρος "Οικιαών Eisenhower</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Viaje A casa Virtual De Eisenhower</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site walks students through the house that was the only place President Eisenhower and his wife ever called home. In 1950, the Eisenhowers, looking forward to retirement, purchased the Allen Redding farm adjoining Gettysburg National Military Park. During his Presidency, President and Mrs. Eisenhower used the farm as a weekend retreat, a refuge in time of illness, and a comfortable meeting place for world leaders.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site geht Kursteilnehmer durch das Haus, das
der einzige Platz Präsident Eisenhower war und seine Frau überhaupt 
Haus benannte. 1950 kaufte das Eisenhowers, vorwärts schauend 
zum Ruhestand, den Allen Redding Bauernhof, der Gettysburg nationalen 
militärischen Park angrenzt. Während seines Vorsitzes 
benutzten Präsident und Mrs Eisenhower den Bauernhof als Wochenende 
Rückzug, einen Schutz in der Zeit der Krankheit und einen bequemen 
Treffpunkt für Weltführer.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site marche des étudiants par la maison qui 
était le seul Président Eisenhower d'endroit et son épouse a jamais
appelé la maison. En 1950, l'Eisenhowers, attendant avec 
intérêt la retraite, a acheté la ferme d'Allen Redding touchant le 
parc militaire national de Gettysburg. Pendant sa présidence, 
président et Mme Eisenhower ont utilisé la ferme comme retraite de 
week-end, un refuge en temps de maladie, et un endroit de réunion 
confortable pour des amorces du monde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local anda estudantes através da casa que 
era o único presidente Eisenhower do lugar e sua esposa chamou sempre
a HOME. Em 1950, o Eisenhowers, olhando para a frente à 
aposentadoria, comprou a fazenda de Allen Redding que é contíguo com
o parque militar nacional de Gettysburg. Durante seu presidency,
o presidente e a Sra. Eisenhower usaram a fazenda como um recuo do fim
de semana, um refúgio a tempo da doença, e um lugar de reunião 
confortável para líderes do mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo cammina allievi attraverso la casa 
che era l'unico presidente Eisenhower del posto e la sua moglie ha 
chiamato mai la sede. In 1950, il Eisenhowers, osservante in 
avanti alla pensione, ha comprato il podere dell'Allen Redding che 
congiunge il parco militare nazionale di Gettysburg. Durante la 
sua presidenza, il presidente e la sig.ra Eisenhower hanno usato il 
podere come ritirata di fine settimana, un rifugio in tempo di 
malattia e un punto d'incontro comodo per i capi del mondo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή περπατά τους σπουδαστές μέσω του 
σπιτιού που ήταν η μόνη θέση Πρόεδρος Eisenhower και η 
σύζυγός του κάλεσε πάντα το σπίτι. Το 1950, το 
Eisenhowers, που αναμένει με ενδιαφέρον την αποχώρηση, αγόρασε 
το αγρόκτημα Αλλεν Redding που γειτονεύει με το εθνικό 
στρατιωτικό πάρκο Gettysburg. Κατά τη διάρκεια της 
προεδρίας, του Προέδρου και της κας του Eisenhower χρησιμοποίησε
το αγρόκτημα ως υποχώρηση Σαββατοκύριακου, ένα καταφύγιο 
εγκαίρως της ασθένειας, και έναν άνετο χώρο συνάντησης για τους 
παγκόσμιους ηγέτες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio recorre los estudiantes a través de la
casa que era el único presidente Eisenhower del lugar y su esposa 
llamó siempre el hogar. En 1950, el Eisenhowers, mirando 
adelante al retiro, compró la granja de Allen Redding que colindaba 
el parque militar nacional de Gettysburg. Durante su 
presidencia, presidente y señora Eisenhower utilizaron la granja como
retratamiento del fin de semana, un refugio en la época de la 
enfermedad, y un lugar de reunión cómodo para los arranques de cinta
del mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207145</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106226</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/eisenhower-home-virtual-tour</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
