<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106846</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106846</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206322</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Einstein Papers Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einstein Tapeziert Projekt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Einstein Empaquette Le Projet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Einstein Papers O Projeto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Einstein Incarta Il Progetto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρόγραμμα εγγράφων Einstein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Einstein Empapela Proyecto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides information about the Einstein Papers Project, which publishes The Collected Papers of Albert Einstein, an edition of 25 planned volumes of Einstein's scientific, professional and personal papers, manuscripts and correspondence. The website lists the contents of each volume with a sample page from each, and tells how to order the series.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Informationen über die Einstein Papiere 
sich projizieren zur Verfügung, die die gesammelten Papiere von 
Albert Einstein veröffentlicht, eine Ausgabe von 25 geplanten 
Datenträgern von Einsteins wissenschaftlich, professionelle und 
persönliche Papiere, Manuskripte und Korrespondenz. Die Web 
site druckt den Inhalt jedes Datenträgers mit einer Beispielseite von
jedem aus und erklärt, wie man die Serie bestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit les informations au sujet des papiers 
d'Einstein projettent, qui éditent les papiers rassemblés d'Albert 
Einstein, une édition de 25 volumes prévus d'Einstein scientifiques,
papiers professionnels et personnels, manuscrits et correspondance. 
Le site Web énumère le contenu de chaque volume avec une page 
témoin de chacun, et indique comment commander la série.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece a informação sobre os papéis de 
Einstein projetam-se, que publica os papéis coletados de Albert 
Einstein, uma edição de 25 volumes de planeamento de Einstein 
científicos, papéis profissionais e pessoais, manuscritos e 
correspondência. O Web site alista os índices de cada volume 
com uma página da amostra de cada um, e diz como requisitar a série.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le informazioni sulle carte da Einstein 
si proiettano, che pubblicano le carte raccolte di Albert Einstein, 
un'edizione di 25 volumi previsti di Einstein scientifici, relazioni 
professionali e, manoscritti e corrispondenza. Il Web site 
elenca il contenuto di ogni volume con una pagina del campione da 
ciascuno e dice a come ordinare la serie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τις πληροφορίες για το πρόγραμμα εγγράφων 
Einstein, το οποίο δημοσιεύει τα συλλεχθέντα έγγραφα Αλβέρτου 
Einstein, μια έκδοση 25 προγραμματισμένων εντάσεων του ήχου 
των επιστημονικών, επαγγελματικών και προσωπικών εγγράφων 
Einstein, των χειρογράφων και της αλληλογραφίας. Ο 
ιστοχώρος εμφανίζει λίστα το περιεχόμενο κάθε τόμου με μια 
σελίδα δειγμάτων από κάθε μια, και λέει πώς να διατάξει τη 
σειρά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a la información sobre los papeles de
Einstein proyectan, que publica los papeles recogidos de Albert 
Einstein, una edición de 25 volúmenes previstos de Einstein 
científicos, los papeles profesionales y personales, los manuscritos 
y correspondencia. El Web site enumera el contenido de cada 
volumen con una paginación de la muestra de cada uno, y dice cómo 
pedir la serie.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206322</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106846</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/einstein-papers-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
