<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106439</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106439</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087694</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Rice University Connexions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reis-Universitätsanschlüsse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Connexions d'Université De Riz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Conexões Da Universidade Do Arroz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Collegamenti Dell'Università Del Riso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πανεπιστημιακές συνδέσεις ρυζιού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Conexiones De la Universidad Del Arroz</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Connexions is an environment for collaboratively developing, freely sharing, and rapidly publishing scholarly content on the Web. Our Content Commons contains educational materials for everyone -- from children to college students to professionals -- organized in small modules that are easily connected into larger courses. All content is free to use and reuse under the Creative Commons "attribution" license.</string>
          </description>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anschlüsse ist eine Umgebung für gemeinschaftlich
sich entwickeln und frei teilt, und schnell Verlags- gelehrter Inhalt 
auf dem Web unsere zufriedenen Common enthält pädagogische 
Materialien für jeder -- von Kinder zu Studenten zu den Fachleuten --
organisiert in den kleinen Modulen, die leicht in größere Kurse 
angeschlossen werden. Aller Inhalt ist frei, unter der kreativen
Common-"Zuerkennung" Lizenz zu verwenden und wiederzuverwenden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les connexions est un environnement pour en 
collaboration se développer, librement partager, et le contenu savant
rapidement d'édition sur le Web. Nos terrains communaux 
contents contient les matériaux éducatifs pour chacun -- des enfants
aux étudiants d'université aux professionnels -- organisé dans de 
petits modules qui sont facilement reliés dans de plus grands cours. 
Tout le contenu est libre pour utiliser et réutiliser sous le 
permis créateur d'"attribution" de terrains communaux.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As conexões são um ambiente para collaboratively 
tornar-se, livremente compartilhando, e o índice scholarly 
ràpidamente publicando no Web nossas terras comuns satisfeitas contem
materiais educacionais para todos -- das crianças aos estudantes de 
faculdade aos profissionais -- organizado nos módulos pequenos que 
são conectados fàcilmente em cursos maiores. Todo o índice 
está livre se usar e reúso sob a licença creativa do "attribution" 
das terras comuns.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I collegamenti è un ambiente per in collaborazione
lo sviluppo, liberamente ripartendosi ed il soddisfare da studioso 
velocemente di pubblicazione sul Web i nostri terreni comunali 
soddisfatti contiene i materiali educativi per tutto -- dai bambini 
agli allievi di università ai professionisti -- organizzato in 
piccoli moduli che sono collegati facilmente nei più grandi corsi. 
Tutto il soddisfare è libero usare e riutilizzare sotto 
l'autorizzazione creativa "di attribuzione" dei terreni comunali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι συνδέσεις είναι ένα περιβάλλον για σε συνεργασία 
να αναπτυχθούν, ελεύθερα να μοιραστούν, και το μορφωμένο 
περιεχόμενο γρήγορα έκδοσης στον Ιστό. Οι ικανοποιημένες 
αστικές τάξεις μας περιέχουν τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά για το καθένα
-- από τα παιδιά στους σπουδαστές κολλεγίων στους επαγγελματίες 
-- που οργανώνονται στις μικρές ενότητες που συνδέονται εύκολα με
τις μεγαλύτερες σειρές μαθημάτων. Όλο το περιεχόμενο είναι
ελεύθερο να χρησιμοποιήσει και επαναχρησιμοποίηση με άδεια 
δημιουργική "απόδοσησ" αστικών τάξεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las conexiones son un ambiente para de 
colaboración convertirse, libremente compartir, y el contenido de 
estudiante rápidamente que publica en el Web. Nuestros 
campos comunes contentos contienen los materiales educativos para cada
uno -- de niños a los estudiantes de universidad a los profesionales 
-- ordenado en los módulos pequeños que están conectados 
fácilmente en cursos más grandes. Todo el contenido está 
libre utilizar y reutilizar bajo la licencia creativa de la 
"atribución" de los campos comunes.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087694</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106439</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/matters/rice-university-connexions</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
