<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108444</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108444</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086349</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"It Set the Indian Aside as a Problem"A Sioux Attorney Criticizes the Indian Reorganization Act</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"sie stellte den Inder beiseite ein, wie ein 
Problem"A Sioux Rechtsanwalt die indische Reorganisierung-Tat 
kritisiert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"elle a placé l'Indien de côté comme un 
mandataire de Problem"A Sioux critique la Loi indienne de 
réorganisation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"ajustou o indian de lado como um advogado de 
Problem"A Sioux critica o ato indian do reorganization</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ha regolato l'indiano da parte come un avvocato 
di Problem"A Sioux critica la Legge indiana della riorganizzazione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Έθεσε τον ινδικό κατά μέρος δεδομένου ότι ένας 
σιού πληρεξούσιος Problem"A επικρίνει τον ινδικό νόμο 
αναδιοργάνωσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"fijó a indio a un lado como un abogado de 
Problem"A Sioux critica el acto indio de la reorganización</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Indian Reorganization Act of 1934, which became known as the Indian New Deal, dramatically changed the federal government's Indian policy. Although John Collier, commissioner of Indian affairs who was responsible for the new policy, may have viewed Indians with great sympathy, not all Native Americans viewed the Indian New Deal in equally positive terms. In this 1968 interview with historian Joseph H. Cash, attorney Ramon Roubideaux, a Brule Sioux, denounced the Indian Reorganization Act as "a white man's idea" of how Indians should live and argued that it "set the Indian people aside from the mainstream of American life and made them a problem."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die indische Reorganisierung-Tat von 1934, die als
das indische neue Abkommen bekannt wurde, indische Politik der 
drastisch geänderten die Bundesregierung. Obgleich John 
Collier, Beauftragter der indischen Angelegenheiten, der für die neue
Politik verantwortlich war, Inder mit großer Sympathie angesehen 
haben kann, sahen nicht alle gebürtigen Amerikaner das indische neue 
Abkommen in den gleichmäßig positiven Bezeichnungen an. In 
diesem Interview 1968 mit Historiker Joseph H. Cash, Rechtsanwalt 
Ramon Roubideaux, ein Brule Sioux, kündigte die indische 
Reorganisierung-Tat als "Idee eines weißen Mannes" von, wie Inder 
leben sollten und argumentierte, daß sie "die indischen Leute neben 
dem Mainstream der amerikanischen Lebensdauer einstellte und bildete 
sie ein Problem."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Loi indienne de réorganisation de 1934, qui 
est devenue notoire comme nouvelle affaire indienne, la politique 
indienne de gouvernement fédéral excessivement changé. Bien 
que John Collier, le commissaire des affaires indiennes qui était 
responsable de la nouvelle politique, ait pu avoir visualisé des 
Indiens avec la grande sympathie, non tous les Américains indigènes 
ont visualisé la nouvelle affaire indienne en termes également 
positifs. Dans cette entrevue 1968 avec l'historien Joseph H. 
Cash, mandataire Ramon Roubideaux, un Brule Sioux, a dénoncé l'acte 
indien de réorganisation en tant que "idée d'un homme blanc" de la 
façon dont les Indiens devraient vivre et a argué du fait qu'elle "a
placé les  indiens hormis le courant principal de la vie américaine 
et leur a fait un problème."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ato indian do reorganization de 1934, que se 
tornou sabido como o negócio novo indian, a política indian de 
governo federal dramàtica mudado. Embora o collier de John, o 
comissário de casos indian que era responsável para a política 
nova, pudesse ter visto indians com sympathy grande, não todos os 
americanos nativos viram o negócio novo indian em termos ingualmente 
positivos. Nesta entrevista 1968 com historian Joseph H. 
Dinheiro, advogado Ramon Roubideaux, um Brule Sioux, denounced o ato 
indian do reorganization como "a idéia de um homem branco" de como os
indians devem viver e discutiu que "ajustou os povos indian com 
exceção do mainstream da vida americana e fêz-lhes um problema."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Legge indiana della riorganizzazione di 1934, 
che è stato conosciuta come il nuovo affare indiano, politica indiana
del governo federale drammaticamente cambiato. Anche se il 
collier del John, commissario degli affari indiani che era 
responsabile di nuova politica, può osservare gli indiani con 
compassione grande, non tutti gli Americani natali hanno osservato il 
nuovo affare indiano nei termini ugualmente positivi. In questa 
intervista 1968 con lo storico Joseph H. Cash, l'avvocato Ramon 
Roubideaux, un Brule Sioux, ha denunciato la Legge indiana della 
riorganizzazione come "idea dell'uomo bianco" di come gli indiani 
dovrebbero vivere ed ha sostenuto che "ha regolato la gente indiana 
oltre alla corrente principale di vita americana ed ha reso loro un 
problema."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ινδικός νόμος αναδιοργάνωσης του 1934, που έγινε 
γνωστός ως ινδική νέα διαπραγμάτευση, άλλαξε εντυπωσιακά την 
ινδική πολιτική της ομοσπονδιακής κυβέρνησης. Αν και John
Collier, Επίτροπος των ινδικών υποθέσεων που ήταν αρμόδιος για
τη νέα πολιτική, μπορεί να είχε εμφανίσει Ινδούς με τη μεγάλη 
συμπόνοια, δεν εμφάνισαν όλοι οι εγγενείς Αμερικανοί την ινδική 
νέα διαπραγμάτευση στους εξίσου θετικούς όρους. Σε αυτήν 
την συνέντευξη του 1968 με τον ιστορικό Joseph H. Cash, 
πληρεξούσιος Ramon Roubideaux, ένα Brule Σιού, κατήγγειλε
τον ινδικό νόμο αναδιοργάνωσης ως "άσπρη ανθρώπινη ιδέα" για το 
πώς Ινδοί πρέπει να ζήσουν και υποστήριξαν ότι "έθεσαν τους 
ινδικούς ανθρώπους εκτός από τάση της αμερικανικής ζωής και 
τους έκαναν ένα πρόβλημα."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El acto indio de la reorganización de 1934, que 
se conocía como el nuevo reparto indio, la política india del 
gobierno federal dramáticamente cambiante. Aunque el collier de
Juan, la comisión de asuntos indios que era responsable de la nueva 
política, pudo haber visto a indios con gran condolencia, no todos 
los americanos nativos vieron el nuevo reparto indio en términos 
igualmente positivos. En esta entrevista 1968 con el historiador
José H. Cash, abogado Ramon Roubideaux, un Brule Sioux, denunci el 
acto indio de la reorganización como "idea de un hombre blanco" de 
cómo los indios deben vivir y discutió que "fijó a gente india 
aparte de la corriente principal de la vida americana y le hizo un 
problema."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086349</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108444</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/it-set-the-indian-aside-as-a-problem-a-sioux-attorney-criticizes-the-indian-reorganization-act</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
