<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108755</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108755</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087019</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The People Were Very Peaceable": The U.S. Senate Investigates the Haitian Occupation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Leute Waren" Sehr Friedlich: Der 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Senat forscht die haitianische Besetzung nach</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Les Personnes Étaient Très Pacifiques" : 
Le sénat des ETATS-UNIS étudie le métier haïtien</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Os Povos Eram Muito Peaceable": O senate de
ESTADOS UNIDOS investiga a ocupação haitian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"La Gente Era Molto Peaceable": Il senato 
degli STATI UNITI studia l'occupazione haitian</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι άνθρωποι ήταν πολύ peaceable": Η 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ Σύγκλητος ερευνά το αϊτινό επάγγελμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"La Gente Era Muy Peaceable": El senado de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS investiga la ocupación haitiana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Largely at the behest of American bankers, U.S. marines occupied Haiti from 1915 to 1934. By 1919, Haitian Charlemagne Pralte had organized more than a thousand  cacos , or armed guerrillas, to militarily oppose the marine occupation. The marines responded to the resistance with a counterinsurgency campaign that razed villages, killed thousands of Haitians, and destroyed the livelihoods of even more. The military atrocities and abuse of power during the  Caco  War of 1919-1920 led to a U.S. Senate investigation into the occupation. In these excerpts from the "Inquiry into Occupation and Administration of Haiti," the U.S. Senate Select Committee on Haiti and Santo Domingo interviewed Haitians about marine conduct in the guerrilla war against the  cacos .</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Groß am Geheiße der amerikanischen Banker, 
besetzten VEREINIGTE STAATEN Marinen Haiti von 1915 bis 1934. 
Bis zum 1919 hatte haitianischer Karl der Große Pralte mehr als
tausend cacos oder bewaffnete Bandenkämpfer organisiert, um der 
Marinebesetzung militärisch entgegenzusetzen. Die Marinen 
reagierten auf den Widerstand mit einer Gegenaufstandkampagne, die 
Dörfer razed, Tausenden Haitianer beendete und die Lebensunterhalt 
von sogar mehr zerstörte. Die militärischen Grausamkeiten und 
der Mißbrauch der Energie während des Caco Krieges von 1919-1920 
führten zu eine VEREINIGTE STAATEN Senatuntersuchung in die 
Besetzung. In diesen Excerpts von der "Anfrage über Besetzung 
und Leitung von Haiti," interviewte der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Senat-auserwählte Ausschuß für Haiti und Santo Domingo Haitianer 
über Marineführung im Bandenkämpferkrieg gegen die cacos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En grande partie à la demande des banquiers 
américains, les soldats de marine des ETATS-UNIS ont occupé le 
Haïti de 1915 à 1934. D'ici 1919, Charlemagne haïtien Pralte 
avait organisé plus que mille cacos, ou les guérilleros armés, pour
s'opposer militairement au métier marin. Les soldats de marine 
ont répondu à la résistance avec une campagne de 
contre-insurrection qui a rasé des villages, a détruit 
des milliers de haïtiens, et a détruit les vies d'encore plus. 
Les atrocités et l'abus militaires de la puissance pendant la 
guerre de Caco de 1919-1920 ont mené à une recherche de sénat des 
ETATS-UNIS sur le métier. Dans ces extraits de l'"enquête dans
le métier et la gestion du Haïti," le comité choisi de sénat des 
ETATS-UNIS du Haïti et du Santo Domingo a interviewé des haïtiens 
au sujet de conduite marine dans la guerre de guérillero contre les 
cacos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pela maior parte no behest de banqueiros 
americanos, os fuzileiros navais de ESTADOS UNIDOS ocuparam Haiti de 
1915 a 1934. Por 1919, Charlemagne haitian Pralte tinha 
organizado mais do que mil cacos, ou guerrillas armados, para opôr 
militar a ocupação marinha. Os fuzileiros navais responderam 
à resistência com uma campanha do counterinsurgency que razed vilas,
matasse milhares dos haitians, e destruísse os meios de subsistência
de mesmo mais. Os atrocities e o abuso militares da potência 
durante a guerra de Caco de 1919-1920 conduziram a uma investigação 
do senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS na ocupação. Nestes excerpts do 
"inquérito na ocupação e na administração de Haiti," o comitê 
seleto do senate de ESTADOS UNIDOS em Haiti e em Santo Domingo 
entrevistou haitians sobre a conduta marinha na guerra do guerrilla de
encontro aos cacos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I banchieri in gran parte sull'ordine di americani, 
fanti di marina degli STATI UNITI hanno occupato l'Haiti da 1915 a 
1934. Entro 1919, Charlemagne haitian Pralte aveva organizzato 
più di mille cacos, o i guerriglieri muniti, per opporre militarmente 
l'occupazione marina. I fanti di marina hanno risposto alla 
resistenza con una campagna del counterinsurgency che razed i 
villaggi, ha ucciso i migliaia dei haitians ed ha distrutto le 
vite di ancor più. Le atrocità e l'abuso militari di potenza
durante la guerra di Caco di 1919-1920 hanno condotto ad una ricerca 
del senato degli STATI UNITI sull'occupazione. In questi brani 
"dall'inchiesta nell'occupazione e nella gestione dell'Haiti," il 
comitato ristretto del senato degli STATI UNITI dell'Haiti e di Santo 
Domingo ha intervistato i haitians circa comportamento marino nella 
guerra del guerrigliero contro i cacos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος στην εντολή των αμερικανικών 
τραπεζιτών, τα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ ναυτικά κατέλαβαν την Αϊτή από το 
1915 ως το 1934. Μέχρι το 1919, αϊτινό 
Charlemagne Pralte είχε οργανώσει περισσότερα από χίλια 
cacos, ή τους οπλισμένους αντάρτες, για να αντιτάξει 
στρατιωτικά το θαλάσσιο επάγγελμα. Τα ναυτικά αποκρίθηκαν 
στην αντίσταση με μια εκστρατεία αντιεξέγερσης που τα χωριά, 
σκότωσε χιλιάδες Αϊτινοί, και κατέστρεψε τα livelihoods ακόμη
και περισσότερο. Οι στρατιωτικές αγριότητες και η κατάχρηση 
της εξουσίας κατά τη διάρκεια του πολέμου Caco του 1919-1920
οδήγησαν σε μια έρευνα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Συγκλήτου σχετικά με το 
επάγγελμα. Σε αυτά τα αποσπάσματα από τη "έρευνα στο 
επάγγελμα και τη διοίκηση της Αϊτής," η επίλεκτη Επιτροπή 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Συγκλήτου της Αϊτής και Santo Domingo πήρε 
συνέντευξη από Αϊτινούς για τη θαλάσσια συμπεριφορά στον πόλεμο
ανταρτών ενάντια στα cacos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En gran parte en el orden de banqueros 
americanos, los infantes de marina de ESTADOS UNIDOS ocuparon Haití a
partir de 1915 a 1934. Antes de 1919, Charlemagne haitiano 
Pralte había ordenado más que mil cacos, o a guerrillas armados, 
para oponer militar la ocupación marina. Los infantes de marina
respondieron a la resistencia con una campaña del counterinsurgency 
que razed aldeas, mató a millares de haitianos, y destruyó los 
sustentos de aún más. Las atrocidades y el abuso militares de 
la potencia durante la guerra de Caco de 1919-1920 condujeron a una 
investigación del senado de ESTADOS UNIDOS en la ocupación. En
estos extractos de la "pregunta en la ocupación y la administración 
de Haití," el comité selecto del senado de ESTADOS UNIDOS sobre 
Haití y Santo Domingo se entrevistó con a haitianos sobre conducta
marina en la guerra del guerrilla contra los cacos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087019</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108755</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-people-were-very-peaceable-the-u-s-senate-investigates-the-haitian-occupation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
