<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108600</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108600</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087103</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"They Want to Muzzle Public Opinion": John Howard Lawson's Warning to the American Public</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"sie möchten Muzzle öffentliche Meinung": 
John Howard Lawsons WARNING zur amerikanischen Öffentlichkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"elles veulent museler l'opinion publique" : 
Avertissement de John Howard Lawson au public américain</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"querem açaimar a opinião pública": Aviso
de John Howard Lawson ao público americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"desiderano mettere la museruola all'opinione 
pubblica": Avvertimento del John Howard Lawson al pubblico 
americano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Θέλουν κατά την κοινή γνώμη ρυγχών": 
Προειδοποίηση John Howard Lawson's στο αμερικανικό 
κοινό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"desean abozalar la opinión pública": 
Alerta de Juan Howard Lawson al público americano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Playwright and screenwriter John Howard Lawson, the president and organizing force of the Screen Writers' Guild and acknowledged leader of the Communist Party in Hollywood in the late 1930s, became the first "unfriendly" witness subpoenaed to testify before the House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC) on October 27, 1947. This followed a week-long session during which numerous studio heads, stars, and others spoke at length about purported Communist activity in the industry. During that first week, film critic and former screenwriter John Charles Moffitt detailed Lawson's supposed instructions to writers on how to get propaganda into films. When his turn came, Lawson attempted unsuccessfully to read a statement into the record warning that the investigation threatened basic American rights and liberties. That statement appears below following the testimonies of Moffitt and Lawson. With nine other "unfriendly" witnesses, Lawson gambled that the Committee would issue contempt citations for their refusal to answer questions about their political associations and beliefs, and that after a court case and appeal, the Supreme Court would rule that such questioning violated their First Amendment rights. Further HUAC interrogations would thus be stopped. In 1949, however, before the appeal reach the high court, two liberal justices died, and the next year, the newly constituted Court refused to hear their appeal. The Ten were sent to prison as a result, and in 1951, HUAC continued its Hollywood probe.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Stückeschreiber und Drehbuchautor John Howard 
Lawson, der Präsident und organisierende Kraft von von der Zünft und
bestätigten dem Führer der Bildschirm-Verfasser der kommunistischen 
Partei in Hollywood in den späten dreißiger Jahren, wurden 
der erste "unfreundliche" Zeuge, der subpoenaed ist, um vor dem 
Haus-Ausschuß für Un-Amerikanische Aktivitäten (HUAC) an Oktober 
27, 1947 zu bezeugen. Dieses folgte einer Woche-langen Sitzung, 
während deren zahlreiches Studio vorangeht, Sternen, und andere 
sprachen ausführlich über behauptete kommunistische Aktivität in 
der Industrie. Während diese erste Woche, des Filmkritikers und
ehemaliges Drehbuchautor Johns Charles Moffitt genau geschildertes 
Lawsons der gesollten Anweisungen zu den Verfassern auf, wie man 
Propaganda in Filme erhält. Als seine Umdrehung kam, versuchte 
Lawson erfolglos, eine Anweisung in das RekordcWarning zu lesen daß 
die Untersuchung bedrohten grundlegenden amerikanischen Rechte und die
Freiheiten. Diese Anweisung erscheint unterhalb des Folgens der 
Zeugnisse von Moffitt und von Lawson. Mit neun anderen 
"unfreundlichen" Zeugen spielte Lawson, daß der Ausschuß 
Verachtungzitieren herausgeben würde, damit ihre Ablehnung Fragen 
über ihre politischen Verbindungen und Glauben beantwortet, und daß,
nachdem ein Gerichtfall und -anklang, das Höchste Gericht anordnen 
würden, daß solches Ausfragen ihre erste Änderung Rechte verletzte.
Weitere HUAC Befragungen würden folglich gestoppt. 1949 
jedoch bevor die Anklangreichweite das hohe Gericht, zwei liberale 
Gerechtigkeit starb, und das folgende Jahr das eben festgesetzte 
Gericht abgelehnt, um ihren Anklang zu hören. Die 10 wurden zum
Gefängnis infolgedessen geschickt, und 1951, setzte HUAC seine 
Hollywood Prüfspitze fort.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le dramaturge et le scénariste John Howard 
Lawson, président et force d'organisation de la guilde et de l'amorce
reconnue des scénaristes du parti communiste dans Hollywood vers la 
fin des années 30, sont devenus le premier témoin "peu amical" cité
pour témoigner devant le comité de Chambre des activités 
Un-Américaines (HUAC) 27 octobre 1947. Ceci a suivi une 
session d'une semaine pendant laquelle les nombreuses têtes de studio,
tient le premier rôle, et d'autres ont parlé longuement sur l'activité 
communiste prétendue dans l'industrie. Pendant des instructions
supposées de cette première semaine, de critique de film et ancien 
de John Charles Moffitt Lawson détaillé de scénariste aux auteurs 
sur la façon dont entrer la propagande dans des films. Quand 
son tour est venu, Lawson a essayé sans succès de lire un rapport 
dans l'avertissement record que les droites et les libertés 
américaines de base menacées par recherche. Ce rapport 
apparaît au-dessous de suivre les témoignages de Moffitt et de 
Lawson. Avec neuf autres témoins "peu amicaux", Lawson a joué 
que le Comité émettrait des citations de mépris pour que leur refus
réponde à des questions au sujet de leurs associations et croyance 
politiques, et qu'après qu'une affaire en jugement et un appel, la 
cour suprême règnent qu'une telle interrogation a violé leurs 
droites de premier amendement. D'autres interrogations de HUAC 
seraient ainsi arrêtées. Par 1949, cependant, avant que 
l'extension d'appel la cour élevée, deux justices libérales soit 
morte, et année suivante, la cour nouvellement constituée refusée 
pour entendre leur appel. Les Dix ont été envoyés à la 
prison en conséquence, et en 1951, HUAC a continué sa sonde de 
Hollywood.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O playwright e o screenwriter John Howard Lawson, 
presidente e força organizando do guild e do líder reconhecido dos 
escritores da tela do partido comunista em Hollywood nos 1930s 
atrasados, transformaram-se a primeira testemunha "hostil" subpoenaed 
para testify antes do comitê da casa nas atividades Un-Americanas 
(HUAC) outubro em 27, 1947. Isto seguiu uma sessão semana-longa
durante que o estúdio numeroso dirige, estrelas, e outro falou no 
comprimento sobre a atividade comunista purported na indústria. 
Durante instruções supostas dessa primeira semana, de crítico
da película e de John Charles Moffitt Lawson detalhado anterior do 
screenwriter aos escritores em como começar o propaganda em 
películas. Quando sua volta veio, Lawson tentou em vão ler uma
indicação no aviso record que as direitas e as liberdades americanas
básicas ameaçadas investigação. Essa indicação aparece 
abaixo de seguir os testimonies de Moffitt e de Lawson. Com 
outras nove testemunhas "hostis", Lawson gambled que o comitê 
emitiria citações do contempt para que sua recusa responda a 
perguntas sobre suas associações e opinião políticas, e que depois
que um exemplo e uma apelação de corte, a corte suprema governariam 
que tal questionar violated suas direitas da primeira emenda. 
Umas interrogações mais adicionais de HUAC seriam paradas 
assim. Em 1949, entretanto, antes que o alcance da apelação a 
corte elevada, duas justiças liberais morrer, e no ano seguinte, a 
corte recentemente constituída recusada ouvir sua apelação. 
Os dez foram emitidos à prisão em conseqüência, e em 1951, 
HUAC continuou sua ponta de prova de Hollywood.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il playwright e lo screenwriter John Howard 
Lawson, il presidente e forza d'organizzazione della cooperativa e del
capo riconosciuto dei produttori dello schermo del partito 
comunista in Hollywood verso la fine dei 1930s, sono diventato il 
primo testimone "unfriendly" subpoenaed per testimoniare prima del 
comitato della Camera delle attività ONU-Americane (HUAC) il 27 
ottobre 1947. Ciò ha seguito una sessione settimana-lunga 
durante cui l'studio numeroso dirige, stelle ed altre hanno parlato 
lungamente di attività comunista pretesa nell'industria. 
Durante le istruzioni supposte di quella prima settimana, del 
critico della pellicola e del John Charles Moffitt Lawson dettagliato 
precedente dello screenwriter ai produttori su come entrare propaganda
nelle pellicole. Quando la sua girata è venuto, Lawson ha 
tentato senza successo di leggere un'istruzione nell'avvertimento 
record che la ricerca ha minacciato i diritti e le libertà americani 
di base. Quell'istruzione compare sotto quanto segue le 
testimonianze di Moffitt e di Lawson. Con altri nove testimoni 
"unfriendly", Lawson ha giocato che il comitato pubblicherebbe le 
citazioni di contempt affinchè il loro rifiuto rispondesse alle 
domande circa le loro associazioni e credenza politiche e che dopo che
un caso e un appello di corte, la Corte suprema regolassero che tale 
interrogazione ha violato i loro diritti di prima correzione. 
Ulteriori interrogazioni di HUAC sarebbero interrotte così. 
Durante 1949, tuttavia, prima che l'estensione di appello l'alta
corte, due giustizie liberali muoia e l'anno prossimo, la corte 
recentemente costituita rifiutata per sentire il loro appello. I
dieci sono stati trasmessi alla prigione di conseguenza ed in 1951, 
HUAC ha continuato la relativa sonda di Hollywood.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο θεατρικός συγγραφέας και screenwriter John 
Howard Lawson, ο Πρόεδρος και η οργάνωση της δύναμης της 
οθόνης του αναγνωρισμένου ηγέτη των συγγραφέων συντεχνίας και του
Κομμουνιστικού Κόμματος σε Hollywood προς το τέλος της 
δεκαετίας του '30, έγιναν ο πρώτος "μη φιλικόσ" μάρτυρας που 
κλητεύθηκε για να πιστοποιήσει ενώπιον της Επιτροπής Βουλών των 
αντιαμερικανικών δραστηριοτήτων (HUAC) στις 27 Οκτωβρίου, το 
1947. Αυτό ακολούθησε μια μίας εβδομάδας περίοδο 
επικοινωνίας κατά τη διάρκεια της οποίας τα πολυάριθμα κεφάλια, 
τα αστέρια, και άλλες στούντιο μίλησαν επί μακρόν για την 
ισχυρισμένη κομμουνιστική δραστηριότητα στη βιομηχανία. 
Κατά τη διάρκεια εκείνης της πρώτης εβδομάδας, ο κριτικός 
και το προηγούμενο screenwriter John Charles Moffitt 
ταινιών απαρίθμησαν τις υποτιθέμενες οδηγίες Lawson στους 
συγγραφείς στο πώς να πάρουν την προπαγάνδα στις ταινίες. 
Όταν η στροφή του ήρθε, Lawson προσπάθησε ανεπιτυχώς να 
διαβάσει μια δήλωση στην προειδοποίηση αρχείων ότι η έρευνα 
απείλησε τα βασικές αμερικανικές δικαιώματα και τις ελευθερίες. 
Εκείνη η δήλωση εμφανίζεται κατωτέρω μετά από τις 
καταθέσεις Moffitt και Lawson. Με εννέα άλλους "μη 
φιλικούσ" μάρτυρες, Lawson που παίζεται ότι η Επιτροπή θα 
εξέδιδε τις παραπομπές περιφρόνησης για την άρνησή τους να 
απαντήσουν στις ερωτήσεις για τις πολιτικές ενώσεις και τις 
πεποιθήσεις τους, και ότι μετά από μια δικαστική υπόθεση και μια
έκκληση, το ανώτατο δικαστήριο θα διέταζε ότι τέτοια επερώτηση 
παραβίασε τα πρώτα δικαιώματα τροποποιήσεών τους. Τις 
περαιτέρω ερωτήσεις HUAC θα σταματούσαν έτσι. Το 1949,
εντούτοις, πριν από την προσιτότητα έκκλησης το ανώτατο 
δικαστήριο, δύο φιλελεύθερα justices πέθανε, και το επόμενο 
έτος, το πρόσφατα αποτελεσμένο δικαστήριο αρνήθηκε να εξετάσει 
την έκκλησή τους. Οι Δέκα στάλησαν στη φυλακή κατά 
συνέπεια, και το 1951, HUAC συνέχισε τον έλεγχο Hollywood 
του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El dramaturgo y el guionista Juan Howard Lawson, 
el presidente y fuerza de ordenación del gremio y del arranque de 
cinta reconocido de los programas de escritura de la pantalla del 
partido comunista en Hollywood en los últimos años 30, hicieron el 
primer testigo "antipático" citado para atestiguar ante el comité de
la casa sobre las actividades Un-Americanas (HUAC) 27 de octubre de
1947. Esto siguió una sesión semana-larga durante la cual el 
estudio numeroso dirigió, estrellas, y otros hablaron largamente 
sobre actividad comunista pretendida en la industria. Durante 
instrucciones supuestas de esa primera semana, del crítico de la 
película y de Juan Charles Moffitt Lawson detallado anterior del 
guionista a los programas de escritura en cómo conseguir propaganda 
en las películas. Cuando vino su vuelta, Lawson procuró sin 
éxito leer una declaración en la alerta de registro que las derechas
y las libertades americanas básicas amenazadas investigación. 
Esa declaración aparece debajo de seguir los testimonios de 
Moffitt y de Lawson. Con nueve otros testigos "antipáticos", 
Lawson jugó que el comité publicaría las citaciones del desprecio 
para que su denegación conteste a preguntas sobre sus asociaciones y 
creencia políticas, y que después de que un proceso legal y una 
súplica, el Tribunal Supremo gobernaran que el tal preguntar violó 
las sus derechas de primera enmienda. Interrogaciones más 
futuras de HUAC serían paradas así. En 1949, sin embargo, 
antes de que el alcance de la súplica la tribunal superior, dos 
justicias liberales muriera, y el año próximo, la corte nuevamente 
constituida rechazada para oír su súplica. Los diez fueron 
enviados a la prisión consecuentemente, y en 1951, HUAC continuó su 
punta de prueba de Hollywood.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087103</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108600</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/they-want-to-muzzle-public-opinion-john-howard-lawsons-warning-to-the-american-public</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
