<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105258</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105258</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206773</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mechanics Hall: Symbol of Pride and Industry</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mechaniker Hall: Symbol des Stolzes und der 
Industrie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mécanique Hall : Symbole de fierté et 
d'industrie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mecânicos Salão: Símbolo do orgulho e da 
indústria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Meccanici Corridoio: Simbolo di orgoglio e 
di industria</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αίθουσα μηχανικών: Σύμβολο της υπερηφάνειας και 
της βιομηχανίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mecánicos Pasillo: Símbolo del orgullo y 
de la industria</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">traces the history of Mechanics Hall and Worcester back to the industrial revolution. Built by the mechanics association for classes, public debates, lectures, and entertainment, the hall opened in 1857 as showcase of innovative building techniques and mechanical systems. It remained the center of Worcester's cultural life into the mid-20th century.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">vollzieht die Geschichte der Mechaniker Hall und 
Worcester zurück zu der industriellen Revolution nach. 
Aufgebaut durch die Mechanikerverbindung für Kategorien, 
allgemeine Debatten, Vorträge und Unterhaltung, die Halle geöffnet 
in 1857 als Schaukasten der erfinderischen Gebäudetechniken und 
mechanische Systeme. Es blieb die Mitte von Worcesters 
kultureller Lebensdauer in das mid-20th Jahrhundert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">trace l'histoire de la mécanique Hall et 
Worcester de nouveau à la révolution industrielle. Construit 
par l'association de mécanique pour des classes, des discussions 
publiques, des conférences, et divertissement, le hall ouvert dans 
1857 comme étalage des techniques innovatrices de bâtiment et 
systèmes mécaniques. C'est resté le centre de la vie 
culturelle de Worcester dans le siècle de mid-20th.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">segue o history da parte traseira dos mecânicos 
Salão e do Worcester à volta industrial. Construído pela 
associação dos mecânicos para classes, debates públicos, lectures,
e entertainment, o salão aberto em 1857 como o showcase de técnicas 
inovativas do edifício e sistemas mecânicos. Remanesceu o 
centro da vida cultural de Worcester no século de mid-20th.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">segue la storia dei meccanici Corridoio e 
Worcester di nuovo alla rivoluzione industriale. Costruito 
dall'associazione dei meccanici per i codici categoria, i dibattiti 
pubblici, conferenze ed intrattenimento, il corridoio si è aperto in 
1857 come montra delle tecniche innovarici della costruzione
e dei sistemi meccanici. È rimasto il centro di vita culturale 
de Worcester nel secolo di mid-20th.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">επισημαίνει την ιστορία της αίθουσας και του 
Worcester μηχανικών πίσω στη βιομηχανική επανάσταση. 
Χτισμένη από την ένωση μηχανικών για τις κλάσεις, δημόσιες
συζητήσεις, διαλέξεις, και ψυχαγωγία, η αίθουσα άνοιξε το 1857
ως προθήκη των καινοτόμων τεχνικών οικοδόμησης και των μηχανικών 
συστημάτων. Παρέμεινε το κέντρο της πολιτιστικής ζωής του 
Worcester στο μέσος-20ό αιώνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">rastrea la historia de los mecánicos Pasillo y 
Worcester de nuevo a la revolución industrial. Construido por 
la asociación de los mecánicos para las clases, discusiones 
públicos, conferencias, y hospitalidad, el pasillo abierto en 1857 
como escaparate de las técnicas innovadoras del edificio y sistemas 
mecánicos. Seguía siendo el centro de la vida cultural de 
Worcester en el siglo de mid-20th.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206773</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105258</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mechanics-hall-symbol-of-pride-and-industry</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
