<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107071</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107071</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086731</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Pilgrims' Progress: A Seventeenth-Century Solution to the Nineteenth-Century Conflict between Labor and Capital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Fortschritt Der Pilgrims': Eine 
Seventeenth-Jahrhundert Lösung zur 19.-Jahrhundert $überschneidung 
zwischen Arbeit und Kapital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Progrès des Pélerins : Une solution de 
Dix-septième-Siècle au conflit de Dix-neuvième-Siècle entre le 
travail et le capital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Progresso Dos Pilgrims': Uma solução de 
Décimo-Século ao conflito de Décimo-Século entre o trabalho e o 
capital</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progresso Dei Pilgrims: Una soluzione di 
Diciassettesimo-Secolo al conflitto di Diciannovesimo-Secolo fra il 
Lavoro ed il capitale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρόοδος προσκυνητών: Μια λύση δέκατος-αιώνα στη
σύγκρουση δέκατος-αιώνα μεταξύ της εργασίας και του κεφαλαίου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Progreso De los Peregrinos: Una solución 
del Decimose'ptimo-Siglo al conflicto del Diecinueveavo-Siglo entre el
trabajo y el capital</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In order to challenge the emphasis on extreme economic individualism espoused by Gilded Age industrialists and laissez-faire theorists in the late 19th century, labor writers drew on diverse historical and religious traditions. Massachusetts labor reformer George McNeill, for example, found in early Pilgrim life and thought the roots of a rejected American tradition of commonwealth and cooperative activity that he thought should be rekindled. In this 1884 piece published in the  Cigar Makers' Official Journal , McNeill invoked the tradition of cooperative living that sustained the Pilgrims in the 1600s in New England as a role model for modern relations between labor and capital.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Um das Hauptgewicht auf dem extremen 
Wirtschaftsindividualismus herauszufordern, der von vergoldeten Alter 
Industriellen und von Laissez-Faire Theoretikern im des späten 19. 
jahrhunderts Jahrhundert unterstützt wurde, zeichneten 
Arbeitsverfasser auf verschiedene historische und fromme Traditionen. 
Massachusetts ArbeitsReformer George McNeill z.B. gefunden
in der frühen Pilgrimlebensdauer und gedacht den Wurzeln einer 
zurückgewiesenen amerikanischen Tradition von Commonwealth und von 
kooperativer Aktivität, daß er dachte, sollte wieder angezündet 
werden. In diesem 1884 Stück veröffentlichte im Amtsblatt der 
Zigarre-Hersteller, rief McNeill die Tradition des kooperativen Lebens
hervor, die die Pilgrims im 1600s in Neu-England als Rolle Modell für
moderne Relationen zwischen Arbeit und Kapital unterstützte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Afin de défier l'emphase sur l'individualisme 
économique extrême embrassé par les industriels d'âge et les 
théoriciens dorés de laissez-faire vers la fin du 19ème siècle, 
les auteurs de travail ont dessiné sur des traditions historiques et 
religieuses diverses. Le réformateur de travail George 
McNeill du Massachusetts, par exemple, trouvé dans la vie tôt de 
pélerin et pensé les racines d'une tradition américaine rejetée de
Commonwealth et d'activité coopérative qu'il a pensé devrait être 
rallumé. Dans ce 1884 morceaux a publié au Journal officiel 
des générateurs de cigare, McNeill a appelé la tradition de la vie 
coopérative qui a soutenu les pélerins dans le 1600s en Nouvelle 
Angleterre comme modèle de rôle pour des relations modernes entre le
travail et le capital.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A fim desafiar a ênfase no individualism 
econômico extremo espoused por industrialistas da idade e por 
theorists gilded do laissez-faire no 1ø século atrasado, os 
escritores labor desenharam em tradições históricas e religiosas 
diversas. O reformer labor George McNeill de Massachusetts, para
o exemplo, encontrado na vida adiantada do pilgrim e pensado as raizes
de uma tradição americana rejeitada da comunidade e da atividade 
cooperativa que pensou deve ser reacendido. Nesta 1884 partes 
publicou no jornal oficial dos fabricantes do charuto, McNeill invocou
a tradição da vida cooperativa que sustentou os pilgrims no 1600s em
Nova Inglaterra como um modelo do papel para relações modernas entre
o trabalho e o capital.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per sfidare l'enfasi su individualism economico 
estremo espoused dagli industriali di età e dai teorici gilded di 
"laissez faire" verso la fine del diciannovesimo secolo, i produttori 
di lavoro hanno dissipato sulle tradizioni storiche e religiose 
varie. Il reformer di lavoro George McNeill del Massachusetts,
per esempio, trovato nella vita in anticipo del pilgrim e pensato le 
radici di una tradizione americana rifiutata del commonwealth e 
dell'attività cooperativa che abbia pensato dovrebbe essere riacceso.
In questa 1884 parti ha pubblicato nella Gazzetta ufficiale dei 
creatori del sigaro, McNeill ha invocato la tradizione della vita 
cooperativa che ha sostenuto i pilgrims nel 1600s in Nuova Inghilterra
come modello di ruolo per i rapporti moderni fra il lavoro ed il
capitale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προκειμένου να προκληθεί η έμφαση στον ακραίο 
οικονομικό ατομικισμό που παντρεύτηκε από τους επιχρυσωμένους 
βιομηχάνους ηλικίας και τους θεωρητικούς ελεύθερης οικονομίας 
προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα, οι συγγραφείς εργασίας επέσυραν 
την προσοχή στις διαφορετικές ιστορικές και θρησκευτικές 
παραδόσεις. Ο μεταρρυθμιστής George McNeill εργασίας 
της Μασαχουσέτης, παραδείγματος χάριν, βρήκε στην πρόωρη ζωή 
προσκυνητών και σκέφτηκε τις ρίζες μιας απορριφθείσας 
αμερικανικής παράδοσης Κοινοπολιτείας και η συνεταιριστική 
δραστηριότητα που σκέφτηκε πρέπει να αναζωπυρωθεί. Σε αυτό 
το 1884 κομμάτι που δημοσιεύθηκε στην Επίσημη Εφημερίδα των 
κατασκευαστών πούρων, McNeill κάλεσε την παράδοση της 
συνεταιριστικής διαβίωσης που στήριξε τους προσκυνητές στο 
1600s στη Νέα Αγγλία ως μοντέλο ρόλου για τις σύγχρονες 
σχέσεις μεταξύ της εργασίας και του κεφαλαίου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para desafiar el énfasis en el individualismo 
económico extremo espoused por los industriales de la edad y los 
teóricos dorados del liberalismo en la a fines del siglo XIX, los 
programas de escritura de trabajo trazaron en tradiciones históricas 
y religiosas diversas. El reformador de trabajo George McNeill 
de Massachusetts, por ejemplo, encontrado en vida temprana del 
peregrino y pensado las raíces de una tradición americana rechazada 
de la Commonwealth y de la actividad cooperativa que él pensó debe 
ser reencendido. En este 1884 pedazos publicó en el diario 
oficial de los fabricantes del cigarro, McNeill invocó la tradición 
de la vida cooperativa que sostuvo a peregrinos en el 1600s en Nueva 
Inglaterra como modelo del papel para las relaciones modernas entre el
trabajo y el capital.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086731</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107071</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/pilgrims-progress-a-seventeenth-century-solution-to-the-nineteenth-century-conflict-between-labor-and-capital</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
