<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107693</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107693</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205620</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The North Carolina mountains in the early 1900s through the writing and photography of Horace Kephart</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Nord-Carolina Berge in den frühen 1900s durch
das Schreiben und die Fotographie von Horace Kephart</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les montagnes du nord de la Caroline au 
début des années 1900 par l'écriture et la photographie de Horace 
Kephart</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As montanhas de North.carolina nos 1900s 
adiantados com a escrita e a fotografia de Horace Kephart</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le montagne del North.carolina all'inizio degli 
anni 1900 con la scrittura e la fotographia di Horace Kephart</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα βουνά της βόρειας Καρολίνας στις αρχές των 
δεκαετιών του 20ου αιώνα μέσω του γραψίματος και της φωτογραφίας 
του Ορατίου Kephart</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las montañas de Carolina del Norte en los 1900s 
tempranos con la escritura y la fotografía de Horace Kephart</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Students will develop an understanding of daily life and culture in the mountains of North Carolina during the early 20th century through photographs and written sources; practice visual literacy skills and gain experience analyzing visual and written sources of historical information; and learn to revise their early analyses of historical sources and to synthesize the information found in different kinds of primary documents by planning a museum exhibit.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kursteilnehmer entwickeln ein Verständnis der 
täglichen Lebensdauer und der Kultur in den Bergen von Nord-Carolina 
während des frühen 20. Jahrhunderts durch Fotographien und 
schriftliche Quellen; üben Sie Sichtbildungsgradfähigkeiten 
und gewinnen Sie die Erfahrung, welche die Sicht- und schriftlichen 
Quellen der historischen Informationen analysiert; und erlernen 
Sie, ihre frühen Analysen der historischen Quellen zu verbessern und 
synthetisieren Sie die Informationen, die in den unterschiedlichen 
Arten der Primärdokumente gefunden werden, indem Sie eine Museum 
Ausstellung planen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les étudiants développeront un arrangement de 
vie quotidienne et de culture dans les montagnes de la Caroline 
du nord pendant le début du 20ème siècle par des photographies
et des sources écrites ; pratiquez les qualifications visuelles
d'instruction et acquérez une expérience analysant des sources 
visuelles et écrites d'information historique ; et apprenez à 
mettre à jour leurs premières analyses des sources historiques et 
synthétisez l'information trouvée dans différents genres de 
documents primaires en projetant un objet exposé de musée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os estudantes desenvolverão uma compreensão da 
vida diária e da cultura nas montanhas de North.carolina durante o 
20o século adiantado com as fotografias e as fontes escritas; 
pratique habilidades visuais do literacy e ganhe a experiência 
que analisa fontes visuais e escritas da informação histórica; 
e aprenda revisar suas análises adiantadas de fontes 
históricas e synthesize a informação encontrada em tipos diferentes
de originais preliminares planeando uma exibição do museu.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli allievi svilupperanno una comprensione della 
vita quotidiana e della coltura nelle montagne di North.carolina 
durante l'inizio del 20esimo secolo con le fotografie e le sorgenti 
scritte; esercitisi nelle abilità visive di literacy e guadagni
l'esperienza che analizza le sorgenti visive e scritte delle 
informazioni storiche; ed impari modificare le loro analisi 
preventive delle sorgenti storiche e sintetizzi le informazioni 
trovate nei generi differenti di documenti primari progettando 
un'esposizione del museo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι σπουδαστές θα αναπτύξουν μια κατανόηση της 
καθημερινής ζωής και τον πολιτισμό στα βουνά της βόρειας 
Καρολίνας κατά τη διάρκεια του πρόωρου 20ού αιώνα μέσω των 
φωτογραφιών και των γραπτών πηγών  οι οπτικά δεξιότητες και
το κέρδος βασικής εκπαίδευσης πρακτικής δοκιμάζουν την ανάλυση 
των οπτικών και γραπτών πηγών ιστορικών πληροφοριών  και 
μάθετε να αναθεωρείτε τις πρόωρες αναλύσεις ιστορικών πηγών τους
και να συνθέτετε τις πληροφορίες που βρίσκονται στα διαφορετικά 
είδη αρχικών εγγράφων με τον προγραμματισμό ενός εκθέματος 
μουσείων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los estudiantes desarrollarán una comprensión de
la vida de cada día y de la cultura en las montañas de Carolina del 
Norte durante el vigésimo siglo temprano con las fotografías y las 
fuentes escritas; practique las habilidades visuales de la 
instrucción y gane la experiencia que analiza fuentes visuales y 
escritas de la información histórica; y aprenda revisar sus 
análisis tempranos de fuentes históricas y sintetice la información
encontrada en diversas clases de documentos primarios planeando un 
objeto expuesto del museo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KATHRYN L. WALBERT
FN:KATHRYN L. WALBERT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205620</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107693</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-north-carolina-mountains-in-the-early-1900s-through-the-writing-and-photography-of-horace-kephart</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
