<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105670</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105670</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212953</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">USGS Natural Hazards and Public Safety</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">USGS natürliche Gefahren und allgemeine 
Sicherheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Risques normaux d'USGS et sûreté publique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Perigos naturais de USGS e segurança pública</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Rischi naturali di USGS e sicurezza pubblica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φυσικοί κίνδυνοι USGS και δημόσια ασφάλεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Peligros naturales de USGS y seguridad pública</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This USGS portal offers information about the origin, frequency, and distribution of natural geologic hazards and catastrophic events, and the resulting impacts on people, property, and the environment. Featured sites provide user-friendly information and graphics about earthquakes, tsunamis, landslides, El Nino, hurricanes, and erosion studies. Information is available about both general topics and specific events, and each site includes additional links to a multitude of other resources within USGS and beyond.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses USGS Portal bietet Informationen über den 
Ursprung, Frequenz und Verteilung der natürlichen geologischen 
Gefahren und der verhängnisvollen Fälle und die resultierenden 
Auswirkungen auf Leute, Eigenschaft und die Umgebung an. 
Gekennzeichnete Sites liefern benutzerfreundliche Informationen 
und Graphiken über Erdbeben, tsunamis, Erdrutsche, EL Nino, 
Hurrikane und Abnutzungstudien. Informationen sind über 
allgemeine Themen und spezifische Fälle vorhanden, und jede Site 
schließt zusätzliche Links zu einer Menge anderer Betriebsmittel 
innerhalb USGS und jenseits ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce portail d'USGS offre des informations sur 
l'origine, fréquence, et distribution des risques géologiques 
normaux et des événements catastrophiques, et les impacts 
résultants sur les personnes, la propriété, et l'environnement. 
Les sites décrits fournissent des informations conviviales et 
des graphiques sur des tremblements de terre, des tsunamis, des 
éboulements, le EL Nino, des ouragans, et des études d'érosion. 
L'information est disponible au sujet des sujets généraux et 
des événements spécifiques, et chaque site inclut des liens 
supplémentaires à une multitude d'autres ressources dans USGS et 
là-bas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este portal de USGS oferece a informação sobre a
origem, freqüência, e distribuição de perigos geologic naturais e 
eventos catastróficos, e os impactos resultantes em povos, em 
propriedade, e no ambiente. Os locais caracterizados fornecem a 
informação user-friendly e os gráficos sobre terremotos, tsunamis, 
landslides, EL Nino, furacões, e estudos da erosão. A 
informação está disponível sobre  tópicos gerais e eventos 
específicos, e cada local inclui as ligações adicionais a um 
multitude de outros recursos dentro de USGS e além.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo portal di USGS offre le informazioni 
sull'origine, frequenza e distribuzione dei rischi geologici naturali 
ed eventi catastrofici e gli effetti risultanti sulla gente, sulla 
proprietà e sull'ambiente. I luoghi descritti forniscono le 
informazioni facili da usare ed i grafici circa i terremoti, i 
tsunamis, i landslides, il EL Nino, gli uragani e gli studi di 
erosione. Le informazioni sono disponibili circa sia i soggetti 
generali che gli eventi specifici ed ogni luogo include i 
collegamenti supplementari ad un gran numero di altre risorse 
all'interno di USGS e di là.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η πύλη USGS προσφέρει τις πληροφορίες για την 
προέλευση, τη συχνότητα, και τη διανομή των φυσικών γεωλογικών 
κινδύνων και των καταστροφικών γεγονότων, και τις προκύπτουσες 
επιδράσεις στους ανθρώπους, την ιδιοκτησία, και το περιβάλλον. 
Οι χαρακτηρισμένες περιοχές παρέχουν τις φιλικές προς το 
χρήστη πληροφορίες και τη γραφική παράσταση για τους σεισμούς, τα
tsunamis, τις καθιζήσεις εδάφους, Ελ Νίνιο, τους τυφώνες, και 
τις μελέτες διάβρωσης. Οι πληροφορίες είναι διαθέσιμες και 
για τα γενικά θέματα και για τα συγκεκριμένα γεγονότα, και κάθε 
περιοχή περιλαμβάνει τις πρόσθετες συνδέσεις με ένα πλήθος 
άλλων στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς μέσα σε USGS και πέρα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este portal de USGS ofrece la información sobre 
el origen, frecuencia, y distribución de peligros geológicos 
naturales y los acontecimientos catastróficos, y los impactos que 
resultan en la gente, la característica, y el ambiente. Los 
sitios ofrecidos proporcionan a la información convivial y a 
gráficos sobre terremotos, tsunamis, derrumbamientos, el EL Nino, 
huracanes, y estudios de la erosión. La información está 
disponible sobre asuntos generales y acontecimientos específicos, y 
cada sitio incluye conexiones adicionales a una multiplicidad de otros
recursos dentro de USGS y más allá.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212953</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105670</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/usgs-natural-hazards-and-public-safety</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
