<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106955</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106955</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086834</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Slaves for sale.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sklaven für Verkauf.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Esclaves à vendre.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Escravos para a venda.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Schiavi da vendere.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σκλάβοι για την πώληση.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esclavos para la venta.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The twenty-three slaves advertised on this poster belonged to a Kentucky planter, John Carter, who decided to "liquidate his assets" before moving to the free state of Indiana. With the westward extension of slavery, planters in older states such as Virginia, Maryland, and North Carolina found they could make up for declining profits by selling slaves to newer areas of cultivation, such as Alabama, Mississippi, Louisiana, and Texas. The internal slave trade destroyed families and brought misery to both individuals and the larger communities in which they lived. Between a fifth and a third of all slave marriages were broken through sale or forced migration, and the expansion of slavery meant that relatives forced to relocate were more likely to end up hundreds of miles away from their families.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die dreiundzwanzig Sklaven machten auf diesem Plakat 
gehörten einem Kentucky Pflanzer, John Carter bekannt, der 
"liquidieren seine Werte" entschied, bevor es auf den freien Zustand 
von Indiana bewog. Mit der nach Westen gerichteten Extension der
Sklaverei, fanden Pflanzer in den älteren Zuständen wie Virginia, 
Maryland und Nord-Carolina sie konnten abfallende Profite ausgleichen,
indem sie Sklaven zu den neueren Bereichen der Bearbeitung, wie 
Alabama, Mississippi, Louisiana und Texas verkauften. Der 
inländische Sklave Handel zerstörte Familien und holte den 
Einzelpersonen und den größeren Gemeinschaften Elend, in denen sie 
lebten. Zwischen einer fünfter und einem Third alles Sklaven 
waren Verbindungen durch Verkauf oder vorverlegte Migration 
unterbrochen, und die Expansion der Sklaverei bedeutete, daß die 
Verwandten, die erzwungen wurden zu verlagern, wahrscheinlicher waren,
herauf Hunderte Meilen entfernt von ihren Familien zu beenden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les vingt-trois esclaves ont annoncé sur cette affiche 
ont appartenu à un planteur du Kentucky, John Charretier, qui a 
décidé "liquident ses capitaux" avant de se déplacer à l'état 
libre de l'Indiana. Avec l'extension à l'ouest de l'esclavage, 
les planteurs dans des états plus anciens tels que la Virginie, le 
Maryland, et la Caroline du nord les ont trouvés pourraient 
compenser des bénéfices en baisse en vendant des esclaves à de plus
nouveaux domaines de culture, tels que l'Alabama, le Mississippi, la 
Louisiane, et le Texas. Les familles détruites commerciales 
slaves internes et la misère apportée aux individus et aux 
communautés plus grandes dans lesquels ils ont vécu. Entre un 
cinquième et un tiers de tous les mariages slaves étaient 
cassés par la vente ou le transfert obligatoire, et l'expansion de 
l'esclavage a signifié que les parents forcés de replacer étaient 
pour terminer vers le haut des centaines de milles loin de leurs 
familles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os vinte e três escravos anunciaram neste poster 
pertenceram a um plantador de Kentucky, John Carter, que se decidiu 
"liquidate seus recursos" antes de se mover para o estado livre de 
Indiana. Com a extensão na direcção ocidental do slavery, os 
plantadores em uns estados mais velhos tais como Virgínia, Maryland, 
e North.carolina encontraram-nos poderiam compensar por lucros 
declinando vendendo escravos a umas áreas mais novas de cultivation, 
tais como Alabama, Mississippi, Louisiana, e Texas. O comércio 
interno do escravo destruiu famílias e trouxe a miséria  aos 
indivíduos e às comunidades maiores em que viveram. Entre umas
quintas e um third de todo o escravo as uniões eram quebradas com a 
venda ou migração forçada, e a expansão do slavery significou que 
os parentes forçados a relocate eram mais prováveis terminar acima 
das centenas das milhas afastado de suas famílias.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I ventitre schiavi hanno fatto pubblicità a su questo 
manifesto hanno appartenuto ad una piantatrice del Kentucky, John 
Carter, che ha deciso "liquida i suoi beni" prima di muoversi verso il
libero dichiara dell'Indiana. Con l'estensione westward 
di slavery, le piantatrici in più vecchio dichiara quale la 
Virginia, Maryland e North.carolina le ha trovate potrebbe compensare 
per i profitti declinanti vendendo gli schiavi alle più nuove zone di
coltura, quali l'Alabama, il Mississippi, la Luisiana ed il Texas. 
Il commercio interno dello schiavo ha distrutto le 
famiglie ed ha portato la miseria sia agli individui che alle più 
grandi Comunità in cui hanno vissuto. Fra lle quinte e un terzo
di tutto lo schiavo unioni erano rotte con la vendita o l'espansione 
forzata e l'espansione di slavery ha significato che i parenti 
costretti a riassegnare erano più probabili concludersi sulle 
centinaia delle miglia via dalle loro famiglie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι είκοσι τρεις σκλάβοι που διαφημίστηκαν σε αυτήν την
αφίσα άνηκαν σε έναν καλλιεργητή του Κεντάκυ, John Carter, 
ο οποίος αποφάσισε "να εκκαθαρίσει τα προτερήματά του" πρίν 
κινείται προς την ελεύθερη κατάσταση του Ινδιάνα. Με τη 
δυτική επέκταση της σκλαβιάς, οι καλλιεργητές στα παλαιότερα 
κράτη όπως η Βιρτζίνια, η Μέρυλαντ, και η βόρεια Καρολίνα 
βρήκαν ότι θα μπορούσαν να αποζημιώσουν τα μειωμένος κέρδη με 
την πώληση των σκλάβων στους νεώτερους τομείς της καλλιέργειας, 
όπως η Αλαμπάμα, ο Μισισιπής, η Λουιζιάνα, και το Τέξας. Το
εσωτερικό εμπόριο σκλάβων κατέστρεψε τις οικογένειες και έφερε 
τη δυστυχία και στα άτομα και στις μεγαλύτερες κοινότητες στην 
οποία έζησαν. _ μεταξύ ένας πέμπτο και ένας τρίτο όλος 
σκλάβος γάμος είμαι σπάζω μέσω πώληση ή αναγκάζω 
μετανάστευση, και ο επέκταση σκλαβιά σημαίνω ότι συγγενής 
αναγκάζω επανεντοπίζω είμαι περισσότερος πιθανός τέλος επάνω 
εκατοντάδα μίλι μακρυά από τους οικογένεια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los veintitrés esclavos anunciaron en este cartel 
pertenecieron a un plantador de Kentucky, Juan Carretero, que decidía
"liquida sus activos" antes de trasladarse al estado libre de Indiana.
Con la extensión que va hacia el oeste de la esclavitud, los 
plantadores en más viejos estados tales como Virginia, Maryland, y 
Carolina del Norte los encontraron podrían compensar beneficios que 
declinaban vendiendo esclavos a más nuevas áreas de la cultivación,
tales como Alabama, Mississippi, Luisiana, y Tejas. El comercio 
interno del esclavo destruyó a familias y trajo miseria a los 
individuos y a las comunidades más grandes en quienes vivieron. 
Entre quinto y un tercero de todo el esclavo las uniones estaban
quebradas con venta o la migración forzada, y la extensión de la 
esclavitud significó que los parientes forzados volver a poner eran 
más probables terminar encima de centenares de millas lejos de sus 
familias.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086834</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106955</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/slaves-for-sale</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
