<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103379</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103379</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087154</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Union-Busting at Cripple Creek</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anschluß-Sprengen am Krüppel-Nebenfluß</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Union-Éclater à la crique d'estropié</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">União-Rebentar no creek do aleijado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Unione-Rompendosi all'insenatura del cripple</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένωση- Busting ακρωτηριάστε τον κολπίσκο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Unio'n-Reventar en el cala del lisiado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">While many assume that workers in the nineteenth-century American West enjoyed easily available land and a fluid social structure, the region's history of radical unionism at the turn of the century suggests otherwise. In 1902, corporate mining interests in Colorado decided to crush the Western Federation of Miners (WFM). By the following year, civil war erupted in Cripple Creek, Colorado, as state and local officials and local businessmen joined with the large corporations against the miners. Before it was over, thirty men had been killed in numerous gun battles. Documents gathered as part of a 1905 federal investigation included a "yellow dog" (anti-union) contract that prospective mining employees were required to sign. The documents also included a letter from mine owners asking landlords not to lease property to union sympathizers; a resolution by the Denver Citizen's Alliance attacking the WFM; orders directing Colorado National Guard troops to deport 73 striking miners and their leaders to Kansas; and finally a plea by a Colorado union official to the Red Cross for the organization's aid.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während viele annehmen, daß Arbeiter im 
19.-Jahrhundert amerikanischer Westen genossenen leicht vorhandenen 
Land und in einer flüssigen Sozialstruktur, die Geschichte der Region
des radikalen unionism an der Jahrhundertwende anders vorschlägt. 
1902 entschieden korporative gewinneninteressen an Kolorado, die
westliche Vereinigung der Bergmänner (WFM) zu zerquetschen. 
Durch das folgende Jahr, den Bürgerkrieg ausgebrochen im 
Krüppel-Nebenfluß, das Kolorado als Zustand und lokale Beamt- und 
lokalegeschäftsmänner verbunden mit den großen Korporationen gegen 
die Bergmänner. Bevor er rüber sein, waren dreißig Männer in
den zahlreichen Gewehrschlachten beendet worden. Dokumente 
erfaßten als Teil 1905, die Bundesuntersuchung einen "gelber Hunde" 
(Anti-Anschluß) Vertrag einschloß, den zukünftigen 
gewinnenangestellten benoetigt wurden zu unterzeichnen. Die 
Dokumente schlossen auch ein Zeichen von den Grube Inhabern ein, die 
Hauswirte, bitten Eigenschaft nicht zu den Anschlußgleichgesinnten zu
mieten; eine Zerlegung durch das Bündnis des Denver Bürgers, 
welches das WFM in Angriff nimmt; die Ordnungen, die Kolorado 
nationalen Schutz verweisen, troops, um 73 auffallende Bergmänner und
ihre Führer zu Kansas zu verbannen; und schließlich ein 
Vorwand durch einen Kolorado Anschlußbeamten zum roten Kreuz für das
Hilfsmittel der Organisation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tandis que beaucoup supposent que les ouvriers 
dans la terre disponible facilement appréciée par ouest américain 
de dix-neuvième-siècle et une structure sociale liquide, l'histoire 
de la région du syndicalisme radical à la fin du siècle suggère 
autrement. En 1902, les intérêts d'extraction de corporation 
dans le Colorado ont décidé d'écraser la fédération occidentale 
des mineurs (WFM). Par l'année suivante, la guerre civile 
éclatée dans la crique d'estropié, le Colorado, comme état et 
hommes d'affaires de fonctionnaire et locaux locaux jointifs avec les 
grandes sociétés contre les mineurs. Avant qu'elle plus de, 
trente hommes avaient été détruits dans de nombreuses fusillades.
Les documents ont recueilli en tant qu'élément des 1905 la 
recherche que fédérale a inclus un contrat "de chien jaune" 
(anti-union) que des employés d'extraction éventuels ont été 
requis de signer. Les documents ont également inclus une lettre
des propriétaires de mine demandant à des propriétaires de ne pas 
louer la propriété aux sympathisants des syndicats ; une 
résolution par l'alliance du citoyen de Denver attaquant le WFM ; 
les commandes dirigeant la garde nationale du Colorado 
s'assemble pour expulser 73 mineurs saisissants et leurs amorces au 
Kansas ; et finalement une réclamation par un fonctionnaire des
syndicats du Colorado à la croix rouge pour l'aide de l'organisation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quando muitos supuserem que os trabalhadores na 
terra disponível fàcilmente apreciada de décimo-século oeste 
americano e em uma estrutura social fluida, o history da região do 
unionism radical na volta do século sugerem de outra maneira. 
Em 1902, os interesses minando incorporados em Colorado 
decidiram-se esmagar o federation ocidental dos mineiros (WFM). 
Pelo seguinte ano, pela guerra civil erupted no creek do 
aleijado, pelo Colorado, como o estado e os homens de negócios locais
do oficial e os locais juntados com os corporation grandes de encontro
aos mineiros. Antes que sobre, trinta homens foram matados em 
batalhas numerosas do injetor. Os originais recolhidos como a 
parte de uma investigação 1905 federal incluíram "um contrato do 
cão amarelo" (anti-união) que os empregados minando em perspectiva 
fossem requeridos assinar. Os originais incluíram também uma 
letra dos proprietários da mina que pedem que os landlords não 
aluguem a propriedade aos sympathizers da união; uma 
definição pelo alliance do cidadão de Denver que ataca o WFM; 
as ordens que dirigem o protetor nacional de Colorado agrupam-se
para deport 73 mineiros impressionantes e seus líderes a Kansas; 
e finalmente um plea por um oficial da união de Colorado à 
cruz vermelha para o dae (dispositivo automático de entrada) da 
organização.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mentre molti suppongono che gli operai nell'ovest 
americano di diciannovesimo-secolo hanno goduto facilmente la terra 
disponibile e una struttura sociale fluida, la storia della regione 
del unionism radicale alla fine del secolo suggerisce al contrario. 
In 1902, gli interessi estraenti corporativi in Colorado hanno 
deciso schiacciare la federazione occidentale dei minatori (WFM). 
Entro il seguente anno, la guerra civile ha scoppiato 
nell'insenatura del cripple, Colorado, come dichiara e 
funzionari locali ed uomini d'affari locali uniti con le grandi 
società contro i minatori. Prima che finito, trenta uomini 
erano stati uccisi nelle battaglie numerose della pistola. I 
documenti hanno riunito come componente dei 1905 che la 
ricerca federale ha incluso "un contratto del cane giallo" 
(anti-unione) che i futuri impiegati estraenti sono stati tenuti a 
firmare. I documenti egualmente hanno incluso una lettera dai 
proprietari della miniera che chiedono ai proprietari di non affittare
la proprietà ai simpatizzanti del sindacato; una risoluzione 
dall'alleanza del cittadino de Denver che attaca il WFM; gli 
ordini che dirigono la protezione nazionale del Colorado si aduna per 
deport 73 minatori notevoli ed i loro capi a Kansas; ed 
infine una richiesta da un funzionario del sindacato del Colorado alla
croce rossa per il sussidio dell'organizzazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενώ πολλοί υποθέτουν ότι οι εργαζόμενοι στην 
αμερικανική δύση δέκατος-αιώνα απόλαυσαν το εύκολα διαθέσιμο 
έδαφος και μια ρευστή κοινωνική δομή, η ιστορία της περιοχής του
ριζικού συνδικαλισμού στο γύρισμα του αιώνα προτείνει ειδάλλως. 
Το 1902, τα εταιρικά ενδιαφέροντα μεταλλείας για το 
Κολοράντο αποφάσισαν να συντρίψουν τη δυτική ομοσπονδία των 
ανθρακωρύχων (WFM). Μέχρι το επόμενο έτος, ο εμφύλιος 
πόλεμος εξερράγη Cripple στον κολπίσκο, Κολοράντο, ως κράτος 
και τοπικοί τοπικών επιχειρηματίες ανώτερων υπαλλήλων και που 
ενώθηκαν με τις μεγάλες εταιρίες ενάντια στους ανθρακωρύχους. 
Προτού να τελειώσει, τριάντα άτομα ήταν σκοτωμένων στις 
πολυάριθμες μάχες πυροβόλων όπλων. Τα έγγραφα που 
μαζεύτηκαν ως τμήμα μιας ομοσπονδιακής έρευνας του 1905 
περιέλαβαν μια σύμβαση "κίτρινων σκυλιών" (αντι-ένωση) ότι οι 
ενδεχόμενοι υπάλληλοι μεταλλείας έπρεπε για να υπογράψουν. 
Τα έγγραφα περιέλαβαν επίσης μια επιστολή από τους 
ιδιοκτήτες ορυχείων που ζητούν από τους ιδιοκτήτες για να μην 
μισθώσουν την ιδιοκτησία στους υποστηρικτές ένωσης  ένα 
ψήφισμα από τη συμμαχία του πολίτη του Ντένβερ που επιτίθεται 
στο WFM  οι κατατάξεις που κατευθύνουν την εθνική φρουρά 
του Κολοράντο συγκεντρώνονται για να απελάσουν 73 εντυπωσιακούς
ανθρακωρύχους και τους ηγέτες τους στο Κάνσας  και τελικά 
μια αίτηση από έναν ανώτερο υπάλληλο ένωσης του Κολοράντο στον 
Ερυθρό Σταυρό για την ενίσχυση της οργάνωσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mientras que muchos asumen que los trabajadores en 
la pista disponible fácilmente gozada oeste americano del 
diecinueveavo-siglo y una estructura social flúida, la historia de la
región del unionism radical al final del siglo sugieren de otra 
manera. En 1902, los intereses que minaban corporativos en 
Colorado decidían a machacar la federación occidental de los mineros
(WFM). Por el año siguiente, la guerra civil entrada en 
erupción en el cala del lisiado, el Colorado, como el estado y 
hombres de negocios locales del funcionario y locales unidos con las 
corporaciones grandes contra los mineros. Antes de que encima, 
habían matado a treinta hombres en batallas numerosas del arma. 
Los documentos recolectaron como parte de 1905 que la 
investigación federal incluyó un contrato del "perro amarillo" 
(contra-unio'n) que requirieron los empleados que minaban anticipados 
firmar. Los documentos también incluyeron una carta de los 
propietarios de la mina que pedían que los propietarios no arrienden 
la característica a los simpatizantes de la unión; una 
resolución por la alianza del ciudadano de Denver que ataca el WFM; 
las órdenes que dirigen a protector nacional de Colorado 
marchan para deportar a 73 mineros llamativos y a sus 
arranques de cinta a Kansas; y finalmente una súplica de un 
funcionario de la unión de Colorado a la Cruz Roja para la ayuda de 
la organización.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087154</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103379</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/union-busting-at-cripple-creek</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
