<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104067</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104067</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086194</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Get the Rope!" Anti-German Violence in World War I-era Wisconsin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"erhalten Sie das Seil!" Anti-Deutsche 
Gewalttätigkeit in der Weltkrieg Ich-Ära Wisconsin</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"obtenez la corde!" Violence Anti-Allemande 
dans la Je-ère le Wisconsin de guerre mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"comece a corda!" Violência Anti-Alemão na
Eu-era Wisconsin da guerra de mundo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ottenga la corda!" Violenza Anti-Tedesca 
nell'Io-era Wisconsin di guerra mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πάρτε το σχοινΐ" Αντι-γερμανικά βία στην 
ι-εποχή Wisconsin παγκόσμιου πολέμου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"consiga la cuerda!" Violencia 
Contra-Alemana en la Yo-era Wisconsin de la guerra mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the early 20th century, German Americans were the nation's largest immigrant group. Although they were regarded as a model of successful assimilation, they faced vicious--and sometimes violent--attacks on their loyalty when the United States went to war against Germany in 1917. The most notorious incident was the lynching of German-born Robert Prager in Colinsville, Illinois, in April 1918. Other incidents stopped just short of murder. In a statement made on October 22, 1918, John Deml, a farmer in Outagamie County, a heavily German and Scandinavian area of Wisconsin, described the nativist mob that had visited him two days earlier. Suspected of not strongly enough supporting the war effort, he was narrowly saved from lynching.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im frühen 20. Jahrhundert waren deutsche 
Amerikaner die größte einwandernde Gruppe der Nation. Obgleich
sie als ein Modell der erfolgreichen Assimilation angesehen wurden, 
stellten sie schändliche -- und manchmal heftig -- Angriffe auf ihrer
Loyalität gegenüber, als die Vereinigten Staaten war gegen 
Deutschland 1917 gingen. Das notorischste Ereignis war das 
Lynchen von Deutsch-getragenem Robert Prager in Colinsville, Illinois,
im April 1918. Andere Ereignisse stoppten gerechten Kurzschluß 
des Mordes. In einer Anweisung, die auf Oktober 22, 1918, John 
Deml, einem Landwirt in der Outagamie Grafschaft, einem schwer 
deutschen und skandinavischen Bereich von Wisconsin abgegeben wurde, 
beschrieb den nativist Pöbel, der ihn zwei Tage früh besucht hatte. 
Vermutet nicht stark genug vom Unterstützen der Kriegbemühung,
wurde er schmal vom Lynchen gesichert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En début du 20ème siècle, les Américains 
allemands étaient le plus grand groupe immigré de la nation. 
Bien qu'ils aient été considérés comme un modèle 
d'assimilation réussie, ils ont fait face -- et parfois violent -- à
des attaques méchantes sur leur fidélité quand les Etats-Unis sont 
allés faire la guerre contre l'Allemagne en 1917. L'incident le
plus notoire était lyncher de Robert Allemand-soutenu Prager dans 
Colinsville, l'Illinois, en avril 1918. D'autres incidents ont 
arrêté le short juste du meurtre. Dans un rapport fait sur 
22 octobre 1918, John Deml, un fermier dans le comté d'Outagamie, 
une région fortement allemande et scandinave du Wisconsin, a décrit 
la foule nativiste qui lui avait rendue visite pendant deux jours plus
tôt. Suspecté assez pas fortement de supporter l'effort de 
guerre, il a été étroitement sauvegardé de lyncher.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 20o século adiantado, os americanos alemães 
eram o grupo immigrant o maior da nação. Embora fossem 
considerados como um modelo do assimilation bem sucedido, enfrentaram 
-- e às vezes violento -- ataques vicious em sua lealdade quando os 
estados unidos foram guerrear de encontro a Germany em 1917. O 
incident o mais notorious era lynching de Robert Alemão-carregado 
Prager em Colinsville, Illinois, em abril 1918. Outros incidents
pararam o short justo do assassinato. Em uma indicação feita 
outubro em 22, 1918, em John Deml, em um fazendeiro no condado de 
Outagamie, em uma área pesadamente alemão e escandinava de 
Wisconsin, descreveu o mob nativist que o tinha visitado dois dias 
mais cedo. Suspeitado não fortemente bastante de suportar o 
esforço da guerra, foi conservado estreita de lynching.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo, gli Americani 
tedeschi erano il più grande gruppo immigrato della nazione. 
Anche se sono stati considerare come un modello di assimilazione
riuscita, hanno affrontato -- ed a volte violento -- gli attacchi 
viziosi alla loro lealtà quando unito Dichiara è andato fare
la guerra contro la Germania in 1917. L'avvenimento più 
rinomato era lynching di Robert Tedesco-sopportato Prager in 
Colinsville, l'Illinois, nel mese di aprile del 1918. Altri 
avvenimenti hanno arrestato lo short giusto dell'omicidio. In 
un'istruzione rilasciata il 22 ottobre 1918, John Deml, un coltivatore
nella contea di Outagamie, una regione pesante tedesca e scandinava di
Wisconsin, ha descritto il mob nativist che lo aveva visitato più 
presto due giorni. Ritenuto sospetto abbastanza non fortemente 
del sostegno dello sforzo di guerra, è stato salvato stretto dal 
lynching.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα, γερμανικοί Αμερικανοί 
ήταν η μεγαλύτερη που έχουν μεταναστεύσει ομάδα του έθνους. 
Αν και θεωρήθηκαν ως μοντέλο της επιτυχούς αφομοίωσης, 
αντιμετώπισαν τις κακοήθεις -- και μερικές φορές βίαιος -- 
επιθέσεις στην πίστη τους όταν πηγαίνω οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες 
στον πόλεμο ενάντια στη Γερμανία το 1917. Το πιό 
πασίγνωστο γεγονός ήταν το λυντσάρισμα γερμανικός-γεννημένου 
Robert Prager σε Colinsville, Ιλλινόις, τις 1918, 
Απριλίου Αλλα γεγονότα που σταματιούνται ακριβώς λίγο πριν
από τη δολοφονία. Σε μια δήλωση που έγινε στις 22 
Οκτωβρίου ..1918, John Deml, ένας αγρότης στο νομό 
Outagamie, μια βαριά γερμανική και Σκανδιναβική περιοχή του 
Wisconsin, περιέγραψαν τον όχλο nativist που τον είχε 
επισκεφτεί δύο ημέρες νωρίτερα. Πιθανός όχι αρκετά 
έντονα της υποστήριξης της πολεμικής προσπάθειας, σώθηκε 
λεπτομερώς από το λυντσάρισμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Del vigésimo siglo temprano, los americanos 
alemanes eran el grupo inmigrante más grande de la nación. 
Aunque los miraron como modelo de la asimilación acertada, 
hicieron frente -- y a veces violento -- a ataques viciosos contra su 
lealtad cuando los Estados Unidos fueron a guerrear contra Alemania en
1917. El incidente más notorio era el lynching de Roberto 
Alema'n-llevado Prager en Colinsville, Illinois, en abril de 1918. 
Otros incidentes pararon el cortocircuito justo del asesinato. 
En una declaración hecha 22 de octubre de 1918, Juan Deml, 
un granjero en el condado de Outagamie, un área pesadamente alemana y
escandinava de Wisconsin, describió a multitud nativista que lo 
había visitado dos días anterior. Sospechado no no fuertemente
bastante de utilizar el esfuerzo de la guerra, lo salvaron estrecho de
lynching.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086194</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104067</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/get-the-rope-anti-german-violence-in-world-war-i-era-wisconsin</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
