<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108118</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108118</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206816</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Fire Administration Kids Page</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Feuer-Leitung Kids Seite</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Gestion du Feu Badine La Page</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Administração Do Fogo Caçoa A Página</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Gestione Del Fuoco Scherza La Pagina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σελίδα κατσικιών πυροσβεστικής διοίκησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Administración Del Fuego Embroma La 
Paginación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers tips that can help children and families remain safe from fire. It discusses the importance of using and maintaining smoke alarms and shows how to draw up a family fire escape plan. The site features a fire safety coloring book, a crossword puzzle, and an interactive game that challenges them to spot common household fire hazards.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Angebotspitzen, die können, Kindern und Familien
helfen, vom Feuer sicher zu bleiben. Es behandelt den Wert des 
Verwendens und des Beibehaltens der Rauchwarnungen und zeigt, wie man 
einen Familie Feuer-Entweichenplan aufstellt. Die 
Situationsmerkmale ein Feuersicherheit Farbtonbuch, ein 
Kreuzworträtsel und ein interaktives Spiel, das sie herausfordert, 
geläufige Haushalt Brandgefährdungen zu beschmutzen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">extrémités d'offres qui peuvent aider des 
enfants et des familles à rester sûres du feu. Il discute 
l'importance d'utiliser et de mettre à jour des alarmes de fumée et 
montre comment élaborer un plan d'évasion du feu de famille. 
Les dispositifs de site un livre de coloration de sûreté de 
feu, un jeu de mots croisé, et un jeu interactif qui les défie de 
repèrer des risques d'incendie communs de ménage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">pontas das ofertas que podem para ajudar a 
crianças e a famílias remanescer seguras do fogo. Discute a 
importância de usar e de manter alarmes do fumo e mostra como 
desenhar acima de uma planta do escape do fogo da família. As 
características de local um livro da coloração da segurança de 
fogo, um enigma de crossword, e um jogo interativo que os desafie 
manchar perigos de fogo comuns da casa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">punte di offerte che possono aiutare i bambini e 
le famiglie a rimanere sicuri da fuoco. Discute l'importanza di 
usando e di effettuare gli allarmi del fumo e mostra come elaborare un
programma di fuga del fuoco della famiglia. Le caratteristiche 
di luogo un libro di coloring di protezione antincendio, un cruciverba
e un gioco interattivo che li sfida a macchiare i rischi d'incendio 
comuni della famiglia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει τις άκρες που μπορούν να βοηθήσουν τα 
παιδιά και τις οικογένειες να παραμείνουν ασφαλείς από την 
πυρκαγιά. Συζητά τη σημασία και τους συναγερμούς καπνού και
επιδεικνύει πώς να συντάξει ένα σχέδιο εξόδων οικογενειακού 
κινδύνου. Η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει ένα χρωματίζοντας βιβλίο 
πυρασφάλειας, έναν γρίφο σταυρόλεξων, και ένα διαλογικό 
παιχνίδι που τους προκαλεί για να επισημάνει τους κοινούς 
κινδύνους οικιακής πυρκαγιάς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">extremidades de las ofertas que pueden ayudar a 
niños y a las familias a seguir siendo seguras del fuego. 
Discute la importancia de usar y de mantener alarmar del humo y 
muestra cómo trazar encima de un plan del escape del fuego de la 
familia. Las características de sitio un libro del colorante de
la seguridad de fuego, un crucigrama, y un juego interactivo que los 
desafía a manchar riesgos de incendios comunes de la casa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206816</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108118</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/fire-administration-kids-page</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
