<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107605</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107605</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086253</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">How do you spell strike?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wie buchstabieren Sie Schlag?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comment orthographiez-vous la grève ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Como você soletra a batida?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Come ortografate il colpo?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πώς συλλαβίζετε την απεργία;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Cómo usted deletrea huelga?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Four million workersone fifth of the nation_s workforcewent out on strike in 1919, seeking to consolidate and expand the gains they had achieved during World War I and to make real the war's rhetoric of democracy. The most important of these strikes began in September, when 350,000 steel workers walked off the job. Steel companies responded with a reign of terror, aided by local governments. Strikers were beaten, arrested, shot, and driven out of steel towns. Management brought in African-American and Mexican-American strikebreakers to split workers along racial and ethnic lines and tried to portray the conflict as an attempted revolution by foreign-born radicals. Eventually, the strike was broken. This strike ballot distributed by the National Committee for Organizing Iron and Steel Workersprinted in English, Croatian, Hungarian, Italian, Slovak, and Polishindicated the range of nationalities composing the industry's workforce in 1919.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vier Million workersone Fünftel der nation_s, die heraus 
auf Schlag 1919, suchend, die Gewinne zu vereinigen und zu erweitern 
hatten sie workforcewent sind, während des Ersten Weltkrieges und 
real die Rhetorik des Krieges von der Demokratie zu bilden erzielt. 
Das wichtigste dieser Schläge fing im September an, als 350.000
Stahlarbeiter weg vom Job gingen. Stahlwerke reagierten mit 
einer Herrschaft des Terrors, unterstützt durch lokale Regierungen. 
Schlaggeräte wurden aus Stahlstädten heraus geschlagen, 
festgehalten, geschossen und angetrieben. Management geholt 
worden in die Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen und 
Mexikanisch-Amerikanischen Streikbrecher, Arbeiter entlang den 
rassischen und ethnischen Zeilen aufzuspalten und, um die 
$überschneidung als versuchte Umdrehung zu schildern durch 
foreign-born Radikale versucht. Schließlich war der Schlag 
unterbrochen. Dieser Schlagstimmzettel verteilt vom nationalen 
Ausschuß für organisierendes Eisen und Stahl Workersprinted auf 
englisches, kroatisches, ungarisches, italienisches, slowakisch und 
Polishindicated die Strecke der Nationalitäten, welche die Mannschaft
der Industrie 1919 bestehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Quatre millions de cinquième de workersone des nation_s 
workforcewent dehors en grève en 1919, recherchant à consolider et 
augmenter les gains ils avaient réalisé pendant la Première Guerre 
Mondiale et à faire vrai la rhétorique de la guerre de la 
démocratie. Le plus important de ces grèves a commencé en 
septembre, quand 350.000 ouvriers en acier ont marché outre du 
travail. Les aciéries ont répondu avec un règne de la 
terreur, facilité par des gouvernements locaux. Des butées ont
été battues, arrêtées, tirées, et pilotées hors des villes en 
acier. Gestion apportée dans les briseurs de grève 
afro-américains et Mexicain-Américains dédoubler des ouvriers le long 
des lignes raciales et ethniques et essayée pour dépeindre le 
conflit comme révolution essayée par les radicaux nés à 
l'étranger. Par la suite, la grève était cassée. Ce 
vote de grève distribué par le Comité national pour le fer et 
l'acier d'organisation Workersprinted en anglais, croate, hongrois, 
italien, slovaque, et Polishindicated l'intervalle des nationalités 
composant la main d'oeuvre de l'industrie en 1919.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quatro milhão fifth do workersone dos nation_s 
workforcewent para fora na batida em 1919, procurando consolidar e 
expandir os ganhos tinham conseguido durante o world.war.i e fazer 
real o rhetoric da guerra da democracia. O mais importante 
destas batidas começou em setembro, quando 350.000 trabalhadores de 
aço andaram fora do trabalho. As companhias de aço responderam
com um reino de terror, ajudado por governos locais. Os 
grevistas foram batidos, prendidos, disparados, e dirigidos fora das 
cidades de aço. Gerência trazida em strikebreakers 
Africano-Americanos e Mexicano-Americanos rachar trabalhadores ao 
longo das linhas raciais e étnicas e tentada portray o conflito como 
uma volta tentada por radicais foreign-born. Eventualmente, a 
batida era quebrada. Esta cédula da batida distribuída pelo 
comitê nacional para o ferro e o aço organizando Workersprinted em 
inglês, em croatian, em hungarian, em italiano, em slovak, e 
Polishindicated a escala das nacionalidades que compõem o workforce 
da indústria em 1919.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Quattro milione fifth di workersone dei nation_s 
workforcewent fuori sul colpo in 1919, cercando di consolidare ed 
espandere i guadagni avevano realizzato durante il world.war.i e di 
rendere reale la retorica della guerra della democrazia. L'più 
importante di questi colpi ha cominciato in settembre, quando 350.000 
lavoratori dell'industria siderurgica hanno camminato fuori del 
lavoro. Le acciaierie hanno risposto con un regno del 
terrore, aiutato dagli enti pubblici territoriali. I percussori 
sono stati battuti, arrestato stati, sparati e sono stati guidati 
dalle città d'acciaio. Gestione portata nei crumiri di 
messicano-american ed Africano-Americani spaccare gli operai seguendo 
le righe razziali ed etniche e provata per ritrarre il conflitto come 
giro tentato dai radicali foreign-born. Finalmente, il colpo era
rotto. Questa scheda elettorale di colpo distribuita dal 
comitato nazionale per ferro ed acciaio d'organizzazione 
Workersprinted in inglese, croatian, ungherese, italiano, slovacco e 
Polishindicated la gamma di nazionalità che compongono la mano 
d'opera dell'industria in 1919.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Workersone πέμπτο τεσσάρων εκατομμυρίων των 
nation_s workforcewent έξω στην απεργία το 1919, επιδιώκων
να παγιώσουν και να επεκτείνουν τα κέρδη είχαν επιτύχει κατά τη 
διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι και να καταστήσουν πραγματική 
την πολεμική ρητορική της δημοκρατίας. Ο σημαντικότερος 
αυτών των απεργιών άρχισε το Σεπτέμβριο, όταν περπάτησαν 
350.000 εργαζόμενοι χάλυβα από την εργασία. Οι 
επιχειρήσεις χάλυβα αποκρίθηκαν με βασιλεύουν του τρόμου, που 
βοηθήθηκε από τις τοπικές κυβερνήσεις. Οι απεργοί 
κτυπήθηκαν, συλλήφθηκαν, πυροβολήθηκαν, και διώχτηκαν των πόλεων 
χάλυβα. Διαχείριση που παρουσιάζεται 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά και Μεξικανοαμερικάά strikebreakers για
να χωρίσει τους εργαζομένους σύμφωνα με τις φυλετικές και εθνικές
γραμμές και που δοκιμάζεται για να απεικονίσει τη σύγκρουση ως 
αποπειραθείσα επανάσταση από τους ξένος-γεννημένους ριζοσπάστες.
Τελικά, η απεργία ήταν σπασμένη. Αυτή η ψήφος 
απεργίας που διανέμεται από την εθνική Επιτροπή για την οργάνωση
του σιδήρου και του χάλυβα Workersprinted αγγλικά, κροατικά, 
ουγγρικά, ιταλικά, σλοβάκικα, και Polishindicated η σειρά των 
υπηκοοτήτων που συνθέτει το εργατικό δυναμικό της βιομηχανίας το 
1919.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cuatro millones de fifth del workersone de los nation_s 
workforcewent hacia fuera en huelga en 1919, intentando consolidar y 
ampliar los aumentos habían alcanzado durante Primera Guerra Mundial 
y hacer verdadero el retórico de la guerra de democracia. El 
más importante de estas huelgas comenzó en septiembre, cuando 
350.000 trabajadores de acero recorrieron del trabajo. Las 
empresas siderúrgicas respondieron con un reinado del terror, ayudado
por gobiernos locales. Los huelguistas fueron batidos, 
arrestados, tirados, y conducidos de las ciudades de acero. 
Gerencia traída en rompehuelgas Africano-Americanos y 
Mexicano-Americanos partir a trabajadores a lo largo de líneas 
raciales y étnicas e intentada para retratar el conflicto como 
revolución procurada por los radicales foreign-born. Eventual, 
la huelga estaba quebrada. Esta balota de la huelga distribuida 
por el comité nacional para el hierro y el acero de ordenación 
Workersprinted en inglés, croata, húngaro, italiano, eslovaco, y
Polishindicated el rango de las nacionalidades que componen a la mano 
de obra de la industria en 1919.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086253</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107605</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/how-do-you-spell-strike</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
