<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108065</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108065</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974089</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Adventures of Captain Chemo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Abenteuer des Kapitäns Chemo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Aventures de capitaine Chemo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Aventuras do capitão Chemo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Avventure del capitano Chemo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιπέτειες του καπετάνιου Chemo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aventuras de capitán Chemo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Watch Captain Chemo and his cadets as they embark on five adventures dealing with different issues concerned with cancer. The animated adventures have been created by Gameplay's specialist multimedia division - doUno.com. The animated and interactive educational site is primarily aimed at cancer patients, relatives and friends to explain the disease and its treatment. You can assist Captain Chemo and Chemo Command to answer questions about cancer and search for the answers to gain points, together with manoeuvring the chemo craft to shoot and destroy tumours.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>es</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Uhr-Kapitän Chemo und seine jüngsteren Söhne, 
wie sie auf fünf Abenteuern sich einschiffen, die die 
unterschiedlichen Ausgaben beschäftigen, die mit Krebs betroffen 
werden. Die lebhaften Abenteuer sind durch 
Fachmann-Multimediaabteilung Gameplays - doUno.com erstellt worden. 
Die lebhafte und interaktive pädagogische Site ist 
hauptsächlich angestrebte Krebspatienten, -verwandte und -freunde, 
zum der Krankheit und seiner Behandlung zu erklären. Sie 
können Kapitän Chemo und Chemo Befehl unterstützen, Fragen über 
Krebs zu beantworten und nach den Antworten zu suchen, um Punkte, 
zusammen mit dem Manövrieren der chemo Fertigkeit zu gewinnen, um 
Tumoren zu schießen und zu zerstören.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Capitaine Chemo et ses cadets de montre comme ils 
s'embarquent sur cinq aventures traitant différentes issues 
concernées par le cancer. Les aventures animées ont été 
créées par la division de multimédia du spécialiste de Gameplay's 
- doUno.com. Le site éducatif animé et interactif est 
principalement les patients, les parents et les amis visés de cancer 
pour expliquer la maladie et son traitement. Vous pouvez aider 
capitaine Chemo et commande de Chemo de répondre à des questions au 
sujet de cancer et de rechercher les réponses pour gagner des points,
ainsi que manoeuvrer le métier de chemo pour tirer et détruire des 
tumeurs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capitão Chemo e seus cadets do relógio como 
embark em cinco aventuras que tratam das edições diferentes 
concernidas com o cancer. As aventuras animated foram criadas 
pela divisão dos multimedia do specialist de Gameplay - doUno.com. 
O local educacional animated e interativo é primeiramente 
pacientes, parentes e amigos visados do cancer para explicar a doença
e seu tratamento. Você pode ajudar ao capitão Chemo e ao 
comando de Chemo responder a perguntas sobre o cancer e procurarar 
pelas respostas para ganhar pontos, junto com manobrar o ofício do 
chemo para disparar e destruir em tumours.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitano Chemo ed i suoi cadets della vigilanza 
come intraprendono cinque avventure che si occupano delle edizioni 
differenti preoccupate di cancro. Le avventure animate sono 
state create da divisione di multimedia dell'esperto del Gameplay - 
doUno.com. Il luogo educativo animato ed interattivo è 
soprattutto pazienti, parenti ed amici puntati su del cancro per 
spiegare la malattia ed il relativo trattamento. Potete aiutare 
il capitano Chemo ed il comando di Chemo rispondere alle domande circa
cancro e cercare le risposte per guadagnare i punti, insieme a 
manovrare il mestiere di chemo per sparare e distruggere i 
tumori.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ρολόι καπετάνιος Chemo και οι μαθητές στρατιωτικής 
σχολής του όπως αρχίζουν πέντε περιπέτειες που εξετάζουν τα 
διαφορετικά ζητήματα ενδιαφερόμενα για τον καρκίνο. Οι 
ζωντανεψοντες περιπέτειες έχουν δημιουργηθεί από το τμήμα 
ειδικών πολυμέσων Gameplay - doUno.com. Τη ζωντανεψοντη 
και διαλογική εκπαιδευτική περιοχή στοχεύουν πρώτιστα στους 
ασθενείς με καρκίνο, τους συγγενείς και τους φίλους να εξηγήσει 
την ασθένεια και τη θεραπεία της. Μπορείτε να βοηθήσετε την 
εντολή Chemo και Chemo καπετάνιου για να απαντήσετε στις 
ερωτήσεις για τον καρκίνο και την αναζήτηση των απαντήσεων για να 
κερδίσετε τους βαθμούς, μαζί με τον ελιγμό της τέχνης chemo 
για να πυροβολήσετε και να καταστρέψετε τους όγκους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capitán Chemo y sus cadetes del reloj como 
emprenden cinco aventuras que se ocupan de diversas ediciones 
referidas al cáncer. Las aventuras animadas han sido creadas 
por la división de las multimedias del especialista de Gameplay - 
doUno.com. El sitio educativo animado e interactivo es sobre 
todo pacientes, parientes y amigos dirigidos del cáncer para explicar
la enfermedad y su tratamiento. Usted puede asistir a capitán 
Chemo y al comando de Chemo de contestar a preguntas sobre cáncer y 
de buscar para las respuestas para ganar puntas, junto con maniobrar 
el arte del chemo para tirar y para destruir a tumores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:BEN DE GARIS
FN:BEN DE GARIS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974089</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108065</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/adventures-of-captain-chemo</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
