<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106021</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106021</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974126</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Human Rights. YES! Action and Advocacy on the
Rights of Persons with Disabilities</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschliche Rechte. JA! Tätigkeit und
Befürwortung auf theRights der Personen mit Unfähigkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Droits de l'homme. OUI ! Action et 
recommandation sur des theRights des personnes avec des incapacités</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Direitas Humanas. SIM! Ação e 
advocacy em theRights das pessoas com inabilidades</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Diritti dell'uomo. SÌ! Azione ed 
avvocatura sui theRights delle persone con le inabilità</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα ανθρώπινα δικαιώματα. ΝΑΪ Ενέργεια και 
υπεράσπιση σε theRights των προσώπων με ειδικές ανάγκες</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Derechos Humanos. ¡SÍ! Acción y 
defensa en theRights de personas con inhabilidades</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This manual is intended to help all those who care about the human rights of persons with disabilities to become effective educators and advocates on human rights and disability, able to share both their passion and their knowledge. Human Rights. YES! draws on the experience of many educators and organizations, illustrating effective advocacy practices and distilling their accumulated insights in the development of participatory exercises. Human Rights. YES! is unique in that it is written and designed for use by people with disabilities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Handbuch soll alles denen helfen, die für 
die menschlichen Rechte der Personen mit Unfähigkeit, wirkungsvolle 
Erzieher und Fürsprecher auf menschlichen Rechten und Unfähigkeit zu
werden sich interessieren, fähig, ihre Neigung und ihr Wissen zu 
teilen. Menschliche Rechte. JA! zeichnet auf die 
Erfahrung vieler Erzieher und Organisationen, veranschaulicht 
wirkungsvolle Befürwortung Praxis und destilliert ihre akkumulierten 
Einblicke in der Entwicklung der teilnehmenden Übungen. 
Menschliche Rechte. JA! ist dadurch eindeutig, daß 
sie für Gebrauch von den Leuten mit Unfähigkeit geschrieben und 
bestimmt wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce manuel est destiné pour aider tout ceux qui 
s'inquiètent des droits de l'homme des personnes avec des 
incapacités de devenir les éducateurs et les avocats pertinents sur 
des droits de l'homme et l'incapacité, capables partager leur passion
et leur connaissance. Droits de l'homme. OUI ! 
tirere parti de l'expérience de beaucoup d'éducateurs et 
organismes, illustrant des pratiques en matière pertinentes de 
recommandation et distillant leurs perspicacités accumulées dans le 
développement des exercices participatoires. Droits de l'homme.
OUI ! est seul parce qu'on lui écrit et est conçu à 
l'usage des personnes avec des incapacités.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este manual é pretendido ajudar todo o àqueles 
que se importam com as direitas humanas das pessoas com inabilidades 
se transformar educadores e advogados eficazes em direitas humanas e 
em inabilidade, capazes de compartilhar  de sua paixão e de seu 
conhecimento. Direitas Humanas. SIM! desenha na 
experiência de muitos educadores e organizações, ilustrando 
práticas eficazes do advocacy e destilando suas introspecções 
acumuladas no desenvolvimento de exercícios participatory. 
Direitas Humanas. SIM! é original  que está 
escrito e projetado para o uso por povos com inabilidades.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo manuale è inteso per aiutare tutto coloro 
che si preoccupa per i diritti dell'uomo delle persone con le 
inabilità diventare educatori e fautori efficaci sui diritti 
dell'uomo e sull'inabilità, in grado di ripartire sia la loro 
passione che la loro conoscenza. Diritti dell'uomo. SÌ! 
dissipa sull'esperienza in molti educatori ed organizzazioni, 
illustrante le pratiche efficaci di avvocatura e distillante le loro 
comprensioni accumulate nello sviluppo delle esercitazioni partecipi. 
Diritti dell'uomo. SÌ! è unico in quanto è 
scritto e progettato ad uso della gente con le inabilità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το εγχειρίδιο προορίζεται να βοηθήσει όλους 
εκείνους που φροντίζουν για τα ανθρώπινα δικαιώματα των προσώπων 
με ειδικές ανάγκες να γίνουν αποτελεσματικοί εκπαιδευτικοί και 
συνήγοροι στα ανθρώπινα δικαιώματα και την ανικανότητα, ικανά να 
μοιραστούν και το πάθος τους και τη γνώση τους. Τα ανθρώπινα
δικαιώματα. ΝΑΪ χρησιμοποιεί την εμπειρία πολλών 
εκπαιδευτικών και οργανώσεων, που επεξηγεί τις αποτελεσματικές 
πρακτικές υπεράσπισης και που αποστάζει τις συσσωρευμένες ιδέες 
τους στην ανάπτυξη των συμμετεχουσών ασκήσεων. Τα ανθρώπινα 
δικαιώματα. ΝΑΪ είναι μοναδικός δεδομένου ότι 
γράφεται και σχεδιάζεται προς χρήση από τους ανθρώπους με 
ειδικές ανάγκες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este manual se piensa para ayudar todo el a los 
que cuiden sobre los derechos humanos de personas con inhabilidades de
hacer educadores y abogados eficaces en derechos humanos e 
inhabilidad, capaces de compartir su pasión y su conocimiento. 
Derechos Humanos. ¡SÍ! traza en la experiencia de 
muchos educadores y organizaciones, ilustrando prácticas eficaces de 
la defensa y destilando sus penetraciones acumuladas en el desarrollo 
de ejercicios participantes. Derechos Humanos. ¡SÍ! 
es único en que es escrito y diseñado para el uso por la gente
con inhabilidades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NANCY FLOWERS
FN:NANCY FLOWERS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JOELLE BALFE
FN:JOELLE BALFE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KATHERINE GUERNSEY
FN:KATHERINE GUERNSEY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:VALERIE KARR
FN:VALERIE KARR
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JANET LORD
FN:JANET LORD
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974126</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106021</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/human-rights-yes-action-and-advocacy-on-the-rights-of-persons-with-disabilities</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
