<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107410</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107410</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206878</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Chatham Plantation: Witness to the Civil War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Chatham Plantage: Zeuge zum Bürgerkrieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Plantation de Chatham : Témoin de la guerre 
civile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Plantação De Chatham: Testemunha à guerra 
civil</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Piantagione Di Chatham: Testimone alla guerra
civile</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φυτεία Chatham: Μάρτυρας στον εμφύλιο πόλεμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Plantación De Chatham: Testigo a la guerra 
civil</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">recounts what happened at this plantation overlooking Fredericksburg, Virginia. The house served as a headquarters and communications center for generals and commanders. When General Irvin McDowell was housed there, President Lincoln visited to confer with about strategy. Later in the war, the house served as a hospital where Clara Barton and Walt Whitman tended to wounded soldiers. Four major battles were fought in the countryside surrounding Chatham.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">zählt nach, was an dieser Plantage geschah, die 
Fredericksburg, Virginia übersieht. Das Haus diente wie 
Hauptsitz- und Kommunikationsmitte für Generäle und Kommandanten. 
Als General Irvin McDowell dort untergebracht wurde, Präsident 
Lincoln besichtigt, um mit ungefähr Strategie zu konferieren. 
Später im Krieg, diente das Haus als Krankenhaus, in dem Clara 
Barton und Walt Whitman zu verletzten Soldaten neigten. Vier 
Hauptschlachten wurden in der Landschaft gekämpft, die Chatham 
umgibt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">raconte ce qui s'est produit à cette plantation 
donnant sur Fredericksburg, la Virginie. La maison a servi  
centre de sièges sociaux et de transmissions pour des généraux et 
des commandants. Quand le Général Irvin McDowell a été logé
là, le Président Lincoln visité pour conférer avec environ la 
stratégie. Plus tard dans la guerre, la maison a servi 
d'hôpital où Clara Barton et Walt Whitman ont tendu aux soldats 
blessés. Quatre batailles principales ont été combattues dans
la campagne entourant Chatham.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">recounts o que aconteceu nesta plantação que 
negligencia Fredericksburg, Virgínia. A casa serviu como 
matrizes e centro de comunicações para generais e comandantes. 
Quando o general Irvin McDowell foi abrigado lá, presidente 
Lincoln visitado para conferenciar com aproximadamente estratégia. 
Mais tarde na guerra, a casa serviu como um hospital onde Clara 
Barton e Walt Whitman tendessem aos soldados feridos. Quatro 
batalhas principais foram lutadas no campo que cerca Chatham.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">racconta che cosa è accaduto a questa piantagione 
che trascura Fredericksburg, la Virginia. La casa ha servito 
come centro di comunicazioni e delle sedi per i General ed i 
comandanti. Quando il General Irvin McDowell è stato alloggiato
là, presidente Lincoln visitata per conferire con circa strategia. 
Più successivamente nella guerra, la casa ha servito da 
ospedale in cui Clara Barton e Walt Whitman hanno teso ai soldati 
ferriti. Quattro battaglie importanti sono state combattute 
nella campagna che circonda Chatham.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">δεύτερες καταμετρήσεις τι συνέβη σε αυτήν την φυτεία 
αγνοώντας Fredericksburg, Βιρτζίνια. Το σπίτι που 
εξυπηρετείται ως την έδρα και το κέντρο επικοινωνιών για τους 
στρατηγούς και τους διοικητές. Όταν ο στρατηγός Irvin 
McDowell στεγάστηκε εκεί, ο Πρόεδρος Lincoln επισκέφτηκε για
να συσκεφτεί με για τη στρατηγική. Αργότερα στον πόλεμο, το 
σπίτι που χρησιμεύεται ως ένα νοσοκομείο όπου Κλάρα Barton 
και Walt Whitman έτειναν στους πληγωμένους στρατιώτες. 
Τέσσερις σημαντικές μάχες πάλεψαν στην επαρχία που 
περιβάλλει Chatham.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">contó de nuevo qué sucedió en esta plantación 
que pasaba por alto Fredericksburg, Virginia. La casa sirvió 
como centro de las jefaturas y de comunicaciones para los generales y 
los comandantes. Cuando contuvieron a general Irvin McDowell 
allí, presidente Lincoln visitada para consultar con alrededor 
estrategia. Más adelante en la guerra, la casa sirvió como 
hospital en donde Clara Barton y Walt Whitman tendieron a los soldados
heridos. Cuatro batallas importantes fueron luchadas en el campo
que rodeaba Chatham.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206878</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107410</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/chatham-plantation-witness-to-the-civil-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
