<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107790</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107790</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086941</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Gigantic Forces of Depression Are Today in Retreat": Hoover Insists That Things Are Getting Better</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die gigantischen Kräfte des Tiefstands sind 
heute im Rückzug": Staubsauger Beharrt, Daß Sachen Besser 
Erhalten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"les forces colossales de la dépression sont 
aujourd'hui en retrait" : l'Aspirateur Insiste Sur le fait que 
Les Choses Vont Mieux</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"as forças gigantescas do depression estão hoje 
no recuo": O Hoover Insiste Que As Coisas Estão começando Mais
melhor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"le forze gigantesche della depressione sono oggi 
nella ritirata": Il Hoover Insiste Che Le Cose Stanno ottenendo 
Più meglio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι γιγαντιαίες δυνάμεις της κατάθλιψης είναι σήμερα 
στην υποχώρηση": Το Hoover επιμένει ότι τα πράγματα 
παίρνουν καλύτερα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"las fuerzas gigantescas de la depresión están 
hoy en retratamiento": La Aspiradora Insiste Que Las Cosas 
Están consiguiendo Mejor</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On the morning of October 24, 1929 ("Black Thursday"), billions of dollars in stock value were wiped out before lunch. Prices recovered somewhat that afternoon, but the Great Crash was underway. The next day President Herbert Hoover counseled reassurance, but as stock prices continued to plummet Hoover's reassurances rang increasingly hollow. The president's efforts to reassure the public did not stop, in part for political reasons. To win reelection in 1932, he would have to convince voters that his policies were bringing recovery. In this excerpt from an October 22, 1932, campaign speech on "The Success of Recovery," Hoover told a partisan crowd of twenty-two thousand in Detroit's Olympia Arena that success would have come even sooner if not for Democratic obstruction. The Detroit faithful and radio audiences heard Hoover hail ten sure signs of "economic recovery." (Less enthusiastic were hundreds of unemployed men who greeted him at the train station with signs like "Hoover--Baloney and Apple Sauce.")</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf dem Morgen von Oktober 24, 1929 ("schwarzer 
Donnerstag"), Milliarden Dollar im auf lagerwert wurden heraus vor dem
Mittagessen abgewischt. Preise stellten ein wenig diesen 
Nachmittag wieder her, aber der große Systemabsturz war unterwegs. 
Der am nächsten Tag Präsident Herbert Hoover riet 
Versicherung, aber, während die Aktienpreise, die fortgesetzt wurden,
um abzusinken Versicherungen des Staubsaugers, in zunehmendem Maße 
hohles schellten. Die Bemühungen des Präsidenten, der 
Öffentlichkeit zu versicheren stoppten, nicht im Teil aus politischen
Gründen. Um Wiederwahl 1932 zu gewinnen, würde er Wähler 
überzeugen müssen daß seine politischen Richtlinien Wiederanlauf 
holten. In diesem Excerpt von einem Oktober 22, 1932, Wahlrede 
auf "dem Erfolg des Wiederanlaufs," erklärte Staubsauger einer 
parteigängerischen Masse von zweiundzwanzig tausend in der Arena 
Olympia Detroits, die Erfolg sogar eher wenn nicht für demokratisches
Hindernis gekommen haben würde. Das Detroit zuverlässige und 
Radiopublikum hörten Staubsauger, 10 sichere Zeichen 
"Wirtschaftsaufschwung zu hageln." (waren Hunderte der 
arbeitslosen Männer weniger enthusiastisch, die ihn an der Serie 
Station mit Zeichen wie "Staubsauger -- Quatsch und Apfelsauce." 
grüßten)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le matin octobre de 24, 1929 ("jeudi noir"), 
milliards de dollars en valeur courante ont été éliminés avant le 
déjeuner. Les prix ont récupéré en quelque sorte cet 
après-midi, mais la grande panne totale était en cours. Le 
jour suivant le Président Herbert Hoover a conseillé la 
réassurance, mais pendant que les cours des actions d'actions 
continués pour descendre les réassurances de l'aspirateur sonnaient 
de plus en plus creux. Les efforts du président de rassurer le 
public ne se sont pas arrêtés, en partie pour des raisons 
politiques. Pour gagner la réélection en 1932, il devrait 
convaincre des électeurs que ses politiques apportaient la reprise. 
Dans cet extrait à partir octobre de 22, 1932, discours de 
campagne sur "le succès de la reprise," l'aspirateur a indiqué une 
foule partisane de vingt-deux mille dans l'arène d'Olympia de Detroit
que le succès serait venue encore plus tôt si pas pour l'obstruction
démocratique. Les assistances fidèles et par radio de Detroit 
ont entendu l'aspirateur grêler dix signes sûrs "de reprise 
économique." (moins enthousiastes étaient les centaines 
d'hommes sans emploi qui l'ont salué à la station de train avec des 
signes comme l'"aspirateur -- idiotie et compote de pommes.")</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na manhã outubro de 24, 1929 ("quinta-feira 
preta"), billions dos dólares no valor conservado em estoque foram 
limpados para fora antes do lunch. Os preços recuperaram um 
tanto essa tarde, mas o ruído elétrico grande era underway. No
dia seguinte o presidente Herbert Hoover aconselhou o reassurance, mas
enquanto os preços conservados em estoque continuados a plummet 
reassurances do hoover soaram cada vez mais oco. Os esforços do
presidente tranquilizar o público não pararam, na peça para razões
políticas. Para ganhar o reelection em 1932, teria que 
convencer eleitores que suas políticas traziam a recuperação. 
Neste excerpt outubro de um 22, 1932, discurso de campanha "no 
sucesso da recuperação," o hoover disse uma multidão partisan de 
vinte e dois mil na arena de Olympia de Detroit que o sucesso viria 
mesmo mais logo if.not para a obstrução democrática. As 
audiências fiéis e de rádio do Detroit ouviram o hoover granizar 
dez sinais certos "da recuperação econômica." (mais menos 
entusiásticas eram as centenas dos homens unemployed que o 
cumprimentaram na estação de trem com sinais como o "hoover -- 
baloney e sauce de Apple.")</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sulla mattina de 24 ottobre 1929 ("giovedì 
nero"), miliardi dei dollari nel valore di riserva sono stati 
eliminati prima di pranzare. I prezzi hanno recuperato piuttosto
quel pomeriggio, ma l'arresto grande era in corso. Il giorno 
seguente il presidente Herbert Hoover ha consigliato la 
riassicurazione, ma mentre i prezzi di riserva continuati per 
discendere riassicurazioni del hoover hanno squillato sempre più 
vuoto. Gli sforzi del presidente riassicurare il pubblico non si
sono arrestati, in parte per i motivi politici. Per vincere la 
rielezione in 1932, dovrebbe convincere gli elettori che le sue 
politiche stavano portando il recupero. In questo brano da 22 
ottobre 1932, discorso di campagna "sul successo del recupero," il 
hoover ha detto ad una folla partigiana di ventidue mila nell'arena di
Olympia de Detroit che il successo avrebbe venuto ancora più presto 
se non per l'ostruzione democratica. I pubblici fedeli e 
radiofonici de Detroit hanno sentito il hoover grandinare dieci segni 
sicuri "del miglioramento della situazione economica." (meno 
entusiastici erano i centinaia degli uomini disoccupati che greeted 
lui alla stazione di treno con i segni come "il hoover -- baloney e 
composta di mele.")</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο πρωί της 24ης Οκτωβρίου ..1929 ("μαύρη 
Πέμπτη"), τα δισεκατομμύρια των δολαρίων στην αξία αποθεμάτων 
σκουπίστηκαν έξω πριν από το μεσημεριανό. Οι τιμές που 
ανακτήθηκαν κάπως εκείνο το απόγευμα, αλλά η μεγάλη συντριβή 
ήταν εν εξελίξει. Η επόμενη ημέρα ο Πρόεδρος Herbert 
Hoover συμβούλευσε τη διαβεβαίωση, αλλά δεδομένου ότι οι 
τιμές αποθεμάτων συνέχισαν να πέφτουν κατακόρυφα οι 
διαβεβαιώσεις Hoover χτύπησαν όλο και περισσότερο κοίλο. 
Οι προσπάθειες του Προέδρου να καθησυχάσει το κοινό δεν 
σταμάτησαν, εν μέρει για πολιτικούς λόγους. Για να κερδίσει
την επανεκλογή το 1932, θα έπρεπε να πείσει τους ψηφοφόρους 
ότι οι πολιτικές του έφερναν την αποκατάσταση. Σε αυτό το 
απόσπασμα από ενός τις 22 Οκτωβρίου ..1932, ομιλία 
εκστρατείας "στην επιτυχία της αποκατάστασης," Hoover είπε σε 
ένα αντιστασιακό πλήθος είκοσι δύο χιλιάδων στο χώρο της 
Ολυμπία του Ντητρόιτ ότι η επιτυχία θα είχε έρθει ακόμα πιό 
σύντομα εάν όχι για τη δημοκρατική παρεμπόδιση. Τα πιστά 
και ραδιο ακροατήρια του Ντητρόιτ άκουσαν το χαλάζι Hoover 
δέκα σίγουρα σημάδια της "οικονομικής ανάκαμψης." 
(Λιγότερο ενθουσιώδης ήταν εκατοντάδες των άνεργων ατόμων 
που τον χαιρέτησαν στο σταθμό τραίνων με τα σημάδια όπως τη 
"σάλτσα Hoover -- Baloney και μήλων.")</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En la mañana del de octubre 24 de 1929 ("jueves 
negro"), mil millones de dólares en el valor común fueron limpiados 
hacia fuera antes de almorzar. Los precios recuperaron algo esa 
tarde, pero la gran caída estaba en curso. El presidente 
Herberto Hoover aconsejó el día siguiente reaseguro, pero como los 
precios comunes continuados para caer a plomo los reaseguros de la 
aspiradora sonaron cada vez más hueco. Los esfuerzos del 
presidente de tranquilizar al público no pararon, en la pieza por 
razones políticas. Para ganar la reelección en 1932, él 
tendría que convencer a votantes de que sus políticas trajeran la 
recuperación. En este extracto del de octubre 22 de 1932, 
discurso de campaña en "el éxito de la recuperación," la aspiradora
dijo a muchedumbre partisana de veintidós miles en la arena de 
Olympia de Detroit que el éxito habría venido incluso más pronto si
no para la obstrucción democrática. Las audiencias fieles y de
radio de la Detroit oyeron la aspiradora granizar diez muestras 
seguras de "recuperación económica." (menos entusiásticos 
eran los centenares de los hombres parados que lo saludaron en la 
estación de tren con las muestras como "aspiradora -- baloney y 
compota de manzanas.")</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086941</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107790</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-gigantic-forces-of-depression-are-today-in-retreat-hoover-insists-that-things-are-getting-better</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
