<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107052</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107052</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205997</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">H.I.P. Pocket Change</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">H.I.P. Tasche Änderung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">H.I.P. Changement de Poche</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">H.I.P. Mudança Do Bolso</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">H.I.P. Cambiamento Della Tasca</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">H.I.P. Αλλαγή τσεπών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">H.I.P. Cambio Del Bolsillo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">explores the history of coins. Teachers can find lesson plans on charting history with pennies, or showing students 293 ways to make change for a dollar. Students can learn how to start their own coin collection, travel back through history using coins as their guide, or design a future coin.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erforscht die Geschichte der Münzen. Lehrer
können Lektionpläne auf dem Entwerfen von von Geschichte mit Pennies
oder dem Zeigen Kursteilnehmern von von 293 Möglichkeiten finden, 
Änderung für einen Dollar vorzunehmen. Kursteilnehmer können 
erlernen, wie man ihre eigene Münzsammlung, Spielraum zurück durch 
Geschichte mit Münzen als ihre Anleitung beginnt, oder konzipieren 
Sie eine zukünftige Münze.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">explore l'histoire des pièces de monnaie. 
Les professeurs peuvent trouver des plans de leçon sur dresser 
une carte l'histoire avec des penny, ou montrer à des étudiants 293 
voies de faire le changement pour un dollar. Les étudiants 
peuvent apprendre comment commencer leur propre collection de pièce 
de monnaie, voyage en arrière par l'histoire en utilisant des pièces
de monnaie en tant que leur guide, ou concevez une future pièce de 
monnaie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">explora o history das moedas. Os professores 
podem encontrar plantas da lição em fazer um mapa do history com 
moedas de um centavo, ou em mostrar a estudantes 293 maneiras fazer a 
mudança para um dólar. Os estudantes podem aprender como 
começar para trás sua própria coleção de moeda, curso com o 
history usando moedas como sua guia, ou projete uma moeda futura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esplora la storia delle monete. Gli 
insegnanti possono trovare i programmi di lezione sul rilevamento 
della storia con i penny, o sul mostrare ad allievi 293 modi fare il 
cambiamento per un dollaro. Gli allievi possono imparare come 
iniziare la loro propria accumulazione di moneta, corsa indietro con 
storia usando le monete come loro guida, o progetti una moneta futura.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ερευνά την ιστορία των νομισμάτων. Οι δάσκαλοι 
μπορούν να βρούν τα σχέδια μαθήματος για την ιστορία 
χαρτογράφησης με τις πένες, ή την εμφάνιση στους σπουδαστές 
293 τρόπων να κάνουν την αλλαγή για ένα δολάριο. Οι 
σπουδαστές μπορούν να μάθουν πώς να αρχίσουν τη συλλογή 
νομισμάτων τους, πλάτη ταξιδιού μέσω της ιστορίας 
χρησιμοποιώντας τα νομίσματα ως οδηγό τους, ή να σχεδιάσουν ένα 
μελλοντικό νόμισμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">explora la historia de monedas. Los 
profesores pueden encontrar planes de la lección en planear historia 
con los peniques, o mostrar a estudiantes 293 maneras de realizar el 
cambio para un dólar. Los estudiantes pueden aprender cómo 
comenzar su propia colección de moneda, recorrido detrás con 
historia usando monedas como su guía, o diseñe una moneda futura.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205997</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107052</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/h-i-p-pocket-change</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
