<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105820</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105820</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086694</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">One Strike Against Her: A Store Clerk Dares to Join the Union</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Schlag Gegen Sie: Eine 
Speicher-Sekretärin-trauen, zum des Anschlußes zu verbinden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une Grève Contre Elle : Défis d'un commis 
de magasin pour joindre l'union</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma Batida De encontro A Ela: Desafios de um
caixeiro de loja para juntar a união</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un Colpo Contro di Lei: Sfide dell'impiegato
di deposito per unire l'unione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια απεργία ενάντια σε την: Ένας υπάλληλος 
καταστημάτων τολμά να ενώσει την Ένωση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una Huelga Contra Ella: Atrevimientos de un 
vendedor de almacén para ensamblar la unión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Around 1903, employers began to mount organized campaigns to break the power of labor unions. Employers had a broad array of tactics at their disposal, including blacklists, strikebreakers, and court injunctions against strikers' use of boycotts and sympathy strikes. Although employers had reliable allies in state and local police forces, they continued to hire their own private police--detective agencies that used secret operatives to disrupt unions and supplied thugs to protect strikebreakers during strikes. Most employers did not, however, need to resort to either spies or state police to break unions. The simplest expedient was to simply fire employees who were perceived as potential troublemakers. Former department store worker Sylvia Schulman testified in 1914 before the U.S. Commission on Industrial Relations about her experience being fired from her job at A. I. Mann &amp; Sons in Brooklyn merely for joining the retail clerks' union.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Herum 1903, Arbeitgeber fing an, organisierte 
Kampagnen einzuhängen, um die Energie der Arbeiterverbände zu 
brechen. Arbeitgeber hatten eine ausgedehnte Reihe Taktiken an 
ihrer Beseitigung, einschließlich schwarze Listen, an den 
Streikbrechern und an den Gerichtinjunktionen gegen Gebrauch der 
Schlaggeräte von Boykotts und Sympathieschlägen. Obgleich 
Arbeitgeber zuverlässige Verbündete im Zustand und in den lokalen 
Polizeikräften hatten, fuhren sie fort, ihre eigene private Polizei 
anzustellen -- Detektivbüros, die geheime Arbeiter verwendeten, um 
Anschlüße zu stören und Schurkeen angaben, um Streikbrecher 
während der Schläge zu schützen. Die meisten Arbeitgeber 
nicht brauchten jedoch, auf die Spione oder Zustandpolizei 
zurückzugreifen entweder, zum der Anschlüße zu brechen. Das 
einfachste Hilfsmittel sollte Angestellte einfach feuern, die als 
mögliche troublemakers wahrgenommen wurden. Ehemaliger 
Abteilung Speicherarbeiter Sylvia Schulman bezeugte 1914, bevor die 
VEREINIGTEN STAATEN auf industriellen Beziehungen zwischen den 
Sozialpartnern über ihre Erfahrung beauftragen, die von ihrem Job an 
A abgefeuert wird. I. Mann u. Söhne in Brooklyn bloß für 
Anschluß der verbindenen den Kleinsekretärinnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Autour 1903, employeurs a commencé à organiser 
des campagnes organisées pour casser la puissance des syndicats. 
Les employeurs ont eu un large choix de la tactique à leur 
disposition, y compris des listes noires, à briseurs de grève, et à
injonctions de cour contre l'utilisation des butées des boycotts et 
des grèves de sympathie de solidarité. Bien que les employeurs
aient eu les alliés dignes de confiance dans l'état et les forces 
locales de police, ils ont continué à louer leur propre police 
privée -- les agences de détectives qui ont utilisé les employés 
secrets pour perturber des syndicats et ont fourni des gangsters pour 
protéger des briseurs de grève pendant les grèves. La plupart
des employeurs, cependant, n'ont pas eu besoin de recourir aux espions
ou à la police d'état pour casser des syndicats. L'expédient 
le plus simple devait mettre le feu simplement aux employés qui ont 
été perçus en tant que fauteurs de troubles potentiels. L'ancien 
ouvrier Sylvia Schulman de grand magasin a témoigné en 1914 avant 
que les ETATS-UNIS commissionnent sur des relations industrielles au 
sujet de son expérience étant mise le feu de son travail à A. 
I. Mann et fils à Brooklyn simplement pour l'union des vendeurs
au détail se joignants.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ao redor 1903, empregadores começaram a montar 
campanhas organizadas para quebrar a potência de uniões labor. 
Os empregadores tiveram uma disposição larga das táticas em 
sua eliminação, including listas negras, em strikebreakers, e em 
injunctions da corte de encontro ao uso dos grevistas dos boycotts e 
das batidas de sympathy. Embora os empregadores tivessem aliados
de confiança no estado e em forças locais das polícias, continuaram
a empregar suas próprias polícias confidenciais -- as agências 
detective que usaram operatives secretos disrupt uniões e forneceram 
thugs para proteger strikebreakers durante batidas. A maioria de
empregadores, entretanto, não necessitaram recorrer aos espiões ou 
às polícias do estado para quebrar uniões. O expediente o 
mais simples devia atear fogo simplesmente aos empregados que foram 
percebidos como troublemakers potenciais. O trabalhador anterior
Sylvia Schulman da loja de departamento testified em 1914 antes que os
ESTADOS UNIDOS comissão em relações industriais sobre sua 
experiência que está sendo ateada fogo de seu trabalho em A. 
I. Mann &amp; filhos em Brooklyn meramente para a união de 
caixeiros de varejo juntando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Intorno 1903, datori di lavoro ha cominciato ad 
organizzare le campagne organizzate per rompere l'potenza dei 
sindacati di lavoro. I datori di lavoro hanno avuti un vasto 
allineamento delle tattiche alla loro eliminazione, compreso le liste 
nere, ai crumiri ed alle ingiunzioni della corte contro uso dei 
percussori dei boicottaggi e dei colpi di compassione. Anche se 
i datori di lavoro hanno fatti gli alleati certi dentro e le forze 
locali della polizia dichiarare, hanno continuato ad assumere la
loro propria polizia riservata -- agenzie detective che hanno usato 
gli operatori segreti per interrompere i sindacati ed hanno fornito i 
thugs per proteggere i crumiri durante i colpi. La maggior parte
dei datori di lavoro, tuttavia, non hanno dovuto ricorrere alle spie o
non hanno dichiarato la polizia per rompere i sindacati. 
L'espediente più semplice doveva infornare semplicemente gli 
impiegati che sono stati percepiti come troublemakers potenziali. 
L'ex operaio Sylvia Schulman del grande magazzino ha 
testimoniato in 1914 prima che gli STATI UNITI Commissione sulle 
relazione industriali circa la sua esperienza che è infornata dal suo
lavoro a A. I. Mann &amp; figli a Brooklyn soltanto per l'unione 
degli impiegati al minuto unentesi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περίπου το 1903, εργοδότες άρχισε να επικολλά τις 
οργανωμένες εκστρατείες για να σπάσει τη δύναμη των εργατικών 
συνδικάτων. Οι εργοδότες είχαν μια ευρεία σειρά τακτικής 
στη διάθεσή τους, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των μαύρων λιστών, 
strikebreakers, και των εντολών δικαστηρίων ενάντια στη χρήση 
των απεργών των μποϊκοταρισμάτων και των απεργιών συμπόνοιας. 
Αν και οι εργοδότες είχαν τους αξιόπιστους συμμάχους στο 
κράτος και τις τοπικές αστυνομικές δυνάμεις, συνέχισαν να 
μισθώνουν την ιδιωτική αστυνομία τους -- αντιπροσωπείες ιδιωτικών
αστυνομικών που χρησιμοποίησαν τους μυστικούς χειριστές για να 
αναστατώσουν τις ενώσεις και παρείχαν τους κακοποιούς για να 
προστατεύσουν strikebreakers κατά τη διάρκεια των απεργιών. 
Οι περισσότεροι εργοδότες, εντούτοις, δεν έπρεπε να 
προσφύγουν είτε στους κατασκόπους είτε την κρατική αστυνομία για
να σπάσουν τις ενώσεις. Το απλούστερο μέσο ήταν να 
απολυθούν απλά οι υπάλληλοι που θεωρήθηκαν ως πιθανοί 
ταραχοποιοί. Ο προηγούμενος εργαζόμενος Σύλβια Schulman 
καταστημάτων τμημάτων πιστοποίησε το 1914 ενώπιον της 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Επιτροπής στις εργασιακές σχέσεις για την εμπειρία 
της που βάζεται φωτιά από την εργασία της στο Α. Ι. Θ*Μανν &amp;
γιοι στο Μπρούκλιν μόνο για την ένωση της ένωσης των λιανικών 
υπαλλήλων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Alrededor 1903, patrones comenzó a montar 
campañas ordenadas para romper la potencia de sindicatos. Los 
patrones tenían un amplio arsenal de táctica en su disposición, 
incluyendo listas negras, los rompehuelgas, y las prescripciones de la
corte contra el uso de los huelguistas de boicoteos y de huelgas de 
condolencia. Aunque los patrones tenían aliados confiables en 
estado y fuerzas locales del policía, continuaron empleando a su 
propio policía privado -- las agencias detectives que utilizaron a 
operarios secretos para interrumpir uniones y proveieron a gamberros 
para proteger a rompehuelgas durante huelgas. La mayoría de los
patrones, sin embargo, no necesitaron recurrir a los espías o al 
policía del estado para romper uniones. El expediente más 
simple era encender simplemente a los empleados que fueron percibidos 
como troublemakers potenciales. El trabajador anterior Sylvia 
Schulman del almacén grande atestiguó en 1914 antes de que los 
ESTADOS UNIDOS Comisión en relaciones laborales sobre su experiencia 
que es encendida de su trabajo en A. I. Mann y hijos en Brooklyn
simplemente para la unión de los vendedores al por menor que 
ensamblan.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086694</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105820</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/one-strike-against-her-a-store-clerk-dares-to-join-the-union</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
