<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108538</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108538</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086826</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Shooting at People Wasn't Our Bag": One of the Inventors of the Computer Speaks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"das Schießen auf Leute war nicht unser Beutel": 
Einer der Erfinder des Computers spricht</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">le "tir aux gens n'était pas notre sac" : 
Un des inventeurs de l'ordinateur parle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"disparar em povos não era nosso saco": Um 
dos inventores do computador fala</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"sparare alla gente non era il nostro sacchetto": 
Uno degli inventori del calcolatore parla</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πυροβολισμός στους ανθρώπους δεν ήταν η τσάντα μασ": 
Ένας από τους εφευρέτες του υπολογιστή μιλά</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el "tirar en la gente no era nuestro bolso": 
Uno de los inventores del ordenador habla</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Who invented the computer? Like many important technological developments, the invention of the computer cannot rightly be attributed to a single person. It is clear, however, that World War II was crucial to the emergence of the electronic digital computer. The first general-purpose electronic computer was the Electronic Numerical Integrator and Computer, the ENIAC, sponsored by the U.S. Army's Ballistics Research Laboratory at the Aberdeen Proving Ground in Maryland and developed at the the Moore School of Electrical Engineering at the University of Pennsylvania. The leaders of the project were physicist John W. Mauchly and a young electrical engineer, John Presper Eckert. In this interview, done in 1988 by David Allison and Peter Vogt for the Smithsonian Institution, Eckert described how the war provided "the opportunity"and the money to solve "engineering problems, scientific problems in general"that interested them.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wer erfand den Computer? Wie viele wichtige 
technologische Entwicklungen kann die Erfindung des Computers nicht 
einer einzelnen Person mit Recht zugeschrieben werden. Sie ist 
jedoch frei daß der Zweite Weltkrieg zum Hervortreten des 
elektronischen Digitalrechners entscheidend war. Der erste 
universelle elektronische Computer war der elektronische numerische 
Integrator und der Computer, das ENIAC, gefördert durch das der 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Ballistik-Forschung Labor Armee in Aberdeen, das 
Boden in Maryland prüft und an der Moore Schule der Elektrotechnik an
der Universität von Pennsylvania entwickelt. Die Führer des 
Projektes waren Physiker John W. Mauchly und ein junger 
Elektroingenieur, John Presper Eckert. In diesem Interview 
erfolgt 1988 mit David Allison und Peter Vogt für die Smithsonian 
Anstalt, beschrieb Eckert, wie der Krieg "das opportunity"and das Geld
lieferte, um Technikprobleme zu lösen ", wissenschaftliche Probleme 
im general"that interessierte sie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Qui a inventé l'ordinateur ? Comme beaucoup
de développements technologiques importants, l'invention de 
l'ordinateur ne peut pas correctement être attribuée à une personne
simple. Elle est claire, cependant, que la deuxième guerre 
mondiale était cruciale à l'apparition du calculateur numérique 
électronique. Le premier ordinateur électronique d'usage 
universel était l'intégrateur et l'ordinateur numériques 
électroniques, l'ENIAC, commandité par le laboratoire de recherches 
de la balistique de l'armée des ETATS-UNIS à Aberdeen prouvant la 
terre dans le Maryland et développé l'à l'école de Moore de 
l'électrotechnique à l'université de la Pennsylvanie. Les 
amorces du projet étaient physicien John W. Mauchly et un jeune 
ingénieur électrique, John Presper Eckert. Dans cette 
entrevue, faite en 1988 par David Allison et Peter Vogt pour 
l'établissement Smithsonien, Eckert a décrit comment la guerre a 
fourni "l'opportunity"and l'argent pour résoudre "des problèmes 
d'ingénierie, des problèmes scientifiques dans le general"that les a
intéressés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Quem inventou o computador? Como muitos 
desenvolvimentos technological importantes, a invenção do computador
não pode direita ser atribuída a uma única pessoa. Está 
desobstruída, entretanto, que a segunda guerra mundial era crucial ao
emergence do computador digital eletrônico. O primeiro 
computador eletrônico general-purpose era o integrador e o computador
numéricos eletrônicos, o ENIAC, patrocinado pelo laboratório de 
pesquisa da balística do exército de ESTADOS UNIDOS no Aberdeen que 
prova a terra em Maryland e desenvolvido o na escola de Moore da 
engenharia elétrica na universidade de Pensilvânia. Os 
líderes do projeto eram físico John W. Mauchly e um coordenador 
elétrico novo, John Presper Eckert. Nesta entrevista, feita em 
1988 por David Allison e em Peter Vogt para a instituição 
smithsonian, Eckert descreveu como a guerra forneceu "o 
opportunity"and o dinheiro para resolver "problemas da engenharia, 
problemas científicos no general"that interessou-os.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Chi ha inventato il calcolatore? Come molti 
sviluppi tecnologici importanti, l'invenzione del calcolatore non può
essere attribuita giustamente ad una singola persona. È chiara,
tuttavia, che la seconda guerra mondiale era cruciale all'emersione 
dell'elaboratore digitale elettronico. Il primo calcolatore 
elettronico per tutti gli usi era l'integratore ed il calcolatore 
numerici elettronici, il ENIAC, promosso dal laboratorio di ricerca di
ballistica dell'esercito degli STATI UNITI a Aberdeen che dimostra la 
terra in Maryland e sviluppato alla scuola di Moore di ingegneria 
elettrica all'università de Pensilvania. I capi del 
progetto erano fisico John W. Mauchly e un assistente tecnico 
elettrotecnico giovane, John Presper Eckert. In questa 
intervista, fatta in 1988 da David Allison ed in Peter Vogt per 
l'istituzione smithsonian, Eckert ha descritto come la guerra ha 
fornito "il opportunity"and i soldi per risolvere "i problemi di 
ingegneria, problemi scientifici nel general"that li ha interessati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ποιος έφηυρε τον υπολογιστή; Όπως πολλές 
σημαντικές τεχνολογικές εξελίξεις, η εφεύρεση του υπολογιστή δεν 
μπορεί σωστά να αποδοθεί σε ένα μεμονωμένο πρόσωπο. Είναι
σαφές, εντούτοις, ότι ο παγκόσμιος πόλεμος ΙΙ ήταν κρίσιμος για
την εμφάνιση του ηλεκτρονικού ψηφιακού υπολογιστή. Ο πρώτος
γενικής χρήσης ηλεκτρονικός υπολογιστής ήταν ο ηλεκτρονικοί 
αριθμητικοί ολοκληρωτής και ο υπολογιστής, το ENIAC, που 
υποστηρίχτηκε από το ballistics του ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟΎ στρατού 
ερευνητικό εργαστήριο στο έδαφος παρουσιάσεων αποδείξεων του 
Αμπερντήν στη Μέρυλαντ και που αναπτύχθηκε στη σχολή Moore της 
ηλεκτρικής εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής στο πανεπιστήμιο της 
Πενσυλβανίας. Οι ηγέτες του προγράμματος ήταν φυσικός 
John W. Mauchly και νέος ηλεκτρολόγος μηχανικός, John 
Presper Eckert. Σε αυτήν την συνέντευξη, που έγινε το 
1988 από το Δαβίδ Allison και Peter Vogt φορ το 
σμιθσονιτικό Όργανο, eckert περιέγραψε πώς ο πόλεμος 
παρείχε "το opportunity"and τα χρήματα για να λύσει "τα 
προβλήματα εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής, τα επιστημονικά προβλήματα στο
general"that τα ενδιέφεραν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Quién inventó el ordenador? Como muchos 
progresos tecnológicos importantes, la invención del ordenador no se
puede atribuir derecho a una sola persona. Está clara, sin 
embargo, que la Segunda Guerra Mundial era crucial a la aparición de 
la calculadora numérica electrónica. El primer ordenador 
electrónico de uso general era el integrador y el ordenador 
numéricos electrónicos, el ENIAC, patrocinado por el laboratorio de 
investigación de la balística del ejército de ESTADOS UNIDOS en la 
Aberdeen que probaba la tierra en Maryland y desarrollado en el 
escuela de Moore de la ingeniería eléctrica en la universidad de 
Pennsylvania. Los arranques de cinta del proyecto eran físico 
Juan W. Mauchly e ingeniero eléctrico joven, Juan Presper Eckert. 
En esta entrevista, hecha en 1988 de David Allison y Peter Vogt 
para la institución smithsonian, Eckert describió cómo la guerra 
proporcionó "al opportunity"and el dinero para solucionar "problemas 
de la ingeniería, los problemas científicos en general"that los 
interesó.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086826</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">unknown</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108538</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/shooting-at-people-wasnt-our-bag-one-of-the-inventors-of-the-computer-speaks</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
