<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103082</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103082</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206289</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Water Science and Technology for Schools</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wasser-Wissenschaft und Technologie für Schulen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie de l'eau pour des 
écoles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia da água para escolas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia dell'acqua per le scuole</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία ύδατος για τα σχολεία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología del agua para las escuelas</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides information on dozens of water topics: what makes water water, how much water is there on earth and where, how water quality and stream flow are measured, the water and water-use cycles, national maps showing how water is used by state, surface and ground water, pesticides in ground water, aquifers, glaciers and icecaps, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Informationen auf Dutzenden Wasserthemen 
zur Verfügung: was Wasserwasser bildet, wieviel Wasser dort auf
Masse ist und wo, wie Wasserqualität und Stromfluß gemessen werden, 
das Wasser und Schleifen, die nationalen Karten Wasser-verwenden, die 
zeigen, wie Wasser durch Zustand benutzt wird, Oberflächen- und 
Grundwasser, Schädlingsbekämpfungsmittel im Grundwasser, Aquifers, 
Gletscher und Eiskappen und mehr.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des informations sur des douzaines de 
sujets de l'eau : ce qui fait l'eau de l'eau, le combien eau 
coûte là sur terre et où, comment la qualité de l'eau et 
l'écoulement de jet sont mesurés, l'eau et eau-utilisent des cycles,
cartes nationales montrant comment l'eau est employée par l'état, 
extérieur et les eaux souterraines, les pesticides en eaux 
souterraines, les couches aquifères, les glaciers et les calottes 
glaciaires, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece a informação em dúzias de tópicos da 
água: o que fazem a água da água, o quanto água está lá na
terra e onde, como a qualidade de água e o fluxo do córrego são 
medidos, a água e água-usa ciclos, mapas nacionais que mostram como 
a água é usada pelo estado, a água de superfície e à terra, os 
pesticides na água à terra, os aquifers, as geleiras e os icecaps, e
mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le informazioni sulle dozzine dei 
soggetti dell'acqua: che cosa fa l'acqua dell'acqua, il quanto 
acqua è là su terra e dove, come la qualità dell'acqua ed il flusso
del flusso sono misurati, l'acqua ed acqua-usa i cicli, programmi 
nazionali che mostrano come l'acqua è usata vicino dichiara, 
acqua superficiale e sotterranea, antiparassitari in acqua 
sotterranea, strati acquiferi, ghiacciai ed icecaps e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τις πληροφορίες για τις δωδεκάδες των θεμάτων 
ύδατος: αυτό που κάνει το ύδωρ ύδατος, πόσο ύδωρ είναι 
εκεί στη γη και όπου, πώς η ροή ποιότητας νερού και ρευμάτων 
μετριέται, οι κύκλοι ύδατος και ύδωρ-χρήσης, εθνικοί χάρτες που
επιδεικνύουν πώς το ύδωρ χρησιμοποιείται από το κράτος, την 
επιφάνεια και το υπόγειο νερό, τα φυτοφάρμακα στο υπόγειο νερό, 
τα υδροφόρα στρώματα, τους παγετώνες και icecaps, και 
περισσότερο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a la información en docenas de 
asuntos del agua: qué hace el agua del agua, cuánto agua está
allí en la tierra y donde, cómo se miden la calidad del agua y el 
flujo de la secuencia, el agua y agua-utiliza los ciclos, 
correspondencias nacionales que muestran cómo el agua es utilizada 
por el estado, superficial y el agua subterránea, los pesticidas en 
el agua subterránea, los acuíferos, los glaciares y las capas de 
hielo, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206289</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103082</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/water-science-and-technology-for-schools</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
