<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104240</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104240</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087448</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Bring Sex Out of the Closet of Fear": A Psychologist Argues that Sex Education Can Save the American Family</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"holen Sie Geschlecht aus dem Wandschrank von 
Furcht heraus": Ein Psychologe argumentiert, daß 
Geschlecht-Ausbildung die amerikanische Familie sichern kann</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"apportez le sexe hors du cabinet de la crainte" :
Un psychologue argue du fait que l'éducation de sexe peut 
sauvegarder la famille américaine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"traga o sexo fora do armário do medo": Um 
psicólogo discute que a instrução do sexo pode conservar a família
americana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"porti il sesso dall'armadio di timore": Uno
psicologo sostiene che la formazione del sesso può salvare la 
famiglia americana</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Φέρτε το φύλο από το ντουλάπι του φόβου": 
Ένας ψυχολόγος υποστηρίζει ότι η εκπαίδευση φύλων μπορεί 
να σώσει την αμερικανική οικογένεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"traiga el sexo del armario del miedo": Un 
psicólogo discute que la educación del sexo pueda salvar a la 
familia americana</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Alfred C. Kinsey published his pathbreaking research on sexual behavior in 1948 and 1953, reporting that premarital and extramarital sexual activity was not uncommon in American life. In fact, Kinsey argued, it had been part of a long-term shift beginning in the 1910s. Alarmed critics in the popular press attacked the study as a threat to the stability of the American family. In an era during which the family symbolized a retreat from Cold War and atomic age political and social tensions, some in the scientific community joined religious figures and cultural commentators in an ideological battle to strengthen the traditional domestic realm. In the following report in the popular magazine  Collier's , a psychology professor characterized his research study as a follow-up to Kinsey that dealt with knowledge and attitudes about sex. Unlike Kinsey's work, however, this report explicitly served as a prescriptive guide--telling Americans how to avoid infidelity, escape divorce, and gain marital happiness through sex education. In attempting to change so-called "incorrect" attitudes, it presented as fact conclusions not warranted by the evidence offered-- that most men wanted wives who were not disinterested in sex but didn't and flaunt it either or that ultimately "the best sex is in marriage." In presenting these beliefs as facts, the report revealed ingrained cultural attitudes at odds with ideals of scientific objectivity. These values, however, conformed with efforts to use potentially disrupting sex research findings to strengthen the one socially approved channel for sexual behavior--marriage.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Alfred C. Kinsey veröffentlichte seine 
pathbreaking Forschung auf sexuellem Verhalten 1948 und 1953 und 
berichtete, daß voreheliche und extramarital sexuelle Aktivität 
nicht in der amerikanischen Lebensdauer selten war. Tatsächlich
argumentierte Kinsey, hatte sie gewesen ein Teil einer langfristigen 
Schicht, die in den 1910s. besorgniserregenden Kritikern in der 
populären Presse anfängt, in Angriff nahm die Studie als Drohung zur
Stabilität der amerikanischen Familie. In einer Ära, während 
deren die Familie einen Rückzug vom kalten Krieg und Atomalter von 
den politischen und Sozialspannkräften symbolisierte, verbanden 
einige in der wissenschaftlichen Gemeinschaft fromme Abbildungen und 
kulturelle Kommentatoren in einer ideologischen Schlacht, um den 
traditionellen inländischen Reich zu verstärken. Im folgenden 
Report im populären Zeitschrift Colliers, kennzeichnete ein 
Psychologieprofessor seine Forschung Studie als Anschluß zu Kinsey, 
das Wissen und Haltung über Geschlecht beschäftigte. Anders 
als Arbeit Kinseys jedoch diente dieser Report ausdrücklich als 
vorschreibende Anleitung -- Amerikanern erklärend, wie man Untreue 
vermeidet, Scheidung entgeht und eheliches Glück durch 
Geschlechtausbildung gewinnt. Beim Versuchen, sogenannte 
"falsche" Haltung zu ändern, stellte sich er dar, während die 
Tatsache Zusammenfassungen, die nicht durch den Beweis gewährleistet 
wurden, anboten -- daß die meisten Männer Frauen wünschten, die 
nicht im Geschlecht selbstlos waren, aber nicht und flaunt es 
irgendein, oder daß schließlich "das beste Geschlecht ist in der 
Verbindung." Wenn er diesen Glauben als Tatsachen darstellte, 
deckte der Report die ingrained kulturelle Haltung auf, die mit 
Idealen der wissenschaftlichen Objektivität uneins ist. Diese 
Werte paßten jedoch sich mit Bemühungen, möglicherweise störende 
Geschlechtforschung Entdeckungen zu verwenden, um die eine sozial 
genehmigte Führung für sexuelles Verhalten zu verstärken -- 
Verbindung an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Alfred C. Kinsey a édité sa recherche 
pathbreaking sur le comportement sexuel en 1948 et 1953, enregistrant 
que l'activité sexuelle prénuptiale et extra-conjugale n'était pas 
rare dans la vie américaine. En fait, Kinsey a discuté, elle a
eu fait partie d'un décalage à long terme commençant dans les 
critiques alarmés par années 10 dans la presse populaire a attaqué 
l'étude comme menace à la stabilité de la famille américaine. 
Dans une ère l'où la famille a symbolisé une retraite de 
guerre froide et de tensions politiques et sociales d'âge atomique, 
certains dans la communauté scientifique ont joint les figures 
religieuses et les commentateurs culturels dans une bataille 
idéologique pour renforcer le royaume domestique traditionnel. 
Dans l'état suivant dans le magasin populaire Collier, un 
professeur de psychologie a caractérisé sa étude de recherches 
comme suivi à Kinsey qui a traité la connaissance et des attitudes 
au sujet de sexe. À la différence du travail de Kinsey, 
cependant, cet état a explicitement servi de guide préscriptif -- 
disant à des Américains comment éviter l'infidélité, échapper au
divorce, et gagner le bonheur matrimonial par l'éducation de sexe. 
En essayant de changer de prétendues attitudes "incorrectes", 
il a présenté pendant que les conclusions de fait non garantiies par
l'évidence offraient -- que la plupart des hommes ont voulu les 
épouses qui n'étaient pas désintéressées dans le sexe mais pas  
et l'afficher l'un ou l'autre ou que finalement "le meilleur sexe est 
dans le mariage." En présentant à ceux-ci la croyance comme 
faits, l'état a indiqué des attitudes culturelles invétérées en 
désaccord avec des idéaux de l'objectivité scientifique. Ces 
valeurs, cependant, se sont conformées aux efforts d'employer des 
résultats potentiellement de perturbation de recherches de sexe pour 
renforcer l'un canal socialement approuvé pour le comportement sexuel
-- mariage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Alfred C. Kinsey publicou sua pesquisa 
pathbreaking sobre o comportamento sexual em 1948 e em 1953, relatando
que a atividade sexual premarital e extramarital não era uncommon na 
vida americana. No fato, Kinsey discutiu, teve sido parte de uma
SHIFT a longo prazo que começa nos críticos alarmados 1910s. na 
imprensa popular atacou o estudo como uma ameaça à estabilidade da 
família americana. Em uma era durante que a família symbolized
um recuo da guerra fria e das tensões políticas e sociais da idade 
atômica, alguns na comunidade científica juntaram figuras religiosas
e comentadores cultural em uma batalha ideological para strengthen o 
reino doméstico tradicional. No seguinte relatório no collier 
popular do compartimento, um professor do psychology caracterizou seu 
estudo da pesquisa como uma continuação a Kinsey que tratou do 
conhecimento e das atitudes sobre o sexo. Ao contrário do 
trabalho de Kinsey, entretanto, este relatório serviu explicitamente 
como uma guia prescriptive -- dizendo a americanos como evitar o 
infidelity, escapar do divórcio, e ganhar a felicidade marital com a 
instrução do sexo. Em tentar mudar atitudes "incorretas" 
so-called, apresentou-se enquanto as conclusões do fato não 
autorizadas pela evidência ofereceram -- que a maioria de homens 
quiseram as esposas que não eram disinterested no sexo mas não  e 
para flaunt o qualquer um ou que finalmente "o mais melhor sexo está 
na união." Em apresentar a estes a opinião como fatos, o 
relatório revelou atitudes cultural ingrained em probabilidades com 
ideals do objectivity científico. Estes valores, entretanto, 
conformaram-se com os esforços usar findings potencial disrupting da 
pesquisa do sexo strengthen a uma canaleta social aprovada para o 
comportamento sexual -- união.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alfred C. Kinsey ha pubblicato la sua ricerca 
pathbreaking su comportamento sessuale in 1948 ed in 1953, segnalando 
che l'attività sessuale prematrimoniale ed extramarital non era rara 
nella vita americana. Infatti, Kinsey ha discusso, ha avuta 
fatto parte di uno spostamento di lunga durata che comincia nei 
critici allarmati gli anni 10 nella pressa popolare ha attacato lo 
studio come minaccia alla stabilità della famiglia americana. 
In un'era où la famiglia ha simbolizzato una ritirata dalla 
guerra fredda e dai tensionamenti politici e sociali di età atomica, 
alcuni nella Comunità scientifica hanno unito le figure religiose ed 
i commentatori culturali in una battaglia ideologica per rinforzare il
regno domestico tradizionale. Nel seguente rapporto nel collier 
popolare dello scomparto, un professore di psicologia ha 
caratterizzato il suo studio di ricerca come aggiornamento a Kinsey 
che si è occupato di conoscenza e degli atteggiamenti circa il sesso.
Diverso del lavoro del Kinsey, tuttavia, questo rapporto ha 
servito esplicitamente da guida normativa -- dicendo ad Americani a 
come evitare il infidelity, fuoriuscire il divorzio e guadagnare la 
felicità coniugale con formazione del sesso. Nel tentare di 
cambiare i cosiddetti atteggiamenti "errati", si è presentato mentre 
le conclusioni di fatto non garantite dalla prova hanno offerto -- che
la maggior parte dei uomini hanno desiderato le mogli che non erano 
disinterested nel sesso ma non e flaunt uno o che infine "il sesso 
migliore è nell'unione." Nel presentare questi la credenza come
fatti, il rapporto ha rivelato gli atteggiamenti culturali ingrained 
in disaccordo con gli ideali dell'obiettività scientifica. 
Questi valori, tuttavia, si sono conformati agli sforzi usare i 
risultati potenzialmente d'interruzione di ricerca del sesso per 
rinforzare l'una scanalatura socialmente approvata per comportamento 
sessuale -- unione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο Alfred C. Kinsey δημοσίευσε την 
pathbreaking έρευνά του για τη σεξουαλική συμπεριφορά το 
1948 και το 1953, αναφέροντας ότι η premarital και 
εξωγαμιαιή σεξουαλική δραστηριότητα δεν ήταν ασυνήθιστη στην 
αμερικανική ζωή. Στην πραγματικότητα, Kinsey που 
υποστηρίχτηκε, αυτό ήταν μέρος μιας μακροπρόθεσμης αρχής 
μετατόπισης στους ανησυχημένους 1910s. κριτικούς στο δημοφιλή 
Τύπο επιτέθηκε στη μελέτη ως απειλή στη σταθερότητα της 
αμερικανικής οικογένειας. Σε μια εποχή κατά τη διάρκεια της
οποίας η οικογένεια συμβόλισε μια υποχώρηση από τις πολιτικές 
και κοινωνικές εντάσεις ψυχρού πολέμου και ατομικής ηλικίας, 
μερικές στην επιστημονική κοινότητα ένωσαν τους θρησκευτικούς 
αριθμούς και τους πολιτιστικούς σχολιαστές σε μια ιδεολογική μάχη
για να ενισχύσουν την παραδοσιακή εσωτερική σφαίρα. Στην 
ακόλουθη έκθεση του δημοφιλούς ανθρακωρύχου περιοδικών, ένας 
καθηγητής ψυχολογίας χαρακτήρισε την ερευνητική μελέτη του ως 
συνέχιση σε Kinsey που εξέτασε τη γνώση και τις τοποθετήσεις 
για το φύλο. Αντίθετα από την εργασία Kinsey, εντούτοις,
αυτή η έκθεση που χρησιμεύεται ρητά ως ένας καθοδηγητικός 
οδηγός -- λέγοντας Αμερικανοί πώς να αποφύγει την απιστία, το 
διαζύγιο διαφυγών, και κερδίζει τη συζυγική ευτυχία μέσω της 
εκπαίδευσης φύλων. Στην προσπάθεια να αλλαχτούν οι 
αποκαλούμενες "ανακριβείσ" τοποθετήσεις, παρουσίασε ως 
συμπεράσματα γεγονότος που δεν επιτράπηκαν από τα στοιχεία 
προσφερθέντα -- ότι τα περισσότερα άτομα θέλησαν τις συζύγους 
που δεν ήταν ανιδιοτελείς στο φύλο αλλά όχι και flaunt αυτό 
καθένα ή ότι τελικά "το καλύτερο φύλο είναι στο γάμο." 
Στην παρουσίαση αυτών των πεποιθήσεων ως γεγονότα, η έκθεση
αποκάλυψε ριζωμένες πολιτιστικές τοποθετήσεις σε διαφωνία με τα 
ιδανικά της επιστημονικής αντικειμενικότητας. Αυτές οι 
τιμές, εντούτοις, προσαρμόστηκαν με στις προσπάθειες να 
χρησιμοποιηθούν τα ενδεχομένως αναστατώνοντας ερευνητικά 
συμπεράσματα φύλων για να ενισχύσουν αυτού κοινωνικά εγκεκριμένο
κανάλι για τη σεξουαλική συμπεριφορά -- γάμος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Alfred C. Kinsey publicó su investigación 
pathbreaking sobre comportamiento sexual en 1948 y 1953, señalando 
que la actividad sexual premarital y extramarital no era infrecuente 
en vida americana. En hecho, Kinsey discutió, tenía sido parte
de una rotación a largo plazo que comenzaba en los críticos 
alarmados los años 10 en la prensa popular atacó el estudio como 
amenaza a la estabilidad de la familia americana. En una era 
durante la cual la familia simbolizó un retratamiento de la guerra 
fría y de tensiones políticas y sociales de la edad atómica, 
algunos en la comunidad científica ensamblaron a figuras religiosas y
a comentaristas culturales en una batalla ideológica para consolidar 
el reino doméstico tradicional. En el informe siguiente en el 
collier popular del compartimiento, un profesor de la psicología 
caracterizó su estudio de la investigación como carta recordativa a 
Kinsey que se ocupó de conocimiento y de actitudes sobre sexo. 
Desemejante del trabajo de Kinsey, sin embargo, este informe 
sirvió explícitamente como guía preceptiva -- diciendo a americanos
cómo evitar infidelidad, escapar divorcio, y ganar felicidad marital 
con la educación del sexo. En procurar cambiar actitudes 
"incorrectas" supuestas, presentó mientras que las conclusiones del 
hecho no autorizadas por la evidencia ofrecieron -- que la mayoría de
los hombres desearon a esposas que no eran disinterested en sexo pero 
no lo hicieron y hacerlo alarde de cualquiera o que "el mejor sexo 
está en última instancia en la unión." En la presentación 
éstos de creencia como hechos, el informe reveló las actitudes 
culturales inculcadas en desacuerdo con ideales de la objetividad 
científica. Estos valores, sin embargo, se conformaron con 
esfuerzos de utilizar resultados potencialmente de interrupción de la
investigación del sexo para consolidar el un canal social aprobado 
para el comportamiento sexual -- unión.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087448</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104240</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/bring-sex-out-of-the-closet-of-fear-a-psychologist-argues-that-sex-education-can-save-the-american-family</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
