<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108333</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108333</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206640</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Early History of the California Coast</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Frühgeschichte der Kalifornien Küste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Histoire des débuts de la côte de la Californie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">History adiantado da costa de Califórnia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Storia remota del litorale della California</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρόωρη ιστορία της ακτής Καλιφόρνιας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Historia temprana de la costa de California</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a travel itinerary that highlights 45 historic places that help tell the story of Spanish colonization of California. Learn about forts, churches, adobe houses, historic districts, and other places. Find out about the Presidio, which was established in 1769 as the base for Spain's colonization efforts and was the first permanent European settlement on the Pacific Coast.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein Spielraumreiseweg, der 45 historische 
Plätze markiert, die helfen, die Geschichte der spanischen Besiedlung
von Kalifornien zu erklären. Erlernen Sie über Forts, Kirchen,
Ziegelsteinhäuser, historische Bezirke und andere Plätze. 
Finden Sie über das Presidio heraus, das in 1769 als die 
Unterseite für Besiedlungbemühungen Spaniens hergestellt wurde und 
die erste permanente europäische Regelung auf der Pazifikküste war.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un itinéraire de voyage qui met en valeur 45 
endroits historiques qui aident à indiquer l'histoire de la 
colonisation espagnole de la Californie. Renseignez-vous sur des
forts, des églises, des maisons d'adobe, des zones historiques, et 
d'autres endroits. Découvrez au sujet du Presidio, qui a été 
établi dans 1769 comme base pour les efforts de la colonisation de 
l'Espagne et était le premier règlement européen permanent sur la 
côte Pacifique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um itinerary do curso que destaque 45 lugares 
historic que ajudam dizer a história da colonização espanhola de 
Califórnia. Aprenda sobre forts, igrejas, casas do adôbe, 
distritos historic, e outros lugares. Encontre para fora sobre o
Presidio, que foi estabelecido em 1769 como a base para esforços da 
colonização de Spain e era o primeiro estabelecimento europeu 
permanente na costa pacífica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un itinerario di corsa che evidenzia 45 posti 
storici che contribuiscono a dire alla storia di colonizzazione 
spagnola della California. Impari circa i forts, le chiese, le 
case dell'adobe, i distretti storici ed altri posti. Scopra 
circa il Presidio, che è stato stabilito in 1769 come la base per gli
sforzi di colonizzazione della Spagna ed era il primo stabilimento 
europeo permanente sul litorale pacifico.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια περιήγηση ταξιδιού που δίνει έμφαση σε 
45 ιστορικές θέσεις ότι οι οδηγίες λένε την ιστορία της 
ισπανικής αποίκισης Καλιφόρνιας. Μάθετε για τα οχυρά, τις 
εκκλησίες, τα σπίτια πλίθας, τις ιστορικές περιοχές, και άλλες 
θέσεις. Ανακαλύψτε για το Presidio, το οποίο καθιερώθηκε 
το 1769 ως βάση για τις προσπάθειες αποίκισης της Ισπανίας και 
ήταν η πρώτη μόνιμη ευρωπαϊκή τακτοποίηση στην ειρηνική ακτή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un itinerario del recorrido que destaca 45 
lugares históricos que ayuden a contar la historia de la 
colonización española de California. Aprenda sobre fortalezas,
iglesias, casas del adobe, districtos históricos, y otros lugares. 
Descubra sobre el Presidio, que fue establecido en 1769 como la 
base para los esfuerzos de la colonización de España y era el primer
establecimiento europeo permanente en la costa pacífica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206640</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108333</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/early-history-of-the-california-coast</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
