<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103981</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103981</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206549</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">New Philadelphia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Neues Philadelphia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Nouvelle Philadelphie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Filadélfia Nova</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nuova Filadelfia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Νέα Φιλαδέλφεια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Philadelphia Nueva</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the story of the first African American to plat and register a town before the Civil War. Born into slavery in 1777 in South Carolina, Frank McWorter moved to Kentucky with his owner, where he married and earned cash as a laborer to purchase freedom for his wife and later himself. He bought a tract of military land in Illinois, where he and his wife planted and raised enough crops to eventually buy freedom for 16 children, grandchildren, and great-grandchildren.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichte des ersten afrikanischen 
Amerikaners, eine Stadt vor dem Bürgerkrieg zu flechten und zu 
registrieren, der in Sklaverei 1777 in Südcarolina getragen wird, 
aufrichtiges McWorter verschoben nach Kentucky mit seinem Inhaber, in 
dem er Bargeld als Hilfsarbeiter zur Erwerb Freiheit für seine Frau 
und später selbst verband und erwarb. Er kaufte eine Fläche 
des militärischen Landes in Illinois, in dem er und seine Frau 
genügende Getreide errichteten und anhoben, um Freiheit für 16 
Kinder, Enkelkinder und Großenkelkinder schließlich zu kaufen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit l'histoire du premier Américain africain de 
plat et enregistrer une ville avant la guerre civile soutenue dans 
l'esclavage en 1777 en Caroline du sud, McWorter franc déplacée
au Kentucky avec son propriétaire, où il a marié et a gagné 
l'argent comptant en tant que travailleur à la liberté d'achat pour 
son épouse et plus tard lui-même. Il a acheté une région de 
terre militaire en Illinois, où lui et son épouse ont planté et ont
élevé assez de collectes pour acheter par la suite la liberté pour 
16 enfants, petits-enfants, et grand-petits-enfants.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz a história do primeiro americano africano 
para plat e registar uma cidade antes da guerra civil carregada no 
slavery em 1777 em carolina sul, McWorter frank movido para Kentucky 
com seu proprietário, onde casou e ganhou o dinheiro como um laborer 
à liberdade da compra para sua esposa e mais tarde ele mesmo. 
Comprou um intervalo da terra militar em Illinois, onde e sua 
esposa plantaram e levantaram bastante colheitas para comprar 
eventualmente a liberdade para 16 crianças, grandchildren, e 
grande-great-grandchildren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alla storia del primo americano africano di 
plat e registrare una città prima della guerra civile sopportata in 
slavery in 1777 in Carolina del Sud, McWorter franco spostata nel 
Kentucky con il suo proprietario, in cui ha sposato e guadagnato i 
contanti come laborer alla libertà dell'acquisto per la sua moglie e 
più successivamente egli stesso. Ha comprato un tratto di terra
militare nell'Illinois, in cui lui e la sua moglie hanno piantato ed 
alzato abbastanza raccolti finalmente per comprare la libertà per 16 
bambini, grandchildren e gran-great-grandchildren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει την ιστορία του πρώτου αφρικανικού Αμερικανού 
στο plat και καταχωρεί μια πόλη πριν από τον εμφύλιο πόλεμο. 
Γεννημένη στη σκλαβιά το 1777 στο νότο η Καρολίνα, 
Frank McWorter κινήθηκε προς το Κεντάκυ με τον ιδιοκτήτη του,
όπου πάντρεψε και κέρδισε τα μετρητά ως laborer για να 
αγοράσει την ελευθερία για τη σύζυγό του και αργότερα τον ίδιο. 
Αγόρασε ένα κομμάτι του στρατιωτικού εδάφους στο Ιλλινόις,
όπου αυτός και η σύζυγός του φύτεψαν και αύξησαν αρκετές 
συγκομιδές για να αγοράσουν τελικά την ελευθερία για τα 16 
παιδιά, εγγόνια, και μεγάλος-εγγόνια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta la historia del primer americano africano 
plat y colocar una ciudad antes de la guerra civil llevada en 
esclavitud en 1777 en Carolina del Sur, McWorter franco movido a 
Kentucky con su propietario, en donde él casó y ganó el efectivo 
como laborer a la libertad de la compra para su esposa y más adelante
sí mismo. Él compró una zona de la pista militar en Illinois,
en donde él y su esposa plantaron y levantaron bastantes cosechas 
para comprar eventual la libertad para 16 niños, nietos, y 
grande-nietos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206549</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103981</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/new-philadelphia</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
