<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108129</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108129</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086776</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Read an Issue of  Yank, The Army Weekly</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lesen Sie eine Ausgabe des plötzlichen Stosses, 
die Armee-Wochenzeitung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Lisez une issue de coup sec, l'hebdomadaire 
d'armée</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Leia uma introdução do arranco, o semanário do 
exército</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Legga un'emissione dello strappo, il settimanale 
dell'esercito</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διαβάστε ότι ένα ζήτημα τραβά, η εβδομαδιαία έκδοση
στρατού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lea una aplicación el tirón, el semanario del 
ejército</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Beginning on June 17, 1942,  Yank , the weekly magazine published by the U.S. Army, began its unprecedented worldwide publishing effort. Most of its 127-member staff of editors, reporters, photographers, artists, and cartoonists rotated from desk jobs in  Yank 's main New York office to cover the war overseas and produce twenty-one separate weekly editions. The New York office published the American edition distributed to army camps in the United States and prepared basic material for  Yank 's overseas operations in London, Sydney, Honolulu, Rome, Paris, Cairo, Tehran, Calcutta, Puerto Rico, and Panama. Sold for five cents,  Yank  reached a combined circulation of two million soldiers. The August 6, 1943, American edition of  Yank , excerpted here, appeared twenty months after the United States entered the conflict, when the outcome of the war was still in doubt. It presented  Yank 's typical miscellany of news, stories, poetry, cartoons, illustrations, photographs, notices, advice, and gripes about enlisted life in the wartime army.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anfangend an Juni 17, 1942, plötzlicher Stoß, 
die wöchentliche Zeitschrift, die von der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Armee 
veröffentlicht wurde, fing seine beispiellose weltweite Verlags- 
Bemühung an. Die meisten seines Personals 127-member der 
Herausgeber, der Reporter, der Photographen, der Künstler und der 
Karikaturenzeichner gedreht von den Schreibtischjobs im plötzlichen 
Stoß ' s Hauptnew York Büro, den Krieg und Erzeugnis übersee zu 
bedecken einundzwanzig verschiedene wöchentliche Ausgaben. Das 
New York Büro veröffentlichte die amerikanische Ausgabe, die auf 
Armeelager in den Vereinigten Staaten verteilt wurde und bereitete 
Grundstoff für plötzlichen Stoß ' s Überseeoperationen in London, 
in Sydney, in Honolulu, in Rom, in Paris, in Kairo, in Tehran, in 
Kalkutta, in Puerto Rico und in Panama vor. Verkauft für fünf 
Cents, erreichte plötzlicher Stoß eine kombinierte Zirkulation von 
zwei Million Soldaten. Der August 6, 1943, amerikanische Ausgabe
des plötzlichen Stosses, hier excerptiert, geerschienen Zwanzig 
Monate nachdem die Vereinigten Staaten die $überschneidung eintrugen,
als das Resultat des Krieges noch innen Zweifel war. Es stellte 
plötzlichem Stoß ' s typisches Gemisch der Nachrichten, der 
Geschichten, der Poesie, der Karikaturen, der Abbildungen, der 
Fotographien, der Begriffe, des Rates und der Griffe über 
eingetragene Lebensdauer in der Kriegarmee dar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Commençant 17 juin 1942, coup sec, le magasin 
hebdomadaire édité par l'armée des ETATS-UNIS, a commencé son 
effort d'édition mondial sans précédent. La majeure partie de
son personnel 127-member des éditeurs, des journalistes, des 
photographes, des artistes, et des réalisateurs de dessins animés 
tournés à partir des travaux de bureau bureau principal de s New 
York dans coup sec 'de couvrir la guerre outre-mer et le produit vingt
et un éditions hebdomadaires séparées. Le bureau de New York 
a édité l'édition américaine distribuée aux camps d'armée aux 
Etats-Unis et a préparé la matière première des exécutions 
d'outre-mer de s pour coup sec 'à Londres, à Sydney, à Honolulu, à
Rome, à Paris, au Caire, Téhéran, à Calcutta, le Porto Rico, et 
le Panama. Vendu pour cinq cents, le coup sec a atteint une 
circulation combinée de deux millions de soldats. Août 6, 
1943, édition américaine du coup sec, extraite ici, apparu pendant 
vingt mois après que les Etats-Unis ont écrit le conflit, quand les 
résultats de la guerre étaient toujours dedans doute. Il a 
présenté au coup sec 's le mélange typique des nouvelles, des 
histoires, de la poésie, des dessins animés, des illustrations, des 
photographies, des notifications, du conseil, et des rognes sur la 
vie enrôlée dans l'armée de temps de guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Começando junho em 17, 1942, arranco, o 
compartimento semanal publicado pelo exército de ESTADOS UNIDOS, 
começou seu esforço publicando worldwide unprecedented. A 
maioria de sua equipe de funcionários 127-member dos editores, dos 
repórteres, dos fotógrafos, dos artistas, e dos cartoonists girados 
dos trabalhos da mesa escritório principal de s New York no arranco '
cobrir no ultramar a guerra e o produto vinte e um edições semanais 
separadas. O escritório de New York publicou a edição 
americana distribuída aos acampamentos do exército nos estados 
unidos e preparou o material básico para operações ultramarinas de 
s do arranco ' em Londres, em Sydney, em Honolulu, em Roma, em Paris, 
em Cairo, em Tehran, em Calcutá, em Puerto Rico, e em Panamá. 
Vendido para cinco centavos, o arranco alcançou uma 
circulação combinada de dois milhão soldados. Agosto o 6, 
1943, edição americana do arranco, excerpted aqui, aparecido vinte 
meses depois que os estados unidos incorporaram o conflito, quando o 
resultado da guerra era ainda dentro dúvida. Apresentou ao 
arranco ' s o miscellany típico da notícia, das histórias, da 
poesia, dos cartoons, das ilustrações, das fotografias, das 
observações, do conselho, e dos gripes sobre a vida alistada no 
exército do wartime.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Cominciando il 17 giugno 1942, lo strappo, lo 
scomparto settimanale pubblicato dall'esercito degli STATI UNITI, ha 
cominciato il relativo sforzo di pubblicazione in tutto il mondo senza
precedente. La maggior parte del relativo personale 127-member 
degli editori, dei reporter, dei photographers, degli artisti e dei
cartoonists ruotati a partire da i lavori dello scrittorio ufficio 
principale di s New York nello strappo 'coprire la guerra oltremare e 
prodotti ventuno edizione settimanale separata. L'ufficio de New
York ha pubblicato l'edizione americana distribuita all'esercito che 
gli accampamenti in unito Dichiara ed ha preparato la materia 
prima per funzionamenti d'oltremare di s dello strappo 'Londra, 
Sydney, Honolulu, Roma, Parigi, Cairo, Tehran, Calcutta, nel Porto 
Rico e nel Panama. Venduto per cinque centesimi, lo strappo ha 
raggiunto una circolazione unita di due milione soldati. 6 
agosto 1943, edizione americana dello strappo, stralciata qui, 
comparso venti mesi dopo che unito Dichiarasse ha entrato nel 
conflitto, quando il risultato della guerra era ancora dentro dubbio. 
Ha presentato a strappo 's la miscellanea tipica delle notizie, 
delle storia, della poesia, dei fumetti, delle illustrazioni, delle 
fotografie, degli avvisi, del consiglio e dei gripes circa vita 
arruolata nell'esercito di wartime.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχίζοντας στις 17 Ιουνίου ..1942, τραβήξτε, το 
εβδομαδιαίο περιοδικό που δημοσιεύεται από τον ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ 
στρατό, άρχισε την πρωτοφανή παγκόσμια προσπάθεια έκδοσής του. 
Το μεγαλύτερο μέρος του προσωπικού 127-μελών του 
επεξεργαστών, δημοσιογράφων, φωτογράφων, καλλιτεχνών, και 
σκιτσογράφων περιστράφηκε από τις εργασίες γραφείων Yank "s
στο βασικό Νέα Υόρκη γραφείο για να καλύψει τον πόλεμο στο 
εξωτερικό και να παραγάγει είκοσι μια χωριστές εβδομαδιαίες 
εκδόσεις. Το γραφείο της Νέας Υόρκης δημοσίευσε την 
αμερικανική έκδοση που διανεμήθηκε στα στρατόπεδα στρατού στις 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες και προετοίμασε το βασικό υλικό για Yank 
"s υπερπόντιες διαδικασία στο Λονδίνο, το Σύδνεϋ, τη 
Χονολουλού, τη Ρώμη, το Παρίσι, το Κάιρο, την Τεχεράνη, την 
Καλκούτα, το Πουέρτο Ρίκο, και τον Παναμά. Πωλημένος για 
πέντε σεντ, τραβήξτε φθαμένος σε μια συνδυασμένη κυκλοφορία δύο 
εκατομμύριο στρατιωτών. 6 Αυγούστου ..1943, αμερικανική 
έκδοση Yank, εδώ, εμφανίστηκε είκοσι μήνες αφότου εισήγαγαν 
οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες τη σύγκρουση, όταν είμαι ακόμα η έκβαση 
του πολέμου στην αμφιβολία. Παρουσίασε τραβά "τη 
χαρακτηριστική σύμμιξη του s των ειδήσεων, ιστορίες, ποίηση, 
κινούμενα σχέδια, απεικονίσεις, φωτογραφίες, ειδοποιήσεις, 
συμβουλές, και gripes για τη στρατολογημένη ζωή στον εν καιρώ 
πολέμου στρατό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comenzando 17 de junio de 1942, tirón, el 
compartimiento semanal publicado por el ejército de ESTADOS UNIDOS, 
comenzó su esfuerzo que publicaba mundial sin precedente. La 
mayoría de su personal 127-member de editores, de reporteros, de 
fotógrafos, de artistas, y de dibujantes rotados de trabajos del 
escritorio en oficina principal de s Nueva York del tirón ' de cubrir
la guerra en ultramar y el producto veintiuno ediciones semanales 
separadas. La oficina de Nueva York publicó la edición 
americana distribuida a los campos del ejército en los Estados Unidos
y preparó la materia prima para operaciones de ultramar de s del 
tirón las ' en Londres, Sydney, Honolulu, Roma, París, El Cairo, 
Tehran, Calcutta, Puerto Rico, y Panamá. Vendido para cinco 
centavos, el tirón alcanzó una circulación combinada de dos 
millones de soldados. 6 de agosto de 1943, edición americana
del tirón, extractada aquí, aparecido veinte meses después de que 
los Estados Unidos incorporaron el conflicto, cuando el resultado de 
la guerra seguía siendo adentro duda. Presentó a tirón ' s la
miscelánea típica de las noticias, de las historias, de la poesía, 
de historietas, de ilustraciones, de fotografías, de avisos, del 
consejo, y de quejas sobre vida alistada en el ejército del tiempo de
guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086776</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108129</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/read-an-issue-of-yank-the-army-weekly</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
