<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105435</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105435</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212411</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Tardigrade Species Distribution Project: Lesson Plan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tardigrade Sorte-Verteilung Projekt: 
Lektion-Plan</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Projet de Distribution d'Espèces de 
Tardigrade : Plan de Leçon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Projeto Da Distribuição Da Espécie De 
Tardigrade: Planta Da Lição</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progetto Di Distribuzione Di Specie Di Tardigrade:
Programma Di Lezione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Tardigrade πρόγραμμα διανομής ειδών: Σχέδιο 
μαθήματος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Proyecto De la Distribución De la Especie De 
Tardigrade: Plan De la Lección</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This online lesson plan was designed for students taking part in the active research project to document the distribution of a new species of tardigrade, a microscopic invertebrate animal. The project is part of a nationwide online collaborative research project. The lesson plan offers instructional procedures for teachers and lists materials and procedures for collecting, observing, and culturing tardigrades. The lesson involves collecting samples in the field, examining and classifying tartigrades in the samples using a microscope and an online taxonomic key, and keeping a biological journal of their study. Links are provided to other components of the species distribution project.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Onlinelektionplan war für die 
Kursteilnehmer konzipiert, die am aktiven Forschung Projekt 
teilnehmen, um die Verteilung einer neuen Sorte tardigrade, ein 
mikroskopisches wirbelloses Tier zu dokumentieren. Das Projekt 
ist ein Teil eines allgemein gemeinschaftlichen Forschung 
Onlineprojektes. Der Lektionplan bietet anweisende Prozeduren 
für Lehrer an und druckt Materialien und Prozeduren für das Sammeln,
das Beobachten und das Züchten von von tardigrades aus. Die 
Lektion bezieht, Proben zu sammeln in auffangene, tartigrades mit 
ein in den Proben mit einem Mikroskop und einer taxonomischen 
Onlinetaste zu überprüfen und einzustufen, und ein biologisches 
Journal ihrer Studie halten. Links werden zu anderen 
Bestandteilen des Sorteverteilung Projektes zur Verfügung gestellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce plan en ligne de leçon a été conçu pour 
des étudiants participant au projet de recherche actif pour 
documenter la distribution de l'de nouvelles espèces de 
tardigrade, un animal invertébré microscopique. Le projet fait
partie d'un projet de recherche de collaboration en ligne dans tout le
pays. Le plan de leçon offre des procédures d'instruction pour
des professeurs et énumère des matériaux et des procédures pour 
rassembler, observer, et cultiver des tardigrades. La leçon 
implique de rassembler des échantillons dans le domaine, d'examiner 
et classifier des tartigrades dans les échantillons en utilisant un 
microscope et une clé taxonomique en ligne, et gardant un journal 
biologique de leur étude. Des liens sont fournis à d'autres 
composants du projet de distribution d'espèces.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta planta em linha da lição foi projetada 
para os estudantes que fazem exame da parte no projeto de pesquisa 
ativo para documentar a distribuição de uma espécie nova do 
tardigrade, um animal invertebrate microscópico. O projeto é 
parte de um projeto de pesquisa collaborative em linha de âmbito 
nacional. A planta da lição oferece procedimentos instrutivos 
para professores e alista materiais e procedimentos para coletar, 
observar, e cultivar tardigrades. A lição envolve coletar 
amostras no campo, examinar e classificar tartigrades nas amostras 
usando um microscópio e uma chave taxonomic em linha, e mantendo um 
jornal biológico de seu estudo. As ligações são fornecidas a
outros componentes do projeto da distribuição da espécie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo programma in linea di lezione è stato 
progettato per gli allievi che partecipano al progetto di ricerca 
attivo per documentare la distribuzione di nuova specie di tardigrade,
un animale invertebrato microscopico. Il progetto fa parte di un
progetto di ricerca di collaborazione in linea nazionale. Il 
programma di lezione offre le procedure didattiche per gli insegnanti 
ed elenca i materiali e le procedure per la raccolta, l'osservazione e
la coltura dei tardigrades. La lezione coinvolge raccogliere i 
campioni nel campo, esaminare e classificare i tartigrades nei 
campioni usando un microscopio e un tasto tassonomico in linea e 
mantenendo un giornale biologico del loro studio. I collegamenti
sono forniti ad altri componenti del progetto di distribuzione di 
specie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το σε απευθείας σύνδεση σχέδιο μαθήματος 
σχεδιάστηκε για τους σπουδαστές που συμμετέχουν στο ενεργό 
ερευνητικό πρόγραμμα να τεκμηριωθεί η διανομή ενός νέου είδους 
tardigrade, ένα μικροσκοπικό ασπόνδυλο ζώο. Το πρόγραμμα
είναι μέρος ενός σε εθνικό επίπεδο σε απευθείας σύνδεση 
συνεργασίας ερευνητικού προγράμματος. Το σχέδιο μαθήματος 
προσφέρει τις εκπαιδευτικές διαδικασίες για τους δασκάλους και 
εμφανίζει λίστα τα υλικά και τις διαδικασίες για, και 
tardigrades. Το μάθημα περιλαμβάνει τη συλλογή των 
δειγμάτων στο πεδίο, την εξέταση και την ταξινόμηση tartigrades
στα δείγματα χρησιμοποιώντας ένα μικροσκόπιο και ένα σε 
απευθείας σύνδεση ταξονομικό πλήκτρο, και κρατώντας ένα 
βιολογικό περιοδικό της μελέτης τους. Οι συνδέσεις 
παρέχονται σε άλλα συστατικά του προγράμματος διανομής ειδών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este plan en línea de la lección fue diseñado 
para los estudiantes que participaban en el proyecto de investigación
activo para documentar la distribución de una nueva especie del 
tardigrade, un animal invertebrado microscópico. El proyecto es
parte de un proyecto de investigación de colaboración en línea a 
nivel nacional. El plan de la lección ofrece los procedimientos
educacionales para los profesores y enumera los materiales y los 
procedimientos para recoger, observar, y cultivar tardigrades. 
La lección implica el recoger de muestras en el campo, el 
examinar y el clasificar de tartigrades en las muestras usando un 
microscopio y un clave taxonómico en línea, y guardando un diario 
biológico de su estudio. Las conexiones se proporcionan a otros
componentes del proyecto de la distribución de la especie.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:KAREN LINDAHL
FN:KAREN LINDAHL
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SUSIE BALSER
FN:SUSIE BALSER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ILLINOIS WESLEYAN UNIVERSITY
FN:ILLINOIS WESLEYAN UNIVERSITY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212411</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105435</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/tardigrade-species-distribution-project-lesson-plan</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
