<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105196</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105196</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087346</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Voice of Moderation: Roosevelt on the Armory Show</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Stimme der Mäßigung: Roosevelt auf 
dem Waffenkammer-Erscheinen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une voix de la modération : Roosevelt sur 
l'exposition d'arsenal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma voz do moderation: Roosevelt na mostra 
do armory</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una voce di moderazione: Roosevelt 
sull'esposizione dell'arsenale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια φωνή της μετριοπάθειας: Το Roosevelt στο 
οπλοστάσιο εμφανίζει</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una voz de la moderación: Roosevelt en la 
demostración del arsenal</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1913, an "International Exhibition of Modern Art," eventually seen by a half million people, rocked the American art world. First mounted at New York City's 69th Regiment Armory, it became known as the Armory Show, and its self-consciously "modern" approach challenged the dominance of conservative, staid styles of European art. Two-thirds of the 1,600 works were by Americans, and the Europeans whose works were exhibited--Picasso, Matisse, Seurat, Van Gogh, Gaughin, and Duchamp among them--were far from the conservatives that Americans were used to. Most critics took extreme positions, either praising or damning the show. In his "A Layman's View of an Art Exhibition," published in the March 29, 1913, issue of  Outlook , Theodore Roosevelt took a moderate approach, lauding the unconventional spirit of the Armory Show while casually dismissing the work of such "European extremists" as the Cubists and the Futurists.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1913 schaukelte eine "internationale Ausstellung 
der modernen kunst," schließlich gesehen durch halbe Million Leute, 
die amerikanische kunstwelt. Zuerst eingehangen an der 
Regiment-Waffenkammer der New York Stadt 69th, wurde sie als das 
Waffenkammer-Erscheinen bekannt, und seine selbstbewußt "moderne" 
Annäherung forderte die Herrschaft des Konservativen, staid Arten der
europäischen kunst heraus. Zweidrittel der 1.600 Arbeiten waren
durch Americans, und die Europäer deren Arbeiten ausgestellt wurden 
-- Picasso, Matisse, Seurat, Van Gogh, Gaughin und Duchamp unter ihnen
-- waren weit von die Konservativen, daß Amerikaner an waren. 
Die meisten Kritiker nahmen die extremen Positionen, entweder 
das Erscheinen preisend oder verdammend. In seiner "die Ansicht 
eines Laien einer Kunstausstellung," veröffentlichte im März 29, 
1913, Ausgabe der Aussicht, Theodore Roosevelt nahm eine gemäßigte 
Annäherung, lauding den unkonventionellen Geist des 
Waffenkammer-Erscheinens beim die Arbeit solcher "europäischer 
Extremisten" wie die Cubists und die Futuristen beiläufig entlassen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1913, "une exposition internationale d'art 
moderne," par la suite vu par demi million de personnes, a basculé le
monde américain d'art. D'abord monté à l'arsenal du régiment
de la ville soixante-neuvième de New York, elle est devenue notoire 
comme exposition d'arsenal, et sa approche "moderne" de 
art de l'auto-portrait-consciously a défié la dominance des modèles 
conservateurs et sérieux d'art européen. Deux-tiers des 
1.600 travaux étaient par Americans, et les Européens dont les 
travaux ont été montrés -- Picasso, Matisse, Seurat, Van Gogh, 
Gaughin, et Duchamp parmi eux -- étaient loin des conservateurs que 
des Américains ont été utilisés à. La plupart des critiques
ont pris des positions extrêmes, félicitant ou damnant l'exposition.
Dans le sien "la vue d'un laïque d'une exposition d'art," a 
édité en 29 mars 1913, issue des perspectives, Theodore Roosevelt a
adopté une approche modérée, glorifiant l'esprit peu usuel de 
l'exposition d'arsenal tout en en passant écartant le travail de tels
"extrémistes européens" comme les cubistes et les futurologues.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1913, "um exhibition internacional da arte 
moderna," visto eventualmente por uns meio milhão povos, balançou o 
mundo americano da arte. Montado primeiramente no armory do 
regiment da cidade 69th de New York, tornou-se sabido como a mostra do
armory, e sua aproximação self-consciously "moderna" desafiou o 
dominance do conservador, estilos do staid da arte européia. 
Dois terços dos 1.600 trabalhos eram por Americano, e os 
Europeus cujos os trabalhos foram exibidos -- Picasso, Matisse, 
Seurat, Camionete Gogh, Gaughin, e Duchamp entre eles -- eram longe 
dos conservadores que os americanos estiveram usados a. A 
maioria de críticos fizeram exame das posições extremas, elogiando 
ou amaldiçoando a mostra. Em his "a opinião de um layman de um
exhibition de arte," publicou março no 29, 1913, introdução do 
outlook, Theodore Roosevelt fêz exame de uma aproximação moderada, 
lauding o espírito unconventional da mostra do armory ao ocasional 
demitir o trabalho de tais "extremists europeus" como os cubists e os 
futurists.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1913, "una mostra internazionale dell'arte 
moderna," finalmente visto da milione di persone mezzo, ha oscillato 
il mondo americano di arte. In primo luogo montato all'arsenale 
del regiment della città sessantanovesima de New York, è stato 
conosciuta come l'esposizione dell'arsenale ed il relativo metodo 
self-consciously "moderno" ha sfidato la dominanza del conservatore, 
stili dello staid dell'arte europea. Due terzi del 1.600 
impianto era da Americans e gli Europei di cui gli impianti sono stati
esibiti -- Picasso, Matisse, Seurat, Van Gogh, Gaughin e Duchamp fra 
loro -- erano lontano dai conservatori che gli Americani sono stati 
usati a. La maggior parte dei critici hanno preso le posizioni 
estreme, elogianti o maledicenti l'esposizione. In suo "il punto
di vista del laico di una mostra di arte," ha pubblicato in 29 marzo 
1913, emissione della prospettiva, Theodore Roosevelt ha adottato un 
metodo moderato, lauding lo spirito non convenzionale dell'esposizione
dell'arsenale mentre con indifferenza allontanava il lavoro di tali 
"estremisti europei" come i cubists ed i futurists.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1913, μια "διεθνής έκθεση της μοντέρνας τέχνης,"
τελικά βλέποντας από μισούς από εκατομμύριο ανθρώπους, 
λίκνισε τον αμερικανικό κόσμο τέχνης. Πρώτα επικολλημένο 
οπλοστάσιο συντάγματος της νέας πόλης της Υόρκης στο 69ο, έγινε 
γνωστό ότι ως οπλοστάσιο εμφανίστε, και η μόνος-συνειδητά 
"σύγχρονη" προσέγγισή της προκάλεσε την κυριαρχία συντηρητικού, 
οι σοβαρές μορφές των ευρωπαϊκών δύο τρίτων αρθ. των 1.600 
εργασιών ήταν από Αμερικανούς, και οι Ευρωπαίοι οι των οποίων 
εργασίες εκτέθηκαν -- Πικάσο, Matisse, Seurat, Van 
Gogh, Gaughin, και Duchamp μεταξύ τους -- ήταν μακριά από
τα συντηρητικά έως τα οποία Αμερικανοί χρησιμοποιήθηκαν. Οι
περισσότεροι κριτικοί υποστήριξαν τις ακραίες θέσεις, είτε που 
εγκωμιάζουν είτε που καταδικάζουν την επίδειξη. Κατά "την 
όψη ενός λαϊκού (μη κληρικού) του μιας έκθεσης τέχνης," 
δημοσιευμένος τις 29 Μαρτίου ..1913, ζήτημα της προοπτικής, 
Theodore Roosevelt υιοθέτησε μια μέτρια μέθοδο, επαινώντας 
το μη συμβατικό πνεύμα του οπλοστάσιου εμφανίστε άνετα 
απομακρύνοντας την εργασία τέτοιων "ευρωπαϊκών εξτρεμιστών" 
όπως τους κυβιστές και το Futurists.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1913, una "exposición internacional del arte 
moderno," considerado eventual por medio millones de personas de, 
osciló el mundo americano del arte. Primero montado en el 
arsenal del regimiento de la ciudad 69.a de Nueva York, se conocía 
como la demostración del arsenal, y su acercamiento tímidamente 
"moderno" desafió la dominación del conservador, estilos del staid 
del arte europeo. Dos tercios de los 1.600 trabajos estaba por 
americans, y los europeos que trabajos fueron exhibidos -- Picasso, 
Matisse, Seurat, Van Gogh, Gaughin, y Duchamp entre ellos -- eran 
lejos de los conservadores que utilizaron a los americanos a. La
mayoría de los críticos tomaron las posiciones extremas, elogiando o
maldiciendo la demostración. En la suya "la opinión de un 
laico de una exposición de arte," publicó en de marcha la 29 de 
1913, aplicación la perspectiva, Theodore Roosevelt tomó un 
acercamiento moderado, alabando el alcohol poco convencional de la 
demostración del arsenal mientras que ocasional despedía el trabajo 
de tales "extremistas europeos" como los cubistas y los futuristas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087346</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105196</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-voice-of-moderation-roosevelt-on-the-armory-show</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
