<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107475</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107475</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211403</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Oceanography Animations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ozeanographie-Animationen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Animations d'Océanographie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Animations Do Oceanography</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Animazioni Di Oceanografia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ζωτικότητες ωκεανογραφίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Animaciones De la Oceanografía</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features QuickTime and Flash animations that illustrate various aspects of ocean-related activity, including normal, El Nino, and La Nina conditions, ocean plant productivity, causes of upwelling, ocean current patterns, and the origin of tides. The animations can be paused and rewound to stress important points. These resources are suitable for use in lectures, labs, or other teaching activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Situationsmerkmale QuickTime und grelle 
Animationen, die verschiedene Aspekte der Ozean-in Verbindung 
stehenden Aktivität, einschließlich Normal, EL Nino und La Nina 
Zustände, Ozeanbetriebsproduktivität, Ursachen von Upwelling, 
aktuelle Muster des Ozeans und den Ursprung von Gezeiten 
veranschaulichen. Die Animationen können pausiert werden und 
gerückspult werden, um wichtige Punkte zu betonen. Diese 
Betriebsmittel sind für Gebrauch in den Vorträgen, in den Labors 
oder in anderen unterrichtenden Aktivitäten verwendbar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dispositifs de ce site QuickTime et animations 
instantanées qui illustrent de divers aspects d'activité 
océan-connexe, y compris la normale, le EL Nino, et les états de 
Nina de La, la productivité végétale d'océan, les causes de 
jaillir, les configurations actuelles d'océan, et l'origine
des marées. Les animations peuvent être faites une pause et 
rebobinées pour soumettre à une contrainte les points importants. 
Ces ressources conviennent pour l'usage dans les conférences, 
les laboratoires, ou d'autres activités d'enseignement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Características deste local QuickTime e 
animations flash que ilustram vários aspectos de atividade 
oceano-relacionada, including o normal, o EL Nino, e as condições de
Nina do la, a produtividade de planta do oceano, as causas de 
upwelling, testes padrões atuais do oceano, e a origem das marés. 
Os animations podem ser pausados e rebobinado para forçar 
pontos importantes. Estes recursos são apropriados para o uso 
nos lectures, nos laboratórios, ou em outras atividades ensinando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Caratteristiche di questo luogo QuickTime ed 
animazioni istantanee che illustrano le varie funzioni di attività 
oceano-relativa, compreso il normale, il EL Nino e gli stati di Nina 
della La, il rendimento di pianta dell'oceano, le cause di upwelling, 
i modelli attuali dell'oceano e l'origine delle maree. Le 
animazioni possono essere fatte una pausa e riavvolte per sollecitare 
i punti importanti. Queste risorse sono adatte ad uso nelle 
conferenze, in laboratori, o in altre attività d'istruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τις ζωτικότητες 
QuickTime και λάμψης που επεξηγούν τις διάφορες πτυχές της 
ωκεάνιος-σχετικής δραστηριότητας, συμπεριλαμβανομένου κανονικού, 
Ελ Νίνιο, και των όρων Λα Νίνα, της ωκεάνιας παραγωγικότητας 
εγκαταστάσεων, των αιτιών του ανεβάσματος των νερών, των ωκεάνιων
παρόντων προτύπων, και της προέλευσης των παλιρροιών. Οι 
ζωτικότητες μπορούν να σταματηθούν και rewound για να τονίζουν 
τα σημαντικά σημεία. Αυτά τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς είναι 
κατάλληλα για τη χρήση στις διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, ή άλλες 
δραστηριότητες διδασκαλίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Características de este sitio QuickTime y 
animaciones de destello que ilustran varios aspectos de la actividad 
oce'ano-relacionada, incluyendo normal, el EL Nino, y las 
condiciones de Nina del la, la productividad de planta del océano, 
las causas de upwelling, los modelos actuales del océano, y el origen
de mareas. Las animaciones se pueden detener brevemente y 
rebobinar para tensionar puntas importantes. Estos recursos son 
convenientes para el uso en conferencias, laboratorios, u otras 
actividades de enseñanza.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211403</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107475</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/oceanography-animations</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
