<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103335</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103335</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086893</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The arraignment."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"das arraignment."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"l'arraignment."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"o arraignment."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"il arraignment."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Το arraignment."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el arraignment."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">John Brown was a staunch abolitionist and a veteran of guerilla warfare in Kansas who alarmed even free soilers with his forceful assertions of African-American equality. On October 16, 1859 Brown, three of his sons, and 19 associates raided the federal arsenal at Harpers Ferry, Virginia. Planning to seize arms stored at the arsenal and set up a base to encourage and assist further slave insurrections, Brown and his men were trapped by U.S. marines, tried for treason, and hanged. Southerners saw in Brown's raid the violent intentions of northerners, while many in the North mourned Brown's death as a revolutionary martyr. A  Harper's Weekly  artist sketched Brown and his co-conspirators as they were charged with treason and murder in a Charlestown, Virginia courtroom.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">John Braun war ein staunch abolitionist und ein Veteran 
der Bandenkämpferkriegsführung in Kansas, das sogar freie soilers 
mit seinen starken Behauptungen der Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen 
Gleichheit alarmierte. An Oktober 16, 1859 überfiel Braun, drei
seiner Söhne und 19 Teilnehmer das Bundesarsenal an der Harpers 
Fähre, Virginia. Planend, die Arme zu ergreifen, die am Arsenal
und eine Unterseite aufzustellen, um weitere Sklavenaufstände, Braun 
und seine Männer anzuregen und zu unterstützen gespeichert wurden, 
wurden von den VEREINIGTE STAATEN Marinen eingeschlossen, versucht 
für Verrat und gehangen. Southerners sah in Überfall 
des Brauns die heftigen Absichten von northerners, während viele im 
Norden braunen Tod als revolutionärer Märtyrer beklagten. 
Eines Harpers wöchentlicher Künstler skizziertes Braun und 
seine Co-Verschwörer, wie sie mit Verrat und Mord in einem 
Charlestown, Virginia Gerichtssaal aufgeladen wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le brun de John était un abolitionniste dévoué et un 
vétéran de guérilla au Kansas qui a alarmé même des soilers 
libres avec ses affirmations puissantes d'égalité afro-américaine. 
16 octobre 1859 le brun, trois de ses fils, et 19 associés a 
pillé l'arsenal fédéral au bac de Harpers, la Virginie. La 
planification pour saisir des bras a enregistré à l'arsenal et a 
installé une base pour encourager et aider encore d'autres 
insurrections slaves, brun et ses hommes ont été emprisonnés 
par des soldats de marine des ETATS-UNIS, jugés pour la trahison, 
et arrêtés. Les habitants du sud ont vu dans l'incursion du brun 
les intentions violentes de habitants du Nord, alors que beaucoup dans le 
nord pleuraient la mort brune en tant que martyre 
révolutionnaire. Le brun esquissé par artiste hebdomadaire et 
ses Co-conspirateurs d'un Harper comme ils ont été chargés de la 
trahison et du meurtre dans un Charlestown, auditoire de tribunal 
de la Virginie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O marrom de John era um abolitionist staunch e um veteran 
da guerra de guerilla em Kansas que alarmou mesmo soilers livres com 
suas afirmações forceful da igualdade Africano-Americana. 
Outubro em 16, 1859 o marrom, três de seus filhos, e 19 
associados invadiu o arsenal federal na balsa de Harpers, Virgínia. 
Planeando apreender os braços armazenados no arsenal e ajustar 
acima uma base para incentivar e ajudar a uns insurrections slave mais
adicionais, a um marrom e a uns seus homens foram prendidos por 
fuzileiros navais de ESTADOS UNIDOS, tentados para o treason, e 
pendurados. Southerners viu na invasão do marrom as intenções
violentas dos northerners, quando muitos no norte mourned a morte 
marrom como um martyr revolucionário. Marrom esboçado e seus 
co-co-conspirators de um Harper artista semanal como foram carregados 
com o treason e o assassinato em um Charlestown, courtroom de 
Virgínia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il colore marrone del John era un abolitionist staunch e 
un veterano di guerra di guerilla in Kansas che ha allarmato persino i
soilers liberi con le sue asserzioni valide di uguaglianza 
Africano-Americana. Il 16 ottobre, 1859 il colore marrone, tre 
dei suoi figli e 19 soci raided l'arsenale federale al traghetto di 
Harpers, la Virginia. La progettazione grippare l'armi 
ha memorizzato all'arsenale ed ha installato una base per consigliare 
a ed aiutare ulteriori insurrections slave, il colore marrone ed i 
suoi uomini sono stati bloccati dai fanti di marina degli STATI UNITI,
sono stati provati per treason e sono stati appesi. Southerners 
ha visto nell'incursione del colore marrone le intenzioni violente dei
northerners, mentre molti nel nord si sono addolorati la morte marrone
come martyr rivoluzionario. Colore marrone abbozzato artista 
settimanale ed i suoi co-co-conspirators del Harper come sono stati 
caricati di treason e dell'omicidio in un Charlestown, aula di tribunale 
della Virginia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Ιοχν Brown ήταν staunch ρεφορμιστής και 
παλαίμαχος της εχθροπραξίας ανταρτών στο Κάνσας που ανησύχησε 
ακόμη και τα ελεύθερα soilers με τους ισχυρούς ισχυρισμούς 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικής ισότητάς του. Στις 16 Οκτωβρίου
..1859 καφετιά, τρεις γιων του, και 19 συνεταίρων επιτέθηκε 
το ομοσπονδιακό οπλοστάσιο Harpers στο πορθμείο, Βιρτζίνια. 
Προγραμματίζοντας να καταλάβουν τα όπλα που καταχωρήθηκαν 
στο οπλοστάσιο και να οργανώσουν μια βάση για να ενθαρρύνουν και 
να βοηθήσουν τις περαιτέρω εξεγέρσεις σκλάβων, καφετιές και τα 
άτομά του παγιδεύτηκαν από τα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΑ ναυτικά, δοκιμάστηκαν 
για την προδοσία, και κρεμάστηκαν. Οι νότιοι εβλέίδαν
στην καφέ επιδρομή τις βίαιες προθέσεις των βορείων, ενώ πολλοί
στο Βορρά πένθησαν τον καφέ θάνατο ως επαναστατικό μάρτυρα. 
Ο εβδομαδιαίος καλλιτέχνης ενός Harper σκιαγράφησε 
καφετή και τους ομο-συνωμότες του όπως χρεώθηκαν με την προδοσία 
και τη δολοφονία σε ένα Charlestown, δικαστήριο της Βιρτζίνια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El marrón de Juan era un abolitionist firme y un 
veterano de la guerra de guerrillas en Kansas que alarmó incluso 
soilers libres con sus aserciones poderosas de la igualdad 
Africano-Americana. De octubre el 16, 1859 el marrón, tres de 
sus hijos, y 19 asociados atacó el arsenal federal en Harpers 
Balsea, Virginia. Planeando agarrar los brazos salvados
en el arsenal e instalar una base para animar y para asistir a otras 
insurrecciones auxiliares, a marrón y a sus hombres fueron atrapados por
los infantes de marina de ESTADOS UNIDOS, intentados para la 
traición, y colgados. Southerners vio en la incursión del 
marrón las intenciones violentas de northerners, mientras que muchos 
en el norte estuvieron de luto muerte marrón como martyr 
revolucionario. Marrón bosquejado artista semanal y sus 
co-co-conspirators de un Harper como fueron cargados con la 
traición y el asesinato en un Charlestown, sala de tribunal de Virginia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086893</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103335</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-arraignment</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
