<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105156</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105156</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212887</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Tsunami Visualizations</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tsunami Sichtbarmachungen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Visualisations de Tsunami</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Visualizations De Tsunami</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Visualizzazioni Di Tsunami</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Απεικονίσεις Tsunami</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Visualizaciones De Tsunami</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This collection provides a wide array of visual resources and supporting material about the December 26, 2004 Indian Ocean Tsunami. Visualizations include simple animations, satellite photographs, Quicktime animations and tsunami models. The collection also contains visualizations related to other historical tsunamis and additional resources (beyond visualizations) about tsunamis. Resources can be incorporated into lectures, labs, or other activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Ansammlung liefert eine breite Reihe 
Sichtbetriebsmittel und Hilfsmaterial über den Dezember 26, 2004 
indischer Ozean Tsunami. Sichtbarmachungen schließen einfache 
Animationen, Satellitenfotographien, Quicktime Animationen und tsunami
Modelle ein. Die Ansammlung enthält auch die Sichtbarmachungen,
die auf anderen historischen tsunamis und zusätzlichen 
Betriebsmitteln in Verbindung gestanden werden (über 
Sichtbarmachungen hinaus) über tsunamis. Betriebsmittel können
in Vorträge, in Labors oder in andere Aktivitäten enthalten werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette collection fournit une grande sélection de 
ressources et de matériel de support visuels au sujet décembre de 
26, 2004 l'Océan Indien Tsunami. Les visualisations incluent 
des animations simples, des photographies satellites, des animations 
de Quicktime et des modèles de tsunami. La collection contient 
également des visualisations liées à d'autres tsunamis historiques 
et ressources supplémentaires (au delà des visualisations) au sujet 
des tsunamis. Des ressources peuvent être incorporées aux 
conférences, aux laboratoires, ou à d'autres activités.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta coleção fornece uma disposição larga de 
recursos visuais e do material suportando sobre dezembro o 26, 2004 
Oceano Índico Tsunami. Os visualizations incluem animations 
simples, fotografias satellite, animations de Quicktime e modelos do 
tsunami. A coleção contem também os visualizations 
relacionados a outros tsunamis históricos e recursos adicionais 
(além dos visualizations) sobre tsunamis. Os recursos podem ser
incorporados em lectures, em laboratórios, ou em outras atividades.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa accumulazione fornisce una grande selezione
delle risorse e del materiale visivi di sostegno circa 26 dicembre 
2004 Oceano Indiano Tsunami. Le visualizzazioni includono le 
animazioni semplici, le fotografie satelliti, le animazioni di 
Quicktime ed i modelli di tsunami. L'accumulazione egualmente 
contiene le visualizzazioni relative ad altri tsunamis storici e 
risorse supplementari (oltre le visualizzazioni) circa i tsunamis. 
Le risorse possono essere comprese nelle conferenze, nei 
laboratori, o in altre attività.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η συλλογή παρέχει μια ευρεία σειρά οπτικών 
στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς και ενισχυτικού υλικού για τις 26 
Δεκεμβρίου ..2004 Ινδικός Ωκεανός Tsunami. Οι 
απεικονίσεις περιλαμβάνουν τις απλές ζωτικότητες, τις δορυφορικές
φωτογραφίες, τις ζωτικότητες Quicktime και τα μοντέλα 
tsunami. Η συλλογή περιέχει επίσης τις απεικονίσεις 
σχετικές με άλλα ιστορικά tsunamis και πρόσθετα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς (πέρα από τις απεικονίσεις) για τα tsunamis. 
Τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς μπορούν να ενσωματωθούν στις 
διαλέξεις, τα εργαστήρια, ή άλλες δραστηριότητες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta colección proporciona a una amplia gama de 
recursos visuales y del material que utiliza sobre 26 de diciembre 
de 2004 el Océano Índico Tsunami. Las visualizaciones incluyen
animaciones simples, las fotografías basadas en los satélites, las 
animaciones de Quicktime y los modelos del tsunami. La 
colección también contiene las visualizaciones relacionadas con 
otros tsunamis históricos y recursos adicionales (más allá de 
visualizaciones) sobre tsunamis. Los recursos se pueden 
incorporar en conferencias, laboratorios, u otras actividades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JOHN MCDARIS
FN:JOHN MCDARIS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212887</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105156</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/tsunami-visualizations</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
