<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105905</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105905</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087440</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Black Comedy: Racial Controversy at the Richmond Convention</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schwarze Komödie: Rassische Kontroverse an
der Richmond Versammlung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Comédie Noir : Polémique raciale à la 
convention de Richmond</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Comedy Preto: Controvérsia racial na 
convenção de Richmond</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Commedia nera: Polemica razziale alla 
convenzione de Richmond</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαύρη κωμωδία: Φυλετική διαμάχη στη Συνθήκη του
Ρίτσμοντ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comedia Negra: Controversia racial en la 
convención de Richmond</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The annual convention of the Knights of Labor convened in Richmond, Virginia, a region divided by racial and political conflict, on October 4, 1886. In the 1880s, Southern politics was split between southern Democrats who sought to "redeem" the old order and a progressive (and in some places interracial) political movement that sought to extend the gains won by ordinary black and white southerners during the Reconstruction era. As more than one thousand delegates gathered from across the country in the former capital of the Confederacy, the labor and political reform movements hoped the convention would be a launching pad for their message of racial peace and political reform. But the convention and the Knights of Labor were quickly plunged into conflict over the organization's attitude toward the question of social equality between the races. The white citizens of Richmond and elsewhere in the country were fascinated and horrified by repeated reports of "race mixing" in press accounts about the Knights of Labor convention, typified by these three items from the Richmond  Dispatch  of October 6, 1886.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die jährliche Versammlung der Ritter der Arbeit 
kam in Richmond, Virginia, eine Region zusammen, die durch rassische 
und politische $überschneidung, an Oktober 4, 1886 geteilt wurde. 
Im 1880s wurde südliche Politik zwischen südlichen Demokraten 
aufgespaltet, die "zurückkaufen" die alte Ordnung und eine 
progressive (und in einigen Plätzen interracial) politische Bewegung 
suchten, die suchten, die Gewinne auszudehnen, die durch gewöhnliche 
schwarze und weiße southerners während der Rekonstruktionära 
gewonnen wurden. Als mehr als tausend Delegierte erfaßte aus 
über dem Land im ehemaligen Kapital der Konföderation, hofften die 
Arbeits- und politischen Reformbewegungen, daß die Vereinbarung eine 
ausstoßende Auflage für ihre Meldung des rassischen Friedens und der
politischen Verbesserung sein würde. Aber die Versammlung und 
die Ritter der Arbeit wurden schnell in $überschneidung über der 
einstellung der Organisation gegenüber der Frage der Sozialgleichheit
zwischen die Rennen getaucht. Die weißen Bürger von Richmond 
und anderwohin im Land wurden durch wiederholte Reports "des Rennens 
fasziniert und erschrocken, das" in den Pressekonten über die Ritter 
der Arbeitsversammlung mischt, verkörpert worden durch diese drei 
Einzelteile von der Richmond Abfertigung von Oktober 6, 1886.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La convention annuelle des chevaliers du travail 
s'est assemblée à Richmond, la Virginie, une région divisée par 
conflit racial et politique, 4 octobre 1886. Dans le 1880s, la 
politique méridionale a été dédoublée entre les démocrates 
méridionaux qui ont recherché "rachètent" la vieille commande et 
(et dans quelques endroits interracial) un mouvement politique 
progressif qui ont recherché à étendre les gains gagnés par les 
habitants du sud noirs et blancs ordinaires pendant l'ère de 
reconstruction. En tant que plus de mille délégués a 
recueilli de à travers le pays dans l'ancienne capitale de la 
confédération, les mouvements de réforme de travail et politiques 
ont espéré que la convention serait une plate-forme de lancement 
pour leur message de paix raciale et de réforme politique. Mais
la convention et les chevaliers du travail ont été rapidement 
plongés dans le conflit au-dessus de l'attitude de l'organisation 
envers la question de l'égalité sociale entre les courses. Les
citoyens blancs de Richmond et dans le pays ont été fascinés et 
ailleurs horrifiés par des états répétés de la "course se 
mélangeant" dans des comptes de presse au sujet des chevaliers de la 
convention de travail, caractérisés par ces trois éléments de 
l'expédition de Richmond octobre de 6, 1886.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A convenção anual dos knights do trabalho 
reuniu-se em Richmond, Virgínia, uma região dividida pelo conflito 
racial e político, outubro em 4, 1886. No 1880s, a política do
sul foi rachada entre as democratas do sul que procuraram "redeem" a 
ordem velha e (e em alguns lugares interracial) um movimento político
progressivo que procuraram estender os ganhos ganhados por southerners
pretos e brancos ordinários durante a era do reconstruction. 
Como mais de mil delegados recolheu através do país no capital
anterior do confederacy, os movimentos de reforma labor e políticos 
esperaram que a convenção fosse uma almofada se lançando para sua 
mensagem da paz racial e da reforma política. Mas a convenção
e os knights do trabalho foram mergulhados rapidamente no conflito 
sobre a atitude da organização para a pergunta da igualdade social 
entre as raças. Os cidadãos brancos de Richmond e em outra 
parte no país foram fascinados e horrorizados por relatórios 
repetidos da "raça que mistura" em clientes da imprensa sobre os 
knights da convenção labor, typified por estes três artigos da 
expedição de Richmond outubro de 6, 1886.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La convenzione annuale dei cavalieri del 
Lavoro si è riunita a Richmond, la Virginia, una regione divisa 
dal conflitto razziale e politico, il 4 ottobre 1886. in 1880s,
la politica del sud è stata spaccata fra le carbossimetilazioni del 
sud che hanno cercato "riacquistano" il vecchio ordine e (ed in alcuni
posti interracial) un movimento politico progressivo che hanno cercato
di estendere i guadagni vinti dai southerners neri e bianchi ordinari 
durante l'era di ricostruzione. Come più di mille delegati ha 
riunito attraverso dal paese nel capitale precedente del 
confederacy, i movimenti di riforma di lavoro e politici hanno 
sperato che la convenzione fosse un rilievo di lancio per il loro 
messaggio di pace razziale e della riforma politica. Ma la 
convenzione ed i cavalieri del Lavoro sono stati immersi 
rapidamente nel conflitto sopra l'atteggiamento dell'organizzazione 
nei confronti della domanda di uguaglianza sociale fra le corse. 
I cittadini bianchi di Richmond ed altrove nel paese sono stati 
affascinati e sconvolto stati dai rapporti ripetuti "della corsa che 
mescola" nei clienti della pressa circa i cavalieri della convenzione 
Di lavoro, caratterizzati da questi tre articoli dalla spedizione de
Richmond de 6 ottobre 1886.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ετήσια σύμβαση των ιπποτών της εργασίας συγκάλεσε 
στο Ρίτσμοντ, Βιρτζίνια, μια περιοχή που διαιρέθηκε με τη 
φυλετική και πολιτική σύγκρουση, στις 4 Οκτωβρίου, 1886. 
Στο 1880s, η νότια πολιτική χωρίστηκε μεταξύ των νότιων 
δημοκρατών που επιδίωξαν "να εξαγοράσουν" την παλαιά κατάταξη και
μια προοδευτική (και σε μερικές θέσεις διαφυλετικές) πολιτική 
μετακίνηση που επιδίωξαν να επεκτείνουν τα κέρδη που κερδήθηκαν 
από τους συνηθισμένους μαύρους και λευκούς νοτίους κατά τη 
διάρκεια της εποχής αναδημιουργίας. Σαν περισσότερους του 
ενός χίλιοι εκπρόσωποι που μαζεύτηκαν από σε ολόκληρη τη χώρα 
στο προηγούμενο κεφάλαιο της συνομοσπονδίας, της εργασίας και των 
πολιτικών κινημάτων μεταρρύθμισης ήλπισαν ότι η σύμβαση θα ήταν
ένα μαξιλάρι προώθησης για το μήνυμά τους φυλετικής ειρήνης και
πολιτικής μεταρρύθμισης. Αλλά η σύμβαση και οι ιππότες της 
εργασίας βυθίστηκαν γρήγορα στη σύγκρουση πέρα από τη στάση της
οργάνωσης απέναντι στο θέμα της κοινωνικής ισότητας μεταξύ των 
φυλών. Οι λευκοί πολίτες του Ρίτσμοντ και αλλού στη χώρα 
ήταν συναρπασμένοι και τρομαγμένοι από τις επαναλαμβανόμενες 
εκθέσεις "της φυλής αναμιγνύοντασ" στους απολογισμούς Τύπου για 
τους ιππότες της σύμβασης εργασίας, που απεικονίστηκαν από αυτά 
τα τρία αντικείμενα από την αποστολή του Ρίτσμοντ της 6ης 
Οκτωβρίου, 1886.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La convención anual de los caballeros del 
trabajo convocó en Richmond, Virginia, una región dividida por 
conflicto racial y político, 4 de octubre de 1886. En el 
1880s, la política meridional estuvo partida entre los demócratas 
meridionales que buscaron "redimen" la vieja orden y (y en algunos 
lugares interracial) un movimiento político progresivo que intentaron
ampliar los aumentos ganados por southerners negros y blancos 
ordinarios durante la era de la reconstrucción. Como más de 
mil delegados recolectó a través del país en el capital anterior 
del confederacy, los movimientos de reforma de trabajo y políticos 
esperaban que la convención fuera una plataforma de lanzamiento para 
su mensaje de la paz racial y de la reforma política. Pero 
hundieron a la convención y a los caballeros del trabajo rápidamente
en conflicto sobre la actitud de la organización hacia la cuestión 
de la igualdad social entre las razas. Informes relanzados de la
"raza fascinaron y fueron horrorizados a los ciudadanos blancos de 
Richmond y a otra parte en el país que se mezclaba" en cuentas de la 
prensa sobre los caballeros de la convención de trabajo, 
caracterizados por estos tres items del envío de Richmond del de 
octubre 6 de 1886.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087440</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105905</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/black-comedy-racial-controversy-at-the-richmond-convention</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
