<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107779</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107779</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086170</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Former Slave Elizabeth Keckley and the "Contraband" of Washington DC, 1862.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ehemaliges Sklavenelizabeth Keckley und die 
"Schmuggelware" von Washington Gleichstrom, 1862.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ancien Elizabeth Slave Keckley et la 
"contrebande" de DC de Washington, 1862.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Elizabeth slave anterior Keckley e o "contraband" 
de C.C. de Washington, 1862.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Elizabeth slave precedente Keckley e "il 
contrabbando" di DC di Washington, 1862.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προηγούμενος σκλάβος Elizabeth Keckley και η 
"παράνομη διακίνηση" της Ουάσιγκτον DC, 1862.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Elizabeth auxiliar anterior Keckley y el 
"contrabando" de C.C. de Washington, 1862.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Elizabeth Hobbs Keckley was born in slavery in Virginia around 1818 and purchased her freedom in 1855. In 1862 she was living in Washington DC and working as a skilled dressmaker; her principal client was Mary Todd Lincoln, wife of the president. Keckley sympathized with the former slaves, or "contraband," as they were called, who fled to the relative safety of Washington during the Civil War. The Contraband Relief Association, which Keckley founded and headed, gathered funds and clothing for the poor former slaves. Yet, as her rather condescending remarks make clear, Keckley felt superior to the people she helped. Keckley's memoir  Behind the Scenes  was published in 1868. The book included revelations about Mary Lincoln's private life, and, feeling betrayed, the former First Lady shunned Keckley. Her dressmaking business declined, and she died in poverty in 1907 at the Home for Destitute Women and Children in Washington, one of the institutions she had helped to found.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Elizabeth Hobbs Keckley wurde in der Sklaverei in Virginia
um 1818 getragen und ihre Freiheit 1855 kaufte. 1862 lebte sie 
in Washington Gleichstrom und arbeitete als erfahrene 
Damenschneiderin; ihr allgemeiner Klient war Mary Todd Lincoln, 
Frau des Präsidenten. Keckley sympathisierte mit den 
ehemaligen Sklaven oder "Schmuggelware,", während sie angerufen 
wurden, die zur relativen Sicherheit von Washington während des 
Bürgerkrieges flohen. Die Schmuggelentlastung Verbindung, die 
Keckley gründete und vorangeht, erfaßte Kapital und Kleidung für 
die schlechten ehemaligen Sklaven. Jedoch als sie bilden eher 
herablassende Anmerkungen klar, Keckley fühlten überlegen den 
Leuten, half sie. Abhandlung Keckleys hinter den Szenen wurde 
1868 veröffentlicht. Die Buch eingeschlossenen Enthüllung 
über Mary Lincolns die private Lebensdauer und, glaubend verrieten, 
das ehemalige erste Dame gemiedene Keckley. Ihr dressmaking 
Geschäft sank und sie starb in der Armut 1907 am Haus für hilflose 
Frauen und Kinder in Washington, eine der Anstalten, die sie zu 
gefunden geholfen hatte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Elizabeth Hobbs Keckley a été soutenu dans 
l'esclavage en Virginie autour de 1818 et a acheté sa liberté en 
1855. En 1862 elle vivait dans DC de Washington et travaillait 
en tant que couturière habile ; sa cliente principale était 
Mary Todd Lincoln, épouse du président. Keckley a sympathisé 
avec les anciens esclaves, ou la "contrebande," pendant qu'ils 
s'appelaient, qui se sont sauvés à la sûreté relative de 
Washington pendant la guerre civile. L'association de 
soulagement de contrebande, que Keckley a fondée et dirige, a 
recueilli les fonds et l'habillement pour les anciens esclaves 
pauvres. Cependant, en tant qu'elle les remarques 
condescendantes plutôt font clairement, Keckley se sont senties 
supérieures au peuple elle a aidé. Le mémoire de Keckley dans
les coulisses a été édité en 1868. Par livre les 
révélations incluses au sujet de la vie privée de Mary Lincoln, et,
se sentant ont trahi, le Keckley évité l'ancienne première par 
Madame. Ses affaires de couture ont diminué, et elle est 
morte dans la pauvreté en 1907 à la maison pour les femmes et les 
enfants indigents à Washington, un des établissements qu'elle avait 
aidés à trouvé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Elizabeth Hobbs Keckley foi carregado no slavery em 
Virgínia em torno de 1818 e comprou sua liberdade em 1855. Em 
1862 estava vivendo na C.C. de Washington e estava trabalhando como 
uma costureira hábil; seu cliente principal era Mary Todd 
Lincoln, esposa do presidente. Keckley sympathized com os 
escravos anteriores, ou o "contraband," enquanto foram chamados, que 
fujiram à segurança relativa de Washington durante a guerra civil. 
A associação do relevo do contraband, que Keckley fundou e 
dirige, recolheu fundos e roupa para os escravos anteriores 
deficientes. Ainda, como ela as observações rather 
condescending fazem claramente, Keckley sentiram superiores aos povos 
ajudou. O memoir de Keckley atrás das cenas foi publicado em 
1868. Livro os revelations incluídos primeira senhora anterior 
o Keckley shunned sobre a vida confidencial de Mary Lincoln, e, 
sentindo betrayed. Seu negócio dressmaking declinou, e morreu 
na pobreza em 1907 na HOME para mulheres e crianças destitute em 
Washington, uma das instituições que tinha ajudado ao encontrado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Elizabeth Hobbs Keckley è stato sopportato nello slavery 
nella Virginia verso 1818 ed ha comprato la sua libertà in 1855. 
In 1862 stava vivendo in DC di Washington e stava lavorando come
in sarto da donna esperto; il suo cliente principale era Mary 
Todd Lincoln, moglie del presidente. Keckley sympathized con gli
schiavi precedenti, o "il contrabbando," mentre sono stati chiamati, 
che sono fuggito alla sicurezza relativa di Washington durante la 
guerra civile. L'associazione di rilievo del contrabbando, che 
Keckley ha fondato e dirige, ha riunito i fondi monetari ed 
i vestiti per i poveri schiavi precedenti. Tuttavia, come 
lei le osservazioni piuttosto condescending fanno chiaramente, Keckley
hanno ritenuto superiori alla gente ha aiutato. La memoria del 
Keckley dietro le scene è stata pubblicata in 1868. Il libro ha
incluso le rivelazioni circa vita riservata della Mary Lincoln e, 
ritenente denunciata, l'ex prima signora ha evitato Keckley. Il 
suo commercio dressmaking ha declinato ed è morto nella povertà in 
1907 a casa per le donne ed i bambini indigenti a Washington, una 
delle istituzioni che aveva aiutato all'trovato a.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Εληζαψετχ Hobbs Keckley γεννήθηκε στη σκλαβιά 
στη Βιρτζίνια περίπου 1818 και αγόρασε την ελευθερία της το 
1855. Το 1862 ζούσε στην Ουάσιγκτον DC και εργαζόταν
ως ειδικευμένη μοδίστρα  ο κύριος χρήστης της ήταν Mary 
todd Λίνκολν, σύζυγος του Προέδρου. Το Keckley 
συμμερίστηκε τους προηγούμενους σκλάβους, ή "την παράνομη 
διακίνηση," καθώς κλήθηκαν, οι οποίοι τρεπόμενος σε φυγή στη 
σχετική ασφάλεια της Ουάσιγκτον κατά τη διάρκεια του εμφύλιου 
πολέμου. Η ένωση ανακούφισης παράνομης διακίνησης, που 
Keckley ίδρυσε και διεύθυνε, σύλλεξε τα κεφάλαια και τον 
ιματισμό για τους φτωχούς προηγούμενους σκλάβους. Ακόμα, 
δεδομένου ότι οι μάλλον condescending παρατηρήσεις της 
καθιστούν σαφές, Keckley αισθητό ανώτερο από τους ανθρώπους 
βοήθησε. Τα απομνημονεύματα του Keckley πίσω από τις 
σκηνές δημοσιεύθηκαν το 1868. Το βιβλίο περιέλαβε τις 
αποκαλύψεις για την ιδιωτική ζωή Mary Λίνκολν, και, το αίσθημα
που προδόθηκε, η προηγούμενη πρώτη κυρία απέφυγε Keckley. 
Dressmaking της η επιχείρηση μειώθηκε, και πέθανε στην 
ένδεια το 1907 στη "Οικία" για τις άπορα γυναίκες και τα 
παιδιά στην Ουάσιγκτον, ένα από τα όργανα που είχε 
βοηθήσει βριαλμένος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Elizabeth Hobbs Keckley fue llevado en esclavitud en 
Virginia alrededor de 1818 y compró su libertad en 1855. En 
1862 ella vivía en la C.C. de Washington y trabajaba como modista 
experta; su cliente principal era Maria Todd Lincoln, esposa del
presidente. Keckley se compadeció de los esclavos anteriores, o
del "contrabando," mientras que les llamaron, que huyeron a la 
seguridad relativa de Washington durante la guerra civil. La 
asociación de la relevación del contrabando, que Keckley fundó y 
dirigió, recolectó fondos y la ropa para los esclavos anteriores 
pobres. Todavía, como ella las observaciones algo condescending
hacen claramente, Keckley se sentían superiores a la gente ella 
ayudó. La memoria de Keckley detrás de las escenas fue 
publicada en 1868. Libro las revelaciones incluidas primera el 
Keckley evitado señora anterior sobre la vida privada de Maria 
Lincoln, y, sintiéndose traicionaron. Su negocio dressmaking 
declinó, y ella murió en pobreza en 1907 en el hogar para las 
mujeres y los niños indigentes en Washington, una de las 
instituciones que ella había ayudado a encontrado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086170</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107779</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/former-slave-elizabeth-keckley-and-the-contraband-of-washington-dc-1862</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
