<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105686</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105686</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206894</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lessons of Liberty</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Lektionen der Freiheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Leçons de la liberté</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Lições da liberdade</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lezioni di libertà</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθήματα της ελευθερίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Lecciones de la libertad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Encourages schools to invite veterans into classrooms before and after Veterans Day, to share their experiences. The website for this initiative, announced by President Bush suggests activities that schools and communities can use to observe Veterans Day. It also offers a Teacher's Guide that includes statistics on America's wars, guidelines on how to display the flag, a history of Veterans Day, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Regt Schulen an, Veterane in Klassenzimmer 
Veteran-Tag vorher und nachher einzuladen, ihre Erfahrungen zu teilen.
Die Web site für diese Initiative, verkündet vom Präsidenten 
Bush schlägt Aktivitäten vor, die Schulen und Gemeinschaften 
verwenden können, um Veteran-Tag zu beobachten. Sie bietet auch
die Anleitung eines Lehrers, die Statistiken über Kriege Amerikas, 
Richtlinien einschließt über, wie man die Markierungsfahne, eine 
Geschichte des Veteran-Tages anzeigt, und mehr an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Encourage des écoles à inviter des vétérans 
dans le jour de vétérans de salles de classe avant et après, à 
partager leurs expériences. Le site Web pour cette initiative, 
annoncé par le Président Bush suggère les activités que les 
écoles et les communautés peuvent employer pour observer le jour de 
vétérans. Il offre également le guide d'un professeur qui 
inclut des statistiques sur les guerres de l'Amérique, directives sur
la façon dont afficher l'indicateur, une histoire de jour de 
vétérans, et plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Incentiva escolas convidar before.and.after 
veterans no dia dos veterans das salas de aula, compartilhar de suas 
experiências. O Web site para esta iniciativa, anunciado pelo 
presidente Bush sugere as atividades que as escolas e as comunidades 
podem usar observar o dia dos veterans. Oferece também a guia 
de um professor que inclui statistics nas guerras de América, 
guidelines em como indicar a bandeira, um history do dia dos veterans,
e o mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Consiglia alle scuole invitare i veterani nel 
giorno dei veterani delle aule prima e dopo, a ripartire le loro 
esperienze. Il Web site per questa iniziativa, annunciato dal 
presidente Bush suggerisce le attività che le scuole e le Comunità 
possono usare per osservare il giorno dei veterani. Egualmente 
offre la guida dell'insegnante che include le statistiche sulle guerre
dell'America, guida di riferimento su come visualizzare la bandierina,
una storia del giorno dei veterani e più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενθαρρύνει τα σχολεία για να προσκαλέσει τους 
παλαιμάχους στις τάξεις πριν και μετά από την ημέρα παλαιμάχων, 
για να μοιραστούν την εμπειρία τους. Ο ιστοχώρος για αυτήν 
την πρωτοβουλία, που αναγγέλλεται από τον Πρόεδρο Bush 
προτείνει τις δραστηριότητες που τα σχολεία και οι κοινότητες 
μπορούν να χρησιμοποιήσουν για να παρατηρήσουν την ημέρα 
παλαιμάχων. Προσφέρει επίσης τον οδηγό ενός δασκάλου που 
περιλαμβάνει τις στατιστικές όσον αφορά τους πολέμους της 
Αμερικής, οδηγίες στο πώς να παρουσιάσει τη σημαία, μια ιστορία 
της ημέρας παλαιμάχων, και περισσότεροι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Anima a escuelas inviten a veteranos en día de 
los veteranos de las salas de clase antes y después, que compartan 
sus experiencias. El Web site para esta iniciativa, anunciado 
por presidente Bush sugiere las actividades que las escuelas y las 
comunidades pueden utilizar para observar día de los veteranos. 
También ofrece la guía de un profesor que incluye estadística
sobre las guerras de América, guías de consulta en cómo visualizar 
el indicador, una historia del día de los veteranos, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206894</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105686</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lessons-of-liberty</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
