<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106817</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106817</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085246</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Dust Bowl Migration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Trockengebiet-Migration</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Transfert de Cuvette de Poussière</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Migração Da Bacia De Poeira</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Espansione Della Ciotola Di Polvere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετανάστευση κύπελλων σκόνης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Migración Del Tazón de fuente De Polvo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1931, a severe drought hit the Southern and Midwestern plains. As crops died and winds picked up, dust storms began. As the "Dust Bowl" photograph shows, crops literally blew away in "black blizzards" as years of poor farming practices and over-cultivation combined with the lack of rain. By 1934, 75% of the United States was severely affected by this terrible drought.The one-two punch of economic depression and bad weather put many farmers out of business. In the early 1930s, thousands of Dust Bowl refugees ? mainly from Oklahoma, Texas, Colorado, Kansas, and New Mexico ? packed up their families and migrated west, hoping to find work. Entire families migrated together (such as the men shown in "Three generations of Texans now Drought Refugees") in search of a better life. Images such as "Midcontinent ? Family Standing on the Road with Car," "Drought Refugees," and "Untitled, ca. 1935 (Worn-Down Family in Front of Tent)" offer a glimpse into their experience on the road, and show that cars provided many families both transportation and shelter on the road. About 200,000 of the migrants headed for California. The state needed to figure out how to absorb the thousands of destitute people crossing its borders daily. One of their tactics was to document the plight of the refugees. In 1935, photographer Dorothea Lange joined the Rural Rehabilitation Division of the California State Emergency Relief Administration (SERA), a section of the Federal Emergency Relief Administration. She was assigned the job of using her camera to document the growing number of homeless Dust Bowl refugees migrating to California. She worked with Paul S. Taylor, a professor at the University of California, Berkeley, who was researching conditions of rural poverty in order to make recommendations on how to improve the workers' conditions. The work by Taylor and Lange played an important role in helping to raise public awareness of the crisis. The reports they made for the government included both data and striking images that revealed the desperate conditions in which the migrants lived and confirmed the need for government intervention. Stark images such as "Home of Oklahoma Drought Refugees" resonated with the public, and portraits of drought refugees like "Ruby from Arkansas" and others shown in this topic humanized the migrants for more fortunate citizens. In March 1936, Lange took what became one of her most famous images, "Migrant Mother." This image of a 32-year-old woman became an icon for the suffering of ordinary people during Great Depression.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1931 schlug eine strenge Dürre die südlichen und
des mittleren Westensebenen. Während Getreide und die Winde 
starben, die aufgehoben wurden, fingen Staubstürme an. Da die 
"Trockengebiet" Fotographie darstellt, brannten Getreide buchstäblich
weg "in den schwarzen Blizzarden" als Jahre der schlechten Praxis und 
der über-Bearbeitung durch, die mit dem Mangel an Regen kombiniert 
wurde. Bis zum 1934 wurde 75% der vereinigten Zustände streng 
durch diesen schrecklichen drought.The one-two Locher der 
Wirtschaftskrise beeinflußt und falsches Wetter setzte viele 
Landwirte heraus des Geschäfts. In den frühen dreißiger 
Jahren Tausenden Trockengebietflüchtlinge? hauptsächlich von 
Oklahoma, von Texas, von Kolorado, von Kansas und von New-Mexico? 
gepackt herauf ihre Familien und fortgezogenes West, hoffend, 
Arbeit zu finden. Gesamte Familien zogen zusammen (wie die 
Männer jetzt gezeigt in "drei Erzeugungen Texans der 
Dürre-Flüchtlinge") auf der Suche nach einer besseren Lebensdauer 
fort. Bilder wie "Midcontinent? Familie, die auf der 
Straße mit Auto, "" Dürre-Flüchtlinge, "und" Untitled, Ca steht. 
1935 (Abgenutzte-Unten Familie vor Zelt)"Angebot ein Blick in 
ihre Erfahrung auf der Straße und zeigen, daß Autos viele Familien 
Transport und Schutz auf der Straße zur Verfügung stellten. 
Ungefähr 200.000 der Wanderer gehen für Kalifornien voran. 
Der Zustand mußte aus, wie man darstellen die Tausenden der 
hilflosen Leute aufsaugt, die täglich seine Ränder kreuzen. 
Eine ihrer Taktiken sollte die Lage der Flüchtlinge 
dokumentieren. 1935 verband Photograph Dorothea Lange die 
landwirtschaftliche Rehabilitation-Abteilung der Kalifornien 
Zustand-Dringlichkeitsentlastung Leitung (SEREN), ein Kapitel der 
Bundesdringlichkeitsentlastung Leitung. Sie wurde den Job des 
Verwendens ihrer Kamera, um die wachsende Zahl den heimatlosen 
Trockengebietflüchtlingen zu dokumentieren zugewiesen, die zu 
Kalifornien fortziehen. Sie arbeitete mit Paul S. Taylor, ein 
Professor an der Universität von Kalifornien, Berkeley, das Zustände
der landwirtschaftlichen Armut erforschte, um Empfehlungen auf, wie 
man zu bilden die Zustände der Arbeiter verbessert. Die Arbeit 
durch Taylor und Lange spielte eine wichtige Rolle beim Helfen, 
allgemeines Bewußtsein der Krise aufzuwerfen. Die Reports, die 
sie für die Regierung bildeten, schlossen beide Daten und 
auffallenden Bilder ein, die die hoffnungslosen Bedingungen 
aufdeckten, in denen die Wanderer die Notwendigkeit an der Regierung 
Intervention lebten und bestätigten. Steife Bilder wie "Haus 
der Oklahoma Dürre-Flüchtlinge", die mit der Öffentlichkeit und den
Portraits der Dürreflüchtlinge wie "Rubin von Arkansas" und der 
anderer gezeigt wurden in diesem Thema mitgeschwungen wurden, 
vermenschlichten die Wanderer für glücklichere Bürger. Im 
März 1936, nahm Lange was eins ihrer berühmtesten Bilder wurde, 
"Wander- Mutter." Dieses Bild einer Frau 32-year-old wurde eine 
Ikone für den Suffering der normalen Leute während des großen 
Tiefstands.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1931, une période de sécheresse grave a 
frappé les plaines méridionales et du milieu du middle-ouest. 
Car les collectes sont mortes et des vents pris, la poussière 
donne l'assaut à a commencé. Car la photographie "de cuvette de
poussière" montre, les collectes ont littéralement soufflé loin 
dans "les tempêtes de neige noires" comme années des pratiques 
agricoles faibles et de l'au-dessus-culture combinées avec le manque 
de pluie. D'ici 1934, 75% des Etats-Unis a été sévèrement 
affecté par ce perforateur terrible d'one-two de drought.The de 
dépression économique et le mauvais survivent à a mis beaucoup 
de fermiers hors des affaires. Au début des années 30, 
milliers de réfugiés de cuvette de poussière ? principalement
l'Oklahoma, le Texas, le Colorado, le Kansas, et du Nouveau-Mexique ? 
emballé vers le haut de leurs familles et occidental passé, 
espérant trouver le travail. Les familles entières ont passé 
ensemble (comme les hommes montrés dans "trois générations des 
réfugiés de sécheresse de Texans maintenant") à la recherche
d'une meilleure vie. Images telles que "Midcontinent ? 
Famille se tenant sur la route avec la voiture, "" réfugiés de
sécheresse, "et" Untitled, ca. 1935 (famille Usée-Vers le bas 
devant la tente)"offres un aperçu dans leur expérience sur la route,
et prouvent que les voitures ont fourni le transport et l'abri de 
beaucoup de familles sur la route. Environ 200.000 des migrants 
se dirigent pour la Californie. L'état a dû figurer hors de la
façon absorber les milliers de personnes indigentes franchissant ses 
frontières quotidiennement. Un de leur tactique devait 
documenter la situation difficile des réfugiés. En 1935, le 
photographe Dorothea Lange a joint la Division rurale de réadaptation
de la gestion de soulagement de secours d'état de la Californie 
(SÉRUMS), une section de la gestion fédérale de soulagement de 
secours. Elle a été assignée le travail d'employer son 
appareil-photo pour documenter le nombre de plus en plus important des
réfugiés sans foyer de cuvette de poussière passant à la 
Californie. Elle a travaillé avec Paul S. Taylor, un professeur
à l'université de la Californie, Berkeley, qui recherchait des 
états de la pauvreté rurale afin de faire des recommandations 
concernant la façon améliorer les conditions des ouvriers. Le 
travail à côté de Taylor et de Lange a joué un rôle important en 
aidant à soulever la conscience publique de la crise. Les 
états qu'ils ont rédigés pour le gouvernement ont inclus les deux 
données et images saisissantes qui ont indiqué les conditions 
désespérées en lesquelles les migrants ont vécu et ont confirmé 
le besoin d'intervention de gouvernement. Les images rigides 
telles que la "maison des réfugiés de sécheresse de l'Oklahoma" 
résonnés avec le public, et des verticales des réfugiés de 
sécheresse comme le "rubis d'Arkansas" et de d'autres montrés dans 
ce sujet ont humanisé les migrants pour des citoyens plus chanceux. 
En mars 1936, Lange a pris ce qui est devenu l'une de ses images
plus célèbres, "la mère migratrice." Cette image d'une femme 
32-year-old est devenue un graphisme pour la douleur des gens du 
commun pendant la grande dépression.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1931, uma seca severa bateu as planícies do 
sul e midwestern. Enquanto as colheitas morreram e os ventos 
escolhidos acima, as tempestades de poeira começaram. Porque de
"a fotografia da bacia poeira" mostra, as colheitas fundiram 
literalmente afastado "em blizzards pretos" como anos de práticas 
cultivando deficientes e do sobre-over-cultivation combinados com a 
falta da chuva. Por 1934, 75% dos estados unidos foi afetado 
severamente por este perfurador terrível do one-two de drought.The do
depression econômico e o tempo mau pôs muitos fazendeiros fora do 
negócio. Nos 1930s adiantados, milhares de refugees da bacia de
poeira? principalmente de Oklahoma, de Texas, de Colorado, de 
Kansas, e de Novo México? embalado acima de do suas famílias e
ocidental migrado, esperando encontrar o trabalho. As famílias 
inteiras migraram junto (como os homens mostrados em "três gerações
de refugees da seca de Texans agora") na busca de uma vida melhor. 
Imagens tais como "Midcontinent? Família que está na 
estrada com carro, "" refugees da seca, "e" Untitled, ca. 1935 
(família Gasta-Para baixo na frente da barraca)"ofertas um glimpse em
sua experiência na estrada, e mostram que os carros forneceram o 
transporte e o abrigo de muitas famílias  na estrada. 
Aproximadamente 200.000 dos emigrantes dirigem para Califórnia.
O estado necessitou figurar para fora de como absorver os 
milhares dos povos destitute que cruzam suas beiras diariamente. 
Uma de suas táticas devia documentar o plight dos refugees. 
Em 1935, o fotógrafo Dorothea Lange juntou a divisão rural da 
reabilitação da administração do relevo da emergência do estado 
de Califórnia (SERA), uma seção da administração federal do 
relevo da emergência. Ela foi atribuída o trabalho de usar sua
câmera documentar o número de crescimento dos refugees desabrigados 
da bacia de poeira que migram a Califórnia. Trabalhou com Paul 
S. Alfaiate, um professor na universidade de Califórnia, Berkeley, 
que pesquisava condições da pobreza rural a fim fazer 
recomendações em como melhorar as condições dos trabalhadores. 
O trabalho por Alfaiate e por Lange jogou um papel importante na
ajuda levantar a consciência pública da crise. Os relatórios 
que fizeram para o governo incluíram ambos os dados e imagens 
impressionantes que revelaram as circunstâncias desesperadas em que 
os emigrantes viveram e confirmaram a necessidade para a intervenção
do governo. As imagens stark tais como a "HOME dos refugees da 
seca de Oklahoma" resonated com o público, e os retratos de refugees 
da seca como o "ruby de Arkansas" e de outros mostrados neste tópico 
humanized os emigrantes para uns cidadãos mais afortunados. Em 
março 1936, Lange fêz exame o que se transformou uma de suas imagens
mais famosas, "da matriz emigrante." Esta imagem de uma mulher 
32-year-old transformou-se um ícone para o sofrimento de povos 
ordinários durante o depression grande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1931, una carestia severa ha colpito le pianure
del sud e midwestern. Mentre i raccolti sono morto e venti 
presi, le tempeste di polvere hanno cominciato. Poichè "la 
fotografia della ciotola di polvere" mostra, i raccolti hanno saltato 
letteralmente via "nei blizzards neri" come anni di povere 
pratiche agricole e di sopra-coltura unite con la mancanza di pioggia.
Entro 1934, 75% del unito Dichiara severamente è stato 
influenzato da questo punzone terribile di one-two di drought.The 
della depressione economica ed il maltempo ha messo molti coltivatori 
dal commercio. Nell'inizio degli anni 30, migliaia dei rifugiati
della ciotola di polvere? pricipalmente da Oklahoma, dal Texas, 
da Colorado, da Kansas e dal Nuovo Messico? imballato sulle sul 
loro famiglie ed ad ovest migrato, sperando di trovare lavoro. 
Le intere famiglie hanno migrato insieme (quali gli uomini ora 
indicati in "tre generazioni dei rifugiati di siccità di Texans") 
alla ricerca di una vita migliore. Immagini quale "Midcontinent?
Famiglia che si leva in piedi sulla strada con l'automobile, "" 
rifugiati di siccità, "e" Untitled, ca. 1935 (famiglia 
Consumata-Giù davanti la tenda)"offerte un glimpse nella loro 
esperienza sulla strada ed indicano che gli automobili hanno fornito 
il trasporto che il riparo di molte famiglie sia sulla strada. 
Circa 200.000 dei migranti dirigono per la California. Il 
dichiarare ha dovuto calcolare verso l'esterno come assorbire i 
migliaia della gente indigente che attraversa giornalmente i relativi 
bordi. Una delle loro tattiche doveva documentare la situazione 
difficile dei rifugiati. In 1935, il photographer Dorothea Lange
ha fatto parte della divisione rurale di riabilitazione della 
California Dichiara la gestione di rilievo di emergenza 
(SIERI), una sezione della gestione federale di rilievo di emergenza. 
Lei è stata assegnata il lavoro di usando la sua macchina 
fotografica per documentare il numero crescere di rifugiati senza casa
della ciotola di polvere che migrano alla California. Ha 
lavorato con Paul S. Taylor, un professore all'università di 
California, Berkeley, che stava ricercando gli stati di povertà 
rurale per fare le raccomandazioni su come migliorare gli stati degli 
operai. Il lavoro da Taylor e da Lange ha svolto un ruolo 
importante nel contribuire a sollevare la consapevolezza del pubblico 
della crisi. I rapporti che hanno stendere per il governo hanno 
incluso entrambi i dati ed immagini notevoli che hanno rivelato le 
circostanze disperate in cui i migranti hanno vissuto e confermato 
l'esigenza di intervento di governo. Le immagini rigide quale 
"la sede dei rifugiati di siccità dell'Oklahoma" risuonati con il 
pubblico ed i ritratti dei rifugiati di siccità come "il rubino 
dall'Arkansas" e di altri indicati in questo soggetto umanizzato i 
migranti per i cittadini più fortunati. Nel mese di marzo del 
1936, Lange ha preso che cosa si è transformato in in una delle sue 
immagini più famose, "la madre migratore." Questa immagine di 
una donna 32-year-old si è transformata in in un'icona per il 
suffering della gente ordinaria durante la depressione grande.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1931, μια αυστηρή ξηρασία χτύπησε τις νότιες και
midwestern πεδιάδες. Δεδομένου ότι οι συγκομιδές πέθαναν
και άνεμοι που πάρθηκαν, οι θύελλες σκόνης άρχισαν. Όπως η
φωτογραφία "κύπελλων σκόνησ" εμφανίζει, οι συγκομιδές φύσηξαν 
κυριολεκτικά μακριά στις "μαύρες χιονοθύελλεσ" ως έτη φτωχών 
πρακτικών καλλιέργειας και πέρα από-καλλιέργειας που 
συνδυάστηκαν με την έλλειψη βροχής. Μέχρι το 1934, 75%
των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών σοβαρά έχω επιπτώσεις από αυτήν την 
φοβερή ξηρασία Η διάτρηση ένας-δύο της οικονομικής ύφεσης
και η κακοκαιρία βάζουν πολλούς αγρότες από την επιχείρηση. 
Στις αρχές της δεκαετίας του '30, χιλιάδες πρόσφυγες 
κύπελλων σκόνης; κυρίως από την Οκλαχόμα, το Τέξας, το 
Κολοράντο, το Κάνσας, και το New Mexico; συσκευασμένος 
επάνω τις οικογένειες και τη μεταναστευμένη δύση τους, που 
ελπίζουν να βρεί την εργασία. Οι ολόκληρες οικογένειες 
μετανάστευσαν μαζί (όπως τα άτομα που εμφανίζονται σε "τρεις 
γενεές τώρα των προσφύγων ξηρασίας Texans") σε αναζήτηση μιας 
καλύτερης ζωής. Εικόνες όπως "Midcontinent; Η 
οικογένεια που στέκεται στο δρόμο με το αυτοκίνητο, "" πρόσφυγες 
ξηρασίας, "και" άτιτλος, περίπου το 1935 (φορώ-κατεβάστε την 
οικογένεια μπροστά από τη σκηνή)"προσφέρει μια αναλαμπή στην 
εμπειρία τους στο δρόμο, και δείχνει ότι τα αυτοκίνητα παρείχαν 
πολλή οικογενειακά και μεταφορά και το καταφύγιο στο δρόμο. 
Περίπου 200.000 των μεταναστών διεύθυναν για Καλιφόρνια. 
Το κράτος έπρεπε να υπολογίσει πώς να απορροφήσει χιλιάδες
άποροι άνθρωποι που διασχίζουν τα σύνορά του καθημερινά. 
Μια από την τακτική τους ήταν να τεκμηριωθεί η δύσκολη 
θέση των προσφύγων. Το 1935, ο φωτογράφος Dorothea 
Lange προσχώρησε στο αγροτικό τμήμα αποκατάστασης της 
διοίκησης ανακούφισης κρατικής έκτακτης ανάγκης Καλιφόρνιας 
(ΟΡΟΙ), ένα τμήμα της ομοσπονδιακής διοίκησης ανακούφισης 
έκτακτης ανάγκης. Της ανατέθηκε η εργασία της 
χρησιμοποίησης της φωτογραφικής μηχανής της για να τεκμηριώσει τον
αυξανόμενο αριθμό άστεγων προσφύγων κύπελλων σκόνης που 
μεταναστεύουν σε Καλιφόρνια. Συνεργάστηκε με Paul S. 
Taylor, ένας καθηγητής στο πανεπιστήμιο Καλιφόρνιας, 
Μπέρκλεϋ, το οποίο ερευνούσε τους όρους της αγροτικής ένδειας 
προκειμένου να υποβληθούν συστάσεις σχετικά με το πώς να 
βελτιώσει τους όρους των εργαζομένων. Η εργασία με taylor
και Lange διαδραμάτισε έναν σημαντικό ρόλο στη βοήθεια να 
βελτιωθεί η δημόσια πληροφόρηση της κρίσης. Οι εκθέσεις 
έκαναν για τα συμπεριλαμβανόμενα κυβέρνηση και στοιχεία και για 
τις εντυπωσιακές εικόνες που αποκάλυψαν τους απελπισμένους όρους 
στους οποίους οι μετανάστες έζησαν και επιβεβαίωσαν την ανάγκη 
για την κυβερνητική επέμβαση. Οι άκαμπτες εικόνες όπως 
"η"Οικία"των προσφύγων ξηρασίας της Οκλαχόμα" αντήχησαν με το 
κοινό, και τα πορτρέτα των προσφύγων ξηρασίας όπως "το ρουμπίνι 
από το Αρκάνσασ" και άλλοι που εμφανίστηκαν σε αυτό το θέμα 
εξανθρώπισαν τους μετανάστες για τους πιό τυχερούς πολίτες. 
Τον Μάρτιο του 1936, Lange πήρε αυτό που έγινε μια 
από τις διασημότερες εικόνες της, "αποδημητική μητέρα." 
Αυτή η εικόνα μιας 32-χρονών γυναίκας έγινε ένα 
εικονίδιο για το βάσανο των απλών ανθρώπων κατά τη διάρκεια της 
μεγάλης οικονομικής κρίσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1931, una sequía severa golpeó los llanos 
meridionales y midwestern. Mientras que las cosechas murieron y 
los vientos tomados , las tormentas de polvo comenzaron. Pues 
"la fotografía del tazón de fuente de polvo" muestra, las cosechas 
soplaron literalmente lejos en "ventiscas negras" como años de 
prácticas agrícolas pobres y de la sobre-cultivacio'n combinadas con
la carencia de la lluvia. Antes de 1934, el 75% de los Estados 
Unidos fueron afectados seriamente por este sacador terrible del 
one-two de drought.The de la depresión económica y el mal tiempo 
puso a muchos granjeros de negocio. ¿En los años 30 tempranos, 
millares de refugiados del tazón de fuente de polvo? 
¿principalmente de Oklahoma, de Tejas, de Colorado, de Kansas, y
de New México? pila de discos encima de sus familias y del 
oeste emigrada, esperando encontrar el trabajo. Las familias 
enteras emigraron juntas (por ejemplo los hombres ahora mostrados en 
"tres generaciones de los refugiados de la sequía de Texans") en 
búsqueda de una vida mejor. ¿Imágenes tales como 
"Midcontinent? Familia que está parada en el camino con el 
coche, "" refugiados de la sequía, "y" Untitled, ca. 1935 
(familia Gastada-Abajo delante de la tienda)"ofertas una ojeada en su 
experiencia en el camino, y muestran que los coches proporcionaron al 
transporte y al abrigo de muchas familias en el camino. Cerca de
200.000 de los nómadas dirigieron hacia California. El estado 
necesitó calcular fuera de cómo absorber a los millares de gente 
indigente que cruzaba sus fronteras diariamente. Una de sus 
táctica debía documentar el apuro de los refugiados. En 1935, 
el fotógrafo Dorothea Lange ensambló la división rural de la 
rehabilitación de la administración de la relevación de la 
emergencia del estado de California (SUEROS), una sección de la 
administración federal de la relevación de la emergencia. Ella
asignaron el trabajo de usar su cámara fotográfica para documentar 
el número creciente de los refugiados sin hogar del tazón de fuente 
de polvo que emigraban a California. Ella trabajó con Paul S. 
Taylor, profesor en la universidad de California, Berkeley, que 
investigaba condiciones de la pobreza rural para hacer recomendaciones
en cómo mejorar las condiciones de los trabajadores. El trabajo
por Taylor y Lange desempeñó un papel importante en ayudar a 
levantar la conciencia pública de la crisis. Los informes que 
hicieron para el gobierno incluyeron ambos datos e imágenes 
llamativas que revelaron las condiciones desesperadas en las cuales 
los nómadas vivieron y confirmaron la necesidad de la intervención 
del gobierno. Las imágenes rígidas tales como "hogar de los 
refugiados de la sequía de Oklahoma" resonados con el público, y los
retratos de los refugiados de la sequía como "rubí de Arkansas" y de
otros mostrados en este asunto humanizaron a nómadas para ciudadanos 
más afortunados. En marcha de 1936, Lange tomó qué se 
convirtió en una de sus imágenes más famosas, a "madre migratoria."
Esta imagen de una mujer 32-year-old se convirtió en un icono 
para el sufrimiento de gentes normales durante la gran depresión.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085246</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106817</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/dust-bowl-migration</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
