<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105321</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105321</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205327</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">You Decide: Should the U. S. government pay African-Americans reparations for slavery?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sie Entscheiden: Sollte die USREGIERUNG 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanern Reparationen für Sklaverei zahlen?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vous Décidez : Le gouvernement des 
États-Unis devrait-il payer des réparations d'Afro-Américains 
l'esclavage ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Você Decide-se: Deve o governo dos E. U. 
pagar a Africano-Americanos reparations pelo slavery?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Decidete: Dovrebbe il governo degli Stati 
Uniti pagare ad Africano-Americani i reparations slavery?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αποφασίζετε: Θα έπρεπε η κυβέρνηση του Θ*u. Θ*ς. 
να πληρώσει τις επιδιορθώσεις αφρικανικός-Αμερικανοί για τη 
σκλαβιά;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usted Decide: ¿Debe el gobierno de los 
E.E.U.U. pagar a Africano-Americanos las reparaciones esclavitud?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This educational guide focuses on whether the United States should pay reparations to modern African-Americans as compensation for the era of slavery. Students are invited to examine the arguments on both sides of the debate, developing critical thinking skills as they work through the activities. Students will learn how to support their arguments with evidence and reason. It is expected that at the end of this guide students will determine where they stand on this controversial issue.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese pädagogische Anleitung fokussiert an, ob die 
Vereinigten Staaten Reparationen als Ausgleich für die Ära der 
Sklaverei zahlen sollten den modernen Afrikanisch-Amerikanern. 
Kursteilnehmer werden eingeladen, die Argumente auf beiden 
Seiten der Debatte zu überprüfen und entwickeln kritische denkende 
Fähigkeiten, während sie durch die Aktivitäten arbeiten. 
Kursteilnehmer erlernen, wie man ihre Argumente mit Beweis und 
Grund unterstützt. Es wird erwartet, daß am Ende dieser 
Anleitung Kursteilnehmer feststellen, wo sie zu diesem umstrittenen 
Punkt stehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce guide éducatif se focalise en fonction si les 
Etats-Unis devraient verser des réparations sur des Afro-Américains 
modernes comme compensation l'ère de l'esclavage. Des 
étudiants sont invités à examiner les arguments des deux côtés de
la discussion, développant des qualifications de pensée critiques 
pendant qu'ils travaillent par les activités. Les étudiants 
apprendront comment supporter leurs arguments avec l'évidence et la 
raison. On s'attend à ce qu'à l'extrémité de ce guide les 
étudiants déterminent où ils se tiennent sur cette question 
controversée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta guia educacional focaliza sobre se os estados unidos 
devem pagar reparations aos Africano-Americanos modernos como a 
compensação pela era do slavery. Os estudantes estão 
convidados examinar os argumentos em ambos os lados do debate, 
desenvolvendo habilidades pensando críticas enquanto trabalham com as
atividades. Os estudantes aprenderão como suportar seus 
argumentos com evidência e razão. Espera-se que na extremidade
desta guia os estudantes determinarão onde estão nesta edição 
controversa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa guida educativa mette a fuoco sopra se unito 
Dichiara dovrebbe pagare i reparations agli Africano-Americani
moderni come compensazione l'era di slavery. Gli allievi sono 
invitati ad esaminare gli argomenti da entrambi i lati del dibattito, 
sviluppanti le abilità pensanti critiche mentre lavorano con le 
attività. Gli allievi impareranno come sostenere i loro 
argomenti con prova e motivo. È previsto che all'estremità di 
questa guida allievi determinino dove si levano in piedi su questa 
edizione discutibile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο εκπαιδευτικός οδηγός εστιάζει εάν οι 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες πρέπει να πληρώσουν τις επιδιορθώσεις σε 
σύγχρονους αφρικανικός-Αμερικανούς ως αποζημίωση για εποχή της 
σκλαβιάς. Οι σπουδαστές καλούνται για να εξετάσουν τα 
ορίσματα και στις δύο πλευρές της συζήτησης, που αναπτύσσει τις 
κρίσιμες δεξιότητες σκέψης όπως λειτουργούν μέσω των 
δραστηριοτήτων. Οι σπουδαστές θα μάθουν πώς να υποστηρίξουν
τα ορίσματά τους με τα στοιχεία και το λόγο. Αναμένεται 
ότι στο τέλος αυτού του οδηγού οι σπουδαστές θα καθορίσουν όπου
στέκονται σε αυτό το αμφισβητούμενο ζήτημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta guía educativa se enfoca encendido si los Estados 
Unidos deben pagar reparaciones a los Africano-Americanos modernos 
como remuneración la era de la esclavitud. Se invita a los 
estudiantes que examinen los argumentos en ambas caras del discusión,
desarrollando habilidades de pensamiento críticas mientras que 
trabajan con las actividades. Los estudiantes aprenderán cómo 
utilizar sus argumentos con evidencia y razón. Se espera que en
el extremo de esta guía los estudiantes se determinen dónde están 
parados en esta edición polémica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205327</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105321</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/you-decide-should-the-u-s-government-pay-african-americans-reparations-for-slavery</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
