<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106895</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106895</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087046</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Senate's Declaration of War": Japan Responds to Japanese Exclusion</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"die Erklärung des Senats des Krieges": 
Japan reagiert auf japanischen Ausschluß</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la déclaration du sénat de la guerre" : Le
Japon répond à l'exclusion japonaise</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a declaração do senate da guerra": Japão 
responde à exclusão japonesa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la dichiarazione del senato della guerra": 
Il Giappone risponde all'esclusione giapponese</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η Διακήρυξη της Συγκλήτου του πολέμου": Η 
Ιαπωνία αποκρίνεται στον ιαπωνικό αποκλεισμό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"el declaración del senado de la guerra": 
Japón responde a la exclusión japonesa</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1924, Congress passed the Johnson-Reed Act (also known as the Immigration Act of 1924), which restricted immigration from many European nations and denied even a token quota to most Asians. The law barred all immigrants who were ineligible for citizenship, and all south and east Asians (including Indians, Japanese, and Chinese) had been deemed ineligible on racial grounds by a 1922 Supreme Court decision. Japan reacted particularly strongly to what it regarded as the insulting treatment of the Japanese under the new law. The Japanese organized consumer boycotts against American goods and demonstrated against American cultural practices like dancing. This  Japan Times &amp; Mail  editorial, entitled "The Senate's Declaration of War," denounced the 1924 immigration law and speculated on the reasons for the decision. The paper suggested that the Senate "deliberately" sought to "insult" the Japanese.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1924 führte Kongreß die Johnson-Schilf Tat (alias
die Immigration-Tat von 1924), die die eingeschränkte Immigration von
vielen europäischen Nationen und sogar eine Scheinquote verweigert 
den meisten Asiaten. Das Gesetz hielt alle Immigranten ab, die 
für Staatsbürgerschaft untauglich waren, und alle Süd- und 
Ostasiaten (einschließlich Inder, Japaner und Chinese) waren 
untauglich auf rassischem Boden durch eine Entscheidung des Höchsten 
Gerichts 1922 gemeint worden. Japan reagierte besonders stark 
zu, was es als die beleidigende Behandlung des Japaners unter dem 
neuen Gesetz ansah. Die japanischen organisierten 
Verbraucherboykotts gegen amerikanische Waren und gegen amerikanische 
kulturelle Praxis demonstriert mögen tanzen. Dieses Japan Zeit-
u. Postleitartikel, erlaubt "die Erklärung des Senats des Krieges," 
gekündigt dem Immigrationgesetz 1924 und spekuliert auf den Gründen 
für die Entscheidung. Das Papier schlug vor, daß der Senat 
"absichtlich" suchte, die Japaner "zu beleidigen".</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1924, le congrès a passé la Loi de 
Johnson-reed (également connue sous le nom d'acte d'immigration de 
1924), qui immigration restreinte de beaucoup de nations européennes 
et refusée même une quote-part symbolique à la plupart des 
Asiatiques. La loi a interdit à tous les immigrés qui étaient
inéligibles pour la citoyenneté, et tous les Asiatiques du sud 
et est (Indiens y compris, Japonais, et Chinois) avaient été 
considérés inéligibles pour les raisons raciales par une décision 
de la cour 1922 suprême. Le Japon a réagi particulièrement 
fortement à ce qu'il a considéré comme le traitement insultant du 
Japonais en vertu de la nouvelle loi. Les boycotts organisés 
japonais du consommateur contre les marchandises américaines et 
démontrés contre des pratiques culturelles américaines aiment 
danser. Éditorial de temps et de courrier du ce Japon, 
intitulé "la déclaration du sénat de la guerre," dénoncé la loi 
1924 d'immigration et speculé sur les raisons de la décision. 
Le papier a suggéré que le sénat "délibérément" ait 
recherché "à insulter" les Japonais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1924, o congress passou o ato da 
Johnson-Lingüeta (sabido também como o ato do immigration de 1924), 
que immigration restrito de muitas nações européias e negado mesmo 
um quota simbólico a a maioria de asians. A lei barrou todos os
immigrants que eram inelegíveis para o citizenship, e todos os asians
sul e do leste (indians including, japonês, e chinês) tinham sido 
julgados inelegíveis em terras raciais por uma decisão da corte 1922
suprema. Japão reagiu particularmente fortemente a o que 
considerou como o tratamento insultando do japonês sob a lei nova. 
Os boycotts organizados japoneses do consumidor de encontro aos 
bens americanos e demonstrados de encontro às práticas cultural 
americanas gostam de dançar. Editorial dos tempos &amp; do correio 
deste Japão, intitulado "a declaração do senate da guerra," 
denounced a lei 1924 do immigration e speculated nas razões para a 
decisão. O papel sugeriu que o senate "deliberadamente" 
procurou "insultar" os japoneses.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1924, il congresso ha passato la Legge della 
Johnson-Canna (anche conosciuta come la Legge di immigrazione di 
1924), che immigrazione limitata da molte nazioni europee e rifiutata 
persino una quota simbolica alla maggior parte dei asiatici. La 
legge ha escluso tutti gli immigranti che erano ineleggibili per la 
cittadinanza e tutti gli asiatici del sud ed orientali (indiani 
compresi, giapponese e cinese) erano stati ritenuti ineleggibili 
per i motivi razziali tramite una decisione della Corte suprema 1922. 
Il Giappone ha reagito particolarmente fortemente a che cosa ha 
considerare come il trattamento insultante del giapponese secondo la 
nuova legge. I boicottaggi organizzati giapponesi del 
consumatore contro le merci americane e dimostrati contro le pratiche 
culturali americane gradiscono ballare. L'editoriale di tempi &amp; 
della posta del questo Giappone, intitolato "la dichiarazione del 
senato della guerra," ha denunciato la legge 1924 di immigrazione ed 
ha speculato sui motivi per la decisione. La carta ha suggerito 
che il senato ha cercato "deliberatamente" "di insultare" i 
giapponesi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1924, το συνέδριο πέρασε το νόμο ιοχνσον-καλάμων
(επίσης γνωστό ως νόμος μετανάστευσης του 1924), ο οποίος 
περιόρισε τη μετανάστευση από πολλά ευρωπαϊκά έθνη και 
αρνήθηκε ακόμη και μια συμβολική ποσόστωση σε στους περισσότερους
Ασιάτες. Ο νόμος έφραξε όλους τους μετανάστες που ήταν μη 
εκλέξιμοι για την υπηκοότητα, και όλοι ο νότος και η ανατολή 
Ασιάτες (συμπεριλαμβανομένων Ινδών, ιαπωνικών, και κινέζικων) 
ήταν κριμένων μη εκλέξιμη για φυλετικούς λόγους με μια απόφαση 
ανώτατου δικαστηρίου του 1922. Η Ιαπωνία αντέδρασε 
ιδιαίτερα έντονα σε αυτό που θεώρησε ως μεταχείριση προσβολής 
των Ιαπώνων βάσει του νέου νόμου. Τα ιαπωνικά οργανωμένα 
καταναλωτικά μποϊκοταρίσματα ενάντια στα αμερικανικά αγαθά και 
καταδειγμένος ενάντια στις αμερικανικές πολιτιστικές πρακτικές 
όπως το χορό. Οι χρόνοι αυτής της Ιαπωνίας &amp; το κύριο 
άρθρο ταχυδρομείου, που τιτλοφορήθηκε "Διακήρυξη της Συγκλήτου 
του πολέμου," κατήγγειλαν το νόμο μετανάστευσης του 1924 και 
σκέφτηκαν στους λόγους για την απόφαση. Το έγγραφο πρότεινε
ότι η Σύγκλητος "σκόπιμα" επιδίωξε "να προσβάλει" τους Ιάπωνες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1924, el congreso pasó el acto de la 
Johnson-Caña (también conocido como el acto de la inmigración de 
1924), que inmigración restricta de muchas naciones europeas y negada
incluso un contingente simbólico a la mayoría de los asiáticos. 
La ley barró a todos los inmigrantes que eran inelegibles para 
la ciudadanía, y una decisión del Tribunal Supremo habían juzgado a
todos los asiáticos del sur y del este (indios incluyendo, japonés, 
y chino) inelegibles en los argumentos raciales 1922. Japón 
reaccionó determinado fuertemente a lo que miró como el tratamiento 
que insultaba del japonés bajo nueva ley. Los boicoteos 
ordenados japoneses del consumidor contra mercancías americanas y 
demostrados contra prácticas culturales americanas tienen gusto de 
bailar. Editorial de los tiempos y del correo de este Japón, 
titulado "el declaración del senado de la guerra," denunci la ley 
1924 de la inmigración y especulado en las razones de la decisión. 
El papel sugirió que el senado intentara "deliberadamente" 
"insultar" a los japoneses.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087046</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106895</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-senates-declaration-of-war-japan-responds-to-japanese-exclusion</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
