<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106830</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106830</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086064</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Declaration of Independence of the Democratic Republic of Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unabhängigkeitserklärung der demokratischen 
Republik von Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Déclaration de l'indépendance de la République 
démocratique du Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Declaração de independência da república 
democrática de Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dichiarazione di indipendenza della Repubblica 
democratica di Vietnam</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διακήρυξη της ανεξαρτησίας της λαϊκής Δημοκρατίας του
Βιετνάμ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Declaración de la independencia de la república 
democrática de Vietnam</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">For the people of Vietnam, who were just beginning to recover from five years of ruthless economic exploitation by the Japanese, the end of World War II promised to bring eighty years of French control to a close. As the League for the Independence of Vietnam (Vietnam Doc Lap Dong Minh Hoi), better known as the Viet Minh, Vietnamese nationalists had fought against the Japanese invaders as well as the defeated French colonial authorities. With the support of rich and poor peasants, workers, businessmen, landlords, students, and intellectuals, the Viet Minh (led by Ho Chi Minh) had expanded throughout northern Vietnam where it established new local governments, redistributed some lands, and opened granaries to alleviate the famine. On September 2, 1945, Ho Chi Minh proclaimed the independent Democratic Republic of Vietnam in Hanoi's Ba Dinh square. The first lines of his speech repeated verbatim the famous second paragraph of America's 1776 Declaration of Independence.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Für die Leute von Vietnam, die der gerechte 
Anfang waren, zum von fünf Jahren unbarmherziger ökonomischer 
Ausnutzung durch den Japaner zu erholen, versprach das Ende des 
Zweiten Weltkrieges, achtzig Jahre französische Steuerung zu einem 
Abschluß zu holen. Als die Liga für die Unabhängigkeit von 
Vietnam (Vietnam Doc. Schoß Dong Minh Hoi), verbessern Sie bekannt 
als das Viet Minh, vietnamesische Nationalisten hatte fought.against 
die japanischen Eindringlinge sowie die besiegten französischen 
Kolonialbehörden. Mit dem Support der reichen und armen 
Landarbeiter, Arbeiter, Geschäftsmänner, Hauswirte, Kursteilnehmer 
und Intellektuelle, hatte das Viet Minh (geführt von Ho Chi Minh) in 
Nordvietnam erweitert, in dem es neue lokale Regierungen herstellte, 
etwas Länder und geöffnete Getreidespeicher neuverteilte, um den 
Hunger zu vermindern. An September 2, 1945, Ho Chi Minh 
proklamierte die unabhängige demokratische Republik von Vietnam im 
Quadrat Dinh Ba Hanois. Die ersten Zeilen seiner Rede 
wiederholten wortwörtlich den berühmten zweiten Paragraphen von 
Amerikas Unabhängigkeitserklärung 1776.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pour le peuple du Vietnam, qui étaient début 
juste à récupérer de cinq ans d'exploitation économique 
impitoyable par le Japonais, la fin de la deuxième guerre mondiale a 
promis d'apporter quatre-vingts ans de commande française à une fin.
En tant que ligue pour l'indépendance du Vietnam (recouvrement 
Dong Minh Hoi de Doc. du Vietnam), améliorez connu comme Viet 
Minh, les nationalistes vietnamiens a eu fought.against les 
envahisseurs japonais aussi bien que les autorités coloniales 
françaises défaites. Avec le support des paysans riches et 
pauvres, ouvriers, hommes d'affaires, propriétaires, étudiants, et 
intellectuels, le Viet Minh (mené par Ho Chi Minh) avait augmenté 
dans l'ensemble du Vietnam nordique où il a établi de nouveaux 
gouvernements locaux, a redistribué quelques terres, et greniers 
ouverts pour alléger la famine. 2 septembre 1945, chi Minh de 
Ho a proclamé la République démocratique indépendante du Vietnam 
dans la place de Dinh du Ba de Hanoï. Les premières lignes de 
son discours ont répété in extenso le deuxième paragraphe 
célèbre de la déclaration 1776 de l'Amérique de l'indépendance.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Para os povos de Vietnam, que eram começo justo a 
recuperar de cinco anos da exploração econômica ruthless pelo 
japonês, o fim da segunda guerra mundial prometeu trazer eighty anos 
do controle francês a um fim. Como a liga para a independência
de Vietnam (regaço Dong Minh Hoi de Vietnam Doc), melhore sabido como
o Viet Minh, nacionalistas vietnamese tinha lutado de encontro aos 
invasores japoneses as.well.as as autoridades coloniais francesas 
derrotadas. Com a sustentação de camponeses ricos e 
deficientes, trabalhadores, homens de negócios, landlords, 
estudantes, e intelectuais, o Viet Minh (conduzido por Ho Chi Minh) 
tinha expandido durante todo Vietnam do norte onde estabeleceu 
governos locais novos, redistributed algumas terras, e granaries 
abertos para aliviar o famine. Setembro em 2, 1945, chi Minh de 
Ho proclamou a república democrática independente de Vietnam no 
quadrado de Dinh do ba de Hanoi. As primeiras linhas de seu 
discurso repetiram verbatim o segundo parágrafo famoso da 
declaração 1776 de América de independência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Per la gente del Vietnam, che era inizio giusto da 
recuperare da cinque anni di sfruttamento economico ruthless dal 
giapponese, la conclusione della seconda guerra mondiale ha promesso 
di portare ottanta anni di controllo francese ad una fine. Come 
la lega per l'indipendenza del Vietnam (giro Dong Minh Hoi del 
documento del Vietnam), migliori conosciuto come il Viet Minh, 
nazionalisti vietnamiti aveva combattuto contro i invaders giapponesi 
così come le autorità coloniali francesi sconfitte. Con il 
supporto dei contadini ricchi e poveri, operai, uomini d'affari, 
proprietari, allievi ed intellettuali, il Viet Minh (condotto da Ho 
Chi Minh) si era espanso durante il Vietnam del Nord in cui ha 
stabilito i nuovi enti pubblici territoriali, ha ridistribuito alcune 
terre ed i granai aperti per alleviare la carestia. Il 2 
settembre 1945, il "chi" Minh di Ho ha affermato la Repubblica 
democratica indipendente di Vietnam nel quadrato di Dinh del Ba de 
Hanoi. Le prime linee il suo discorso hanno ripetuto verbatim il
secondo paragrafo famoso della dichiarazione 1776 dell'America di 
indipendenza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Για τους πληθυσμούς του Βιετνάμ, που άρχιζαν ακριβώς 
να ανακτούν από πέντε έτη άσπλαχνης οικονομικής εκμετάλλευσης 
από τους Ιάπωνες, το τέλος του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ υποσχέθηκε 
να φέρει ογδόντα έτη γαλλικού ελέγχου σε έναν περίβολο. 
Σαν ένωση για την ανεξαρτησία του Βιετνάμ (Dong Minh 
Hoi περιτυλίξεων εγγράφου του Βιετνάμ), καλύτερα γνωστή ως 
Viet Minh, οι βιετναμέζικοι εθνικιστές είχαν παλεψει ενάντια
στους ιαπωνικούς εισβολείς καθώς επίσης και τις νικημένες 
γαλλικές αποικιακές αρχές. Με την υποστήριξη των πλούσιων 
και φτωχών αγροτών, των εργαζομένων, των επιχειρηματιών, των 
ιδιοκτητών, των σπουδαστών, και των διανοούμενων, το Viet 
Minh (που οδηγείται από Ho Chi Minh) είχε επεκταθεί σε
όλο το βόρειο Βιετνάμ όπου καθιέρωσε τις νέες τοπικές 
κυβερνήσεις, ανακατένειμε μερικά εδάφη, και άνοιξε τους 
σιτοβολώνες για να ανακουφίσει την πείνα. Στις 2 Σεπτεμβρίου
..1945, Ho chi Minh πιστοποίησε την ανεξάρτητη λαϊκή 
Δημοκρατία του Βιετνάμ στο τετράγωνο BA Dinh του Ανόι. 
Οι πρώτες γραμμές ομιλίας του επανέλαβαν κατά λέξη τη 
διάσημη δεύτερη παράγραφο της Διακήρυξης 1776 της Αμερικής της
ανεξαρτησίας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Para la gente de Vietnam, que era principio justo a
recuperarse a partir de cinco años de explotación económica 
despiadada del japonés, el final de la Segunda Guerra Mundial 
prometió traer ochenta años de control francés a un cierre. 
Como la liga para la independencia de Vietnam (regazo Dong Minh 
Hoi de Vietnam doc.), mejore conocido como el Viet Minh, los 
nacionalistas vietnamitas había luchado contra los invasores 
japoneses así como las autoridades coloniales francesas derrotadas. 
Con la ayuda de los campesinos ricos y pobres, trabajadores, 
hombres de negocios, propietarios, estudiantes, e intelectuales, el 
Viet Minh (conducido por Ho Chi Minh) se había ampliado a través de 
Vietnam norteño en donde estableció nuevos gobiernos locales, 
redistribuyó algunas pistas, y graneros abiertos para aliviar el 
hambre. 2 de septiembre de 1945, chi Minh de Ho proclamó la 
república democrática independiente de Vietnam en el cuadrado de Dinh 
del Ba de Hanoi. Las primeras líneas de su discurso relanzaron 
in extenso el segundo párrafo famoso del declaración 1776 de 
América de la independencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086064</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106830</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/declaration-of-independence-of-the-democratic-republic-of-vietnam</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
