<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103950</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103950</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206047</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Brighten Up the Classroom</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erhellen Sie herauf das Klassenzimmer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Éclairez vers le haut de la salle de classe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Brighten acima da sala de aula</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Illumini sull'aula</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λαμπρύνετε επάνω την τάξη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aclare encima de la sala de clase</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides papers on the aurora and ionosphere, scales for measuring space weather, and a textbook for high school teachers and advanced students -- Solar Physics and Terrestrial Effects. The textbook examines a range of topics: the evolution and structure of the sun, sunspots and solar flares, the corona and chromosphere, solar-terrestrial interactions, building a spectroscope, measuring the solar constant, and seeing at different wavelengths.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Papiere auf der Aurora und dem ionosphere, 
Skalen für messendes Platzwetter und ein Lehrbuch für High School 
Lehrer und hochentwickelte Kursteilnehmer -- Solarphysik und 
terrestrische Effekte zur Verfügung. Das Lehrbuch überprüft 
eine Strecke der Themen: die Entwicklung und die Struktur der 
Sonne, der Sunspots und der Sonneneruptionen, der Corona und des 
chromosphere, Solar-terrestrische Interaktionen, einen Spectroscope 
aufbauend, messen die Solarkonstante, und sehen an den 
unterschiedlichen Wellenlängen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des papiers sur l'aurore et l'ionosphère,
échelles pour l'espace de mesure survivent à, et un manuel pour 
des professeurs de lycée et des étudiants avançés -- physique 
solaire et effets terrestres. Le manuel examine un intervalle 
des sujets : l'évolution et la structure du soleil, les taches 
solaires et les éruptions chromosphériques, la corona et 
chromosphere, interactions solaire-terrestres, construisant un 
spectroscope, mesurant la constante solaire, et voyant à différentes
longueurs d'onde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece papéis no aurora e no ionosphere, escalas
para o tempo de medição do espaço, e um textbook para professores 
da High School e estudantes avançados -- física solar e efeitos 
terrestrial. O textbook examina uma escala dos tópicos: a
evolução e a estrutura do sol, os sunspots e os alargamentos 
solares, a corona e chromosphere, interações 
solar-solar-terrestrial, construindo um spectroscope, medindo a 
constante solar, e vendo em wavelengths diferentes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le carte sul aurora e sullo ionosphere, 
le scale per il tempo di misurazione dello spazio e un manuale per gli
insegnanti della High School e gli allievi avanzati -- la fisica 
solare ed effetti terrestri. Il manuale esamina una gamma di 
soggetti: lo sviluppo e la struttura del sole, i sunspots ed i 
chiarori solari, la corona e chromosphere, interazioni 
solare-terrestri, costruendo uno spectroscope, misurando il costante 
solare e vedendo alle lunghezze d'onda differenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα έγγραφα για την αυγή και την ιονόσφαιρα, 
κλίμακες για τη μέτρηση του διαστημικού καιρού, και ενός 
εγχειριδίου για τους δασκάλους γυμνασίου και τους προηγμένους 
σπουδαστές -- ηλιακή φυσική και επίγεια αποτελέσματα. Το 
εγχειρίδιο εξετάζει μια σειρά των θεμάτων: η εξέλιξη και η 
δομή του ήλιου, των ηλιακών κηλίδων και των ηλιακών φλογών, της 
κορώνας και chromosphere, ηλιακός-επίγειες αλληλεπιδράσεις, της
οικοδόμησης ενός σπεκτροσκοπίου, μετρώντας την ηλιακή σταθερά, 
και βλέποντας στα διαφορετικά μήκη κύματος.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a los papeles en el aurora y el 
ionosphere, a las escalas para el tiempo del espacio que mide, y a un 
libro de textos para los profesores y los estudiantes avanzados -- 
física solar y efectos terrestres de la High School secundaria. 
El libro de textos examina un rango de asuntos: la 
evolución y la estructura del sol, las manchas solares y las flamas 
solares, la corona y chromosphere, interacciones solar-terrestres, 
construyendo un espectroscopio, midiendo la constante solar, y viendo 
en diversas longitudes de onda.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206047</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103950</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/brighten-up-the-classroom</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
