<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103620</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103620</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201829</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Youth Perspectives as Primary Sources </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Jugend-Perspektiven als Primärquellen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Perspectives de la jeunesse en tant que sources 
primaires</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Perspectives da juventude como fontes 
preliminares</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Prospettive della gioventù come sorgenti 
primarie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προοπτικές νεολαίας ως αρχικές πηγές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Perspectivas de la juventud como fuentes 
primarias</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A special issue of Panorama, the online magazine of TakingITGlobal, was dedicated to the Millennium Development Goals and One World Youth Project Ambassadors from seven countries maintain a group blog that details the issues they have identified in their communities and action projects they are undertaking. Using these articles, students can apply previous learning about primary sources to understand the perspectives of youth around the world who are identifying issues and addressing the Goals in their communities. </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Sonderausgabe des Panoramas, die 
Onlinezeitschrift von TakingITGlobal, wurde den 
Jahrtausend-Entwicklung Zielen eingesetzt und ein die 
Weltjugend-Projekt-Botschafter aus sieben Ländern behalten ein Gruppe
blog bei, das die Ausgaben genau schildert, die, sie in ihren 
Gemeinschaften und in Tätigkeit Projekten gekennzeichnet haben, sie 
sich aufnehmen. Mit diesen Artikeln können Kursteilnehmer das 
vorhergehende Lernen über Primärquellen anwenden, die Perspektiven 
von Jugend um die Welt zu verstehen, die Ausgaben kennzeichnen und die
Ziele in ihren Gemeinschaften adressieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une édition spéciale de panorama, le magazine en
ligne de TakingITGlobal, a été consacrée aux buts de développement
de millénium et les ambassadeurs d'un du monde projet de la jeunesse 
de sept pays mettent à jour un blog de groupe qui détaille les 
issues qu'elles ont identifiées dans les leurs communautés et 
projets d'action ils entreprennent. En utilisant ces articles, 
les étudiants peuvent appliquer se renseigner précédent sur des 
sources primaires pour comprendre les perspectives de la jeunesse 
autour du monde qui identifient des issues et adressent les buts dans 
leurs communautés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma introdução especial do panorama, o 
compartimento em linha de TakingITGlobal, foi dedicada aos objetivos 
do desenvolvimento do millennium e os embaixadores de um projeto da 
juventude do mundo de sete países mantêm um blog do grupo que 
detalhe as edições que identificaram em seus comunidades e projetos 
da ação estão empreendendo. Usando estes artigos, os 
estudantes podem aplicar a aprendizagem precedente sobre fontes 
preliminares compreender os perspectives da juventude em torno do 
mundo que estão identificando edições e se estão dirigindo aos 
objetivos em suas comunidades.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un numero speciale del panorama, lo scomparto in 
linea di TakingITGlobal, è stato dedicato agli obiettivi di sviluppo 
di millennio e gli ambasciatori di un del mondo progetto della 
gioventù da sette paesi effettuano un blog del gruppo che dettaglia 
le edizioni che hanno identificato nelle loro Comunità e progetti di 
azione stanno intraprendendo. Usando questi articoli, gli 
allievi possono applicare imparare precedente circa le sorgenti 
primarie capire le prospettive della gioventù intorno al mondo che 
stanno identificando le edizioni e stanno richiamando gli obiettivi 
nelle loro Comunità.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια ειδική έκδοση του πανοράματος, το σε απευθείας 
σύνδεση περιοδικό TakingITGlobal, αφιερώθηκε στους στόχους 
ανάπτυξης χιλιετίας και οι πρεσβευτές ενός προγράμματος 
παγκόσμιας νεολαίας από επτά χώρες διατηρούν μια ομάδα blog 
ότι λεπτομέρειες τα ζητήματα έχουν προσδιορίσει στις κοινότητες 
και τα προγράμματα δράσης τους που αναλαμβάνουν. 
Χρησιμοποιώντας αυτά τα άρθρα, οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να 
εφαρμόσουν την προηγούμενη εκμάθηση για τις αρχικές πηγές να 
καταλαβαίνουν τις προοπτικές της νεολαίας σε όλο τον κόσμο που 
προσδιορίζουν τα ζητήματα και εξετάζουν τους στόχους στις 
κοινότητές τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una edición especial del panorama, el 
compartimiento en línea de TakingITGlobal, fue dedicada a las metas 
del desarrollo del milenio y los embajadores de un del mundo proyecto 
de la juventud a partir de siete países mantienen un blog del grupo 
que detalle las ediciones que han identificado en sus comunidades y 
proyectos de la acción están emprendiendo. Usando estos 
artículos, los estudiantes pueden aplicar aprender anterior sobre 
fuentes primarias entender las perspectivas de la juventud alrededor 
del mundo que están identificando ediciones y están tratando las 
metas en sus comunidades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201829</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103620</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/youth-perspectives-as-primary-sources</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
