<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108659</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108659</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086130</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Every Two Or Three Weeks Someone Would Die:" Michael Yantsos on Protesting AIDS Treatment in Prison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Alle Zwei Oder Drei Wochen Würde Jemand 
Sterben:" Michael Yantsos auf dem Protestieren von von AIDS 
Behandlung im Gefängnis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Toutes les Deux Ou Trois Semaines Quelqu'un 
Mourrait :" Michael Yantsos sur protester le traitement de SIDA 
en prison</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Cada Duas Ou Três Semanas Alguém Morreria:" 
Michael Yantsos em protestar o tratamento do AIDS na prisão</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Ogni Due O Tre Settimane Qualcuno Morrebbe:" 
Michael Yantsos sulla protesta del trattamento del AIDS in 
prigione</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κάθε δύο ή τρεις εβδομάδες κάποιος θα πέθαινε:" 
Michael Yantsos στη διαμαρτυρία της επεξεργασίας του 
AIDS στη φυλακή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Cada Dos O Tres Semanas Alguien Moriría:" 
Michael Yantsos en la protesta del tratamiento del SIDA en la 
prisión</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">As the severity of the AIDS epidemic increased during the mid-1980s, the inadequacy of AIDS education and treatment came under assault from activists, many of whom were themselves infected with the disease. Michael Yantsos, who became infected with AIDS in prison in 1983, was one of those who spoke out when conditions at Rikers Island Prison Hospital in New York City became unbearable. In 1986, as prisoners were dying at the rate of one every two weeks from AIDS, Yantsos and his fellow inmates went on hunger strike to publicize the unsanitary conditions in the prison's AIDS ward, which included leaks, rodents, insects, and inadequate food and medical attention. The prisoners' efforts succeeding in publicizing the issue and winning some reforms in the ward's conditions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Als die Schwierigkeit der AIDS-Epidemie erhöhte 
sich während der Mitte der 80iger Jahre, die Unzulänglichkeit der 
AIDS-Ausbildung und Behandlung kam unter Angriff von den Aktivisten, 
viele von, wurden wem selbst mit der Krankheit angesteckt. 
Michael Yantsos, der mit AIDS im Gefängnis 1983 angesteckt 
wurde, war einer von denen, die heraus sprachen, als Bedingungen am 
Rikers Insel-Gefängnis-Krankenhaus in New York City unbearable 
wurden. 1986 während Gefangene mit der Kinetik von einer alle 
zwei Wochen von den AIDS starben, fuhr Yantsos und seine Mitinsassen 
Hungerstreik fort, die unhygienischen Bedingungen im AIDS-Bezirk des 
Gefängnisses zu publizieren, der Leckstellen, Nagetiere, Insekte und 
unzulängliche Nahrung- und ärztlichebehandlung einschloß. Die
Bemühungen der Gefangenen, die mit die, Ausgabe zu publizieren und 
einige Verbesserungen in Zuständen des Bezirks zu gewinnen folgen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À mesure que la sévérité de l'épidémie de 
SIDA a augmenté pendant le milieu des années 80, l'insuffisance de 
l'éducation de SIDA et le traitement a relevé de l'assaut des 
activistes, beaucoup de qui eux-mêmes ont été atteints de la 
maladie. Michael Yantsos, qui est devenu infecté avec le SIDA 
en prison en 1983, était l'un de ceux qui ont parlé dehors quand les
conditions à l'hôpital de prison d'île de Rikers à New York City 
sont devenues insupportables. En 1986, pendant que les 
prisonniers mouraient à la cadence d'une toutes les deux semaines des
SIDAS, Yantsos et ses détenus de camarade a fait la grève de faim 
pour donner de la publicité aux conditions antihygiéniques dans la 
salle du SIDA de la prison, qui a inclus des fuites, des rongeurs, des
insectes, et une attention de nourriture et médicale insatisfaisante.
Les efforts des prisonniers réussissant à donner de la 
publicité à l'issue et à gagner quelques réformes en conditions de
la salle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Como a severidade da epidemia de AIDS aumentou 
durante os mid-1980s, o inadequacy da instrução do AIDS e o 
tratamento veio sob o assalto das activistas, muitas de quem elas 
mesmas infected com a doença. Michael Yantsos, que se tornou 
infected com o AIDS na prisão em 1983, era um daqueles que falaram 
para fora quando as condições no hospital da prisão do console de 
Rikers em New York City se tornaram unbearable. Em 1986, 
enquanto os prisioneiros estavam morrendo na taxa de uma cada duas 
semanas dos AIDS, Yantsos e seus inmates do companheiro foi na batida 
de fome publicize as condições unsanitary na divisão do AIDS da 
prisão, que incluiu escapes, roedores, insetos, e a atenção 
inadequada do alimento e a médica. Os esforços dos 
prisioneiros que sucedem em publicizing a edição e em ganhar algumas
reformas nas condições da divisão.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Come la severità dell'epidemia di AIDS è 
aumentato durante i mid-1980s, la deficienza di formazione del AIDS ed
il trattamento è rientrato in assalto dagli attivisti, molti di chi
essi stessi sono stati infettati con la malattia. Michael 
Yantsos, che è stato infettato con il AIDS in prigione in 1983, era 
uno di coloro che ha parlato fuori quando i termini all'ospedale della
prigione dell'isola di Rikers a New York City sono diventato 
unbearable. In 1986, mentre i prigionieri stavano morendo al 
tasso di uno ogni due settimane dai AIDS, Yantsos ed i suoi interni 
del collega è andato sul colpo di fame divulg i termini antigienici 
nel quartiere del AIDS della prigione, che ha incluso le perdite, i 
roditori, gli insetti e l'attenzione medica inadeguata e 
dell'alimento. Gli sforzi dei prigionieri che riescono a divulg 
l'edizione e la vincita delle alcune riforme negli stati del 
quartiere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δεδομένου ότι η δριμύτητα της επιδημίας του AIDS 
αυξήθηκε κατά τη διάρκεια τα μέσα τησδεκαετίας του '80, η 
ανεπάρκεια της εκπαίδευσης και της επεξεργασίας του AIDS ήρθε 
κάτω από την επίθεση από τα ενεργά στελέχη, πολλά από τα 
οποία οι ίδιοι μολύνθηκαν με την ασθένεια. Michael 
Yantsos, που έγινε μολυσμένος με το AIDS στη φυλακή το 
1983, ήταν ένας από εκείνους που μίλησαν έξω όταν οι όροι 
στο νοσοκομείο φυλακών νησιών Rikers στην πόλη της Νέας 
Υόρκης έγιναν αφόρητοι. Το 1986, δεδομένου ότι οι 
φυλακισμένοι πέθαιναν στο ποσοστό μιας κάθε δύο εβδομάδων από 
το AIDS, Yantsos και οι συντροφικοί τρόφιμοί του πήγαν στην 
απεργία πείνας να κοινοποιήσουν τους unsanitary όρους στο 
θάλαμο του AIDS της φυλακής, οι οποίοι περιέλαβαν τις 
διαρροές, τα τρωκτικά, τα έντομα, και την ανεπαρκή ιατρικής 
προσοχή τροφίμων και. Οι προσπάθειες των φυλακισμένων που 
πετυχαίνουν στην κοινοποίηση του ζητήματος και τη νίκη μερικών 
μεταρρυθμίσεων στους όρους του θαλάμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Como la severidad de la epidemia de SIDA aumentó 
durante los a mediados de los años ochenta, la insuficiencia de la 
educación del SIDA y el tratamiento vino bajo asalto de los 
activistas, muchos de quién ellos mismos fueron infectadas con la 
enfermedad. Michael Yantsos, que se infectó con el SIDA en la 
prisión en 1983, era uno de los que hablaron hacia fuera cuando las 
condiciones en el hospital de la prisión de la isla de Rikers en New 
York City llegaron a ser unbearable. En 1986, como los presos 
morían en el índice de uno cada dos semanas de SIDA, Yantsos y sus 
internos del compañero fue en huelga de hambre a publicar las 
condiciones antihigiénicas en la sala del SIDA de la prisión, que 
incluyó los escapes, los roedores, los insectos, y la atención 
inadecuada del alimento y médica. Los esfuerzos de los presos 
que tienen éxito en la publicación de la edición y ganar algunas 
reformas en las condiciones de la sala.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086130</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108659</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/every-two-or-three-weeks-someone-would-die-michael-yantsos-on-protesting-aids-treatment-in-prison</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
