<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105675</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105675</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086093</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Do Insects Think?" Robert Benchley Satirizes Science</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Tun Sie Insekte Denken?" Robert Benchley 
Satirizes Wissenschaft</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Faites Les Insectes Pensent?" Robert 
Benchley Satirise La Science</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Faça Insetos Pensam?" Ciência De Robert 
Benchley Satirizes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Faccia Gli Insetti Pensano?" Scienza Del 
Robert Benchley Satirizes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Κάνετε τα έντομα σκέφτεται;" Θ*Ροψερτ 
Benchley Satirizes Science</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Haga Los Insectos Piensan?" Ciencia De 
Roberto Benchley Satirizes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The 1920s and 1930s gave rise to new forms of popular humor, humor with a sophisticated edge drawn from a more prosperous, cosmopolitan urban experience. In New York, a circle of urbane humorists with a national audience rose around the  New Yorker  magazine and the famous "Algonquin Round Table," an informal group that met occasionally at the Algonquin Hotel. Ironic, witty, emphasizing word play and "in jokes," the  New Yorker  work of Benchley, Thurber, Perelman, and Dorothy Parker satirized the pretensions of ordinary middle-class life. "Do Insects Think?," a 1922 essay by Robert Benchley, gleefully mocked the pretentious tone of American science, as well as the cult of pep, productivity, and activity that characterized the 1920s. Doing nothing, it suggested, offered the best evidence of intelligence.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die zwanziger Jahre und die dreißiger Jahre 
verursachten neue Formulare der populären Stimmung, Stimmung mit 
einem hoch entwickelten Rand, der von einer wohlhabenderen, 
städtischen kosmopolitischerfahrung gezeichnet wurde. In New 
York stieg ein Kreis der urbane Humoristen mit einem nationalen 
Publikum um die neue Yorker Zeitschrift und die berühmte "Algonquin 
runde Tabelle," eine formlose Gruppe, die gelegentlich im Algonquin 
Hotel traf. Ironisch, witty, Wortspiel und "in den Witzen 
hervorhebend," satirized die neue Yorker Arbeit von Benchley, Thurber,
Perelman und Dorothy Parker die Ansprüche der gewöhnlichen 
Mittelklasselebensdauer. "Tun Sie Insekte Denken?," ein 
Versuch 1922 durch Robert Benchley, vergnügt verspottet dem 
pretentious Ton der amerikanischen Wissenschaft, sowie den Kult von 
Pep, von Produktivität und von Aktivität, der die zwanziger Jahre 
kennzeichnete, die nichts tun, schlug sie vor, den besten Beweis der 
Intelligenz angeboten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les années 20 et les années 30 ont provoqué de 
nouvelles formes de l'humeur populaire, humeur avec un bord 
sophistiqué tiré d'une expérience urbaine plus prospère et plus 
cosmopolite. À New York, un cercle des humoristes courtois 
avec une assistance nationale a monté autour du nouveau magazine de 
Yorker et table ronde de la "d'Algonquin célèbre," un groupe sans
cérémonie qui s'est réuni de temps en temps à l'hôtel 
d'Algonquin. Ironique, plein d'esprit, soulignant le jeu de 
mot et "dans les plaisanteries," le nouveau travail de Yorker de 
Benchley, Thurber, Perelman, et Dorothy Parker ont satirisé 
les prétensions de la vie ordinaire de classe moyen. "Faites 
Les Insectes Pensent ?," un essai 1922 par Robert Benchley, 
allègrement moqueur la tonalité prétentieuse de la science 
américaine, aussi bien que le culte du dynamisme, de la 
productivité, et de l'activité qui a caractérisé les années 20 ne
faisant rien, elle a suggéré, offert la meilleure évidence de 
l'intelligence.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os 1920s e os 1930s deram a ascensão aos 
formulários novos do humor popular, humor com uma borda sofisticada 
desenhada de uma experiência urbana mais próspera, mais 
cosmopolitan. Em New York, um círculo de humorists do urbane 
com uma audiência nacional levantou-se em torno do compartimento novo
de Yorker e de "da tabela redonda famosa Algonquin," um grupo informal
que se encontrasse com ocasionalmente no hotel de Algonquin. 
Ironic, witty, emfatizando o jogo da palavra e "nos gracejos," o
trabalho novo de Yorker de Benchley, Thurber, Perelman, e Dorothy 
Parker satirized os pretensions da vida ordinária do middle-class. 
"Faça Insetos Pensam?," um essay 1922 por Robert 
Benchley, mocked gleefully o tom pretentious da ciência americana, 
as.well.as o cult do pep, da produtividade, e da atividade que 
caracterizou os 1920s. que não fazem nada, sugeriu, oferecido a mais 
melhor evidência da inteligência.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli anni 20 ed i 1930s hanno provocato le nuove 
forme di umore popolare, umore con un bordo specializzato estratto da 
un'esperienza urbana più prosperosa e più cosmopolita. A New 
York, un cerchio dei humorists del urbane con un pubblico nazionale è
aumentato intorno al nuovo scomparto di Yorker e "alla tavola rotonda 
famosa di Algonquin," un gruppo informale che ha venuto a contatto di 
occasionalmente all'hotel di Algonquin. Ironico, witty, dando 
risalto al gioco di parola e "negli scherzi," il nuovo lavoro di 
Yorker di Benchley, Thurber, Perelman e Dorothy Parker satirized i 
pretensions di vita ordinaria della classe media. "Faccia Gli 
Insetti Pensano?," un saggio 1922 da Robert Benchley, gleefully 
deriso il tono pretentious della scienza americana, così come il cult
di pep, di rendimento e di attività che ha caratterizzato gli anni 20
che non fanno niente, ha suggerito, offerto la prova migliore di 
intelligenza.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η δεκαετία του '20 και η δεκαετία του '30 προκάλεσαν 
τις νέες μορφές του δημοφιλούς χιούμορ, χιούμορ με μια περίπλοκη
άκρη που προήλθε από μια πιό ακμάζουσα, κοσμοπολίτικη αστική 
εμπειρία. Στη Νέα Υόρκη, ένας κύκλος των ευγενικών 
ευθυμογράφων με ένα εθνικό ακροατήριο αυξήθηκε γύρω από το 
περιοδικό Νεοϋρκέζου και τη διάσημη "algonquin διάσκεψη 
στρογγυλής τραπέζης," μια άτυπη ομάδα που συναντήθηκε 
περιστασιακά στο algonquin ξενοδοχείο. Ειρωνική, 
πνευματώδης, υπογραμμίζοντας το παιχνίδι λέξης και "στα αστεία," 
η εργασία Νεοϋρκέζου Benchley, Thurber, Perelman, και 
Dorothy Parker σατίρισαν τις αξιώσεις της συνηθισμένης ζωής 
μεσαίων τάξεων. "Κάνετε τα έντομα σκέφτεται;," ένα 
δοκίμιο του 1922 από Robert Benchley, χλεύασε gleefully
τον επιτηδευμένο τόνο της αμερικανικής επιστήμης, καθώς επίσης 
και τη λατρεία του pep, παραγωγικότητα, και η δραστηριότητα που 
χαρακτήρισε τη δεκαετία του '20 μην κάνοντας τίποτα, αυτό 
πρότεινε, πρόσφερε τα καλύτερα στοιχεία της νοημοσύνης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los años 20 y los años 30 dieron lugar a nuevas 
formas del humor popular, humor con un borde sofisticado trazado de 
una experiencia urbana más próspera, más cosmopolita. En 
Nueva York, un círculo de los humoristas del urbane con una 
audiencia nacional se levantó alrededor del compartimiento nuevo de 
Yorker y del "vector redondo famoso de Algonquin," un grupo informal 
que satisfizo de vez en cuando en el hotel de Algonquin. 
Irónico, ingenioso, acentuando el juego de la palabra y "en 
bromas," el nuevo trabajo de Yorker de Benchley, Thurber, Perelman, y 
Dorothy Parker satirized los pretensions de la vida ordinaria de la 
clase media. "Haga Los Insectos Piensan?," un ensayo 1922 
de Roberto Benchley, gleefully de imitación el tono pretentious de la
ciencia americana, así como el culto del pep, de la productividad, y 
de la actividad que caracterizó los años 20 que no hacían nada, 
sugirió, ofrecido la mejor evidencia de la inteligencia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086093</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105675</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/do-insects-think-robert-benchley-satirizes-science</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
