<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105042</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105042</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206320</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Sioux Treaty of 1868</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Sioux Vertrag von 1868</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Traité de Sioux de 1868</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O tratado de Sioux de 1868</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Trattato del Sioux di 1868</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η σιού Συνθήκη 1868</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El tratado de Sioux de 1868</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines Native American sovereignty and the Constitutional power granted to the president and the Senate to make treaties with foreign nations. The site presents the Treaty and related documents, including a photograph of the Indian leader, Spotted Tail. Explanatory text, materials for teachers, and links to further resources accompany the documents.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft gebürtige amerikanische Hoheit und 
konstitutionelle die Energie, die dem Präsidenten und dem Senat 
bewilligt wird, um Verträge mit fremden Nationen zu bilden. Die
Site stellt den Vertrag und die in Verbindung stehenden Dokumente, 
einschließlich eine Fotographie des indischen Führers, beschmutztes 
Endstück dar. Erläuternder Text, Materialien für Lehrer und 
Links zu den weiteren Betriebsmitteln begleiten die Dokumente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine la souveraineté américaine indigène et 
la puissance constitutionnelle accordée au président et au sénat 
pour faire des traités avec des nations étrangères. Le site 
présente le Traité et les documents relatifs, y compris une 
photographie de l'amorce indienne, queue repèrée. Le texte 
explicatif, les matériaux pour des professeurs, et les liens d'autres
à ressources accompagnent les documents.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina o sovereignty americano nativo e a 
potência constitutional concedida ao presidente e ao senate para 
fazer tratados com nações extrangeiras. O local apresenta o 
tratado e os originais relacionados, including uma fotografia do 
líder indian, cauda manchada. O texto explanatório, os 
materiais para professores, e as ligações a uns recursos mais 
adicionais acompanham os originais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina la sovranità americana natale e l'potenza
costituzionale assegnata al presidente ed al senato per fare i 
trattati con le nazioni straniere. Il luogo presenta il Trattato
ed i documenti relativi, compreso una fotografia del capo 
indiano, coda macchiata. Il testo esplicativo, i materiali per 
gli insegnanti ed i collegamenti ad ulteriori risorse accompagnano i 
documenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει την εγγενή αμερικανική κυριαρχία και τη 
συνταγματική δύναμη που χορηγείται στον Πρόεδρο και τη Σύγκλητο 
για να κάνει τις συνθήκες με τα ξένα έθνη. Η περιοχή 
παρουσιάζει τη Συνθήκη και τα σχετικά έγγραφα, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης μιας φωτογραφίας του ινδικού ηγέτη, 
επισημασμένη ουρά. Το επεξηγηματικό κείμενο, τα υλικά για 
τους δασκάλους, και οι συνδέσεις με τα περαιτέρω στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς συνοδεύουν τα έγγραφα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina soberanía americana nativa y la potencia 
constitucional concedida al presidente y al senado para hacer tratados
con naciones no nativas. El sitio presenta el tratado y los 
documentos relacionados, incluyendo una fotografía del arranque de 
cinta indio, cola manchada. El texto explicativo, los materiales
para los profesores, y las conexiones a otros recursos acompañan los 
documentos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206320</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105042</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-sioux-treaty-of-1868</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
