<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105351</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105351</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087090</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"There Grew Up this Whole Culture and Feeling of Sisterhood:" Shelley Ettinger Recalls Working for the Ann Arbor Bus Company</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wuchsen oben diese vollständige Kultur und 
Gefühl von Sisterhood:" Shelley Ettinger Rückrufe, die für 
die Ann Arbor Bus-Firma arbeiten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"là a accru vers le haut ces culture et sentiment
entiers de fraternité :" Rappels de Shelley Ettinger 
fonctionnant pour la compagnie de bus d'Ann Arbor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"cresceu acima estes cultura e sentimento inteiros
do sisterhood:" Recordações de Shelley Ettinger que trabalham 
para a companhia de barra-ônibus de Ann Arbor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ha sviluppato in su queste coltura e sensibilità
intere del sisterhood:" Richiami di Shelley Ettinger che 
funzionano per l'azienda di bus de Ann Arbor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αυξήθηκε επάνω αυτόν τον ολόκληρο πολιτισμό και το 
αίσθημα της αδελφότητας:" Οι ανακλήσεις Ettinger 
Shelley που λειτουργούν για το Αν Αρμπορ μεταφέρουν την 
επιχείρηση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"creció para arriba esta cultura y sensación 
enteros de la hermandad:" Memorias de Shelley Ettinger que 
trabajan para la compañía de megabus de Ann Arbor</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Although the 1970's saw an increase of women entering non-traditional and unionized jobs, many skilled and building trades remained effectively closed to women. As a result, in many cities throughout the 1970's and 1980's, private and city bus companies provided important opportunities for women interested in non-traditional jobs. Boasting large numbers of women and lesbians and an atmosphere of social tolerance, these jobs were seen as gay-friendly and provided female workers with a strong voice in union politics and a sense of community and solidarity. Shelley Ettinger took a bus job in the midst of a bus strike in Ann Arbor, Michigan in 1977. Encouraged to join by other lesbians, Ettinger remembered an atmosphere of female and lesbian camaraderie that expanded beyond the bus yard into social gatherings and soft-ball games.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Obgleich die siebziger Jahre eine Zunahme der 
Frauen sahen, die nicht traditionel hereinkommen und Jobs unionized, 
blieb viel erfahrenes und Baugewerbe effektiv zu den Frauen 
geschlossen. Infolgedessen in vielen Städte während der 
siebziger Jahre und der achtziger Jahre, stellten private und 
Stadtbusfirmen wichtige Gelegenheiten für die Frauen zur Verfügung, 
die an nicht traditionelen Jobs interessiert wurden. Viele 
Frauen und Lesbier und eine Atmosphäre der Sozialtoleranz rühmend, 
wurden diese Jobs als homosexuell-freundliches und vorausgesetzt 
weibliche Arbeiter mit einer starken Stimme in der Anschlußpolitik 
und einer Richtung der Gemeinschaft und der solidarität gesehen. 
Shelley Ettinger nahm einen Busjob in der Mitte eines 
Busschlages in Ann Arbor, Michigan 1977. Angeregt, um durch 
andere Lesbier, Ettinger zu verbinden erinnerte sich eine an 
Atmosphäre des weiblichen und lesbischen Kameradschaftsgeisten, die 
über dem Busyard hinaus in Sozialversammlungen und in Soft-ballspiele
erweiterte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bien que les années 70 aient vu une augmentation 
des femmes les travaux non traditionnels et syndiqués 
entrants dans, beaucoup d'industries du bâtiment habiles et sont 
demeurées pertinemment fermées aux femmes. En conséquence, 
dans beaucoup de villes tout au long des années 70 et des années 80,
les compagnies privées et de ville de bus ont présenté des moyens 
importants des femmes intéressées aux travaux non traditionnels. 
Revendiquant un grand nombre de femmes et de lesbiennes et une 
atmosphère de tolérance sociale, ces travaux ont été vus en tant 
que gai-amical et si les ouvriers féminins avec une voix forte dans 
la politique des syndicats et un sens de la communauté et de la 
solidarité. Shelley Ettinger a pris un travail de bus au milieu
d'une grève de bus à Ann Arbor, Michigan en 1977. Encouragé 
à se joindre par d'autres lesbiennes, Ettinger s'est rappelé une 
atmosphère de camaraderie femelle et lesbienne qui a augmenté au 
delà de la cour de bus dans des rassemblements et des jeux sociaux du
base-ball.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Embora os 1970's vissem um aumento das mulheres 
que entram non-traditional e unionized trabalhos, muitos comércios 
hábeis e de edifício remanesceram fechados eficazmente às mulheres.
Em conseqüência, em muitas cidades durante todo os 1970's e os
1980's, as companhias confidenciais e da cidade de barra-ônibus 
forneceram oportunidades importantes para as mulheres interessadas em 
trabalhos non-traditional. Boasting um grande número mulheres e
lesbians e uma atmosfera da tolerância social, estes trabalhos foram 
vistos como gay-amigável e desde que trabalhadores fêmeas com uma 
voz forte na política da união e um sentido da comunidade e do 
solidarity. Shelley Ettinger fêz exame de um trabalho da 
barra-ônibus no meio de uma batida da barra-ônibus em Ann Arbor, 
Michigan em 1977. Incentivado para juntar por outros lesbians, 
Ettinger recordou uma atmosfera do camaraderie fêmea e lesbian que 
expandisse além da jarda da barra-ônibus em recolhimentos e em jogos
sociais do soft-ball.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Anche se gli anni 70 hanno visto un aumento delle 
donne che entrano non tradizionale ed unionized i lavori, molti 
commerci di costruzione ed esperti sono rimasto efficacemente 
chiusi alle donne. Di conseguenza, in molte città durante 
gli anni 70 e gli anni 80, le aziende della città e riservate di bus 
hanno offerto le occasioni importanti delle donne interessate ai 
lavori non tradizionali. Vantandosi tantissime donne e lesbiche 
e un atmosfera di tolleranza sociale, questi lavori sono stati visti 
come gay-friendly e se operai femminili con una voce forte nella 
politica del sindacato e un senso di Comunità e della solidarietà. 
Shelley Ettinger ha preso ad un lavoro del bus in mezzo a un 
colpo del bus a Ann Arbor, Michigan in 1977. Consigliato a per 
unirsi da altre lesbiche, Ettinger si è ricordato di un atmosfera di 
camaraderie femminile e lesbico che si è espanso oltre l'iarda del 
bus nelle riunioni e nei giochi sociali di soft-ball.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αν και η δεκαετία του '70 εβλέίδε μια αύξηση 
των γυναικών που εισάγουν τις μη παραδοσιακές και συνδικαλιστικές 
εργασίες, πολλά ειδικευμένα και εμπόρια οικοδόμησης παρέμειναν 
αποτελεσματικά κλειστά στις γυναίκες. Σαν αποτέλεσμα, σε 
πολλές πόλεις καθ' όλη τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '70 και της 
δεκαετίας του '80, οι επιχειρήσεις ιδιωτικών και διαδρόμων πόλεων
παρείχαν τις σημαντικές ευκαιρίες για τις γυναίκες ενδιαφερόμενες
στις μη παραδοσιακές εργασίες. Οι μεγάλοι αριθμοί 
καυχησιολογίας γυναικών και λεσβιών και μιας ατμόσφαιρας της 
κοινωνικής ανοχής, αυτές οι εργασίες εβλέίδαν όπως 
εύθυμος-φιλικοί και παρείχαν στη γυναίκα εργαζόμενοι μια ισχυρή 
φωνή στην πολιτική ένωσης και μια αίσθηση της κοινότητας και της 
αλληλεγγύης. Το Shelley Ettinger ανάλαβε δουλειά 
διαδρόμων στη μέση μιας απεργίας διαδρόμων σε ANN Arbor, 
Μίτσιγκαν σε 1977, που ενθαρρύνθηκαν για να ενώσουν από άλλες 
λεσβίες, Ettinger αναφερόμενο μια ατμόσφαιρα της θηλυκής και 
λεσβιακής συναδελφικότητας που επεκτάθηκε πέρα από το ναυπηγείο 
διαδρόμων στις κοινωνικές συλλογές και soft-ball τα παιχνίδια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Aunque los años 70 consideraron un aumento de las
mujeres que entraban no tradicional y unionized trabajos, muchos 
comercios expertos y de edificio seguían cerrados con eficacia a las 
mujeres. Consecuentemente, en muchas ciudades a través de los 
años 70 y de los años 80, las compañías privadas y de la ciudad de
megabus proporcionaron a las oportunidades importantes para las 
mujeres interesadas en trabajos no tradicionales. Jactándose a 
una gran cantidad de mujeres y de lesbianas y una atmósfera de la 
tolerancia social, estos trabajos fueron considerados como 
gay-friendly y con tal que los trabajadores femeninos con una voz
fuerte en política de la unión y un sentido de la comunidad y de la 
solidaridad. Shelley Ettinger tomó un trabajo del megabus en el
medio de una huelga del megabus en Ann Arbor, Michigan en 1977. 
Animado para ensamblar por otras lesbianas, Ettinger recordó 
una atmósfera del camaraderie femenino y lesbiano que se amplió más
allá de la yarda del megabus en reuniones y juegos sociales del 
beísbol con pelota blanda.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087090</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105351</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/there-grew-up-this-whole-culture-and-feeling-of-sisterhood-shelley-ettinger-recalls-working-for-the-ann-arbor-bus-company</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
