<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108234</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108234</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087028</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Project Method": Child-Centeredness in Progressive Education</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Die Projekt-Methode": Kind-Centeredness in 
der progressiven Ausbildung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"La Méthode de Projet" : 
Enfant-Centeredness dans l'éducation progressive</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O Método Do Projeto": 
Criança-Centeredness na instrução progressiva</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Metodo Di Progetto": 
Bambino-Centeredness nella formazione progressiva</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η μέθοδος προγράμματοσ": Παιδί- Centeredness 
στην προοδευτική εκπαίδευση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"El Método Del Proyecto": 
Niño-Centeredness en la educación progresiva</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the early 20th century, progressive education reformers promoted a pedagogy that emphasized flexible, critical thinking and looked to schools for the political and social regeneration of the nation. The founding of the Progressive Education Association (PEA) in 1919 accompanied the growing prestige of leading educational theorists at Teachers College, Columbia University. Increasingly, however, the movement became preoccupied with methodology and, specifically, with the controversial "child-centered" approach, later criticized by both radicals and conservatives. Imbued with Freudianism and child psychology, the child-centered method asked teachers to position each child at the center of the learning process by focusing activities around the interests of the pupil. William H. Kilpatrick, a professor at Teachers College, outlined the theory of "wholehearted purposeful activity" by a child as the  pinnacle  of postwar progressive education in the following, widely-read essay, initially published in the  Teachers College Record  in 1918.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im frühen 20. Jahrhundert förderten progressive 
Ausbildung Reformer ein pedagogy, das das flexible, kritische 
Denken hervorhob und schauten zu den Schulen nach der politischen und 
Sozialregeneration der Nation. Die Gründung der progressiven 
Ausbildung Verbindung (ERBSE) in 1919 begleitete das wachsende 
Prestige des Führens der pädagogischen Theoretiker an den Lehrern 
Hochschule, Kolumbien Universität. In zunehmendem Maße jedoch 
wurde die Bewegung mit Methodenlehre und spezifisch mit dem 
umstrittenen "Kind-zentrierte" die Annäherung in Anspruch genommen, 
später kritisiert von den Radikalen und von den Konservativen. 
Erfüllt mit Freudianism und Kindpsychologie, bat die 
Kind-zentrierte Methode Lehrer, jedes Kind in der Mitte des 
Lernprozesses in Position zu bringen, indem sie Aktivitäten um die 
Interessen der Pupille fokussierte. William H. Kilpatrick, ein 
Professor an der Lehrer-Hochschule, umriß die Theorie "der 
uneingeschränkten zweckmäßigen Aktivität" durch ein Kind als der 
Pinnacle der progressiven Nachkriegsausbildung im folgenden, breit-las
den Versuch, zuerst veröffentlicht im Lehrer-Hochschulsatz 1918.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En début du 20ème siècle, les réformateurs 
progressifs d'éducation ont favorisé une pédagogie qui a souligné 
la pensée flexible et critique et ont regardé aux écoles pour la 
régénération politique et sociale de la nation. La fondation 
de l'association progressive d'éducation (POIS) dans 1919 a 
accompagné le prestige croissant de mener les théoriciens éducatifs
aux professeurs université, université de Colombie. De plus en
plus, cependant, le mouvement est devenu préoccupé avec la 
méthodologie et, spécifiquement, avec le controversé "enfant-a 
centré" l'approche, plus tard critiquée par des radicaux et des 
conservateurs. Imprégné avec Freudianism et psychologie 
d'enfant, la méthode enfant-centrée a demandé à des professeurs de
placer chaque enfant au centre de l'apprentissage en focalisant des 
activités autour des intérêts de la pupille. William H. 
Kilpatrick, un professeur à l'université de professeurs, a tracé 
les grandes lignes de la théorie "d'activité utile sincère" par un 
enfant comme pinacle d'éducation progressive d'après-guerre dans le 
suivant, large-a lu l'essai, au commencement édité dans 
l'enregistrement d'université de professeurs en 1918.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No 20o século adiantado, os reformers 
progressivos da instrução promoveram um pedagogy que emfatizasse 
pensar flexível, crítico e olharam às escolas para a regeneração 
política e social da nação. Fundar da associação 
progressiva da instrução (ERVILHA) em 1919 acompanhou o prestige 
crescente de conduzir a theorists educacionais em professores 
faculdade, universidade de Colômbia. Cada vez mais, entretanto,
o movimento tornou-se preoccupied com metodologia e, especificamente, 
com o controverso "criança-centrou" a aproximação, criticada mais 
tarde  por radicais e por conservadores. Imbued com Freudianism 
e psychology da criança, o método criança-centrado pediu que os 
professores posicionassem cada criança no centro do processo de 
aprendizagem focalizando atividades em torno dos interesses da pupila.
William H. Kilpatrick, um professor na faculdade dos 
professores, esboçou a teoria "da atividade purposeful wholehearted" 
por uma criança como o pinnacle da instrução progressiva postwar no
seguinte, largo-leu o essay, publicado inicialmente no registro da 
faculdade dos professores em 1918.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo, i reformers 
progressivi di formazione hanno promosso un pedagogy che ha dato 
risalto a pensare flessibile e critico ed hanno osservato alle scuole 
per la rigenerazione politica e sociale della nazione. Fondare 
dell'associazione progressiva di formazione (PISELLI) in 1919 ha 
accompagnato il prestigio crescente di condurre i teorici educativi 
agli insegnanti l'università, università della Colombia. 
Sempre più, tuttavia, il movimento è stato preoccupato con la 
metodologia e, specificamente, con il discutibile "bambino-ha 
centrato" il metodo, più successivamente criticato sia dai radicali 
che dai conservatori. Imbued con Freudianism e la psicologia del
bambino, il metodo bambino-centrato ha chiesto agli insegnanti di 
posizionare ogni bambino al centro dell'apprendimento mettendo a fuoco
le attività intorno agli interessi della pupilla. William H. 
Kilpatrick, un professore all'università degli insegnanti, ha 
descritto la teoria "di attività utile illimitata" da un bambino come
il pinnacle di formazione progressiva dopoguerra in quanto segue, 
largo-ha letto il saggio, inizialmente pubblicato nel record 
dell'università degli insegnanti in 1918.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα, οι προοδευτικοί 
μεταρρυθμιστές εκπαίδευσης προώθησαν μια παιδαγωγική που 
υπογράμμισε την εύκαμπτη, κρίσιμη σκέψη και κοίταξε στα σχολεία 
για την πολιτική και κοινωνική αναγέννηση του έθνους. Η 
ίδρυση της προοδευτικής ένωσης εκπαίδευσης (ΜΠΙΖΕΛΙ) το 1919 
συνόδευσε το αυξανόμενο γόητρο των κορυφαίων εκπαιδευτικών 
θεωρητικών στο κολλέγιο δασκάλων, πανεπιστήμιο της Κολούμπια. 
Όλο και περισσότερο, εντούτοις, η μετακίνηση έγινε 
ανησυχημένη με τη μεθοδολογία και, συγκεκριμένα, με την 
αμφισβητούμενη "παιδί-κεντροθετημένη" προσέγγιση, που επικρίθηκε 
αργότερα και από τους ριζοσπάστες και από τα συντηρητικά. 
Εμποτισμένη με την ψυχολογία Freudianism και παιδιών, η 
παιδί-κεντροθετημένη μέθοδος ζήτησε από τους δασκάλους για να 
τοποθετήσει κάθε παιδί στο κέντρο της διαδικασίας εκμάθησης με 
τη συγκέντρωση των δραστηριοτήτων γύρω από τα συμφέροντα του 
μαθητή. Θ*Ωηλληαμ H. Kilpatrick, ένας καθηγητής στο 
κολλέγιο δασκάλων, περιέγραψε τη θεωρία της "ειλικρινούς 
σκόπιμης δραστηριότητασ" από ένα παιδί ως πυραμίδα της 
μεταπολεμικής προοδευτικής εκπαίδευσης στον ακόλουθο, που 
διαβάστηκε το δοκίμιο, που δημοσιεύθηκε αρχικά στο αρχείο 
κολλεγίου δασκάλων το 1918.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el vigésimo siglo temprano, los reformadores 
progresivos de la educación promovieron un pedagogy que acentuó el 
pensamiento flexible, crítico y miraban a las escuelas para la 
regeneración política y social de la nación. La fundación de
la asociación progresiva de la educación (GUISANTE) en 1919 
acompañó el prestigio cada vez mayor de conducir a teóricos 
educativos en los profesores universidad, universidad de Colombia. 
Cada vez más, sin embargo, el movimiento se preocupó con la 
metodología y, específicamente, con el polémico "niño-centro'" el 
acercamiento, criticado más adelante por los radicales y los 
conservadores. Imbuido con Freudianism y psicología del niño, 
el método niño-centrado pidió que los profesores colocaran a cada 
niño en el centro del proceso de aprendizaje enfocando actividades 
alrededor de los intereses de la pupila. Guillermo H. 
Kilpatrick, profesor en la universidad de los profesores, contorneó 
la teoría de la "actividad útil sincera" por un niño como el 
pináculo de la educación progresiva de la posguerra en el siguiente,
ancho-leyo' el ensayo, publicado inicialmente en el expediente de la 
universidad de los profesores en 1918.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087028</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108234</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-project-method-child-centeredness-in-progressive-education</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
