<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108321</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108321</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086202</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">GM Rejects Reuther's Call to "Open the Books": The Post-WWII Strike Wave</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Aufruf GR. Ausschußreuthers "öffnen die 
Bücher": Die Pfosten-WWII Schlag-Welle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'appel de Reuther d'anomalies de GM "ouvrent les 
livres" : La Vague de Grève de Poteau-WWII</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O atendimento de Reuther das rejeições do GM 
"abre os livros": A Onda Da Batida Do Borne-WWII</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La chiamata del Reuther di scarti di GM "apre i 
libri": L'Onda Di Colpo Dell'Alberino-WWII</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κλήση Reuther απορριμάτων της GM για "να ανοίξει 
τα βιβλία": Το κύμα απεργίας μετα- Wwii</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La llamada de Reuther de los rechazos del GM "abre
los libros": La Onda De la Huelga Del Poste-WWII</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The end of World War II unleashed a new "war" at home--a war that pitted workers against employers. The year following V-J day saw more strikes than any other twelve-month period in American history: 4,630 work stoppages involving 5 million strikers and 120 million days of lost work. One of the most revealing of the postwar confrontations between labor and capital came in the November 1945 strike by 320,000 autoworkers against the nation's largest corporation, General Motors. UAW leader Walter Reuther took a new and radical negotiating stance, arguing that GM could afford to increase wages without increasing prices. In the process, Reuther challenged what had been a fundamental corporate prerogative to set its own prices. GM sharply rejected his demand that they "open the books" and show why they couldn't afford both lower prices and higher wages. That confrontation was captured in this transcript from one of the negotiating sessions.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Ende des Zweiten Weltkrieges unleashed einen 
neuen "Krieg" zu Hause -- ein Krieg, der Arbeiter gegen Arbeitgeber 
Löcher bildete. Das Jahr sah V-J folgend Tag mehr Schläge als 
jede mögliche andere Zwölfmonat Periode in der amerikanischen 
Geschichte: 4.630 Arbeitsniederlegungen, die 5 Million 
Schlaggeräte und 120 Million Tage verlorene Arbeit mit einbeziehen. 
Ein des Aufdeckens der Nachkriegskonfrontationen zwischen Arbeit
und Kapital kam in den November 1945 Schlag durch 320.000 autoworkers 
gegen die größte Korporation der Nation, General Motors. Uaw 
Führer Walter Reuther nahm eine neue und radikale vermittelnde 
Position und argumentierte, daß GR. sich leisten könnte, Löhne ohne
zunehmende Preise zu erhöhen. Im Prozeß forderte Reuther 
heraus, was ein grundlegendes korporatives Vorrecht gewesen war, zum 
seiner eigenen Preise einzustellen. GR. wies scharf seine 
Nachfrage zurück, daß sie "die Bücher" öffnen und zeigen, warum 
sie nicht niedrigere Preise und höhere Löhne sich leisten konnten. 
Diese Konfrontation wurde in dieser Abschrift von einer der 
vermittelnden Sitzungen erfaßt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La fin de la deuxième guerre mondiale a lâché 
une nouvelle "guerre" à la maison -- une guerre qui a piqué des 
ouvriers contre des employeurs. L'année le jour suivant V-J a 
vu plus de grèves que n'importe quelle autre période de douze-mois 
dans l'histoire américaine : 4.630 arrêts de travail 
impliquant 5 millions de butées et 120 millions de jours de travail 
perdu. Un de la indication des confrontations d'après-guerre 
entre le travail et le capital est venu dans la grève de novembre 
1945 par 320.000 autoworkers contre la plus grande société de la 
nation, General Motors. Le Chef Walter Reuther de t.u.a. a pris 
une nouvelle et radicale position de négociation, arguant du fait que
le GM pourrait avoir les moyens d'augmenter des salaires sans prix 
croissants. Dans le processus, Reuther a défié ce qui avait 
été une prérogative de corporation fondamentale pour fixer ses 
propres prix. Le GM a brusquement rejeté sa demande qu'ils 
"ouvrent les livres" et montrent pourquoi ils ne pourraient pas avoir 
les moyens des prix inférieurs et des salaires plus élevés. 
Cette confrontation a été capturée dans cette transcription 
d'une des sessions de négociation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O fim da segunda guerra mundial desencadeou uma 
"guerra nova" na HOME -- uma guerra que pitted trabalhadores de 
encontro aos empregadores. O ano que segue o dia de V-J viu mais
batidas do que todo o outro período de doze-mês no history 
americano: 4.630 paradas de trabalho que envolvem 5 milhão 
grevistas e 120 milhão dias de trabalho perdido. Um de revelar 
dos confrontations postwar entre o trabalho e o capital veio na batida
de novembro 1945 por 320.000 autoworkers de encontro ao corporation o 
maior da nação, General Motors. O líder Walter Reuther do UAW
fêz exame de um stance negociando novo e radical, discutindo que o GM
poderia ter recursos para aumentar salários sem preços crescentes. 
No processo, Reuther desafiou o que tinha sido um prerogative 
incorporado fundamental para ajustar seus próprios preços. O 
GM rejeitou agudamente sua demanda que "abrem os livros" e mostram 
porque não poderiam ter recursos para  uns preços mais baixos e uns 
salários mais elevados. Esse confrontation foi capturado neste 
transcript de uma das sessões negociando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La conclusione della seconda guerra mondiale ha 
liberato una nuova "guerra" nel paese -- una guerra che ha scavato gli
operai contro i datori di lavoro. L'anno che segue il giorno di 
V-J ha visto più colpi che qualunque altro periodo di dodici-mese 
nella storia americana: 4.630 interruzioni di lavoro che 
coinvolgono 5 milione percussori e 120 milione giorni di lavoro perso.
Uno del rivelare dei confronti dopoguerra fra il lavoro ed 
il capitale è venuto nel colpo di novembre 1945 da 320.000 
autoworkers contro la più grande società della nazione, General 
Motors. Il capo Walter Reuther del UAW ha preso una nuova
e posizione di negoziazione radicale, sostenente che il GM potrebbe 
permettersi di aumentare gli stipendi senza prezzi aumentanti. 
Nel processo, Reuther ha sfidato che cosa era stato una 
prerogativa corporativa fondamentale per fissare i relativi propri 
prezzi. Il GM ha rifiutato acutamente la sua richiesta che 
"aprono i libri" e mostrano perchè non potrebbero permettersi sia i 
prezzi più bassi che gli più alti stipendi. Quel confronto è 
stato bloccato in questa trascrizione da una delle sessioni di 
negoziazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το τέλος του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ εξαπέλυσε έναν 
νέο "πόλεμο" στο σπίτι -- ένας πόλεμος που κοίλανε τους 
εργαζομένους ενάντια στους εργοδότες. Το έτος μετά από την
ημέρα β-j εβλέίδε περισσότερες απεργίες από 
οποιαδήποτε άλληδήποτε περίοδο δωδεκαμήνου στην αμερικανική 
ιστορία: 4.630 στάσεις εργασίας που περιλαμβάνουν 5 
εκατομμύριο απεργούς και 120 εκατομμύριο ημέρες της χαμένης 
εργασίας. Μια από την αποκάλυψη των μεταπολεμικών 
αντιπαραθέσεων μεταξύ της εργασίας και του κεφαλαίου ήρθε στην 
απεργία Νοεμβρίου 1945 από 320.000 autoworkers ενάντια 
στη μεγαλύτερη εταιρία του έθνους, General Motors. UAW ο ηγέτης walter Reuther πήρε μια νέα και ριζική θέση
διαπραγμάτευσης, υποστηρίζοντας ότι η GM θα μπορούσε να 
αντέξει οικονομικά να αυξήσει τις αμοιβές χωρίς αυξανόμενες 
τιμές. Στη διαδικασία, Reuther προκάλεσε αυτό που ήταν 
ένα θεμελιώδες εταιρικό δικαίωμα για να θέσει τις τιμές του. 
Η GM απέρριψε αισθητά την απαίτησή του ότι "ανοίγουν τα
βιβλία" και εμφανίζουν γιατί δεν θα μπορούσαν να αντέξουν 
οικονομικά και τις χαμηλότερες τιμές και τις υψηλότερες αμοιβές. 
Εκείνη η αντιμετώπιση συλλήφθηκε σε αυτό το αντίγραφο από 
μια από τις περιόδους επικοινωνίας διαπραγμάτευσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El final de la Segunda Guerra Mundial destrailló 
una nueva "guerra" en el país -- una guerra que marcó con hoyos a 
trabajadores contra patrones. El año que seguía el día de V-J
consideró más huelgas que cualquier otro período del doce-mes en 
historia americana: 4.630 paradas de trabajo que implican 5 
millones de huelguistas y 120 millones de días de trabajo perdido. 
Uno de revelar de las confrontaciones de la posguerra entre el 
trabajo y el capital vino en la huelga de noviembre 1945 por 320.000 
autoworkers contra la corporación más grande de la nación, General 
Motors. El arranque de cinta Walter Reuther del UAW tomó una 
nueva y radical postura de negociación, discutiendo que el GM podría
producir aumentar salarios sin precios de aumento. En el 
proceso, Reuther desafió cuál había sido una prerrogativa 
corporativa fundamental para fijar sus propios precios. El GM 
rechazó sostenidamente su demanda que "abren los libros" y muestran 
porqué no podrían producir precios bajos y salarios más altos. 
Esa confrontación fue capturada en esta transcripción a partir
de la una de las sesiones de negociación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086202</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108321</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/gm-rejects-reuthers-call-to-open-the-books-the-post-wwii-strike-wave</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
