<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106125</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106125</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087307</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Healthy Public Opinion": Terence V. Powderly Distances the Knights of Labor from the Haymarket Martyrs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Eine Gesunde Öffentliche Meinung": Terence
V. Powderly Distances die Ritter der Arbeit von den Haymarket 
Märtyrern</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Un Opinion Publique Sain" : Terence V. 
Powderly Distances les chevaliers du travail des martyres de 
Haymarket</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Uma Opinião Pública Saudável": Terence 
V. Powderly Distância os knights do trabalho dos martyrs de 
Haymarket</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Un'Opinione Pubblica Sana": Terence V. 
Powderly Distances i cavalieri del Lavoro dai martyrs di 
Haymarket</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μια υγιής κοινή γνώμη": Terence Θ*Β. 
Powderly Distances οι ιππότες της εργασίας από τους μάρτυρες
Haymarket</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Una Opinión Pública Sana": Terence V. 
Powderly Distances los caballeros del trabajo de los martyrs de 
Haymarket</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Haymarket Affair, as it is known today, began on May 1, 1886 when a labor protester threw a bomb at police, killing one officer, and ended with the arrest of eight anarchist leaders, three of whom were executed and none of whom was ever linked to the bombing. Some labor organizations saw the executed men as martyrs and tried to rally support but in the end, the hanging of the Haymarket anarchists not only emboldened capitalists, it undercut labor unity. Knights of Labor leader Terence V. Powderly was desperate to distance his organization from the accused anarchists and maintain the order's respectability. In this excerpt from his 1890 autobiography Powderly explained his decision three years earlier to keep mainstream labor out of the furor that surrounded the Haymarket Affair.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Haymarket Angelegenheit, da es heute bekannt, 
fing an Mai 1, 1886 an, als ein Arbeitsprotester eine Bombe an der 
Polizei warf und einen Offizier beendete, und beendete mit dem 
Anhalten von acht Anarchist Führern, drei von, wurden wem 
durchgeführt und keine von, wurde wem überhaupt mit der 
Bombardierung gebunden. Einige Gewerkschaften sahen die 
durchgeführten Männer als Märtyrer und versuchten, Support zu 
sammeln, aber im Ende, ermutigte das Hängen der Haymarket Anarchisten
nicht nur Kapitalisten, es unterschnitt Arbeitseinheit. Ritter 
des Gewerkschaftsführers Terence V. Powderly waren hoffnungslos, 
seine Organisation von den beschuldigten Anarchisten zu überholen und
den Respectability der Ordnung beizubehalten. In diesem Excerpt 
von seiner Autobiographie 1890 erklärte Powderly seine Entscheidung 
drei Jahre früher Unterhaltmainstreamarbeit aus dem furor heraus, das
die Haymarket Angelegenheit umgab.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'affaire de Haymarket, car on le connaît 
aujourd'hui, a commencé 1 mai 1886 où un protestataire de travail a
jeté une panne à la police, détruisant un officier, et a terminé 
avec l'arrestation de huit amorces d'anarchiste, trois de qui ont 
été exécutés et aucun de qui a été jamais joint au bombardement.
Quelques organismes de travail ont vu les hommes exécutés 
comme martyres et ont essayé de rassembler le support mais à la fin,
s'arrêter des anarchistes de Haymarket a non seulement encouragé des
capitalistes, il a dégagé l'unité de travail. Les chevaliers 
du dirigeant syndical Terence V. Powderly étaient désespérés pour 
distancer son organisation des anarchistes accusés et pour mettre à 
jour la respectabilité de la commande. Dans cet extrait de sa 
autobiographie 1890 Powderly a expliqué sa décision trois ans de 
plus tôt au travail de courant principal de subsistance hors du furor
qui a entouré l'affaire de Haymarket.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O caso de Haymarket, porque se sabe hoje, começou
maio em 1, 1886 em que um protester labor jogou uma bomba em 
polícias, matando um oficial, e terminou com a apreensão de oito 
líderes do anarquista, três de quem foram executadas e nenhuns de 
quem foi ligado sempre ao bombardeio. Algumas organizações 
labor viram os homens executados como martyrs e tentaram-nos rally a 
sustentação mas na extremidade, a suspensão dos capitalistas 
emboldened dos anarquistas de Haymarket não somente, undercut a 
unidade labor. Os knights do líder labor Terence V. Powderly 
eram desesperados distance sua organização dos anarquistas acusados 
e manter o respectability da ordem. Neste excerpt de seu 
autobiography 1890 Powderly explicou sua decisão três anos mais 
adiantada ao trabalho do mainstream do sustento fora do furor que 
cercou o caso de Haymarket.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'affare di Haymarket, poichè è conosciuto oggi,
ha cominciato maggio su 1, 1886 in cui un contestatore di lavoro ha 
gettato una bomba alla polizia, uccidendo un ufficiale e si è 
concluso con l'arresto di otto capi dell'anarchico, tre di chi
sono stati eseguiti e nessun di chi è stato collegato mai al 
bombardamento. Alcune organizzazioni di lavoro hanno visto gli
uomini eseguiti come martyrs ed hanno provato a radunare il supporto 
ma alla fine, appendere dei capitalisti emboldened degli anarchici di 
Haymarket non soltanto, ha tagliato l'unità di lavoro. I 
cavalieri del capo Di lavoro Terence V. Powderly erano 
disperati distance la sua organizzazione dagli anarchici accusati ed 
effettuare il respectability dell'ordine. In questo brano dal 
suo autobiography 1890 Powderly ha spiegato la sua decisione più in 
anticipo tre anni al lavoro tradizionale di conservazione dal 
furor che ha circondato l'affare di Haymarket.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η υπόθεση Haymarket, δεδομένου ότι είναι γνωστή 
σήμερα, άρχισε σε Μάιος 1 ..1886 όταν έριξε ένας 
διαμαρτυρόμενος εργασίας μια βόμβα στην αστυνομία, που σκοτώνει 
έναν ανώτερο υπάλληλο, και τελείωσε με τη σύλληψη οκτώ ηγετών 
αναρχικών, τρεις από οποίοι εκτελέσθηκαν και κανένας του οποίου 
συνδέθηκε πάντα με το βομβαρδισμό. Μερικές οργανώσεις 
εργασίας εβλέίδαν τα εκτελεσμένα άτομα ως μάρτυρες και 
προσπάθησαν να συναθροίσουν την υποστήριξη αλλά στο τέλος, η 
ένωση των ενθαρρυνμένων κεφαλαιοκρατών αναρχικών Haymarket όχι
μόνο, περιέκοψε την ενότητα εργασίας. Οι ιππότες του ηγέτη
Terence Θ*Β. Powderly εργασίας ήταν απελπισμένοι για να 
απομακρύνουν την οργάνωσή του από τους κατηγορούμενους 
αναρχικούς και να διατηρήσουν τη σεβασμιότητα της κατάταξης. 
Σε αυτό το απόσπασμα από την αυτοβιογραφία 1890 του 
Powderly εξήγησε στην απόφασή του τρία έτη για να κρατήσει 
νωρίτερα την επικρατούσα εργασία από το σάλο που περιέβαλε την 
υπόθεση Haymarket.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El asunto de Haymarket, pues se sabe hoy, comenzó
1 de mayo de 1886 en que un manifestante de trabajo lanzó una bomba 
en el policía, matando a un oficial, y terminó con la detención de 
ocho arranques de cinta del anarquista, tres de quién fueron 
ejecutadas y ningunos de quién fue conectada siempre al bombardeo. 
Algunas organizaciones de trabajo consideraron a hombres 
ejecutados como martyrs e intentaron reunir la ayuda pero en el 
extremo, el colgar de los capitalistas emboldened de los anarquistas 
de Haymarket no solamente, socavó la unidad de trabajo. Los 
caballeros del arranque de cinta de trabajo Terence V. Powderly eran 
desesperados distanciar su organización de los anarquistas acusados y
mantener la respetabilidad de la orden. En este extracto de su 
autobiografía 1890 Powderly explicó su decisión tres años de 
anterior al trabajo de la corriente principal del mantiene fuera del 
furor que rodeó el asunto de Haymarket.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087307</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106125</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-healthy-public-opinion-terence-v-powderly-distances-the-knights-of-labor-from-the-haymarket-martyrs</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
