<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105509</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105509</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204072</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Moon Phases</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mond-Phasen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Phases de Lune</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fases Da Lua</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fasi Della Luna</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φάσεις φεγγαριών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fases De la Luna</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Moon Phases java applet provides an animated view of the moon, either from Earth, or from above the ecliptic. The animation changes phases and can be seen from a top view, earth view or both. The page also provides vocabulary terms for each of the phases and other interesting information.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Mond-Phasen Java applet liefert eine lebhafte 
Ansicht des Mondes, entweder von der Masse oder über von der 
Sonnenbahn. Die Animation ändert Phasen und kann von einer 
Draufsicht, von der Masse Ansicht oder von beiden gesehen werden. 
Die Seite stellt auch Wortschatzbezeichnungen für jede der 
Phasen und anderer interessanter Informationen zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Java applet de phases de lune fournit une vue 
animée de la lune, de la terre, ou de au-dessus de l'écliptique. 
L'animation change des phases et peut être vue d'une vue 
supérieure, de la vue de la terre ou de toutes les deux. La 
page fournit également des limites de vocabulaire pour chacune des 
phases et de toute autre information intéressante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Java applet das fases da lua fornece uma vista 
animated da lua, da terra, ou acima da eclíptica. O animation 
muda fases e pode ser visto de uma vista superior, da vista da terra 
ou de ambos. A página fornece também termos do vocabulário 
para cada uma das fases e da outra informação interessante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Java applet di fasi della luna fornisce una 
vista animata della luna, da terra, o sopra dal ecliptic. La 
animazione cambia le fasi e può essere vista da una vista superiore, 
dalla vista della terra o da entrambe. La pagina egualmente 
fornisce i termini di vocabolario per ciascuna delle fasi e di altre 
informazioni interessanti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το applet της Ιάβας φάσεων φεγγαριών παρέχει μια 
ζωντανεψοντη όψη του φεγγαριού, είτε από τη γη, είτε από επάνω 
από τον εκλειπτικό. Η ζωτικότητα αλλάζει τις φάσεις και 
μπορεί να δει και από μια κορυφαία όψη, τη γήινη όψη
ή τις δύο. Η σελίδα παρέχει επίσης τους όρους λεξιλογίου 
για κάθε μια από τις φάσεις και άλλες ενδιαφέρουσες πληροφορίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Java applet de las fases de la luna proporciona
a una vista animada de la luna, de la tierra, o sobre de la 
eclíptica. La animación cambia fases y se puede considerar de 
una visión superior, de la opinión de la tierra o de ambas. La
paginación también proporciona a los términos del vocabulario para 
cada uno de las fases y de la otra información interesante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CHRISTOPHER DOLAN
FN:CHRISTOPHER DOLAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770204072</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105509</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/moon-phases</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
