<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103818</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103818</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206675</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Civil War as Photographed by Mathematics and Statisticsew Brady</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Bürgerkrieg, wie durch Mathematics und 
Statisticsew Brady fotografiert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La guerre civile comme photographiée par 
Mathematics et Statisticsew Brady</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A guerra civil como fotografada por Matemática e 
por Statisticsew Brady</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La guerra civile come fotografata dalla 
Mathematics e da Statisticsew Brady</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο εμφύλιος πόλεμος όπως φωτογραφισμένος από 
Mathematics και Statisticsew Brady</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La guerra civil según lo fotografiado por 
Mathematics y Statisticsew Brady</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">asks students to visualize the Civil War by studying dozens of period photographs, and illustrates how the Civil War threatened the very purpose of the Constitution as stated in the Preamble. This lesson correlates to the National History Standards and the National Standards for Civics and Social Sciences. It also has cross-curricular connections with history, American studies, and language arts.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bittet Kursteilnehmer, den Bürgerkrieg, indem das
Studieren von von Dutzenden Periode Fotographien sichtbar zu machen, 
und veranschaulicht, wie der Bürgerkrieg den Zweck der Beschaffenheit
bedrohte, wie in der Präambel angegeben. Diese Lektion bezieht 
mit den nationalen Geschichte Standards und den nationalen Standards 
für Gemeinschaftskunde und Sozialwissenschaften aufeinander. 
Sie hat auch Kreuzlehrplananschlüsse mit Geschichte, 
amerikanischen Studien und Sprachenkünsten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">demande à des étudiants de visualiser la guerre 
civile en étudiant des douzaines de photographies de période, et 
illustre comment la guerre civile a menacé le but même de la 
constitution comme indiqué dans le préambule. Cette leçon se 
corrèle avec les normes nationales d'histoire et les normes 
nationales pour l'éducation civique et les sciences sociales. 
Elle a également les connexions croix-curriculaires avec 
l'histoire, les études américaines, et les arts de langage.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">pede que os estudantes visualizem a guerra civil 
estudando dúzias de fotografias do período, e ilustra como a guerra 
civil ameaçou a finalidade very do constitution como indicado no 
preamble. Esta lição correlaciona aos padrões nacionais do 
history e aos padrões nacionais para o civics e ciências sociais. 
Tem também conexões cruz-cross-curricular com o history, os 
estudos americanos, e as artes da língua.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">chiede agli allievi di prevedere la guerra civile 
studiando le dozzine delle fotografie di periodo ed illustra come la 
guerra civile ha minacciato lo scopo stesso della costituzione come 
dichiarato nella premessa. Questa lezione correla agli 
standard nazionali di storia ed agli standard nazionali per civics e 
le scienze sociali. Egualmente ha collegamenti 
traversa-d'insegnamento con storia, gli studi americani e le arti di 
linguaggio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ζητά από τους σπουδαστές για να απεικονίσει τον 
εμφύλιο πόλεμο με τη μελέτη των δωδεκάδων των φωτογραφιών 
περιόδου, και επεξηγεί πώς ο εμφύλιος πόλεμος απείλησε τον ίδιο
τον σκοπό του συντάγματος όπως δηλώνεται στον πρόλογο. 
Αυτό το μάθημα συσχετίζει στα εθνικά πρότυπα ιστορίας και 
τα εθνικά πρότυπα για Civics και τις κοινωνικές επιστήμες. 
Έχει επίσης τις διαγώνιος-διδακτικές συνδέσεις με την 
ιστορία, τις αμερικανικές μελέτες, και τις γλωσσικές τέχνες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">pide que los estudiantes visualicen la guerra 
civil estudiando docenas de fotografías del período, e ilustra cómo
la guerra civil amenazó el mismo propósito de la constitución 
según lo indicado en el preámbulo. Esta lección correlaciona 
a los estándares nacionales de la historia y a los estándares 
nacionales para el civics y las ciencias sociales. También 
tiene conexiones cruz-del plan de estudios con historia, estudios 
americanos, y artes del lenguaje.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206675</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103818</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-civil-war-as-photographed-by-mathematics-and-statisticsew-brady</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
