<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103937</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103937</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203835</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mass Balance Model With a Leaky Bucket</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ausgleichsmasse-Modell mit einer undichten Wanne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Modèle de bilan de matière avec une position 
perméable</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Modelo do contrapeso maciço com uma cubeta 
gotejante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Modello dell'equilibrio totale con una benna 
incapace di ritenere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μοντέλο μαζικής ισορροπίας με έναν leaky κάδο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Modelo del equilibrio total con un compartimiento 
agujereado</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this JAVA based online interactive modeling activity, students are introduced to the concept of mass balance, flow rates, and equilibrium using a simple water bucket model. Students can vary flow rate into the bucket, initial water level in the bucket, and residence time of water in the bucket. After running the model, the bucket's water level as a function of time is presented graphically and in tabular form. On this Starting Point page, users can access information about the exercise's learning goals, context for use, teaching notes and tips, teaching materials, assessment ideas, references and topics covered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In diesem gegründeten JAVA interaktives 
formenwerden online-Dienst, Kursteilnehmer zum Konzept der 
Ausgleichsmasse, der Strömungsgeschwindigkeiten und des 
Gleichgewichts mit einem einfachen Wasserwanne Modell eingeführt. 
Kursteilnehmer können Strömungsgeschwindigkeit in die Wanne, 
Ausgangswasserstufe in der Wanne und Verweilzeit des Wassers in der 
Wanne verändern. Nachdem man das Modell laufen gelassen hat, 
wird die Wasserstufe der Wanne als Funktion der Zeit graphisch und in 
tabellarischer Darstellung dargestellt. Auf dieser 
Ausgangspunktseite können Benutzer auf Informationen über die 
erlernenziele der Übung, Kontext für Gebrauch-, die 
Unterrichtenumfaßten anmerkungen und Spitzen, Lehrmittel, 
Einschätzung Ideen, Referenzen und Themen zugreifen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans ce JAVA basé l'activité modelante 
interactive en ligne, étudiants sont présentées au concept du bilan
de matière, des débits, et de l'équilibre en utilisant un modèle 
simple de position de l'eau. Les étudiants peuvent changer le 
débit dans la position, le niveau d'eau initial dans la position, et 
le temps de séjour de l'eau dans la position. Après exécution
du modèle, le niveau d'eau de la position en fonction du temps est 
présenté en forme de graphiques et en forme de tableaux. À 
cette page de point de départ, les utilisateurs peuvent accéder aux 
informations sur les buts d'étude de l'exercice, contexte pour les 
extrémités d'utilisation, d'enseignement les notes et, le matériel 
didactique, les idées d'évaluation, les références et les sujets 
couverts.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Neste JAVA baseado a atividade modelando 
interativa em linha, estudantes é introduzida ao conceito do 
contrapeso maciço, das taxas de fluxo, e do equilíbrio usando um 
modelo simples da cubeta da água. Os estudantes podem variar a 
taxa de fluxo na cubeta, o nível de água inicial na cubeta, e o 
tempo de residência da água na cubeta. Após ter funcionado o 
modelo, o nível de água da cubeta em função do tempo é 
apresentado gràfica e no formulário tabular. Nesta página do 
ponto começar, os usuários podem alcançar a informação sobre os 
objetivos de aprendizagem do exercício, contexto para as pontas do 
uso, ensinar as notas e, os materiais de ensino, as idéias da 
avaliação, as referências e os tópicos cobertos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questo JAVA basato l'attività modellante 
interattiva in linea, allievi è introdotta al concetto di equilibrio 
totale, delle portate e dell'equilibrio usando un modello semplice 
della benna dell'acqua. Gli allievi possono variare la portata 
nella benna, il livello d'acqua iniziale nella benna ed il tempo di 
soggiorno di acqua nella benna. Dopo il funzionamento del 
modello, il livello d'acqua della benna in funzione del tempo è 
presentato in forma di grafico e sotto forma di tabella. A 
questa pagina del punto di partenza, gli utenti possono accedere alle 
informazioni sugli obiettivi imparanti dell'esercitazione, contesto 
per le punte di istruzione, di uso note e, i materiali didattici, le 
idee di valutazione, i riferimenti ed i soggetti coperti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την βασισμένη στην ΙΑΒΑ σε απευθείας σύνδεση 
διαλογική δραστηριότητα διαμόρφωσης, οι σπουδαστές εισάγονται 
στην έννοια της μαζικής ισορροπίας, των ποσοστών ροής, και της 
ισορροπίας χρησιμοποιώντας ένα απλό μοντέλο κάδων ύδατος. 
Οι σπουδαστές μπορούν να ποικίλουν το ποσοστό ροής στον 
κάδο, την αρχική στάθμη ύδατος στον κάδο, και το χρόνο 
κατοικιών του ύδατος στον κάδο. Μετά από να τρέξει το 
μοντέλο, η στάθμη ύδατος του κάδου ως λειτουργία του χρόνου 
παρουσιάζεται γραφικά και υπό μορφήν πίνακος. Σε αυτήν την
σελίδα αφετηρίας, οι χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στις 
πληροφορίες για τους στόχους εκμάθησης της άσκησης, πλαίσιο για 
τη χρήση, τις σημειώσεις και τις άκρες διδασκαλίας, τα 
εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, τις ιδέες αξιολόγησης, τις αναφορές και τα 
θέματα που καλύπτονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta JAVA basada la actividad que modela 
interactiva en línea, estudiantes se introduce al concepto del 
equilibrio total, de los caudales, y del equilibrio usando un modelo 
simple del compartimiento del agua. Los estudiantes pueden 
variar caudal en el compartimiento, el nivel del agua inicial en el 
compartimiento, y el tiempo de residencia del agua en el 
compartimiento. Después de ejecutar el modelo, el nivel del 
agua del compartimiento en función de tiempo se presenta 
gráficamente y en forma tabular. En esta paginación del punto 
de partida, los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la información 
sobre las metas que aprenden del ejercicio, contexto para las 
extremidades del uso, de la enseñanza las notas y, los materiales 
didácticos, las ideas del gravamen, las referencias y los asuntos 
cubiertos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:R. MACKAY
FN:R. MACKAY
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203835</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103937</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/mass-balance-model-with-a-leaky-bucket</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
