<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106697</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106697</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206543</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Nile of the New World: Lower Mississippi River Valley</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nil der neuen Welt: Senken Sie Mississippi 
River Valley</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Nil du nouveau monde : Abaissez Le 
Mississippi River Valley</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nile do mundo novo: Abaixe Mississippi River 
Valley</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nilo di nuovo mondo: Abbassi Il Mississippi 
River Valley</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Νείλος του νέου κόσμου: Χαμηλότερη κοιλάδα 
ποταμών του Μισισιπή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Nilo del mundo nuevo: Baje Mississippi 
River Valley</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features stories and resources to help students learn about the heritage of this diverse region. Stories form a picture of the Delta's natural, historic, and cultural resources, and specific subject areas offer more detailed information on the area's role during the Civil War, its plantations, timber industry, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale Geschichten und Betriebsmittel, zum der 
Kursteilnehmer zu helfen, über das Erbe dieser verschiedenen Region 
zu erlernen. Geschichten bilden eine Abbildung der natürlichen,
historischen und kulturellen Betriebsmittel des Dreiecks, und 
spezifische Bereiche bieten ausführlichere Informationen über die 
Rolle des Bereiches während des Bürgerkrieges, seiner Plantagen, der
Bauholzindustrie und mehr an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">histoires et ressources de dispositifs pour aider 
des étudiants à se renseigner sur l'héritage de cette région 
diverse. Les histoires forment une image des ressources 
naturelles, historiques, et culturelles du delta, et les domaines 
spécifiques offrent l'information plus détaillée sur le rôle de la
zone pendant la guerre civile, ses plantations, industrie de bois de 
construction, et les plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">histórias e recursos das características para 
ajudar a estudantes aprender sobre o heritage desta região diversa. 
As histórias dão forma a um retrato dos recursos naturais, 
historic, e cultural do delta, e as áreas sujeitas específicas 
oferecem uma informação mais detalhada no papel da área durante a 
guerra civil, suas plantações, indústria da madeira, e mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">storia e risorse delle caratteristiche per aiutare
gli allievi ad imparare circa l'eredità di questa regione varia. 
Le storia formano un'immagine delle risorse naturali, storiche e
culturali del delta ed i settori specifici offrono informazioni più 
dettagliate sul ruolo della zona durante la guerra civile, le relative
piantagioni, l'industria del legname ed il più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ιστορίες και στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς χαρακτηριστικών 
γνωρισμάτων για να βοηθήσει τους σπουδαστές να μάθουν για την 
κληρονομιά αυτής της διαφορετικής περιοχής. Οι ιστορίες 
διαμορφώνουν μια εικόνα των φυσικών, ιστορικών, και πολιτιστικών 
στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς του δέλτα, και οι συγκεκριμένες θεματικές 
περιοχές προσφέρουν περισσότερες αναλυτικές πληροφορίες για το 
ρόλο της περιοχής κατά τη διάρκεια του εμφύλιου πολέμου, οι 
φυτείες της, βιομηχανία ξυλείας, και περισσότερο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">historias y recursos de las características para 
ayudar a estudiantes a aprender sobre la herencia de esta región 
diversa. Las historias forman un cuadro de los recursos 
naturales, históricos, y culturales del delta, y los temas 
específicos ofrecen una información más detallada sobre el papel 
del área durante la guerra civil, sus plantaciones, la industria de 
la madera, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206543</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106697</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nile-of-the-new-world-lower-mississippi-river-valley</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
