<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104428</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104428</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087203</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We Sang Rock of Ages": Frances Willard Battles Alcohol in the late 19th century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"wir sangen Felsen des Alters": Frances 
Willard Schlacht-Spiritus im des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"nous avons chanté la roche des âges" : 
Alcool de batailles de Frances Willard vers la fin de 19ème 
siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"nós cantamos a rocha das idades": Álcool 
das batalhas de Frances Willard no 1ø século atrasado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"abbiamo cantato la roccia delle età": 
Alcool di battaglie di Frances Willard verso la fine del 
diciannovesimo secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Τραγουδήσαμε το βράχο των ηλικιών": Θ*Φρανθες 
Willard Battles Alcohol προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"cantamos la roca de edades": Alcohol de las 
batallas de Frances Willard en la a fines del siglo XIX</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Among the social movements joined and led by women in the late 19th century, including unionization and women's suffrage, none had either the widespread fervor or success enjoyed by the temperance movement. The Woman's Christian Temperance Union (WCTU), founded in 1873, drew widespread support from labor movements such as the Knights of Labor by linking the fight against liquor with the desire to protect home and family against the ravages of the new industrial order. Frances Willard was one of the leaders of the WCTU who vocally sought the alliance of the temperance movement with Labor. In this selection from her autobiography  Glimpses of Fifty Years , Willard described the WCTU's most widely known tactic, the praying-in-saloons crusade.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unter den Sozialbewegungen, die von den Frauen im 
des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert, einschließlich 
Unionization- und Fraustimmrecht verbunden wurden und geführt waren, 
hatten keine entweder die weitverbreitete Leidenschaft oder Erfolg, 
die durch die temperance Bewegung genossen wurden. Der 
christliche Anschluß Temperance der Frau (WCTU), gegründet 1873, 
zeichnete weitverbreiteten Support von den Arbeiterbewegungen wie den 
Rittern der Arbeit, indem er den Kampf gegen Alkohol mit dem Wunsch, 
Haus und Familie gegen die ravages der neuen industriellen Ordnung zu 
schützen band. Frances Willard war einer der Führer des WCTU, 
das vocally das Bündnis der temperance Bewegung mit Arbeit suchte. 
In dieser Auswahl von ihren Autobiographie Blicken von fünfzig 
Jahren, beschrieb Willard die WCTU's weit bekannte Taktik, den 
Beten-inPraying-in-saloonskreuzzug.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Parmi les mouvements sociaux jointifs et menés 
par des femmes vers la fin du 19ème siècle, y compris le suffrage de
syndicalisation et de femmes, aucun n'a eu la ferveur répandue ou 
le succès apprécié par le mouvement de modération. L'union 
chrétienne de la Modération de la femme (WCTU), fondée en 1873, a 
tiré le support répandu des mouvements de travail tels que les 
chevaliers du travail en joignant le combat contre la boisson 
alcoolisée avec le désir de protéger la maison et la famille contre
les ravages de la nouvelle commande industrielle. Frances 
Willard était l'une des amorces du WCTU qui a vocally recherché 
l'alliance du mouvement de modération avec le travail. Dans 
cette sélection à partir de ses aperçus d'autobiographie de 
cinquante ans, Willard a décrit la tactique le plus largement connue 
de WCTU's, la croisade de prier-dans-salles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Entre os movimentos sociais juntados e conduzidos 
por mulheres no 1ø século atrasado, including o suffrage do 
unionization e das mulheres, nenhuns tiveram o fervor difundido ou o 
sucesso apreciado pelo movimento do temperance. A união 
christian de Temperance da mulher (WCTU), fundada em 1873, desenhou 
sustentação difundida dos movimentos labor tais como os knights do 
trabalho ligando a luta de encontro ao licor com o desejo proteger a 
HOME e a família de encontro aos ravages da ordem industrial nova. 
Frances Willard era um dos líderes do WCTU que procurou vocally
o alliance do movimento do temperance com trabalho. Nesta 
seleção de seus glimpses do autobiography de cinqüênta anos, 
Willard descreveu a tática o mais extensamente sabida de WCTU's, o 
crusade dos praying-em-praying-in-saloons.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fra i movimenti sociali fatti parte di e condotti 
dalle donne verso la fine del diciannovesimo secolo, compreso suffrage
delle donne e di unionization, nessun hanno avuti il fervor diffuso o 
successo goduto tramite il movimento di temperance. L'unione 
cristiana di Temperance della donna (WCTU), fondata in 1873, ha 
dissipato il supporto diffuso dai movimenti di lavoro quali i 
cavalieri del Lavoro collegando la lotta contro liquore con il 
desiderio proteggere la sede e la famiglia contro devasta di 
nuovo ordine industriale. Frances Willard era uno dei 
capi del WCTU che vocally ha cercato l'alleanza del movimento 
di temperance con il Lavoro. In questa selezione dai suoi 
glimpses del autobiography di cinquanta anni, Willard ha descritto la 
tattica il più ampiamente conosciuta di WCTU's, il crusade dei 
preg-in-saloni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μεταξύ των κοινωνικών μετακινήσεων που ενώθηκαν και 
που οδηγήθηκαν από τις γυναίκες προς το τέλος του 19$ου αιώνα, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της συνδικαλικοποίησης και της ψήφου των 
γυναικών, καμία απολήφθηκε είτε τη διαδεδομένη ζέση είτε την 
επιτυχία από τη μετακίνηση μετριοπάθειας. Η χριστιανική 
ένωση μετριοπάθειας της γυναίκας (WCTU), που ιδρύθηκε το 
1873, έσυρε τη διαδεδομένη υποστήριξη από τις μετακινήσεις 
εργασίας όπως οι ιππότες της εργασίας με τη σύνδεση της πάλης 
ενάντια στο ποτό με την επιθυμία να προστατευθεί το σπίτι και η 
οικογένεια από τις καταστροφές της νέας βιομηχανικής κατάταξης. 
Η Frances Willard ήταν ένας από τους ηγέτες του 
WCTU που επιδίωξαν φωνητικώς τη συμμαχία της μετακίνησης 
μετριοπάθειας με την εργασία. Σε αυτήν την επιλογή από τις 
αναλαμπές αυτοβιογραφιών πενήντα ετών της, Willard περιέγραψε 
τη γνωστή τακτική του WCTU ευρύτατα, η σταυροφορία 
προσεύχομαι-$$$-ΑΙΘΟΥΣΏΝ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Entre los movimientos sociales unidos y conducidos
por las mujeres en la a fines del siglo XIX, incluyendo sufragio de la
sindicalización y de las mujeres, ningunos tenían el fervor 
extenso o éxito gozado por el movimiento del temperance. La 
unión cristiana de Temperance de la mujer (WCTU), fundada en 1873, 
trazó la ayuda extensa de los movimientos de trabajo tales como los 
caballeros del trabajo conectando la lucha contra el licor al deseo de
proteger el hogar y a familia contra los ravages de la nueva orden 
industrial. Frances Willard era uno de los arranques de cinta 
del WCTU que vocally buscó la alianza del movimiento del temperance 
con el trabajo. En esta selección de sus ojeadas de la 
autobiografía de cincuenta años, Willard describió la táctica lo 
más extensamente posible sabida de WCTU's, la cruzada de los 
rogar-en-salones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087203</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104428</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-sang-rock-of-ages-frances-willard-battles-alcohol-in-the-late-19th-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
