<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106594</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106594</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087025</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Print of My Ancestors' Houses are Every Where to be Seen": Little Turtle Balks at Giving Up Land to General Anthony Wayne, 1795</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"der Druck der Häuser meiner Vorfahren sind jeder,
wo man" sieht: Kleine Schildkröte-Hindernisse am Geben dem 
General Anthony Wayne, 1795 herauf Land</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"la copie des Chambres de mes ancêtres sont chaque
où être vu" : Petits obstacles de tortue à donner vers le 
haut de la terre au Général Anthony Wayne, 1795</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"a cópia de casas dos meus antepassados é cada 
onde ser visto": Balks pequenos da tartaruga em dar acima da 
terra ao general Anthony Wayne, 1795</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la stampa delle Camere dei miei antenati è ogni 
dove essere visto": Ostacoli piccoli della tartaruga a dare 
sulla terra al General Anthony Wayne, 1795</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η τυπωμένη ύλη των σπιτιών των προγόνων μου είναι 
κάθε πού Να δει": Λίγη χελώνα εμποδίζει να 
σταματήσει το έδαφος στο στρατηγό Anthony Wayne, 1795</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"la impresión de las casas de mis antepasados es 
cada donde ser visto": Pequeños obstáculos de la tortuga en 
dar encima de pista a general Anthony Wayne, 1795</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">At the close of the American Revolution the British ignored their Indian allies and ceded all British lands from the Atlantic coast to the Mississippi River to the new United States. Increasing numbers of settlers in the Ohio Valley often skirmished with the many woodland Indian peoples who stayed on their ancestral lands. President Washington sent the first of three armies into the region in 1790. When the first two expeditions failed, Washington turned to General Anthony Wayne. After his victory in the Battle of Fallen Timbers in 1795, Wayne staged an elaborate ceremony at Fort Greenville to recognize American sovereignty over the land and his paternalistic authority over the Indians. Little Turtle, a Miami leader integral to the first two Indian victories, balked at Wayne's terms and was the last Indian participant to agree to cede two thirds of northern Ohio and southeastern Indiana. In exchange, the Americans agreed to Indian occupancy of the remaining lands. But this agreement was not to last for long.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Am Abschluß der amerikanischen Umdrehung 
ignorierten die Briten ihre indischen Verbündeten und überließen 
alle britischen Länder von der atlantischen Küste zum Mississippi 
Fluß in die neuen Vereinigten Staaten. Die zunehmenden Anzahlen
von Siedleren in der Ohio Senke skirmished häufig mit den vielen 
Waldindischen Völkern, die auf ihren ancestral Ländern blieben. 
Präsident Washington sendete das erste von drei Armeen in die 
Region 1790. Als die ersten zwei Expeditionen ausfielen, wendete
Washington an General Anthony Wayne. Nach seinem Sieg in der 
Schlacht der gefallenen Bauhölzer 1795, inszenierte Wayne eine 
durchdachte Zeremonie am Fort Greenville, um amerikanische Hoheit 
über dem Land und seine paternalistische Berechtigung über den 
Indern zu erkennen. Kleine Schildkröte, ein Miami 
Führerintegral zu den ersten zwei indischen Siegen, verhindert an den
Bezeichnungen Waynes und waren der letzte indische Teilnehmer, zum 
damit einverstanden zuSEIN, zwei an dritter Stelle von Nordohio und 
von südöstlichem Indiana zu überlassen. Im Austausch stimmten
die Amerikaner indischer Inanspruchnahme der restlichen Länder zu. 
Aber diese Vereinbarung war nicht dauern für langes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À l'issue de la révolution américaine les 
Anglais ont ignoré leurs alliés indiens et ont cédé toutes les 
terres britanniques de la côte atlantique au fleuve du Mississippi 
aux nouveaux Etats-Unis. Les nombres croissants de colons dans 
la vallée de l'Ohio skirmished souvent avec les nombreux peuples 
indiens de régfion boisée qui sont restés sur leurs terres 
héréditaires. Le Président Washington a envoyé le premier de
trois armées dans la région en 1790. Quand les deux premières
expéditions ont échoué, Washington s'est tourné vers le Général 
Anthony Wayne. Après sa victoire dans la bataille des bois de 
construction tombés en 1795, Wayne a mis en scène une cérémonie 
raffinée au fort Greenville pour identifier la souveraineté 
américaine au-dessus de la terre et sa autorité paternaliste 
au-dessus des Indiens. La petite tortue, une intégrale d'amorce
de Miami aux deux premières victoires indiennes, hésitées devant 
les limites de Wayne et étaient le dernier participant indien à 
accepter de céder deux troisièmement de l'Ohio nordique et de 
l'Indiana du sud-est. Dans l'échange, les Américains étaient 
d'accord sur l'occupation indienne des terres restantes. Mais 
cet accord n'était pas durent long.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">No fim da volta americana os Ingleses ignoraram 
seus aliados indian e ceded todas as terras britânicas da costa 
atlantic ao rio de Mississippi aos estados unidos novos. Os 
números crescentes dos settlers no vale de Ohio skirmished 
frequentemente com muitos povos indian da floresta que permaneceram em
suas terras ancestral. O presidente Washington emitiu o primeiro
de três exércitos na região em 1790. Quando as primeiras duas
expedições falharam, Washington girou para o general Anthony Wayne. 
Após sua vitória na batalha de madeiras caídas em 1795, Wayne
encenou um ceremony elaborado no fort Greenville para reconhecer o 
sovereignty americano sobre a terra e sua autoridade paternalistic 
sobre os indians. A tartaruga pequena, uma integral do líder de
Miami às primeiras duas vitórias indian, balked em termos de Wayne e
eram o último participant indian a concordar cede dois em terceiro 
lugar de Ohio do norte e de Indiana do sudeste. Na troca, os 
americanos concordaram ao occupancy indian das terras restantes. 
Mas este acordo não era dura para longo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alla fine della rivoluzione americana i Britannici 
hanno ignorato i loro alleati indiani ed hanno ceduto tutte le terre 
britanniche dal litorale atlantico al fiume del Mississippi al nuovo 
unito Dichiara. I numeri aumentanti di settlers nella 
valle dell'Ohio skirmished spesso con la molta gente indiana del 
terreno boscoso che ha rimasto sulle loro terre ancestral. Il 
presidente Washington ha trasmesso il primo di tre eserciti nella 
regione in 1790. Quando le prime due spedizioni sono venuto a 
mancare, Washington si è girata verso il General Anthony Wayne. 
Dopo la sua vittoria nella battaglia dei legnami caduti in 1795,
Wayne ha organizzato una cerimonia elaborata a Greenville Forte 
per riconoscere la sovranità americana sopra la terra e la sua 
autorità paternalistic sopra gli indiani. La tartaruga piccola,
un integrale del capo de Miami alle prime due vittorie indiane,
esitate davanti ai termini del Wayne ed erano l'ultimo partecipante 
indiano da accosentire per cedere due terzo dell'Ohio del Nord e 
dell'Indiana del sud-est. Nello scambio, gli Americani hanno 
accosentito ad occupazione indiana delle terre restanti. Ma
questo accordo non era dura lungo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στον περίβολο της αμερικανικής επανάστασης οι Βρετανοί
αγνόησαν τους ινδικούς συμμάχους τους και εκ:χωρώ όλα τα 
βρετανικά εδάφη από την ατλαντική ακτή στον ποταμό του Μισισιπή
στις νέες Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. Οι αυξανόμενοι αριθμοί 
αποίκων στην κοιλάδα του Οχάιου ηιμάχησαν συχνά με τους πολλούς 
δασόβιους ινδικούς λαούς που έμειναν στα προγονικά εδάφη τους. 
Ο Πρόεδρος Washington έστειλε τον πρώτο τριών στρατών 
στην περιοχή το 1790. Όταν οι πρώτες δύο αποστολές 
απέτυχαν, Ουάσιγκτον που γυρίζουν στο στρατηγό Anthony 
Wayne. Μετά από τη νίκη του στη μάχη των πεσμένων 
ξυλειών το 1795, ο Wayne οργάνωσε μια επιμελημένη τελετή στο
οχυρό Γκρήνβιλ για να αναγνωρίσει την αμερικανική κυριαρχία πέρα
από το έδαφος και την paternalistic αρχή του πέρα από τους 
Ινδούς. Λίγη χελώνα, ένα ολοκλήρωμα ηγετών του Μαϊάμι 
στις πρώτες δύο ινδικές νίκες, εμπόδισε στους όρους του Wayne
και ήταν ο τελευταίος ινδικός συμμετέχων για να συμφωνήσει να 
εκχωρήσει τα δύο τρίτα του βόρειου Οχάιου και του 
νοτιοανατολικού Ινδιάνα. Στην ανταλλαγή, οι Αμερικανοί 
συμφώνησαν με την ινδική κατοχή των υπόλοιπων εδαφών. Αλλά
αυτή η συμφωνία δεν ήταν να διαρκέσει για πολύ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el cierre de la revolución americana los 
Británicos no hicieron caso de sus aliados indios y cedieron todas 
las pistas británicas de la costa atlántica al río de Mississippi a
los Estados Unidos nuevos. Los números de aumento de colonos en
el valle de Ohio skirmished a menudo con la mucha gente india del 
arbolado que permanecía en sus pistas ancestrales. Presidente 
Washington envió el primer de tres ejércitos en la región en 1790. 
Cuando las primeras dos expediciones fallaron, Washington dio 
vuelta a general Anthony Wayne. Después de su victoria en la 
batalla de maderas caídas en 1795, Wayne efectuó una ceremonia 
elaborada en la fortaleza Greenville para reconocer soberanía 
americana sobre la pista y su autoridad paternalistic sobre los 
indios. La pequeña tortuga, un integral del arranque de cinta 
de Miami a las primeras dos victorias indias, frustradas en los 
términos de Wayne y eran el participante indio pasado a acordar ceder
dos tercero de Ohio norteño y de Indiana del sudeste. En 
intercambio, los americanos convinieron la ocupación india de las 
pistas restantes. Pero este acuerdo no era dura para largo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087025</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106594</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-print-of-my-ancestors-houses-are-every-where-to-be-seen-little-turtle-balks-at-giving-up-land-to-general-anthony-wayne-1795</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
