<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106658</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106658</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206932</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Bent's Old Fort National Historic Site's Learning Page</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erlernenseite Der Verbogenes Altes Fort-Nationalen
Historischen Sites</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Page D'Étude du Site Historique National de 
Vieux Fort Coudé</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Página De Aprendizagem Do Local Historic Nacional
Do Fort Velho Curvado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pagina Imparante Del Vecchio Luogo Storico 
Nazionale Forte Piegato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σελίδα εκμάθησης της καμμμένης παλαιάς περιοχής 
οχυρών εθνικής ιστορικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Paginación Que aprende Del Sitio Histórico 
Nacional De la Vieja Fortaleza Doblada</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines the people and construction of Bent's Fort, and the Santa Fe Trail. Built originally in 1833, this adobe fort became a center of trade with Indians and trappers. For much of its 16-year history, it was the only major permanent white settlement on the Santa Fe Trail. It provided explorers, adventurers, and the U.S. Army a place to get supplies, wagon repairs, livestock, good food, water, company, rest and protection in this vast Great American Desert.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft die Leute und den Aufbau des 
verbogenen Forts und die Santa Fe Spur. Ursprünglich aufgebaut 
1833, wurde dieses Ziegelsteinfort eine Mitte des Handels mit Indern 
und Trappers. Für viel seiner Geschichte 16-year, war es die 
einzige permanente weiße hauptsächlichregelung auf der Santa Fe 
Spur. Es lieferte Forscher, Abenteurer und die VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Armee ein Platz, um Zubehör, Lastwagenreparaturen, Vieh, gute
Nahrung, Wasser, Firma, Rest und Schutz in dieser beträchtlichen 
großen amerikanischen Wüste zu erhalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine les personnes et la construction du fort 
coudé, et la traînée de technicien de Santa. Construit 
initialement en 1833, ce fort d'adobe est devenu un centre du commerce
avec des Indiens et des trappeurs. Pour beaucoup de sa histoire 
16-year, c'était le seul règlement blanc permanent principal sur la 
traînée de technicien de Santa. Il a fourni des explorateurs, 
des aventuriers, et l'armée des ETATS-UNIS un endroit pour obtenir 
des approvisionnements, des réparations de chariot, le bétail, la 
bonne nourriture, l'eau, la compagnie, le repos et la protection dans 
ce vaste grand désert américain.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina os povos e a construção de fort curvado,
e a fuga de Fe de Santa. Construído originalmente em 1833, este
fort do adôbe transformou-se um centro do comércio com indians e 
caçadores. Para muito de seu history 16-year, era o único 
estabelecimento branco permanente principal na fuga de Fe de Santa. 
Forneceu exploradores, adventurers, e o exército de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS um lugar para começar fontes, reparos do vagão, animais 
domésticos, o alimento bom, a água, a companhia, o descanso e a 
proteção neste deserto americano grande vasto.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina la gente e la costruzione di Forte 
piegato e della traccia di tecnico di assistenza di Santa. 
Costruito originalmente in 1833, questo adobe forte si è 
transformato in in un centro di commercio con gli indiani ed i 
cacciatori di pelli. Per molta della relativa storia 16-year, 
era l'unico stabilimento bianco permanente principale sulla traccia di
tecnico di assistenza di Santa. Ha fornito agli esploratori, ai 
adventurers ed all'esercito degli STATI UNITI un posto per ottenere i 
rifornimenti, le riparazioni del vagone, il bestiame, il buon 
alimento, l'acqua, l'azienda, il resto e la protezione in questo 
deserto americano grande ampio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει τους ανθρώπους και την κατασκευή του οχυρού 
της κλίσης, και το ίχνος Φε Santa. Χτισμένο αρχικά το 
1833, αυτό το οχυρό πλίθας έγινε κέντρο του εμπορίου με 
Ινδούς και τα trappers. Για ένα μεγάλο μέρος της 
ιστορίας 16-έτους του, ήταν η μόνη σημαντική μόνιμη άσπρη 
τακτοποίηση στο ίχνος Φε Santa. Παρείχε τους εξερευνητές,
τους τυχοδιώκτες, και τον ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ στρατό μια θέση για να πάρει
τις προμήθειες, τις επισκευές βαγονιών εμπορευμάτων, το ζωικό 
κεφάλαιο, τα καλά τρόφιμα, το ύδωρ, την επιχείρηση, το υπόλοιπο 
και την προστασία σε αυτήν την απέραντη μεγάλη αμερικανική 
έρημο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina la gente y la construcción de la 
fortaleza doblada, y el rastro de FE de santa. Construido 
originalmente en 1833, esta fortaleza del adobe se convirtió en un 
centro del comercio con los indios y los tramperos. Para mucha 
de su historia 16-year, era el único establecimiento blanco 
permanente principal en el rastro de FE de santa. Proporcionó a
exploradores, a los aventureros, y al ejército de ESTADOS UNIDOS un 
lugar para conseguir fuentes, reparaciones del carro, el ganado, el 
buen alimento, el agua, la compañía, el resto y la protección en 
este gran desierto americano extenso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206932</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106658</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/bents-old-fort-national-historic-sites-learning-page</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
