<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108674</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108674</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086165</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"For Oregon!" Settlers From Illinois Describe the New Territory, 1847</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Für Oregon!" Siedleren von Illinois 
beschreiben die neue Gegend, 1847</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Pour l'Orégon!" Les colons de l'Illinois 
décrivent le nouveau territoire, 1847</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Para Oregon!" Os settlers de Illinois 
descrevem o território novo, 1847</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Per L'Oregon!" I settlers dall'Illinois 
descrivono il nuovo territorio, 1847</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Για το Όρεγκον!" Οι άποικοι από το Ιλλινόις 
περιγράφουν το νέο έδαφος, 1847</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Para Oregon!" Los colonos de Illinois 
describen el territorio nuevo, 1847</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">On June 15, 1846, the United States and Britain signed a treaty dividing the Oregon Territory--which at that time stretched into British Columbia--at the forty-ninth parallel. The acquisition of Oregon, like the acquisition of Texas, was part of President Polk's program of territorial expansion. In 1847 the  Illinois Journal , a newspaper based in Springfield, Illinois, decided to publish letters from former Illinoisans who had been tempted by the promise of Oregon and emigrated there. Readers curious about what life was like in the wild, northern territory got a mixed bag of reviews. While all the settlers agreed that the region was healthy, they had different views regarding its climate, soil, water, timber--and its overall capacity to provide permanent happiness to restless Americans. The newspaper's selections from these letters are included here.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auf Juni 15, 1846, den Vereinigten Staaten und 
Großbritannien unterzeichnete einen Vertrag, der die Oregon Gegend 
teilt -- die zu dieser Zeit in Britisch-Kolumbien ausdehnte -- an der 
vierzig-9. Ähnlichkeit. Die Datenerfassung von Oregon, wie der 
Datenerfassung von Texas, war ein Teil Präsident Polks des Programms 
der territorialen Expansion. In 1847 entschied das Illinois 
Journal, eine Zeitung, die in Springfield, Illinois gegründet wurde, 
Zeichen von ehemaligem Illinoisans zu veröffentlichen, das durch die 
Versprechung von Oregon gereizt worden war und wanderte dort aus. 
Die Leser, die neugierig sind über, welche Lebensdauer wie in 
der wilden war, Nordgegend erhielten einen Mischbeutel von 
Zusammenfassungen. Während alle Siedleren darin 
übereinstimmten, daß die Region gesund war, hatten sie die 
unterschiedlichen Ansichten betreffend sind sein Klima, Boden, Wasser,
Bauholz -- und seine gesamte Kapazität, permanentes Glück zu den 
rastlosen Amerikanern zur Verfügung zu stellen. Die 
Anwählungen der Zeitung von diesen Zeichen sind hier eingeschlossen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">15 juin 1846, les Etats-Unis et la 
Grande-Bretagne a signé un traité divisant le territoire de 
l'Orégon -- qui à ce moment-là s'est étendu dans Colombie 
britannique -- au quarante-neuvième parallèle. La saisie de 
l'Orégon, comme la saisie du Texas, faisait partie de programme du 
Président Polk's d'expansion territoriale. Dans 1847 le journal
de l'Illinois, un journal basé à Springfield, l'Illinois, a décidé
d'éditer des lettres d'ancien Illinoisans qui avait été tenté par 
la promesse de l'Orégon et a émigré là. Les lecteurs curieux
au sujet quelle vie était comme dans le territoire sauvage et 
nordique ont obtenu un sac mélangé des revues. Tandis que tous
les colons convenaient que la région était saine, ils ont eu 
différentes vues concernant son climat, sol, l'eau, bois de 
construction capacité -- et sa globale de fournir le bonheur 
permanent aux Américains agités. Les sélections du journal à
partir de ces lettres sont incluses ici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Junho em 15, 1846, nos estados unidos e em Grâ 
Bretanha assinou um tratado que divide o território de Oregon -- que 
nesse tempo esticou em Colômbia britânica -- na quarenta-nona 
paralela. A aquisição de Oregon, como a aquisição de Texas, 
era parte do programa do presidente Polk da expansão territorial. 
Em 1847 o jornal de Illinois, um jornal baseado em Springfield, 
Illinois, decidiu-se publicar letras de Illinoisans anterior que 
tempted pela promessa de Oregon e emigrated lá. Os leitores 
curiosos sobre que vida era como no território selvagem, do norte 
começaram um saco misturado das revisões. Quando todos os 
settlers concordaram que a região era saudável, tiveram as vistas 
diferentes a respeito de seu clima, solo, água, madeira -- e sua 
capacidade total fornecer a felicidade permanente aos americanos 
agitados. As seleções do jornal destas letras são incluídas 
aqui.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il 15 giugno 1846, unito Dichiara e la 
Gran-Bretagna ha firmato un trattato che divide il territorio 
dell'Oregon -- che a quel tempo ha allungato in Colombia britannica --
al quaranta-nono parallelo. L'aquisizione dell'Oregon, come 
l'aquisizione del Texas, faceva parte del programma del presidente 
Polk di espansione territoriale. In 1847 il giornale 
dell'Illinois, un giornale basato a Springfield, l'Illinois, ha deciso
pubblicare le lettere da Illinoisans precedente che era stato tentato 
dalla promessa dell'Oregon ed ha emigrato là. I lettori curiosi
circa che vita era come nel territorio selvaggio e nordico hanno 
ottenuto un sacchetto mixed delle revisioni. Mentre tutti i 
settlers hanno accosentito che la regione era sana, hanno avuti 
viste differenti per quanto riguarda il relativo clima, il terreno, 
l'acqua, legname -- e relativa la capacità generale di fornire la 
felicità permanente agli Americani agitati. Le selezioni del 
giornale da queste lettere sono incluse qui.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στις 15 Ιουνίου ..1846, τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες 
και τη Μεγάλη Βρετανία υπέγραψε μια συνθήκη διαιρώ το έδαφος του
Όρεγκον -- που εκείνη την περίοδο τέντωσε στη βρετανική 
Κολούμπια -- στο σαράντα-ένατο παράλληλο. Η απόκτηση του 
Όρεγκον, όπως την απόκτηση του Τέξας, ήταν μέρος του 
προγράμματος Προέδρου Polk's της εδαφικής επέκτασης. Το 
1847 το περιοδικό του Ιλλινόις, μια εφημερίδα που βασίστηκε στο
Σπρίνγκφιλντ, Ιλλινόις, αποφάσισε να δημοσιεύσει τις επιστολές 
από προηγούμενο Illinoisans που είχε μπεί στον πειρασμό από 
την υπόσχεση του Όρεγκον και μετανάστευσε εκεί. Οι 
αναγνώστες περίεργοι για ποια ζωή ήταν όπως στο άγριο, βόρειο 
έδαφος πήραν μια μικτή τσάντα των αναθεωρήσεων. Ενώ όλοι 
οι άποικοι συμφώνησαν ότι η περιοχή ήταν υγιής, είχαν τις 
διαφορετικές όψεις σχετικά με το κλίμα του, χώμα, ύδωρ, ξυλεία 
-- και γενική ικανότητά του να παρασχεθεί η μόνιμη ευτυχία σε 
ανήσυχους Αμερικανούς. Οι επιλογές της εφημερίδας από 
αυτές τις επιστολές συμπεριλαμβάνονται εδώ.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">15 de junio de 1846, los Estados Unidos y Gran 
Bretaña firmó un tratado que dividía el territorio de Oregon -- que
en aquella 'epoca estiró en Colombia británico -- en el 
cuarenta-noveno paralelo. La adquisición de Oregon, como la 
adquisición de Tejas, era parte del programa de presidente Polk de la
extensión territorial. En 1847 el diario de Illinois, un 
periódico basado en Springfield, Illinois, decidía a publicar cartas
de Illinoisans anterior que había sido tentado por la promesa de 
Oregon y emigrado allí. Los programas de lectura 
curiosos sobre qué vida era como en el territorio salvaje, norteño 
consiguieron un bolso mezclado de revisiones. Mientras que todos
los colonos convinieron que la región era sana, tenían diversas 
visiónes con respecto a su clima, suelo, agua, madera -- y su total 
capacidad de proporcionar a felicidad permanente a los americanos 
agitados. Las selecciones del periódico de estas cartas se 
incluyen aquí.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086165</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108674</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/for-oregon-settlers-from-illinois-describe-the-new-territory-1847</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
