<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107204</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107204</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211254</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Ocean and Atmospheric Administration: Oceans in the spotlight</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationaler Ozean und atmosphärische Leitung: 
Ozeane im Scheinwerfer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Océan national et gestion atmosphérique : 
Océans dans le projecteur</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Oceano nacional e administração atmosférica: 
Oceanos no spotlight</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Oceano nazionale e gestione atmosferica: 
Oceani nel riflettore</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνική ωκεάνια και ατμοσφαιρική διοίκηση: 
Ωκεανοί στο επίκεντρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Océano nacional y administración atmosférica: 
Océanos en el proyector</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">NOAA Ocean Service (NOS) is responsible for the observation, measurement, assessment and management of the nation's vast coastal and ocean areas. NOS provides world-class products and services that protect millions of lives, billions of dollars in property and irreplaceable natural resources daily. This website is a portal to all the NOS observations, information, measurements and programs. In the Oceans In the Spotlight section, users will find nautical charts, animations of monthly ocean temperatures, diving resources, global seafloor tomography and much more. This site contains a wealth of information collected for the NOAA Ocean Service projects.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">NOAA Ozean-Service (Nr.) ist für die Beobachtung,
das Messen, die Einschätzung und das Management der beträchtlichen 
bereiche Küsten- der Nation und Ozeanverantwortlich. Nr. 
liefert Welt-Kategorie Produkte und Dienstleistungen, die Millionen 
Leben schützen, Milliarden Dollar in der Eigenschaft und die 
unersetzlichen täglichen Naturresourcen. Diese Web site ist ein
Portal zu allen den Nr. Beobachtungen, Informationen, den Messen und 
den Programmen. In den Ozeanen im Scheinwerferkapitel, finden 
Benutzer Seediagramme, Animationen der Monatsozeantemperaturen, 
tauchende Betriebsmittel, globale seafloor Tomographie und viel mehr. 
Diese Site enthält eine Fülle der Informationen gesammelt für
die NOAA Ozean-Service-Projekte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le service d'océan de NOAA (numéros) est 
responsable de l'observation, de la mesure, de l'évaluation et de la 
gestion des vastes zones côtières de la nation et d'océan. 
Les numéros fournit les produits et les services de 
monde-classe qui protègent des millions des vies, des milliards de 
dollars dans la propriété et des ressources naturelles 
irremplaçables quotidiennes. Ce site Web est un portail à 
toutes les observations, à l'information, aux mesures et aux 
programmes de numéros. Dans les océans dans la section de 
projecteur, les utilisateurs trouveront les diagrammes nautiques, 
animations des températures mensuelles d'océan, ressources de 
plongée, tomographie globale de seafloor et beaucoup davantage. 
Ce site contient une richesse d'information rassemblée pour les
projets de service d'océan de NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O serviço do oceano de NOAA (no.) é responsável
para a observação, a medida, a avaliação e a gerência das áreas 
vastas litorais da nação e do oceano. Os no. fornecem os 
produtos e os serviços da mundo-classe que protegem milhões das 
vidas, billions dos dólares na propriedade e os recursos naturais 
insubstituíveis diários. Este Web site é um portal a todas as
observações, à informação, às medidas e aos programas dos no.. 
Nos oceanos na seção do spotlight, os usuários encontrarão 
as cartas náuticas, animations de temperaturas mensais do oceano, 
recursos mergulhando, tomography global do seafloor e muito mais. 
Este local contem uma riqueza da informação coletada para os 
projetos do serviço do oceano de NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il servizio dell'oceano di NOAA (no.) è 
responsabile dell'osservazione, della misura, della valutazione e 
della gestione delle zone litoranee della nazione e dell'oceano ampie.
I no. fornisce i prodotti ed i servizi del mondo-codice 
categoria che proteggono milioni di vite, i miliardi dei dollari nella
proprietà e le risorse naturali irreplaceable quotidiane. 
Questo Web site è un portal a tutte le osservazioni, alle 
informazioni, alle misure ed ai programmi di no.. Negli oceani 
nella sezione del riflettore, gli utenti troveranno le tabelle 
nautiche, animazioni delle temperature mensili dell'oceano, le risorse
subacquee, tomografia globale di seafloor e molto di più. 
Questo luogo contiene una ricchezza delle informazioni raccolta 
per i progetti di servizio dell'oceano di NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ωκεάνια υπηρεσία NOAA (αριθ.) είναι αρμόδια για 
την παρατήρηση, τη μέτρηση, την αξιολόγηση και τη διαχείριση των 
απέραντων παράκτιων και ωκεάνιων περιοχών του έθνους. Αριθ.
παρέχουν τα παγκόσμιας ποιότητας προϊόντα και τις υπηρεσίες που 
προστατεύουν τα εκατομμύρια των ζωών, τα δισεκατομμύρια των 
δολαρίων στην ιδιοκτησία και τα αναντικατάστατα φυσικά στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς καθημερινά. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος είναι μια πύλη 
σε όλες τις παρατηρήσεις, τις πληροφορίες, τις μετρήσεις και τα 
προγράμματα αριθ.. Στους ωκεανούς στο τμήμα επικέντρων, οι 
χρήστες θα βρούν τα ναυτικά διαγράμματα, ζωτικότητες των 
μηνιαίων ωκεάνιων θερμοκρασιών, στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς κατάδυσης,
σφαιρική τομογραφία θαλάσσιου πυθμένα και πολύ περισσότερο. 
Αυτή η περιοχή περιέχει έναν πλούτο των πληροφοριών που 
συλλέγεται για τα ωκεάνια προγράμματα υπηρεσιών NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El servicio del océano de NOAA (No.) es 
responsable de la observación, de la medida, del gravamen y de la 
gerencia de las áreas costeras de la nación y del océano extensas. 
Los No. proporcionan a los productos y a los servicios de la 
mundo-clase que protegen millones de vidas, mil millones de dólares 
en característica y los recursos naturales irreemplazables diarios. 
Este Web site es un portal a todas las observaciones, a la 
información, a las medidas y a los programas de los No.. En los
océanos en la sección del proyector, los utilizadores encontrarán 
las cartas náuticas, animaciones de las temperaturas mensuales del 
océano, recursos que se zambullen, tomography global del seafloor y 
mucho más. Este sitio contiene una abundancia de la 
información recogida para los proyectos del servicio del océano de 
NOAA.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211254</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107204</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-ocean-and-atmospheric-administration-oceans-in-the-spotlight</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
