<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107924</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107924</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086718</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Painting the American Scene: Artists Assess the Federal Art Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Malen der amerikanischen Szene: Künstler 
setzen das Bundeskunst-Projekt fest</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Peindre la scène américaine : Les artistes
évaluent le projet fédéral d'art</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pintando a cena americana: Os artistas 
avaliam o projeto federal da arte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Verniciatura della scena americana: Gli 
artisti valutano il progetto federale di arte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ζωγραφική της αμερικανικής σκηνής: Οι 
καλλιτέχνες αξιολογούν το ομοσπονδιακό πρόγραμμα τέχνης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pintar la escena americana: Los artistas 
evalúan el proyecto federal del arte</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">New Deal arts projects were guided by two novel assumptions: artists were workers and art was cultural labor worthy of government support. That commitment was demonstrated most dramatically in the Federal Art Project (FAP), a relief program for depression-era artists. Some painters and sculptors continued working in their studios with the assistance of relief checks and the occasional supervision of WPA administrators--their work was placed in libraries, schools, and other public buildings. Others lent their talents to community art centers that made art training and appreciation accessible to wider audiences. FAP also sponsored hundreds of murals and sculptures designed for municipal buildings and public spaces. In essays written as part of the New Deal's documentation of its own efforts, artist Louis Guglielmi found the social consciousness of the 1930s and the support of the New Deal a spur to his artistic development. Artist Julius Bloch praised the FAP for bringing art to new audiences, including his African-American subjects.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Kunstprojekte des neuen Abkommens wurden durch 
zwei Romanannahmen geführt: Künstler waren Arbeiter und kunst 
war der Regierungsunterstützung kulturelles Arbeitsangemessenes. 
Diese Verpflichtung wurde drastisch im Bundeskunst-Projekt 
(FAP), ein Entlastung Programm für Tiefstand-Ära Künstler 
demonstriert. Einige Maler und Sculptors fuhren fort, in ihren 
Studios mit der Unterstützung der Entlastung Überprüfungen und der 
gelegentlichen Überwachung der WPA Verwalter zu arbeiten -- ihre 
Arbeit wurde in Bibliotheken, in Schulen und in andere allgemeine 
Gebäude gelegt. Andere verliehen ihre Talente zu den 
Gemeinschaftskunstmitten, die das kunsttraining und -anerkennung 
zugänglich zu den breiteren Publikum bildeten. FAP auch 
geförderte Hunderte Wandbilder und Skulpturen konzipierten für 
städtische Gebäude und allgemeine Platz. In den Versuchen, die
als Teil der Unterlagen des neuen Abkommens seiner eigenen Bemühungen
geschrieben wurden, fand Künstler Louis Guglielmi das 
Sozialbewußtsein der dreißiger Jahre und den Support des neuen 
Abkommens ein Sporn zu seiner künstlerischen Entwicklung. 
Künstler Julius Bloch pries das FAP für das Holen den neuen 
Publikum, einschließlich seine Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Themen von 
von kunst.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Des projets d'arts de nouvelle affaire ont été 
guidés par deux prétentions de roman : les artistes étaient 
des ouvriers et l'art était digne de travail culturel du soutien 
gouvernemental. Cet engagement a été démontré le plus 
excessivement dans le projet fédéral d'art (FAP), un programme de 
soulagement pour des artistes de dépression-ère. Quelques 
peintres et sculpteurs ont continué de travailler dans leurs studios 
avec l'aide des contrôles de soulagement et de la surveillance 
occasionnelle des administrateurs de WPA -- leur travail a été 
placé dans les bibliothèques, les écoles, et d'autres bâtiments 
publics. D'autres ont prêté leurs talents aux centres d'art de
la communauté qui ont rendu la formation et l'appréciation d'art 
accessibles à des assistances plus larges. Les centaines 
également commanditées de FAP de muraux et sculptures ont conçu 
pour les bâtiments municipaux et les espaces publics. Dans les 
essais écrits en tant qu'élément de la documentation de nouvelle 
affaire de ses propres efforts, l'artiste Louis Guglielmi a trouvé la
conscience sociale des années 30 et le support de la nouvelle affaire
une dent à son développement artistique. L'artiste Jules Bloch
a félicité le FAP pour apporter l'art à de nouvelles assistances, y
compris ses sujets afro-américains.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os projetos das artes do negócio novo foram 
guiados por duas suposições da novela: os artistas eram 
trabalhadores e a arte era digna labor cultural da sustentação de 
governo. Esse compromisso foi demonstrado o mais dramàtica no 
projeto federal da arte (FAP), um programa do relevo para artistas da 
depression-era. Alguns pintores e sculptors continuaram 
trabalhando em seus estúdios com o auxílio de verificações do 
relevo e da supervisão ocasional de administradores de WPA -- seu 
trabalho foi colocado nas bibliotecas, nas escolas, e em outros 
edifícios públicos. Outros emprestaram seus talents aos 
centros da arte da comunidade que fizeram o treinamento e a 
apreciação da arte acessíveis a umas audiências mais largas. 
As centenas também patrocinadas de FAP dos murals e dos 
sculptures projetaram para edifícios municipais e espaços públicos.
Nos essays escritos como a parte da documentação de negócio 
novo de seus próprios esforços, o artista Louis Guglielmi encontrou 
o consciousness social dos 1930s e a sustentação do negócio novo um
dente reto a seu desenvolvimento artístico. O artista Julius 
Bloch elogiou o FAP para trazer a arte às audiências novas, 
including seus assuntos Africano-Americanos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I progetti di arti di nuovo affare sono stati 
guidati da due presupposti del romanzo: gli artisti erano operai
e l'arte era degno di lavoro culturale del supporto di governo. 
Quell'impegno è stato dimostrato il più drammaticamente nel 
progetto federale di arte (FAP), un programma di rilievo per gli 
artisti di depressione-era. Alcuni pittori e scultori hanno 
continuato a lavorare nei loro studi con l'assistenza dei controlli di
rilievo e del controllo occasionale degli amministratori di WPA -- il 
loro lavoro è stato disposto in librerie, in scuole ed in altre 
costruzioni pubbliche. Altri hanno prestato i loro talenti ai 
centri di arte della Comunità che hanno reso l'addestramento e 
l'apprezzamento di arte accessibili ai pubblici più larghi. FAP
egualmente ha patrocinato le centinaia dei murals e delle sculture 
progettati per le costruzioni comunali e gli spazi pubblici. Nei
saggi scritti come componente della documentazione del nuovo affare 
dei relativi propri sforzi, l'artista Louis Guglielmi ha trovato la 
coscienza sociale dei 1930s ed il supporto di nuovo affare un dente 
cilindrico al suo sviluppo artistico. L'artista Julius Bloch ha 
elogiato il FAP per portare l'arte ai nuovi pubblici, compreso i suoi 
oggetti Africano-Americani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τα νέα προγράμματα τεχνών διαπραγμάτευσης 
καθοδηγήθηκαν από δύο νέες υποθέσεις: οι καλλιτέχνες ήταν
εργαζόμενοι και η τέχνη ήταν πολιτιστική εργασία αντάξια της 
κυβερνητικής υποστήριξης. Εκείνη η υποχρέωση καταδείχθηκε ο
πιό εντυπωσιακά στο ομοσπονδιακό έργο τέχνης (FAP), ένα 
πρόγραμμα ανακούφισης για τους καλλιτέχνες κατάθλιψη-εποχής. 
Μερικοί ζωγράφοι και γλύπτες συνέχισαν στα στούντιό τους 
με τη βοήθεια των ελέγχων ανακούφισης και την περιστασιακή 
επίβλεψη των διοικητών WPA -- η εργασία τους τοποθετήθηκε στις 
βιβλιοθήκες, τα σχολεία, και άλλα δημόσια κτήρια. Αλλοι 
δάνεισαν τα ταλέντα τους στα κοινοτικά κέντρα τέχνης που 
κατέστησαν την κατάρτιση και την εκτίμηση τέχνης προσιτές στα 
ευρύτερα ακροατήρια. FAP υποστήριξε επίσης τις 
εκατοντάδες των τοιχογραφιών και των γλυπτών που σχεδιάστηκαν για 
τα δημοτικά κτήρια και τους δημόσιους χώρους. Στα δοκίμια 
που γράφτηκαν ως τμήμα της τεκμηρίωσης της νέας διαπραγμάτευσης 
των προσπαθειών του, ο καλλιτέχνης Louis Guglielmi βρήκε την 
κοινωνική συνείδηση της δεκαετίας του '30 και την υποστήριξη της 
νέας διαπραγμάτευσης ένα κέντρισμα στην καλλιτεχνική ανάπτυξή 
του. Ο καλλιτέχνης Julius Bloch εγκωμίασε το FAP για 
να φέρει την τέχνη στα νέα ακροατήρια, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικών υπηκόων του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los proyectos de los artes del nuevo reparto 
fueron dirigidos por dos asunciones de la novela: los artistas 
eran trabajadores y el arte era digno de trabajo cultural de la ayuda 
de gobierno. Esa consolidación fue demostrada lo más 
dramáticamente posible en el proyecto federal del arte (FAP), un 
programa de la relevación para los artistas de la depresio'n-era. 
Algunos pintores y escultores continuaron trabajando en sus 
estudios con la ayuda de los cheques de la relevación y de la 
supervisión ocasional de los administradores de WPA -- su trabajo fue
puesto en bibliotecas, escuelas, y otros edificios públicos. 
Otros prestaron sus talentos a los centros del arte de la 
comunidad que hicieron el entrenamiento y el aprecio del arte 
accesibles a audiencias más anchas. Los centenares también 
patrocinados de FAP de murals y de esculturas diseñaron para los 
edificios municipales y los espacios públicos. En los ensayos 
escritos como parte de la documentación del nuevo reparto de sus 
propios esfuerzos, el artista Louis Guglielmi encontró el sentido 
social de los años 30 y la ayuda del nuevo reparto un estímulo a su 
desarrollo artístico. El artista Julio Bloch elogió el FAP 
para traer arte a las nuevas audiencias, incluyendo sus temas 
Africano-Americanos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086718</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107924</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/painting-the-american-scene-artists-assess-the-federal-art-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
