<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105112</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105112</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201822</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Reflections on Playing Ayiti: The Cost of Life</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Reflexionen auf dem Spielen von von Ayiti: 
Die Kosten des Lebens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Réflexions sur jouer Ayiti : Le coût de la
vie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Reflexões em jogar Ayiti: O custo da vida</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Riflessioni sul gioco del Ayiti: Il costo di
vita</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αντανακλάσεις στο παιχνίδι Ayiti: Το κόστος 
της ζωής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Reflexiones en jugar Ayiti: El coste de 
vida</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Ayiti: The Cost of Life is a role-playing video game in which the player assumes the roles of family members living in rural Haiti. At the start of the game, the player chooses a primary goal for his/her family: achieve education, make money, stay healthy, or maintain happiness. During the course of the game, the player encounters unexpected events and must make decisions that contribute to or detract from achieving the chosen goal. After students have played the game they will need to reflect upon as well as share their experiences. The discussion questions are designed to explore: The correlation between choices made, their respective outcomes, and the constraints faced within the game. How the students' own lives and situations compare and contrast with those of the family members in the game.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ayiti: Die Kosten des Lebens sind ein Rolle 
spielendes videospiel, in dem der Spieler die Rollen der Familie 
Bauteile annimmt, die in landwirtschaftlichem Haiti leben. Beim 
Anfang des Spiels, wählt der Spieler ein Primärziel für seine/ihr 
Familie: erzielen Sie Ausbildung, verdienen Sie Geld, bleiben 
Sie gesund oder behalten Sie Glück bei. Während des Spiels 
müssen die unerwarteten Fälle des Spielertreffens und Entscheidungen
treffen, die zu beitragen oder vom Erzielen des gewählten Ziels 
abziehen. Nachdem Kursteilnehmer das Spiel gespielt haben, 
müssen sie nach sowie Anteil ihre Erfahrungen reflektieren. Die
Diskussion Fragen sind konzipiert, um zu erforschen: Die 
Wechselbeziehung zwischen den Wahlen getroffen, ihren jeweiligen 
Resultaten und den Begrenzungen gegenübergestellt innerhalb des 
Spiels. Wie eigene Lebensdauern und Situationen der 
Kursteilnehmer zu denen der Familie Bauteile im Spiel vergleichen und 
kontrastieren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ayiti : Le coût de la vie est un 
jeu vidéo jouant un rôle en lequel le joueur assume les rôles des 
membres de famille vivant au Haïti rural. Au début du jeu, le 
joueur choisit un but primaire pour sa famille : réalisez 
l'éducation, faites l'argent, restez sain, ou mettez à jour le 
bonheur. Pendant le jeu, les événements inattendus de 
rencontre de joueur et doivent prendre les décisions qui contribuent 
à ou amoindrissent réaliser le but choisi. Après que les 
étudiants aient joué le jeu ils devront refléter sur aussi bien que
la part leurs expériences. Les questions de discussion sont 
conçues pour les explorer : La corrélation entre les choix 
faits, leurs résultats respectifs, et les contraintes faites face 
dans le jeu. Comment les propres vies et les situations des 
étudiants rivalisent et contrastent avec ceux des membres de famille 
dans le jeu.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ayiti: O custo da vida é um jogo video 
role-playing em que o jogador supõe os papéis dos membros da 
família que vivem em Haiti rural. No início do jogo, o jogador
escolhe um objetivo preliminar para his/her família: consiga a 
instrução, faça o dinheiro, permaneça saudável, ou mantenha a 
felicidade. Durante o jogo, os eventos inesperados do encontro 
do jogador e devem fazer as decisões que contribuem a ou diminuem de 
conseguir o objetivo escolhido. Depois que os estudantes jogaram
o jogo necessitarão refletir em cima as.well.as da parte suas 
experiências. As perguntas da discussão são projetadas 
explorar: A correlação entre as escolhas feitas, seus 
resultados respectivos, e os confinamentes enfrentados dentro do jogo.
Como vidas e as situações dos estudantes próprias comparam e 
contrastam com as aquelas dos membros da família no jogo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ayiti: Il costo di vita è un gioco video 
d'atteggiamento in cui il giocatore ammette i ruoli dei membri della 
famiglia che vivono in Haiti rurale. All'inizio del gioco, il 
giocatore sceglie un obiettivo primario per la sua famiglia: 
realizzi la formazione, faccia i soldi, rimanga sano, o effettui
la felicità. Durante il corso del gioco, gli eventi inattesi di
incontro del giocatore e devono prendere le decisioni che 
contribuiscono a o riducono realizzare l'obiettivo scelto. Dopo 
che gli allievi gioc il gioco dovranno riflettere così come sulla 
parte le loro esperienze. Le domande di discussione sono 
destinate per esplorare: La correlazione fra le scelte fatte, i 
loro risultati rispettivi ed i vincoli affrontati all'interno del 
gioco. Come le proprie vite e le situazioni degli allievi 
paragonano e contrappongono a quelle dei membri della famiglia nel 
gioco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ayiti: Το κόστος της ζωής είναι ένα 
ρόλος-παίζοντας τηλεοπτικό παιχνίδι στο οποίο ο παίκτης 
υποθέτει τους ρόλους των οικογενειακών μελών που ζουν στην 
αγροτική Αϊτή. Στην έναρξη του παιχνιδιού, ο παίκτης 
επιλέγει έναν αρχικό στόχο για την οικογένειά του/της: 
επιτύχετε την εκπαίδευση, κάνετε τα χρήματα, μείνετε 
υγιής, ή διατηρήστε την ευτυχία. Κατά τη διάρκεια του 
παιχνιδιού, ο παίκτης αντιμετωπίζει τα απροσδόκητα γεγονότα και 
πρέπει να λάβει τις αποφάσεις που συμβάλλουν ή μειώνουν την 
επίτευξη του επιλεγμένου στόχου. Αφότου έχουν παίξει οι 
σπουδαστές το παιχνίδι θα πρέπει να απεικονίσουν επάνω καθώς 
επίσης και να μοιραστούν την εμπειρία τους. Οι ερωτήσεις 
συζήτησης έχουν ως σκοπό να εξερευνήσουν: Ο συσχετισμός 
μεταξύ των επιλογών έκανε, οι αντίστοιχες εκβάσεις τους, και οι 
περιορισμοί που αντιμετωπίστηκαν μέσα στο παιχνίδι. Πώς οι 
ζωές και οι καταστάσεις των σπουδαστών συγκρίνουν και 
αντιπαραβάλλουν με εκείνους των οικογενειακών μελών στο παιχνίδι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ayiti: El coste de vida es un juego video de
actuación de papeles en el cual el jugador asume el papeles de los 
miembros de la familia que viven en Haití rural. En el comienzo
del juego, el jugador elige una meta fundamental para su familia: 
alcance la educación, haga el dinero, permanezca sano, o 
mantenga la felicidad. Durante el curso del juego, los 
acontecimientos inesperados del encuentro del jugador y deben tomar 
las decisiones que contribuyen a o detraen de alcanzar la meta 
elegida. Después de que los estudiantes hayan jugado el juego 
necesitarán reflejar sobre así como la parte sus experiencias. 
Las preguntas de la discusión se diseñan para explorar: 
La correlación entre las opciones hechas, sus resultados 
respectivos, y los apremios hechos frente dentro del juego. 
Cómo propias vidas y las situaciones de los estudiantes 
comparan y ponen en contraste con las de los miembros de la familia en
el juego.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201822</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105112</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/reflections-on-playing-ayiti-the-cost-of-life</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
