<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108560</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108560</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086073</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Didactic Dramas: Antiwar Plays of the 1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Didaktische Dramen: Antikriegsspiele der 
dreißiger Jahre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Drames Didactiques : Jeux pacifistes des 
années 30</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dramas Didactic: Jogos antiwar dos 1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Drammi Didattici: Giochi pacifisti dei 
1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διδακτικά δράματα: Αντιπολεμικά παιχνίδια της 
δεκαετίας του '30</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Dramas Didácticos: Juegos pacifistas de los
años 30</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The interwar peace movement was arguably the largest mass movement of the 1920s and 1930s, a mobilization often overlooked in the wake of the broad popular consensus that ultimately supported the U.S. involvement in World War II. The destruction wrought in World War I (known in the 1920s and 1930s as the "Great War") and the cynical nationalist politics of the Versailles Treaty had left Americans disillusioned with the Wilsonian crusade to save the world for democracy. The antiwar movement drew on many tactics honed in earlier suffrage campaigns, including the use of pageants and plays. Circulated by the New Deal-sponsored Federal Theatre Project (FTP), these play synopses suggested the range and diversity of antiwar sentiment in the 1930s. The FTP vetted hundreds of scripts and prepared lists of plays for the use of community theaters. Antiwar dramas were among the most popular, with themes of religious pacifism, moral motherhood, and condemnation of war profiteering.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die interwar Friedensbewegung war diskutierbar die
größte Massenbewegung der zwanziger Jahre und der dreißiger Jahre, 
eine Mobilisierung, die häufig unmittelbar nach der ausgedehnten 
populären Übereinstimmung übersehen wurde, die schließlich die 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Miteinbeziehung im Zweiten Weltkrieg unterstützte.
Die Zerstörung, die im Ersten Weltkrieg wrought sind (bekannt 
in den zwanziger Jahren und in den dreißiger Jahren als der "große 
Krieg") und die zynische nationalistische Politik des Versailles 
Vertrags hatten die linken Amerikaner, die mit dem Wilsonian Kreuzzug 
ernüchtert wurden, um die Welt für Demokratie zu sichern. Die 
Antikriegsbewegung zeichnete auf viele Taktiken, die in den früheren 
Stimmrechtkampagnen, einschließlich den Gebrauch von Pageants und 
Spielen abgezogen wurden. Verteilt durch das neue 
Behandeln-geförderte Bundestheater-Projekt (ftp), schlugen diese 
Spielsynopsen die Strecke und die Verschiedenartigkeit des 
Antikriegsgefühls in den dreißiger Jahren vor. Die ftp vetted 
Hunderte der Indexe und vorbereitete Listen der Spiele für den 
Gebrauch von Gemeinschaftstheatern. Antikriegsdramen gehörten 
zu der populärsten, mit Themen des frommen Pazifismus, 
moralischsten Mutterschaft und Verurteilung von Krieg Profiteering.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mouvement de paix d'entre-deux guerres était 
discutablement le plus grand mouvement de masse des années 20 et des 
années 30, une mobilisation souvent négligée à la suite du large 
consensus populaire qui a finalement supporté l'intervention des 
ETATS-UNIS dans la deuxième guerre mondiale. La destruction 
travaillée dans la Première Guerre Mondiale (connue dans les années
20 et les années 30 comme "grande guerre") et la politique 
nationaliste cynique du Traité de Versailles ont eu les Américains 
gauches désillusionnés avec la croisade de Wilsonian pour 
sauvegarder le monde pour la démocratie. Le mouvement pacifiste
a dessiné sur beaucoup de tactique rectifiée dans de premières 
campagnes de suffrage, y compris l'utilisation des reconstitutions 
historiques et des jeux. Circulé par le nouveau projet 
fédéral Occuper-commandité de théâtre (ftp), ces synthèses de 
jeu ont suggéré l'intervalle et la diversité du sentiment pacifiste
dans les années 30. Les centaines de séquences type 
contrôlées par ftp et listes préparées de jeux pour l'usage des 
théâtres de la communauté. Les drames pacifistes étaient 
parmi la maternité la plus populaire, avec des thèmes de pacifisme 
religieux et la plus morale, et la condamnation du mercantilisme de 
guerre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O movimento interwar da paz era arguably o 
movimento maciço o maior dos 1920s e dos 1930s, um mobilization 
negligenciado frequentemente na vigília do consenso popular largo que
suportou finalmente a participação de ESTADOS UNIDOS na segunda 
guerra mundial. A destruição feita no world.war.i (sabido nos 
1920s e nos 1930s como "a guerra grande") e a política nacionalista 
cínica do tratado de Versalhes tiveram os americanos esquerdos 
disillusioned com o crusade de Wilsonian para conservar o mundo para a
democracia. O movimento antiwar desenhou em muitas táticas 
afiadas em umas campanhas mais adiantadas do suffrage, including o uso
dos pageants e dos jogos. Circulado pelo projeto federal 
Negoci-patrocinado novo do theatre (ftp), estes synopses do jogo 
sugeriram a escala e a diversidade do sentiment antiwar nos 1930s. 
As centenas vetted ftp dos certificados e listas preparadas dos 
jogos para o uso de teatros da comunidade. Os dramas antiwar 
eram entre o motherhood o mais popular, com temas do pacifism 
religioso, o mais moral, e o condemnation do profiteering da guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il movimento interwar di pace era discutibilmente 
il più grande movimento totale degli anni 20 e dei 1930s, una 
mobilizzazione trascurata spesso come conseguenza di vasto consenso 
popolare che infine ha sostenuto la partecipazione degli STATI UNITI 
alla seconda guerra mondiale. La distruzione modellata nel 
world.war.i (conosciuto negli anni 20 e nei 1930s come "la guerra 
grande") e la politica nazionalista cinica del Trattato de Versailles 
hanno avute Americani di sinistra disillusi con il crusade di 
Wilsonian per salvare il mondo per la democrazia. Il movimento 
pacifista ha dissipato su molte tattiche smerigliatrice nelle campagne
più iniziali di suffrage, compreso l'uso degli spettacoli e dei 
giochi. Circolato dal nuovo progetto federale Tratt-patrocinato 
del teatro (ftp), queste sinossi del gioco hanno suggerito la gamma e 
la diversità di sentimento pacifista nei 1930s. Le centinaia 
degli scritti controllare ftp e liste redatte dei giochi per l'uso dei
teatri della Comunità. I drammi pacifisti erano fra la 
maternità più popolare, con i temi del pacifism religioso e più 
morale e la condanna dell'affarismo di guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μετακίνηση ειρήνης μεσοπολέμου ήταν αμφισβητήσιμα η
μεγαλύτερη μαζική μετακίνηση της δεκαετίας του '20 και της 
δεκαετίας του '30, μια κινητοποίηση που αγνοήθηκε συχνά αμέσως 
μετά την ευρεία δημοφιλή συναίνεση που υποστήριξε τελικά την 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ συμμετοχή στον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο ΙΙ. Η καταστροφή
επεξεργασμένη στον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι (γνωστό στη δεκαετία του 
'20 και τη δεκαετία του '30 ως "μεγάλος πόλεμοσ") και η κυνική 
εθνικιστική πολιτική της Συνθήκης των Βερσαλλιών είχαν αφήσει 
Αμερικανούς απογοήτεψαν με τη σταυροφορία Wilsonian για να 
σώσουν τον κόσμο για τη δημοκρατία. Η αντιπολεμική 
μετακίνηση επέσυρε την προσοχή σε πολλή τακτική που ακονίστηκε 
στις προηγούμενες εκστρατείες ψήφου, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της 
χρήσης των θεαμάτων και των παιχνιδιών. Κυκλοφορημένες από 
το νέο διαπραγμάτευση-υποστηριγμένο ομοσπονδιακό πρόγραμμα 
θεάτρων (FTP), αυτές οι συνόψεις παιχνιδιού πρότειναν τη 
σειρά και την ποικιλομορφία του αντιπολεμικού συναισθήματος στη 
δεκαετία του '30. Το FTP εξέτασε τις εκατοντάδες των 
αρχείων εντολών και προετοίμασε τους καταλόγους παιχνιδιών για τη
χρήση των κοινοτικών θεάτρων. Τα αντιπολεμικά δράματα ήταν
μεταξύ της δημοφιλέστερης, με τα θέματα του θρησκευτικού 
φιλειρηνισμού, ηθικής μητρότητας, και καταδίκη πολεμικό 
profiteering.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El movimiento interwar de la paz era discutible el
movimiento total más grande de los años 20 y de los años 30, una 
movilización pasada por alto a menudo en la estela del amplio 
consenso popular que utilizó en última instancia la implicación de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS en la Segunda Guerra Mundial. La destrucción 
labrada en la Primera Guerra Mundial (sabida en los años 20 y los 
años 30 como la "gran guerra") y la política nacionalista cínica 
del tratado de Versalles tenían americanos izquierdos desilusionados 
con la cruzada de Wilsonian para salvar el mundo para la 
democracia. El movimiento pacifista trazó en muchas táctica 
afiladas con piedra en campañas anteriores del sufragio, incluyendo 
el uso de desfiles y de juegos. Circulado por el nuevo proyecto 
federal Repartir-patrocinado del teatro (ftp), estas sinopsis del 
juego sugirieron el rango y la diversidad del sentimiento pacifista en
los años 30. Los centenares revisados ftp de escrituras y 
listas elaboradas de los juegos para el uso de los teatros de la 
comunidad. Los dramas pacifistas estaban entre la maternidad 
más popular, con temas del pacifism religioso, más moral, y la 
condenación del mercantilismo de la guerra.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086073</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108560</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/didactic-dramas-antiwar-plays-of-the-1930s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
