<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108766</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108766</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200770</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">C.S.I. on the Deep Reef</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">C.S.I. auf dem tiefen Reef</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C.S.I. sur le récif profond</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">C.S.I. no recife profundo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">C.S.I. sul reef profondo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">C.S.I. στο βαθύ σκόπελο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">C.S.I. en el filón profundo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this lesson students discover the factors that are indicative of chemotrophic nutritional strategies. This NOAA lesson plan is designed to teach students about the factors that are indicative of chemotrophic nutritional strategies. Students will be able to describe at least three chemotrophic symbioses known from deep-sea habitats. They will identify and explain three indicators of chemotropic nutrition. This hands-on activity uses online data resources and includes: focus questions, background information, evaluations and extensions, as well as resources and student handouts.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Lektion entdecken Kursteilnehmer die 
Faktoren, die von den chemotrophic Ernährungsstrategien hinweisend 
sind. Dieser NOAA Lektionplan ist konzipiert, um Kursteilnehmer 
über die Faktoren zu unterrichten, die von den chemotrophic 
Ernährungsstrategien hinweisend sind. Kursteilnehmer können, 
mindestens drei chemotrophic Symbiosen zu beschreiben, die von den 
Tiefseelebensräumen bekannt sind. Sie kennzeichnen und 
erklären drei Anzeigen von chemotropic Nahrung. Diese 
Blindeinschub Aktivität benutzt Onlinedatenbetriebsmittel und 
schließt ein: fokussieren Sie Fragen, Hintergrundinformationen,
Auswertungen und Extensionen, sowie Betriebsmittel und Handbücher.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dans cette leçon les étudiants découvrent les 
facteurs qui sont indicatifs des stratégies alimentaires 
chemotrophic. Ce plan de leçon de NOAA est conçu pour 
enseigner des étudiants au sujet des facteurs qui sont indicatifs des
stratégies alimentaires chemotrophic. Les étudiants pourront 
décrire au moins trois symbioses chemotrophic connues des habitats 
hauturiers. Ils identifieront et expliqueront trois indicateurs 
de la nutrition chemotropic. Cette activité à commande 
manuelle utilise les ressources en ligne de données et les inclut : 
focalisez les questions, l'information de fond, les évaluations
et les extensions, aussi bien que des ressources et des aumônes 
d'étudiant.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta lição os estudantes descobrem os fatores 
que são indicativos de estratégias nutritivas chemotrophic. 
Esta planta da lição de NOAA é projetada ensinar estudantes 
sobre os fatores que são indicativos de estratégias nutritivas 
chemotrophic. Os estudantes poderão  descrever ao menos três 
symbioses chemotrophic sabidos dos habitats deep-sea. 
Identificarão e explicarão três indicadores do nutrition 
chemotropic. Esta atividade hands-on usa recursos em linha dos 
dados e inclui-os: focalize perguntas, informação de fundo, 
avaliações e extensões, as.well.as recursos e handouts de 
estudante.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa lezione allievi scoprono i fattori che 
sono indicativi delle strategie nutrizionali chemotrophic. 
Questo programma di lezione di NOAA è destinato per insegnare 
gli allievi circa i fattori che sono indicativi delle strategie 
nutrizionali chemotrophic. Gli allievi potranno descrivere 
almeno tre simbiosi chemotrophic conosciute dagli habitat di alto 
mare. Identificheranno e spiegheranno tre indicatori di 
nutrizione chemotropic. Questa attività hands-on usa le risorse
in linea di dati ed include: metta a fuoco le domande, le 
informazioni di base, le valutazioni e le estensioni, così come le 
risorse e le dispense di allievo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτό το μάθημα οι σπουδαστές ανακαλύπτουν τους 
παράγοντες που είναι ενδεικτικοί των χημιοτροφικών θρεπτικών 
στρατηγικών. Αυτό το σχέδιο μαθήματος NOAA σχεδιάζεται 
για να διδάξει τους σπουδαστές για τους παράγοντες που είναι 
ενδεικτικοί των χημιοτροφικών θρεπτικών στρατηγικών. Οι 
σπουδαστές θα είναι σε θέση να περιγράψουν τουλάχιστον τρεις 
χημιοτροφικές συμβιώσεις που είναι γνωστές από τους βαθύβιους 
βιότοπους. Θα προσδιορίσουν και θα εξηγήσουν τρεις δείκτες 
της chemotropic διατροφής. Αυτή η εμπράγματη 
δραστηριότητα χρησιμοποιεί τα σε απευθείας σύνδεση στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς στοιχείων και περιλαμβάνει: ερωτήσεις 
εστίασης, βασικές πληροφορίες, αξιολογήσεις και επεκτάσεις, 
καθώς επίσης και στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς και φυλλάδια σπουδαστών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta lección los estudiantes descubren los 
factores que son indicativos de estrategias alimenticias chemotrophic.
Este plan de la lección de NOAA se diseña para enseñar a 
estudiantes sobre los factores que son indicativos de estrategias 
alimenticias chemotrophic. Los estudiantes podrán describir por
lo menos tres simbiosis chemotrophic sabidas de habitat de alta mar. 
Identificarán y explicarán tres indicadores de la nutrición 
chemotropic. Esta actividad con manos utiliza recursos en línea
de los datos y los incluye: enfoque las preguntas, la 
información de fondo, las evaluaciones y las extensiones, así como 
recursos y folletos de estudiante.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:OCEAN EXPLORER
FN:OCEAN EXPLORER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:NOAA
FN:NOAA
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200770</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108766</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/c-s-i-on-the-deep-reef</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
