<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103056</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103056</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201050</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Contaminated Sediment in Water</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verschmutztes Sediment im Wasser</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sédiment souillé dans l'eau</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sedimento contaminado na água</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sedimento contaminato in acqua</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μολυσμένο ίζημα στο ύδωρ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sedimento contaminado en agua</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This EPA site provides information about how sediments get contaminated, where the pollutants come from, how contaminated sediments become concentrated in lakes, rivers and oceans, their effects on plants and animals, and strategies used to treat and prevent contaminated sediments. Extensive links provide access to publications and additional information from other state and federal agencies. The site also features a glossary and a list of acronyms to help readers understand the material.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Von diese EPA Site liefert Informationen über, 
wie Sedimente verschmutzt erhalten, wo die Verschmutzungsstoffe, wie 
verschmutzte Sedimente in den Seen, Flüsse und Ozeane, ihre Effekte 
auf Betriebe und Tiere konzentriert werden und die Strategien kommen, 
die verwendet werden, um verschmutzte Sedimente zu behandeln und zu 
verhindern. Umfangreiche Links liefern Zugriff zu den 
Publikationen und zusätzliche Informationen von anderem Zustand und 
von Bundesämtern. Die Site kennzeichnet auch ein Glossar und 
eine Liste von Akronymen, um Lesern zu helfen, das Material zu 
verstehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site d'EPA fournit des informations au sujet de
la façon dont les sédiments obtiennent souillés, d'où les 
polluants viennent, comme les sédiments souillés deviennent 
concentrés dans les lacs, les fleuves et les océans, leurs effets 
sur des usines et les animaux, et des stratégies employées pour 
traiter et empêcher les sédiments souillés. Les liens 
étendus fournissent l'accès aux publications et les informations 
supplémentaires d'autres état et agences fédérales. Le site 
comporte également un glossaire et une liste d'acronymes pour aider 
des lecteurs à comprendre le matériel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local de EPA fornece a informação sobre 
como os sedimentos começam contaminados, de onde os pollutants vêm, 
como os sedimentos contaminados se tornam concentrados nos lagos, os 
rios e os oceanos, os seus efeitos em plantas e os animais, e as 
estratégias usadas tratar e impedir sedimentos contaminados. As
ligações extensivas fornecem o acesso às publicações e a 
informação adicional de outros estado e agências federais. O 
local caracteriza também um glossário e uma lista dos acrônimos 
para ajudar a leitores compreender o material.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo di EPA fornisce le informazioni su 
come i sedimenti ottengono contaminati, da dove le sostanze inquinanti
vengono, come i sedimenti contaminati sono concentrati in laghi, fiumi
ed oceani, i loro effetti sulle piante ed animali e strategie usate 
per trattare ed impedire i sedimenti contaminati. I vasti 
collegamenti forniscono l'accesso alle pubblicazioni e le informazioni
supplementari da altra dichiarano ed enti federali. Il 
luogo egualmente caratterizza un glossario e una lista degli acronimi 
per aiutare i lettori a capire il materiale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή EPA παρέχει τις πληροφορίες για το 
πώς τα ιζήματα παίρνουν μολυσμένα, όπου οι ρύποι προέρχονται 
από, πώς τα μολυσμένα ιζήματα γίνονται συγκεντρωμένα στις 
λίμνες, τους ποταμούς και τους ωκεανούς, τα αποτελέσματά τους στα
φυτά και τα ζώα, και τις στρατηγικές που χρησιμοποιούνται για να 
μεταχειριστούν και να αποτρέψουν τα μολυσμένα ιζήματα. Οι 
εκτενείς συνδέσεις παρέχουν την πρόσβαση στις δημοσιεύσεις και 
τις πρόσθετες πληροφορίες από άλλες κράτος και ομοσπονδιακές 
αντιπροσωπείες. Η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει επίσης ένα γλωσσάρι
και έναν κατάλογο αρκτικολέξων για να βοηθήσει τους αναγνώστες να
καταλάβουν το υλικό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio de EPA proporciona a la información 
sobre cómo los sedimentos consiguen contaminados, de donde los 
agentes contaminadores vienen, cómo los sedimentos contaminados se 
concentran en los lagos, los ríos y los océanos, sus efectos en las 
plantas y los animales, y las estrategias usadas para tratar y para 
prevenir los sedimentos contaminados. Las conexiones extensas 
proporcionan al acceso a las publicaciones y a la información 
adicional de otro estado y agencias federales. El sitio también
ofrece un glosario y una lista de siglas para ayudar a programas de 
lectura a entender el material.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201050</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103056</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/contaminated-sediment-in-water</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
