<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103821</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103821</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087348</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Well-Mannered Bandit and a Killer": Little Berta Ballard Remembers Billy the Kid</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein Well-Mannered Bandit und ein Mörder": 
Wenig Berta Ballard erinnert sich an Billy das Zicklein</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un bandit de Well-Mannered et un tueur" : 
Peu de Berta Ballard se rappelle Billy le gosse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um bandido de Well-Mannered e um assassino": 
Pouco Berta Ballard recorda o billy o miúdo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un bandito di Well-Mannered e un assassino": 
Poco Berta Ballard si ricorda del billy il capretto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένας καλά-επιτηδευμένος ληστής και ένας δολοφόνοσ":
Λίγο Berta Ballard θυμάται το Billy το κατσίκι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un bandido de Well-Mannered y un asesino": 
Poco Berta Ballard recuerda el billy el cabrito</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The New Deal tried to end the Depression by spending government money to employ the jobless. One of its most ambitious efforts, the Works Progress Administration (WPA), put 8.5 million people to work between 1935 and 1943, mostly on projects that required manual labor, but also on projects for artists, writers, actors, and musicians. At its peak, the Federal Writers Project employed about 6,500 men and women, some of whom later became famous. In the late 1930s the project's writers began a series of "life histories," recording the experiences of diverse Americans from Florida to Alaska. Sometimes they recorded people's words verbatim; other times they rewrote them into narratives. In this example, Berta Ballard Manning recalled meeting the famous outlaw "Billy the Kid" as a child in New Mexico. He was unassuming and gentle, with good manners, but she also remembered him as a bandit and killer who kept their county in turmoil</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das neue Abkommen versuchte, den Tiefstand zu 
beenden, indem es Regierung Geld ausgab, um das arbeitslose 
einzusetzen. Eine seiner ehrgeizigsten Bemühungen, die Arbeiten
Fortschritt-Leitung (WPA), setzte 8.5 Million Leute, um zwischen 1935 
und 1943, meistens auf Projekten, die Handarbeit benötigten, aber 
auch auf Projekten für Künstler, Verfasser, Schauspieler und Musiker
zu arbeiten. An seiner Spitze projizieren sich die 
Bundesverfasser beschäftigt ungefähr 6.500 Männern und Frauen, 
einigem von, wurde wem später berühmt. In Verfasser des 
spätem dreißiger Jahre fingen die Projektes eine Reihe 
"Lebengeschichten an,", die Erfahrungen der verschiedenen Amerikaner 
von Florida nach Alaska speichernd. Manchmal speicherten sie 
Wörter der Leute wortwörtlich; andere Male schrieben sie sie 
in Darstellungen neu. In diesem Beispiel Berta Ballard rief das 
Bemannen wieder auf, das berühmte zu treffen, "Billy das Zicklein" 
als Kind in New-Mexico zu ächten. Er unassuming und mildert, 
mit guten Weise, aber sie erinnerte an ihn sich auch als Bandit und 
Mörder, die ihre Grafschaft im Tumult hielten</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La nouvelle affaire a essayé de terminer la 
dépression en dépensant l'argent de gouvernement pour utiliser le 
sans emploi. Un de ses efforts plus ambitieux, la gestion 
d'avancement de travaux (WPA), a mis 8.5 millions de personnes pour 
travailler entre 1935 et 1943, la plupart du temps sur les projets qui
ont exigé le travail manuel, mais également sur des projets pour des
artistes, des auteurs, des acteurs, et des musiciens. À sa 
crête, les auteurs fédéraux projettent employé environ 6.500 
hommes et femmes, une partie de qui plus tard est devenu célèbre. 
Vers la fin des années 30 les auteurs du projet ont commencé 
une série d'"histoires de la vie," enregistrant les expériences des 
Américains divers de la Floride en Alaska. Parfois ils ont 
enregistré in extenso les mots des personnes ; d'autres fois 
ils les ont récrits dans des récits. Dans cet exemple, 
équiper de Berta Ballard s'est rappelé rencontrer le célèbre pour 
proscrire "Billy le gosse" en tant qu'enfant au Nouveau-Mexique. 
Il était modeste et adoucit, avec de bonnes façons, mais 
elle s'est également rappelée l'en tant qu'un bandit et tueuse qui 
ont maintenu leur comté dans l'agitation</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O negócio novo tentou terminar o depression 
gastando o dinheiro do governo para empregar o jobless. Um de 
seus esforços mais ambiciosos, a administração do progresso de 
trabalhos (WPA), pôs 8.5 milhão povos para trabalhar entre 1935 e 
1943, na maior parte nos projetos que requereram o trabalho manual, 
mas também em projetos para artistas, escritores, atores, e músicos.
Em seu pico, os escritores federais projetam-se empregado 
aproximadamente 6.500 homens e mulheres, algum de quem se tornou mais 
tarde famoso. Os escritores em atrasado 1930s do projeto 
começaram uma série da "de histories vida," gravando as 
experiências de americanos diversos de Florida a Alaska. Às 
vezes gravaram palavras do pessoa verbatim; outras vezes 
reescreveram-nos em narrativas. Neste exemplo, equipar de Berta 
Ballard recordou encontrar-se com o famoso para outlaw o "billy o 
miúdo" como uma criança em Novo México. Unassuming e doma, 
com maneiras boas, mas recordou-o também como um bandido e um 
assassino que mantivessem seu condado no turmoil</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il nuovo affare ha provato a concludere la 
depressione spendendo i soldi di governo per impiegare il senza
lavoro. Uno dei relativi sforzi più ambiziosi, la gestione di 
progresso degli impianti (WPA), ha messo 8.5 milione di persone per 
funzionare fra 1935 e 1943, principalmente sui progetti che hanno 
richiesto il lavoro manuale, ma anche sui progetti per gli 
artisti, i produttori, gli attori ed i musicisti. Al relativo 
picco, i produttori federali si proiettano impiegato circa 6.500 
uomini e donne, alcuno di chi più successivamente è diventato 
famoso. Verso la fine dei 1930s i produttori del progetto hanno 
cominciato una serie "di dati storici di vita," registrando le 
esperienze negli Americani vari da Florida nell'Alaska. A volte 
hanno registrato le parole della gente verbatim; altre volte lo 
hanno riscritti nelle descrizioni. In questo esempio, 
equipaggiare di Berta Ballard ha ricordato venire a contatto del 
famoso per proscrivere "il billy il capretto" come bambino nel Nuovo 
Messico. Unassuming ed addolcisce, con i buoni modi, ma 
egualmente se lo è ricordato di come un bandito ed assassino che 
hanno mantenuto la loro contea nell'agitazione</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η νέα διαπραγμάτευση προσπάθησε να τελειώσει την 
κατάθλιψη με τα έξοδα των κυβερνητικών χρημάτων για να 
απασχολήσει τους ανέργους. Μια από τις πιό φιλόδοξες 
προσπάθειές της, η διοίκηση προόδου εργασιών (WPA), έβαλε 
8,5 εκατομμύριο ανθρώπους στην εργασία μεταξύ 1935 και 
1943, συνήθως στα προγράμματα που απαίτησαν τη χειρωνακτική 
εργασία, αλλά και στα προγράμματα για τους καλλιτέχνες, τους 
συγγραφείς, τους δράστες, και τους μουσικούς. Στην αιχμή 
του, το ομοσπονδιακό πρόγραμμα συγγραφέων απασχόλησε περίπου 
6.500 άνδρες και γυναίκες, μερικές από τους οποίους έγιναν 
αργότερα διάσημες. Προς το τέλος της δεκαετίας του '30 οι 
συγγραφείς του προγράμματος άρχισαν μια σειρά "ιστοριών ζωής," 
καταγράφοντας την εμπειρία διαφορετικών Αμερικανών από τη 
Φλώριδα στην Αλάσκα. Μερικές φορές κατέγραψαν τις λέξεις 
των ανθρώπων κατά λέξη  άλλοι χρόνοι τους ξανέγραψαν στα 
αφηγήματα. Παράδειγμα, επάνδρωση Berta Ballard που 
υπενθυμίζεται σε αυτό το συναντώντας το διάσημο εκτός νόμου 
"Billy το κατσίκι" ως παιδί στο New Mexico. Ήταν 
ταπεινός και ευγενής, με τους καλούς τρόπους, αλλά τον θυμήθηκε 
επίσης ως ληστή και δολοφόνο που κράτησαν το νομό τους στην 
αναταραχή</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El nuevo reparto intentó terminar la depresión 
pasando el dinero del gobierno para emplear el desempleado. Uno 
de sus esfuerzos más ambiciosos, la administración del progreso de 
trabajos (WPA), puso a 8.5 millones de personas de para trabajar entre
1935 y 1943, sobre todo en los proyectos que requirieron el trabajo 
manual, pero también en los proyectos para los artistas, los 
programas de escritura, los agentes, y los músicos. En su pico,
los programas de escritura federales proyectan empleado cerca de 6.500
hombres y mujeres, algunos de quién llegó a ser más adelante 
famoso. En los programas de escritura atrasado los años 30 del 
proyecto comenzaron una serie de "historias de la vida," registrando 
las experiencias de americanos diversos de la Florida a Alaska. 
Registraron a veces las palabras de la gente in extenso; 
otras veces los reescribieron en narrativas. En este 
ejemplo, el servir de Berta Ballard recordó el resolver del famoso 
para proscribir el "billy el cabrito" como niño en New México. 
Él unassuming y trata con suavidad, con buenas maneras, pero 
ella también lo recordó como un bandido y asesino que mantuvieron su
condado la agitación</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087348</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103821</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-well-mannered-bandit-and-a-killer-little-berta-ballard-remembers-billy-the-kid</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
