<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104741</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104741</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086082</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Dissatisfied With the Lives They Live: Farm Women Describe Their Work in a 1913 U.S. Department of Agriculture Report</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unzufrieden gemacht mit den Lebensdauern leben 
sie: Bauernhof-Frauen beschreiben ihre Arbeit in einem 1913 
VEREINIGTE STAATEN Landwirtschaftsministerium Report</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mécontent avec les vies ils vivent : Les 
femmes de ferme décrivent leur travail dans un ministère de 
l'agriculture des 1913 ETATS-UNIS l'état</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Descontentado com as vidas vivem: As 
mulheres da fazenda descrevem seu trabalho em um departamento de 1913 
ESTADOS UNIDOS do relatório da agricultura</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Insoddisfatto con le vite vivono: Le donne 
dell'azienda agricola descrivono il loro lavoro in un ministero 
dell'agricoltura dei 1913 STATI UNITI il rapporto</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δυσαρεστημένοι με τις ζωές ζουν: Οι αγροτικές 
γυναίκες περιγράφουν την εργασία τους σε ένα ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ τμήμα 
του 1913 έκθεσης γεωργίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Descontentado con las vidas viven: Las 
mujeres de la granja describen su trabajo en un Ministerio de 
Agricultura de 1913 ESTADOS UNIDOS el informe</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Statistics on women's work in the early 20th century were invariably misleading: most women worked but only a minority were formally in the wage labor force. Nowhere was the discrepancy between the domestic ideal and the reality of women's work lives wider than in rural America. In 1913 the U. S. Department of Agriculture decided to investigate and document the lives of farm woman they discovered a vast reservoir of discontent. The report, reproduced here, was culled from letters responding to a questionnaire sent to the wives of farmers and commented on all aspects of rural life, especially the enormous burden of labor that these officially non-working women were expected to carry out.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Statistiken über Arbeit der Frauen im frühen 20.
Jahrhundert führten unveränderlich irre: die meisten Frauen 
arbeiteten, aber nur eine Minorität galten formal die Arbeitskräfte 
des Lohnes. Nirgendwo war die Diskrepanz zwischen dem 
inländischen idealen und der Wirklichkeit der Leben Arbeit der Frauen
weit als in landwirtschaftlichem Amerika. In 1913 entschied das 
USLANDWIRTSCHAFTSMINISTERIUM, die Leben der Bauernhoffrau 
nachzuforschen und zu dokumentieren, die sie einen beträchtlichen 
Vorratsbehälter von Unzufriedenheit entdeckten. Der Report, 
hier reproduziert, wurde von den Zeichen ausgewählt, die auf einen 
Fragebogen reagieren, der den Frauen der Landwirte geschickt wurde und
alle Aspekte der landwirtschaftlichen Lebensdauer, besonders die 
enorme Belastung von der Arbeit kommentiert war, die diese offiziell 
non-working Frauen erwartet wurden, durchzuführen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les statistiques sur le travail des femmes en 
début du 20ème siècle trompaient invariablement : la plupart 
des femmes ont travaillé mais seulement une minorité étaient 
formellement dans la main-d'oeuvre de salaire. Nulle part était
l'anomalie entre l'idéal domestique et la réalité des vies du 
travail des femmes plus au loin qu'en Amérique rurale. Dans 
1913 le ministère de l'agriculture des États-Unis a décidé 
d'étudier et documenter les vies de la femme de ferme qu'elles ont 
découvert un vaste réservoir du mécontentement. L'état, 
reproduit ici, a été cueilli des lettres répondant à un 
questionnaire envoyé aux épouses des fermiers et présenté ses 
observations sur tous les aspects de la vie rurale, particulièrement 
l'énorme fardeau du travail qu'on s'est attendu à ce que ces femmes 
officiellement non-travaillantes effectuent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os statistics no trabalho das mulheres no 20o 
século adiantado misleading invariàvel: a maioria de mulheres 
trabalharam mas somente um minority estava formalmente na força labor
do salário. A nenhumaa parte era a discrepância entre o ideal 
doméstico e a realidade de vidas do trabalho das mulheres mais 
largamente do que em América rural. Em 1913 o departamento dos 
E. U. de agricultura decidiu-se investigar e documentar as vidas da 
mulher que da fazenda descobriram um reservatório vasto do 
discontent. O relatório, reproduzido aqui, culled das letras 
que respondem a um questionário emitido às esposas dos fazendeiros e
comentado em todos os aspectos da vida rural, especial o burden enorme
do trabalho que estas mulheres oficialmente non-working se esperaram 
realizar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le statistiche sul lavoro delle donne nell'inizio 
del 20esimo secolo stavano fuorviando invariabilmente: la 
maggior parte delle donne hanno lavorato ma soltanto una minoranza era
formalmente nella forza di lavoro dello stipendio. Nessuna
parte era la discrepanza fra il ideale domestico e la realtà delle 
vite del lavoro delle donne più largamente di in America rurale. 
In 1913 il ministero dell'agricoltura degli Stati Uniti ha 
deciso studiare e documentare le vite della donna che dell'azienda 
agricola hanno scoperto un serbatoio ampio di discontent. Il 
rapporto, riprodotto qui, si è raccolto dalle lettere che rispondono 
ad un questionario trasmesso alle mogli dei coltivatori e commentato 
tutte le funzioni di vita rurale, particolarmente la difficoltà 
enorme del lavoro che queste donne ufficialmente non-working si 
sono pensate che effettuassero.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι στατιστικές όσον αφορά την εργασία των γυναικών 
στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα ήταν αμετάβλητα παραπλανητικές: 
οι περισσότερες γυναίκες εργάστηκαν αλλά μόνο μια 
μειονότητα ήταν τυπικά στο εργατικό δυναμικό αμοιβών. Δεν 
ήταν πουθενά η απόκλιση μεταξύ εσωτερικού του ιδανικού και της 
πραγματικότητας των ζωών εργασίας των γυναικών ευρύτερων απ'ό,τι
στην αγροτική Αμερική. Το 1913 το Θ*u. το Θ*ς. τμήμα της 
γεωργίας αποφάσισε να ερευνήσει και να τεκμηριώσει τις ζωές της 
αγροτικής γυναίκας που ανακάλυψαν μια απέραντη δεξαμενή της 
δυσαρέσκειας. Η έκθεση, που αναπαρήχθη εδώ, επιλέχτηκε από
τις επιστολές που αποκρίνονται σε ένα ερωτηματολόγιο που στάλη 
στις συζύγους των αγροτών και σχολίασε όλες τις πτυχές της 
αγροτικής ζωής, ειδικά το τεράστιο φορτίο της εργασίας που 
αυτές οι επίσημα μη εργάσιμες γυναίκες αναμένονταν για να 
πραγματοποιήσουν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La estadística sobre el trabajo de las mujeres en
el vigésimo siglo temprano engañaba invariable: la mayoría de
las mujeres trabajaron pero solamente una minoría estaba formalmente 
en la mano de obra del salario. Ninguna parte era la 
discrepancia entre el ideal doméstico y la realidad de las vidas del 
trabajo de las mujeres más de par en par que en América rural. 
En 1913 el Ministerio de Agricultura de los E.E.U.U. decidía a 
investigar y a documentar las vidas de la mujer de la granja que 
descubrieron un depósito extenso del descontento. El informe, 
reproducido aquí, fue entresacado de las cartas que respondían a un 
cuestionario enviado a las esposas de granjeros y comentado respecto a
todos los aspectos de la vida rural, especialmente la carga enorme de 
trabajo que se esperaba que estas mujeres oficialmente non-working 
realizaran.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086082</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104741</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/dissatisfied-with-the-lives-they-live-farm-women-describe-their-work-in-a-1913-u-s-department-of-agriculture-report</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
