<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103436</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103436</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211161</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ten Activities to Consider Before Developing Your First Online Course</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">10 bevor zu betrachten Aktivitäten, Ihr erster 
Onlinekurs entwickelt wird</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Dix activités à considérer avant de développer
votre premier cours en ligne</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dez atividades a considerar antes de desenvolver 
seu primeiro curso em linha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dieci attività da considerare prima di sviluppare
il vostro primo corso in linea</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δέκα δραστηριότητες που εξετάζουν πρίν αναπτύσσει την
πρώτη σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρά μαθημάτων σας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Diez actividades a considerar antes de desarrollar
su primer curso en línea</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many educators have asked me what they can do to prepare before they formally begin to develop an online course. Becoming familiar with the online learning environment and knowing how to create web pages can give you a head start in developing your course.  Consider preparing with one or more of the 10 activities presented.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele Erzieher haben mich gefragt, was sie tun 
können, um sich vorzubereiten, bevor sie formal anfangen, einen 
Onlinekurs zu entwickeln. Das Werden vertraut mit der 
Onlineerlernenumgebung und das Können Webseiten erstellen können 
Ihnen einen Hauptanfang geben, wenn sie Ihren Kurs entwickeln. 
Erwägen Sie, mit einer oder mehr der 10 dargestellten 
Aktivitäten sich vorzubereiten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Beaucoup d'éducateurs m'ont demandé ce qu'ils 
peuvent faire pour préparer avant qu'ils commencent formellement à 
développer un cours en ligne. Se familiariser avec 
l'environnement d'étude en ligne et savoir créer des pages Web 
peuvent vous donner un début principal en développant votre cours. 
Considérez préparer avec un ou plusieurs des 10 activités 
présenté.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muitos educadores têm-me perguntado o que podem 
fazer para se preparar antes que comecem formalmente a desenvolver um 
curso em linha. Tornar-se familiar com o ambiente de 
aprendizagem em linha e saber criar Web pages podem dar-lhe um começo
principal em desenvolver seu curso. Considere preparar-se com 
uma ou o mais das 10 atividades apresentadas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molti educatori lo hanno chiesto che cosa possono 
fare per prepararsi prima che comincino formalmente a sviluppare un 
corso in linea. Diventare esperto con l'ambiente imparante in 
linea e sapere creare i Web pagi possono darvi un inizio capo nello 
sviluppare il vostro corso. Studii la possibilità di prepararsi
con uno o più delle 10 attività presentato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλοί εκπαιδευτικοί μου έχουν ρωτήσει τι μπορούν να 
κάνουν για να προετοιμαστούν προτού να αρχίσουν να αναπτύσσουν 
τυπικά μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρά μαθημάτων. Να γίνει 
εξοικειωμένος με το σε απευθείας σύνδεση μαθησιακό περιβάλλον και
ξέροντας πώς να δημιουργήσει ιστοσελίδας μπορεί να σας δώσει μια
επικεφαλής έναρξη στην ανάπτυξη της σειράς μαθημάτων σας. 
Θεωρήστε με μια ή περισσότερες από τις 10 δραστηριότητες 
που παρουσιάζονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Muchos educadores me tienen preguntado lo que 
pueden hacer para prepararse antes de que comiencen formalmente a 
desarrollar un curso en línea. El llegar a ser familiar con el 
ambiente que aprende en línea y saber crear Web pages pueden darle 
una ventaja en desarrollar su curso. Considere el prepararse con
una o más de las 10 actividades presentado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PATRICIA DELICH
FN:PATRICIA DELICH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211161</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103436</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ten-activities-to-consider-before-developing-your-first-online-course</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
