<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105324</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105324</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086851</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Stereatronics--A New Science That Will Change Your Way of Life"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Stereatronics -- eine neue Wissenschaft, die Ihre
Lebensart ändert"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Stereatronics -- la nouvelle Science qui changera
votre façon de vivre"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Stereatronics -- uma ciência nova que mude sua 
maneira de vida"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Stereatronics -- una nuova scienza che cambierà 
il vostro modo di vivere"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Stereatronics -- μια νέα επιστήμη που θα αλλάξει 
τον τρόπο ζωής σασ"</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Stereatronics -- una nueva ciencia que cambiará 
su manera de la vida"</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Research and development scientists at Bell Laboratories introduced a device in 1947 that heralded a technological revolution with widespread consequences for consumers, industry, and the armed forces: the tiny transistor. Replacing the vacuum tube as the basic component for a host of electronic products, this semi-conductor solid-state device and such later developments in electronics as the integrated circuit, lasers, fiber optics, and digitization techniques, allowed the miniaturization of conveniences as with radios and computers, and made possible many aspects of present-day life and work--from telecommunications to automated factory operations. The following Collier's article from 1954, by renowned World War II reporter and novelist Cornelius Ryan, dubbed the new science "Stereatronics" and predicted revolutionary changes in the offing. Though the name did not survive the times in which it was coined, the electronics industry it described would soon become the largest manufacturing industry in the United States.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Forschung und Entwicklung Wissenschaftler an den 
Bell Labors stellten eine Einheit 1947 vor, das eine technologische 
Umdrehung mit weitverbreiteten Konsequenzen für Verbraucher, 
Industrie und die bewaffneten Kräfte ankündigte: der kleine 
Transistor. Das Vakuumgefäß als der grundlegende Bestandteil 
für einen Hauptrechner der elektronischen Produkte, dieses 
Festkörperelements des Halbleiters und solcher neuerer Entwicklungen 
in der Elektronik ersetzen, die die integrierte Schaltung, Laser, 
Faseroptik und Digital-Analog-Wandlung Techniken, der Miniaturisierung
der Bequemlichkeiten wie mit Radios und Computern erlaubte und 
möglich viele Aspekte von der heutigen Lebensdauer und von der Arbeit
-- von Telekommunikation gebildet zu Produktionsstätteoperationen. 
Der folgenden Artikel des Colliers von 1954, durch berühmten 
Weltkriegreporter und Novelist Cornelius Ryan, betitelte die neue 
Wissenschaft "Stereatronics" und vorausgesagter Revolutionär ändert 
in Aussicht. Obwohl der Name nicht die Zeiten überlebte, in 
denen er geprägt wurde, würde die Elektronikindustrie, die er 
beschrieb, bald die größte verarbeitendee Fertigungsindustrie in den
Vereinigten Staaten werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les scientifiques de recherches et de 
développement aux laboratoires de Bell ont présenté un dispositif 
en 1947 qui a annoncé une révolution technologique avec des 
conséquences répandues pour des consommateurs, l'industrie, et les 
forces armées : le transistor minuscule. Substituant le 
tube à vide comme composant de base pour une foule de produits 
électroniques, de ce dispositif semi-conducteur de semi-finale-conductor
et de tels développements postérieurs dans l'électronique que le 
circuit intégré, lasers, optique des fibres, et techniques de 
numérotisation, a permise à la miniaturisation des convenances comme
avec des radios et des ordinateurs, et fait possible beaucoup 
d'aspects de la vie et du travail actuels -- des télécommunications 
aux exécutions de usine automatisée. L'article suivant de 
Collier de 1954, par le journaliste et le romancier renommés 
Cornelius Ryan de la deuxième guerre mondiale, a doublé la nouvelle 
science "Stereatronics" et le révolutionnaire prévu change en 
perspective. Bien que le nom n'ait pas survécu les temps dans 
lesquels il a été inventé, l'industrie d'électronique qu'il a 
décrite deviendrait bientôt la plus grande industrie aux Etats-Unis.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os cientistas da pesquisa e do desenvolvimento em 
laboratórios de Bell introduziram um dispositivo em 1947 que heralded
uma volta technological com conseqüências difundidas para 
consumidores, indústria, e as forças armadas: o transistor 
minúsculo. Substituindo o tubo de vácuo como o componente 
básico para um anfitrião de produtos eletrônicos, deste dispositivo
solid-state do semicondutor e de tais desenvolvimentos mais atrasados 
na eletrônica como o circuito integrado, lasers, sistema ótico de 
fibra, e técnicas do digitization, permitiu ao miniaturization das 
conveniências como com rádios e computadores, e feito possível 
muitos aspectos da vida e do trabalho present-day -- das 
telecomunicações às operações da fábrica automatizada. O 
artigo do seguinte collier de 1954, por repórter da segunda guerra 
mundial e por novelist renowned Cornelius Ryan, dubbed a ciência nova
"Stereatronics" e mudanças preditas do revolucionário no offing. 
Embora o nome não sobreviveu os tempos em que foi inventado, a 
indústria que de eletrônica descreveu transformar-se-ia logo a 
indústria de manufacturing a maior nos estados unidos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli scienziati di sviluppo e di ricerca ai 
laboratori della Bell hanno introdotto un dispositivo in 1947 che ha 
annunziato un giro tecnologico con le conseguenze diffuse per i 
consumatori, l'industria e le forze munite: il transistore molto
piccolo. Sostituendo la valvola elettronica come il componente 
di base per una miriade di prodotti elettronici, questo dispositivo a 
semiconduttore solid-dichiarare e tali sviluppi successivi 
nell'elettronica come il circuito integrato, i laser, ottica delle 
fibre e tecniche di digitalizzazione, ha conceduto alla 
minaturizzazione delle convenienze come con le radio ed i calcolatori 
e reso possibile molte funzioni di vita e di lavoro attuali -- dalle 
telecomunicazioni ai funzionamenti della fabbrica automatizzata. 
L'articolo del seguente collier da 1954, dal reporter della 
seconda guerra mondiale e dal romanziere renowned Cornelius Ryan, 
dubbed la nuova scienza "Stereatronics" ed il rivoluzionario previsto 
cambia in vista. Benchè il nome non sopravviva i tempi in cui 
è stato coniato, l'industria che di elettronica ha descritto presto 
si transformerebbe in nella più grande industria manufatturiera in 
unito Dichiara.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι επιστήμονες έρευνας και ανάπτυξης στα εργαστήρια 
κουδουνιών εισήγαγαν μια συσκευή το 1947 που ανακοίνωσε μια 
τεχνολογική επανάσταση με τις διαδεδομένες συνέπειες για τους 
καταναλωτές, τη βιομηχανία, και τις οπλισμένες δυνάμεις: η 
μικροσκοπική κρυσταλλολυχνία. Αντικαθιστώντας τον κενό 
σωλήνα ως βασικό συστατικό για έναν πλήθο των ηλεκτρονικών 
προϊόντων, αυτή η στερεάς κατάστασης συσκευή ημιαγωγών και 
τέτοιες πιό πρόσφατες εξελίξεις στην ηλεκτρονική όπως το 
ολοκληρωμένο κύκλωμα, τα λέιζερ, την οπτική ινών, και τις 
τεχνικές ψηφιακής αναλογικής μεταλλαγής, επέτρεψαν τη 
μικρογράφηση των ευκολιών όπως με τα ραδιόφωνα και τους 
υπολογιστές, και κατέστησαν πιθανές πολλές πτυχές της παρουσών 
ζωής και της εργασίας -- από τις τηλεπικοινωνίες στις 
αυτοματοποιημένες διαδικασίες εργοστασίων. Το άρθρο του 
ακόλουθου ανθρακωρύχου από το 1954, από το διάσημο παγκόσμιο 
πόλεμο ΙΙ δημοσιογράφος και μυθιστοριογράφος Cornelius Ryan, 
μεταγλώττισε τη νέα επιστήμη "Stereatronics" και πρόβλεψε τις 
επαναστατικές αλλαγές επικείμενες. Αν και το όνομα δεν 
επέζησε των χρόνων στους οποίους πλάθηκε, η βιομηχανία 
ηλεκτρονικής που περιέγραψε θα γινόταν σύντομα η μεγαλύτερη 
βιομηχανία κατασκευής στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los científicos de investigación y del 
desarrollo en los laboratorios de Bell introdujeron un dispositivo en 
1947 que anunció una revolución tecnológica con las consecuencias 
extensas para los consumidores, la industria, y las fuerzas armadas: 
el transistor minúsculo. Substituyendo el tubo de vacío 
como el componente básico para un ordenador principal de productos 
electrónicos, de este dispositivo de estado sólido del semiconductor
y de tales progresos más últimos en la electrónica que el circuito 
integrado, lasers, la óptica de fibra, y técnicas de la numeración,
no prohibió a miniaturización de conveniencias como con las radios y
los ordenadores, y hecho posible muchos aspectos de vida y de trabajo 
actuales -- de telecomunicaciones a las operaciones de la fábrica 
automatizada. El artículo del collier siguiente a partir de 
1954, por el reportero y el novelista renombrados Cornelius Ryan de la
Segunda Guerra Mundial, dobló la nueva ciencia "Stereatronics" y 
cambios predichos del revolucionario en offing. Aunque no 
sobrevivió el nombre los tiempos en los cuales fue acuñado, la 
industria de electrónica que describió pronto se convirtió en la 
industria fabril más grande de los Estados Unidos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086851</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105324</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/stereatronics-a-new-science-that-will-change-your-way-of-life</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
