<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106589</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106589</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973952</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hurricane Katrina: Tempest in Crescent City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hurrikan Katrina: Tempest in der gerundeten 
Stadt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ouragan Katrina : Tempête dans la ville en 
croissant</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Furacão Katrina: Tempestade na cidade 
crescente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Uragano Katrina: Tempesta in città a 
mezzaluna</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τυφώνας Katrina: Θύελλα στην ημισεληνοειδή 
πόλη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Huracán Katrina: Tempestad en ciudad 
crescent</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Tempest is a side-scrolling platform game set in New Orleans during the Hurricane Katrina Disaster of 2005. The game's main character is Vivica Water, a young woman from New Orleans who moved to New York after surviving the storm. The game takes place in a dream Vivica has where she searches for her mother and helps her neighbors as the hero she wishes she could have been. Tempest is meant to be a fun adventure game that also addresses meaningful, accurate and difficult historical situations. Includes curriculum resources for teachers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tempest ist ein Seite-Verschieben der 
Bildschirmanzeige Plattformspiel, das in New-Orleans während des 
Hurrikan Katrina Unfalles von 2005 eingestellt wird. Das 
Hauptzeichen des Spiels ist Vivica Wasser, eine junge Frau von 
New-Orleans, das nach New York bewog, nachdem es der Sturm überlebt 
hatte. Das Spiel findet in einem Traumvivica hat, wo sie nach 
ihrer Mutter sucht und hilft ihren Nachbarn statt, wie der Held, den 
sie wünscht, daß sie gewesen sein könnte. Tempest wird 
bedeutet, um ein Spaßabenteuerspiel zu sein, das auch die 
aussagefähigen, genauen und schwierigen historischen Situationen 
adressiert. Schließt Lehrplanbetriebsmittel für Lehrer ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La tempête est un jeu de plateforme de 
côté-défilement réglé à la Nouvelle-Orléans pendant le 
désastre de Katrina d'ouragan de 2005. Le caractère principal 
du jeu est l'eau de Vivica, une jeune femme de la Nouvelle-Orléans 
qui s'est déplacée à New York après avoir survécu le donner l'assaut à. 
Le jeu a lieu dans un Vivica rêveur a où elle recherche sa 
mère et aide ses voisins comme le héros qu'elle souhaite qu'elle 
pourrait avoir été. La tempête est censée pour être un jeu 
d'aventure d'amusement qui adresse également des situations 
historiques signicatives, précises et difficiles. Inclut des 
ressources de programme d'études pour des professeurs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A tempestade é um jogo da plataforma do 
lado-desdobramento ajustado em Nova Orleães durante o disastre de 
Katrina do furacão de 2005. O caráter principal do jogo é a 
água de Vivica, uma mulher nova de Nova Orleães que se moveu para 
New York após sobreviver a tempestade. O jogo ocorre em um 
Vivica ideal tem onde procurara por sua matriz e ajuda a seus vizinhos
como o herói que deseja que poderia ter sido. A tempestade é 
significada ser um jogo da aventura do divertimento que se dirija 
também a situações históricas significativas, exatas e difíceis. 
Inclui recursos do curriculum para professores.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La tempesta è un gioco della piattaforma di 
lato-side-scrolling regolato a New Orleans durante il disastro di 
Katrina di uragano di 2005. Il carattere principale del gioco è
acqua di Vivica, una donna giovane da New Orleans che si è mossa 
verso New York dopo la sopravvivenza la tempesta. Il gioco 
avviene in un Vivica di sogno ha dove cerca la sua madre ed aiuta i 
suoi vicinoi come il hero desidera che potrebbe essere. La 
tempesta è significata per essere un gioco di avventura di 
divertimento che egualmente richiama le situazioni storiche 
espressive, esatte e difficili. Include le risorse di programma 
di studi per gli insegnanti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η θύελλα είναι ένα να δευτερεύων-τυλίξει παιχνίδι 
πλατφορμών που τίθεται στη Νέα Ορλεάνη κατά τη διάρκεια του 
τυφώνα Katrina Disaster του 2005. Ο βασικός 
χαρακτήρας του παιχνιδιού είναι Vivica ύδωρ, μια νέα γυναίκα 
από τη Νέα Ορλεάνη που κινήθηκε προς τη Νέα Υόρκη μετά από να 
επιζήσει της θύελλας. Το παιχνίδι πραγματοποιείται σε ένα 
όνειρο Vivica έχει όπου ψάχνει για τη μητέρα της και βοηθά 
τους γείτονές της όπως ο ήρωας επιθυμεί ότι θα μπορούσε να 
είναι. Η θύελλα προορίζεται να είναι ένα παιχνίδι 
περιπέτειας διασκέδασης που εξετάζει επίσης τις σημαντικές, 
ακριβείς και δύσκολες ιστορικές καταστάσεις. Περιλαμβάνει 
τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς προγράμματος σπουδών για τους δασκάλους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La tempestad es un juego de la plataforma del 
cara-movimiento en sentido vertical fijado en New Orleans durante el 
desastre de Katrina del huracán de 2005. El carácter principal
del juego es el agua de Vivica, mujer joven de New Orleans que se 
movió a Nueva York después de sobrevivir la tormenta. El juego
ocurre en un Vivica ideal tiene donde ella busca para a su madre y 
ayuda a sus vecinos como el héroe que ella desea que ella habría 
podido ser. La tempestad se significa para ser un juego de la 
aventura de la diversión que también trata situaciones históricas 
significativas, exactas y difíciles. Incluye los recursos del 
plan de estudios para los profesores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973952</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106589</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/hurricane-katrina-tempest-in-crescent-city</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
