<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106544</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106544</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086276</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Can't Fight Alone": James Meredith Calls on All Blacks to Participate in the Struggle for Racial Equality</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ich Kann Nicht Alleine Kämpfen": James 
Meredith ersucht um alle Schwarzen, am Kampf für rassische Gleichheit
teilzunehmen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Je Ne peux pas Seul Combattre" : 
James Meredith invite tous les noirs à participer à la 
lutte pour l'égalité raciale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Eu Não posso Lutar Sozinho": James 
Meredith convida todos os pretos participar no esforço para a 
igualdade racial</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Non posso Combattere Da solo": James 
Meredith invita tutti i neri partecipare alla lotta per uguaglianza 
razziale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"δεν μπορώ να παλεψω μόνο": James Meredith 
καλεί όλους τους Μαύρους για να συμμετέχει στην προσπάθεια για τη
φυλετική ισότητα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"No puedo Luchar Solamente": James Meredith 
invita todos los negros a participar en la lucha para la igualdad 
racial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">James Meredith (b. 1933) served in the U.S. Air Force from 1951 to 1960, then attended Jackson State College in Mississippi. Inspired by President John F. Kennedy's inaugural address, Meredith applied to the all-white University of Mississippi believing, as he later wrote, that he had "Divine Responsibility to break White Supremacy in Mississippi." After his application was denied, he sued the university with legal help from the NAACP. In June 1962, a Federal court ruled that the school must admit Meredith. Although accompanied by Federal officials, Meredith encountered repeated resistance in his efforts to register from Mississippi Governor Ross Barnett. In a move modeled on President Dwight D. Eisenhower's response to the similar situation in Little Rock, Arkansas, six years earlier, Kennedy sent Army troops to quell mob violence that had resulted in two deaths. In the following  Look  magazine article, Meredith assessed the situation at "Ole Miss" following his first semester and expressed the view that all African Americans had a responsibility "to do their part to bring about the changes necessary to equalize opportunity."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">James Meredith (b. 1933) diente in der VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Luftwaffe von 1951 bis 1960, dann bediente Jackson 
Zustand-Hochschule in Mississippi. Angespornt durch Präsident 
John F. Kennedy Eröffnungsadresse, Meredith angewendet an der 
all-weißen Universität von Mississippi glaubend, wie er später 
schrieb, daß er "göttliche Verantwortlichkeit hatte, weiße 
Vorherrschaft in Mississippi zu brechen." Nachdem seine 
Anwendung verweigert wurde, klagte er die Universität mit 
zugelassener Hilfe vom NAACP. Im Juni 1962, ordnete ein 
Bundesgerichtshof an, daß die Schule Meredith zulassen muß. 
Obgleich begleitet von den Federalbeamten, traf Meredith 
wiederholte Widerstand in seinen Bemühungen, vom Mississippi Regler 
Ross Barnett zu registrieren an. In einer Bewegung formte auf 
Präsident Dwight D. Eisenhowers Antwort zur ähnlichen Situation in 
Little Rock, Arkansas, sechs Jahre früher, Kennedy gesendete 
Armeetruppen, um Pöbelgewalttätigkeit zu unterdrücken, die zwei 
Todesfälle ergeben hatte. Im folgenden Blickzeitschrift Artikel
setzte Meredith die Situation "am Ole Fräulein fest", das seinem 
ersten Semester folgt und drückte die Meinung aus, daß alle 
afrikanischen Amerikaner eine Verantwortlichkeit "hatten, ihr Teil zu 
tun, um die Änderungen hervorzubringen, die notwendig sind, 
Gelegenheit auszugleichen."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">James Meredith (b. 1933) a servi dans 
l'Armée de l'Air des ETATS-UNIS de 1951 à 1960, université alors 
occupée d'état de Jackson au Mississippi. Inspiré par adresse
inaugurale du Président John F. Kennedy, Meredith appliqué à 
l'université tout-blanche du Mississippi croyant, comme il plus tard 
a écrit, qu'il a eu "la responsabilité divine de casser la 
Suprématie blanche au Mississippi." Après que son application 
ait été niée, il a poursuivi l'université avec l'aide légale du 
NAACP. En juin 1962, une cour fédérale a régné que l'école 
doit admettre Meredith. Bien qu'accompagné des fonctionnaires 
de Federal, Meredith a rencontré a répété la résistance dans ses 
efforts de s'enregistrer du Gouverneur Ross Barnett du Mississippi. 
Dans un mouvement a modelé sur la réponse du Président Dwight
D. Eisenhower's à la situation semblable dans peu de roche, Arkansas,
six ans plus tôt, Kennedy envoyé des troupes d'armée pour 
apaiser la violence de foule qui avait eu comme conséquence les deux 
décès. En article de magazine suivant de regard, Meredith a 
évalué la situation "à la Mlle ole" suivant son premier semestre et
était à du avis que tous les Américains africains ont eu une 
responsabilité "de faire leur partie pour provoquer les changements 
nécessaires pour égaliser l'occasion."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">James Meredith (b. 1933) serviu na força aérea 
de 1951 a 1960, faculdade então atendida de ESTADOS UNIDOS do estado 
de Jackson em Mississippi. Inspirado pelo endereço inaugural do
presidente John F. Kennedy, Meredith aplicado à universidade 
todo-branca de Mississippi que acredita, como escreveu mais tarde, que
teve "a responsabilidade divine quebrar Supremacy branco em 
Mississippi." Depois que sua aplicação foi negada, sued a 
universidade com ajuda legal do NAACP. Em junho 1962, uma corte 
federal governou que a escola deve admitir Meredith. Embora 
acompanhado por oficiais de Federal, Meredith encontrou repetiu a 
resistência em seus esforços registar do regulador Ross Barnett de 
Mississippi. Em um movimento modelou na resposta à situação 
similar em pouca rocha, Arkansas do presidente Dwight D. Eisenhower, 
seis anos mais adiantado, tropas emitidas Kennedy do exército para 
quell a violência do mob que tinha resultado em duas mortes. No
seguinte artigo do compartimento do olhar, Meredith avaliou a 
situação "na senhorita ole" que segue seu primeiro semester e 
expressou a vista que todos os americanos africanos tiveram uma 
responsabilidade "fazer sua parte para causar as mudanças 
necessárias igualar a oportunidade."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">James Meredith (b. 1933) ha servito 
nell'aeronautica degli STATI UNITI da 1951 a 1960, Jackson allora 
assistita a Dichiara l'università nel Mississippi. 
Ispirato dall'indirizzo inaugurale del presidente John F. 
Kennedy, Meredith applicato all'università tutto-bianca de 
Mississippi che crede, più successivamente ha scritto, che ha avuto 
"responsabilità divine di rompere Supremacy bianco nel Mississippi." 
Dopo che la sua applicazione sia negata, ha citato l'università
con aiuto legale dal NAACP. Nel mese di giugno del 1962, una 
corte federale ha regolato che la scuola deve ammettere Meredith. 
Anche se accompagnato dai funzionari del Federal, Meredith ha 
incontrato ha ripetuto la resistenza nei suoi sforzi registrare dal 
regolatore Ross Barnett del Mississippi. In un movimento ha 
modellato sulla risposta alla situazione simile in poca roccia, 
Arkansas, sei anni più in anticipo, del presidente Dwight D. 
Eisenhower truppe dell'esercito trasmesse Kennedy per acquietare la 
violenza del mob che aveva provocato due morti. Nel seguente 
articolo dello scomparto di sguardo, Meredith ha valutato la 
situazione "alla sig.na ole" che segue il suo primo semestre ed ha 
espresso l'opinione che tutti gli Americani africani hanno avuti una 
responsabilità "di fare la loro parte per determinare i cambiamenti 
necessari per livellare l'occasione."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">James Meredith (β. 1933) εξυπηρέτησε στην 
Πολεμική Αεροπορία των Η.Π.Α. από το 1951 ως το 1960, 
κατόπιν παρευρέθηκε στο κρατικό κολλέγιο του Τζάκσον στο 
Μισισιπή. Εμπνευσμένο από την εναρκτήρια διεύθυνση 
Προέδρου John F. Kennedy's, Meredith ίσχυσε για το 
όλος-άσπρο πανεπιστήμιο της πίστης του Μισισιπή, όπως έγραψε 
αργότερα, ότι είχε "θεία ευθύνη να σπάσει την άσπρη υπεροχή 
στο Μισισιπή." Αφότου αμφισβητήθηκε η αίτησή του, μήνυσε 
το πανεπιστήμιο με τις νομικές οδηγίες από το NAACP. Τον 
Ιούνιο του 1962, ένα ομοσπονδιακό δικαστήριο διέταξε ότι το 
σχολείο πρέπει να αναγνωρίσει Meredith. Αν και 
συνοδεύεται από τους ομοσπονδιακούς ανώτερους υπαλλήλους, 
Meredith αντιμετώπισε την επαναλαμβανόμενη αντίσταση στις 
προσπάθειές του να καταχωρήσει από τον κυβερνήτη Ross 
Barnett του Μισισιπή. Σε μια κίνηση που διαμορφώθηκε 
σύμφωνα με την απάντηση Προέδρου Dwight D. Eisenhower's 
στην παρόμοια κατάσταση σε λίγο βράχο, Αρκάνσας, έξι έτη 
νωρίτερα, Kennedy έστειλε τα στρατεύματα στρατού για να 
καταστείλει τη βία όχλου που είχε οδηγήσει σε δύο θανάτους. 
Στο ακόλουθο άρθρο περιοδικών βλέμματος, Meredith 
αξιολόγησε την κατάσταση "στη Δεσποινίς Ole" μετά από το 
πρώτο εξάμηνό του και εξέφρασε την όψη ότι όλοι οι αφρικανικοί
Αμερικανοί είχαν την ευθύνη "να κάνουν το μέρος τους για να 
επιφέρουν τις αλλαγές απαραίτητες να εξισώσουν την ευκαιρία."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">James Meredith (b. 1933) sirvió en la fuerza 
aérea a partir de 1951 a 1960, universidad entonces atendida de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS del estado de Jackson en Mississippi. Inspirado 
por direccionamiento inaugural de presidente John F. Kennedy, Meredith
aplicado a la universidad todo-blanca de Mississippi que cree, como 
él escribió más adelante, que él tenía "responsabilidad divina de
romper la Supremacía blanca en Mississippi." Después de que su 
aplicación fuera negada, él demandó la universidad con ayuda legal 
del NAACP. En junio de de 1962, una corte federal gobernó que 
la escuela debe admitir Meredith. Aunque fue acompañado por los
funcionarios Federal, Meredith encontró relanzó resistencia en sus 
esfuerzos de colocarse del gobernador Ross Barnett de Mississippi. 
En un movimiento modeló en la respuesta a la situación similar
en poca roca, Arkansas, seis años anterior, de presidente Dwight D. 
Eisenhower las tropas enviadas Kennedy del ejército para calmar la 
violencia de la multitud que había dado lugar a dos muertes. En
el artículo siguiente del compartimiento de la mirada, Meredith 
evaluó la situación en la "Srta. ole" que seguía su primer semestre
y expresó la opinión que todos los americanos africanos tenían una 
responsabilidad "de hacer su parte para causar los cambios necesarios 
para igualar oportunidad."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086276</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106544</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-cant-fight-alone-james-meredith-calls-on-all-blacks-to-participate-in-the-struggle-for-racial-equality</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
