<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106896</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106896</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207272</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Chicago's Columbus Park: The Prairie Idealized</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Park Columbus Chicagos: Das Grasland 
Idealisierte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Parc de Columbus de Chicago : La Prairie A 
idéalisé</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Parque De Columbo De Chicago: A Pradaria 
Idealized</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Parco De Columbus Del Chicago: Il Prairie Ha
idealizzato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πάρκο του Columbus του Σικάγου: Το λιβάδι που 
εξιδανικεύεται</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Parque De Columbus De Chicago: La Pradera 
Idealizada</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents the story of Jens Jensen, who immigrated from Denmark to the U.S. in the 1880s, took a job as a Chicago street sweeper, was promoted to gardener, and rose to renown as a landscape architect. Jensen aimed to portray the soul of the landscape and developed the Prairie style, incorporating regional trees and flowers in idealized settings of groves, streams, limestone outcroppings, and flat fields.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt die Geschichte von Jens Jensen dar, die von
Dänemark in die VEREINIGTEN STAATEN im 1880s einwanderte, einen Job 
als Chicago Straße Kehrmaschine nahm, zum Gärtner gefördert wurde
und zum Renommee als Landschaftsarchitekt stieg. Jensen 
zielte darauf ab, die Seele der Landschaft zu schildern und 
entwickelte die Graslandart, die verbindenen regionalen Bäume und 
die Blumen in idealisierten Einstellungen der Waldungen, Ströme, 
Kalkstein outcroppings und fängt flach auf.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente l'histoire de Jens Jensen, qui a 
immigré du Danemark aux ETATS-UNIS dans le 1880s, a pris un travail 
comme balayeuse de Chicago, a été favorisée au jardinier, et a 
monté à la renommée en tant qu'architecte paysagiste. Jensen
a visé à dépeindre l'âme de l'horizontal et a développé le 
modèle de prairie, les arbres régionaux d'incorporation et les 
fleurs dans les configurations idéalisées des plantations, des jets,
des outcroppings de pierre à chaux, et des zones plates.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta a história de Jens Jensen, que 
immigrated de Dinamarca aos ESTADOS UNIDOS no 1880s, fêz exame de um 
trabalho como um sweeper de rua de Chicago, foi promovida ao gardener,
e se levantou ao renown como um arquiteto de paisagem. Jensen 
apontou portray a alma da paisagem e desenvolveu o estilo da pradaria,
as árvores regionais incorporando e as flores em ajustes idealized 
dos bosques, dos córregos, dos outcroppings da pedra calcária, e de 
campos lisos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta la storia di Jens Jensen, che immigrated 
dalla Danimarca negli STATI UNITI nel 1880s, ha preso un lavoro come 
spazzatrice di via del Chicago, è stata promossa al giardiniere ed è
aumentato a renown come architetto pæsaggista. Jensen ha mirato 
a ritrarre l'anima del paesaggio ed ha sviluppato lo stile del 
prairie, gli alberi regionali d'incorporazione ed i fiori nelle 
regolazioni idealizzate dei boschetti, dei flussi, dei outcroppings 
del calcare e dei campi piani.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει την ιστορία του Jens Jensen, που 
μετανάστευσε από τη Δανία στις ΗΠΑ στο 1880s, ανάλαβε δουλειά 
όπως ένα όχημα αποκομιδής απορριμμάτων οδών του Σικάγου, 
προήχθη στον κηπουρό, και ανήλθε στη φήμη ως αρχιτέκτονας 
τοπίων. Το Jensen στόχευσε να απεικονίσει την ψυχή του 
τοπίου και ανέπτυξε το ύφος λιβαδιών, που ενσωματώνει τα 
περιφερειακά δέντρα και τα λουλούδια στις εξιδανικευμένες τιμές 
των παραμέτρων των αλσών, των ρευμάτων, των outcroppings 
ασβεστόλιθων, και των επίπεδων πεδίων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta la historia de Jens Jensen, que 
immigrated de Dinamarca a los ESTADOS UNIDOS en el 1880s, tomó un 
trabajo como barrendero de calle de Chicago, fue promovida al 
jardinero, y se levantó al renombre como arquitecto de paisaje. 
Jensen apuntó retratar el alma del paisaje y desarrolló el 
estilo de la pradera, los árboles regionales que incorporaban y las 
flores en configuraciones idealizadas de arboledas, de secuencias, de 
outcroppings de la piedra caliza, y de campos planos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207272</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106896</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/chicagos-columbus-park-the-prairie-idealized</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
