<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106747</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106747</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203505</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Investigate Biosphere 2 by Modeling and Designing Experiments</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Forschen Sie Biosphäre 2 nach, indem Sie 
Experimente formen und konzipieren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Étudiez la biosphère 2 en modelant et en 
concevant des expériences</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Investigue o biosphere 2 modelando e projetando 
experiências</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi la biosfera 2 modellando e progettando gli 
esperimenti</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ερευνήστε τη βιόσφαιρα 2 με τη διαμόρφωση και το 
σχεδιασμό των πειραμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Investigue la biosfera 2 modelando y diseñando 
experimentos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This case study developed as part of the BioQuest project uses data from the actual Biosphere 2 experiment to construct a model for Sim-Bio 2. This case study provides information on how to access the model and explains how the model can be used to explore problems encountered with Biosphere 2. The study poses several scenarios and asks questions that can be addressed with the model. The case study provides scenario questions, additional information on the model, multiple simulation ideas and a short explanation of Biosphere processes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Fallstudie entwickelte sich als Teil der 
BioQuest Projekt-Gebrauchdaten vom tatsächlichen Experiment der 
Biosphäre 2, um ein Modell für SimBio2 zu konstruieren. Diese 
Fallstudie stellt Informationen auf zur Verfügung, wie man auf das 
Modell zugreift und erklärt, wie das Modell benutzt werden kann, um 
die Probleme zu erforschen, die mit Biosphäre 2 angetroffen werden. 
Die Studie wirft einige Drehbücher auf und stellt Fragen, die 
mit dem Modell adressiert werden können. Die Fallstudie stellt 
Drehbuchfragen, zusätzliche Informationen auf dem Modell, mehrfache 
Simulation Ideen und eine kurze Erklärung der Biosphäreprozesse zur 
Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette étude de cas s'est développée en tant 
qu'élément des données d'utilisations de projet de BioQuest de 
l'expérience réelle de la biosphère 2 pour construire un modèle 
pour Sim-Bio 2. Cette étude de cas fournit des informations sur
la façon dont accéder au modèle et explique comment le modèle peut
être employé pour explorer des problèmes produits avec la 
biosphère 2. L'étude pose plusieurs scénarios et pose les 
questions qui peuvent être adressées avec le modèle. L'étude
de cas fournit des questions de scénario, l'information 
supplémentaire sur le modèle, des idées multiples de simulation et 
une explication courte des processus de biosphère.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este estudo de caso desenvolvido como a parte do 
projeto de BioQuest usa dados da experiência real do biosphere 2 
construir um modelo para 2 Sim-sim-Bio. Este estudo de caso 
fornece a informação em como alcançar o modelo e explica como o 
modelo pode ser usado explorar os problemas encontrados com biosphere 
2. O estudo poses diversos scenarios e faz as perguntas que 
podem ser dirigidas com o modelo. O estudo de caso fornece 
perguntas do scenario, a informação adicional no modelo, idéias 
múltiplas da simulação e uma explanação curta de processos do 
biosphere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa inchiesta si è sviluppata come componente 
dei dati di usi di progetto BioQuest dall'esperimento reale di 
biosfera 2 per costruire un modello per Sim-Bio- 2. Questa 
inchiesta fornisce le informazioni su come accedere al modello e 
spiega come il modello può essere usato per esplorare i problemi 
incontrati con biosfera 2. Lo studio propone parecchi piani 
d'azione e fa le domande che possono essere indirizzate con il 
modello. L'inchiesta fornisce le domande del piano d'azione, le 
informazioni supplementari sul modello, le idee multiple di 
simulazione e una spiegazione corta dei processi di biosfera.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιπτωσιολογική μελέτη που αναπτύσσεται ως 
τμήμα του προγράμματος BioQuest χρησιμοποιεί τα στοιχεία από 
την πραγματική βιόσφαιρα 2 πείραμα για να κατασκευάσει ένα 
μοντέλο για σημ-βιο 2. Αυτή η περιπτωσιολογική μελέτη 
παρέχει τις πληροφορίες για το πώς να έχει πρόσβαση στο μοντέλο 
και εξηγεί πώς το μοντέλο μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί για να 
ερευνήσει τα προβλήματα που αντιμετωπίζονται με τη βιόσφαιρα 2. 
Η μελέτη θέτει διάφορα σενάρια και υποβάλλει τις ερωτήσεις
που μπορούν να εξεταστούν με το μοντέλο. Η περιπτωσιολογική 
μελέτη παρέχει τις ερωτήσεις σεναρίου, τις πρόσθετες πληροφορίες
για τις πρότυπες, πολλαπλάσιες ιδέες προσομοίωσης και μια σύντομη
εξήγηση των διαδικασιών βιόσφαιρας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este estudio de caso se convirtió como parte de 
los datos de las aplicaciones del proyecto de BioQuest del experimento
real de la biosfera 2 para construir un modelo para Sim-Bio 2. 
Este estudio de caso proporciona a la información en cómo 
tener acceso al modelo y explica cómo el modelo se puede utilizar 
para explorar los problemas encontrados con la biosfera 2. El 
estudio plantea varios decorados y hace preguntas que se puedan tratar
con el modelo. El estudio de caso proporciona a preguntas del 
decorado, a la información adicional en el modelo, a ideas múltiples
de la simulación y a una explicación corta de los procesos de la 
biosfera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:ELISABETH ODUM
FN:ELISABETH ODUM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:H. ODUM
FN:H. ODUM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770203505</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106747</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/investigate-biosphere-2-by-modeling-and-designing-experiments</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
