<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104633</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104633</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087439</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Bitter Harvest: A Puerto Rican Farmer Laments U.S. Control of the Island</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bittere Ernte: Ein Puerto Rican Landwirt 
bejammert VEREINIGTE STAATEN Steuerung der Insel</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Moisson Amère : Un fermier de Puerto Rican 
déplore la commande des ETATS-UNIS de l'île</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Colheita Amarga: Um fazendeiro de Puerto 
Rican laments o controle de ESTADOS UNIDOS do console</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Raccolta Amara: Un coltivatore di Puerto 
Rican deplora il controllo degli STATI UNITI dell'isola</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πικρή συγκομιδή: Ένας αγρότης Puerto Rican
θρηνεί τον ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ έλεγχο του νησιού</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cosecha Amarga: Un granjero de Puerto Rican 
lamenta del control de ESTADOS UNIDOS de la isla</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1898, the United States took control of the Caribbean island of Puerto Rico, intending to use it as a base for strategic naval operations. Most of the island's 900,000 inhabitants welcomed the end of Spanish rule. But they were divided about the U.S. presence. Some hoped links with the United States would lead to increased trade and prosperity; others wanted total independence. Some who initially welcomed the United States quickly became disillusioned. Severo Tulier, a small farmer from Vega Baja, had to sell his farm in 1899; he worked first as a field laborer, and then moved to San Juan to learn a trade. He described the conditions of life among farm workers to Henry K. Carroll, the special commissioner for the United States to Puerto Rico, who interviewed hundreds of Puerto Ricans as part of his effort to formulate U.S. policy for governing the island.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1898 nahmen die Vereinigten Staaten Steuerung der 
karibischen Insel von Puerto Rico und beabsichtigten, sie als 
Unterseite für strategische Marineoperationen zu benutzen. Die 
meisten Einwohnern der Insel 900.000 begrüßten das Ende der 
spanischen Richtlinie. Aber sie wurden über die VEREINIGTE 
STAATEN Anwesenheit geteilt. Einige gehoffte Links mit den 
Vereinigten Staaten würden zu erhöhten Handel und Wohlstand führen;
andere wünschten Gesamtunabhängigkeit. Einige, die 
zuerst die Vereinigten Staaten schnell begrüßten, wurden 
ernüchtert. Severo Tulier, ein kleiner Landwirt von Vega Baja, 
mußte seinen Bauernhof 1899 verkaufen; er arbeitete zuerst als 
auffangenhilfsarbeiter und zog dann auf San Juan um, um einen 
Handel zu erlernen. Er beschrieb die Lebensbedingungen unter 
Landarbeitern zum Henry K. Carroll, der spezielle Beauftragte für die
Vereinigten Staaten nach Puerto Rico, das Hunderte von Puerto Ricans 
als Teil seiner Bemühung, VEREINIGTE STAATEN Politik für die 
Regelung der Insel zu formulieren interviewte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1898, les Etats-Unis ont pris la commande de 
l'île des Caraïbes du Porto Rico, entendant l'utiliser comme base 
pour des exécutions navales stratégiques. La plupart des 
habitants de l'île 900.000 ont fait bon accueil à la fin de la 
règle espagnole. Mais elles ont été divisées au sujet de la 
présence des ETATS-UNIS. Quelques liens espérés avec les 
Etats-Unis mèneraient au commerce et à la prospérité accrus ; 
d'autres ont voulu l'indépendance totale. Certains qui au
commencement ont accueilli les Etats-Unis rapidement sont devenus 
désillusionnés. Severo Tulier, un petit fermier de Vega Baja, 
a dû vendre sa ferme en 1899 ; il a travaillé d'abord en tant 
que travailleur de zone, et s'est ensuite déplacé à San Juan
pour apprendre un commerce. Il a décrit les conditions de la 
vie parmi des ouvriers de ferme à Henry K. Carroll, commissaire 
spécial pour les Etats-Unis vers le Porto Rico, qui a interviewé des
centaines de Puerto Ricans en tant qu'élément de son effort de 
formuler la politique des ETATS-UNIS pour régir l'île.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1898, os estados unidos fizeram exame do 
controle do console do Cararibe de Puerto Rico, pretendendo usá-lo 
como uma base para operações navais estratégicas. A maioria 
dos habitantes do console 900.000 deram boas-vindas ao fim da régua 
espanhola. Mas foram divididos sobre a presença de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS. Alguns esperaram que as ligações com os estados unidos
conduzissem ao comércio e à prosperidade aumentados; outros 
quiseram a independência total. Algum que deu boas-vindas 
inicialmente ao unido indica tornou-se rapidamente disillusioned. 
Severo Tulier, um fazendeiro pequeno de Vega Baja, teve que 
vender sua fazenda em 1899; trabalhou primeiramente como um 
laborer do campo, e moveu-se então para San Juan para aprender um 
comércio. Descreveu as condições de vida entre trabalhadores 
de fazenda ao Henry K. Carroll, comissário especial para os estados 
unidos a Puerto Rico, que entrevistou centenas de Puerto Ricans como a
parte de seu esforço formular a política de ESTADOS UNIDOS para 
governar o console.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1898, unito Dichiara ha preso il 
controllo dell'isola caraibica del Porto Rico, intendente usarla come 
base per i funzionamenti navali strategici. La maggior parte 
degli abitanti dell'isola 900.000 hanno accolto favorevolmente la 
conclusione della regola spagnola. Ma sono stati divisi circa la
presenza degli STATI UNITI. Alcuni hanno sperato che i 
collegamenti con unito Dichiarasse conducessero a commercio ed 
alla prosperità aumentati; altri hanno desiderato 
l'indipendenza totale. Alcuno che inizialmente abbia accolto 
favorevolmente unito Dichiara rapidamente è stato disilluso. 
Severo Tulier, un piccolo coltivatore da Vega Baja, ha dovuto 
vendere il suo podere in 1899; ha lavorato in primo luogo come 
laborer del campo ed allora si è mosso verso il San Juan per imparare
un commercio. Ha descritto gli stati di vita fra la manodopera 
agricola al henry K. Carroll, il commissario speciale per unito 
Dichiara nel Porto Rico, che ha intervistato le centinaia di 
Puerto Ricans come componente del suo sforzo formulare la politica 
degli STATI UNITI per governare l'isola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1898, οι Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες πήραν τον έλεγχο του
καραϊβικού νησιού του Πουέρτο Ρίκο, που σκοπεύει να τον 
χρησιμοποιήσουν ως βάση για τις στρατηγικές ναυτικές διαδικασίες.
Οι περισσότεροι από τους 900.000 κατοίκους του νησιού 
χαιρέτισαν το τέλος του ισπανικού κανόνα. Αλλά διαιρέθηκαν
για την ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ παρουσία. Μερικές αναμενόμενες συνδέσεις
με τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες οδηγώ στο αυξανόμενες εμπόριο και την 
ευημερία  άλλοι θέλησαν τη συνολική ανεξαρτησία. 
Μερικοί που καλωσόρισαν αρχικά τις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες 
έγιναν γρήγορα απογοητευμένοι. Το Severo Tulier, ένας 
μικρός αγρότης από Vega Baja, έπρεπε να πωλήσει το 
αγρόκτημά του το 1899  εργάστηκε πρώτα ως laborer 
πεδίων, και κινήθηκε έπειτα προς το SAN Juan για να μάθει 
ένα εμπόριο. Περιέγραψε τους όρους της ζωής μεταξύ των 
αγροτών σε Henry K. Carroll, ο ειδικός Επίτροπος για τις 
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες στο Πουέρτο Ρίκο, το οποίο πήρε συνέντευξη 
από τις εκατοντάδες Puerto Ricans ως τμήμα της προσπάθειάς 
του να διατυπώσει ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗ πολιτική για την κυβέρνηση του 
νησιού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1898, los Estados Unidos tomaron el control de 
la isla del Caribe de Puerto Rico, preponiéndose utilizarla como base
para las operaciones navales estratégicas. La mayoría de los 
habitantes de la isla 900.000 dieron la bienvenida al final de la 
regla española. Pero los dividieron sobre la presencia de 
ESTADOS UNIDOS. Algunas conexiones esperadas con los Estados 
Unidos conducirían al comercio y a la prosperidad crecientes; 
otros desearon independencia total. Algunos que dieron la 
bienvenida inicialmente a los Estados Unidos rápidamente se 
desilusionaron. Severo Tulier, granjero pequeño de Vega Baja, 
tuvo que vender su granja en 1899; él trabajó primero como 
laborer del campo, y en seguida se trasladó a San Juan para aprender 
un comercio. Él describió las condiciones de la vida entre 
trabajadores de granja al Henrio K. Carroll, la comisión especial 
para los Estados Unidos a Puerto Rico, que se entrevistó con 
centenares de Puerto Ricans como parte de su esfuerzo de formular la 
política de ESTADOS UNIDOS para gobernar la isla.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087439</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104633</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/bitter-harvest-a-puerto-rican-farmer-laments-u-s-control-of-the-island</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
