<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107306</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107306</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086351</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"It Was a Wildly Exciting Time": Milton Meltzer Remembers the New Deal's Federal Theatre Project</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"es war eine wild aufregende Zeit": Milton 
Meltzer erinnert sich das an Bundestheater-Projekt des neuen 
Abkommens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"c'était un temps excitant d'une manière 
extravagante" : Milton Meltzer se rappelle le projet fédéral 
du théâtre de nouvelle affaire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"era uma estadia descontroladamente excitando": 
Milton Meltzer recorda o projeto federal do theatre de negócio 
novo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"era un tempo sfrenatamente emozionante": 
Milton Meltzer si ricorda del progetto federale del teatro del 
nuovo affare</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ήταν ένας άγρια συναρπαστικός χρόνοσ": Το 
Milton Meltzer θυμάται το ομοσπονδιακό πρόγραμμα θεάτρων της
νέας διαπραγμάτευσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"era un rato violentamente que excitaba": 
Milton Meltzer recuerda el proyecto federal del teatro del nuevo
reparto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Part of the New Deal's Works Progress Administration (WPA), the Federal Theatre Project (FTP) was one indication of the breadth of that program. Governments, including that of the United States, had long been important patrons of the arts, but New Deal support for art was unprecedented in American political life. Like the other New Deal arts projects, the FTP treated creative endeavors as work; it used government funds to hire unemployed actors, stage hands, and playwrights Perhaps best known for its trenchant political satire and innovative presentations, the FTP actually represented a much broader range of activity. Its productions included classics of the dramatic repertoire by such playwrights as Euripides and Shakespeare; foreign-language plays; and contemporary dramas. In an interview done in 1978 by Elizabeth C. Stevens, Milton Meltzer remembered the vibrant, creative energy along with the political controversies that he witnessed during his stint as a publicist for the New York unit of the FTP.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zerteilen Sie von der Fortschritt-Leitung Arbeiten
des neuen Abkommens (WPA), das Bundestheater-Projekt (ftp) war eine 
Anzeige über die Breite dieses Programms. Regierungen, 
einschließlich die der Vereinigten Staaten, waren lang wichtige 
Gönner der künste gewesen, aber Support des neuen Abkommens für 
kunst war in der amerikanischen politischen Lebensdauer beispiellos. 
Wie die anderen kunstprojekte des neuen Abkommens behandelte das
ftp kreative Bemühungen als Arbeit; es benutzte Regierung 
Kapital, um arbeitslose Schauspieler, Stadium Hände anzustellen, und 
die Stückeschreiber möglicherweise gut bekannt für seine trenchant 
politische Satire und erfinderischen Darstellungen, das ftp 
stellten wirklich eine viel ausgedehntere Strecke der Aktivität dar. 
Seine Produktionen enthielten Klassiker des drastischen 
Repertoires durch solche Stückeschreiber wie Euripides und 
Shakespeare; Fremdsprachenspiele; und zeitgenössische 
Dramen. In einem Interview, das 1978 mit Elizabeth C. Stevens 
erfolgt war, erinnerte sich Milton Meltzer an die vibrant, kreative 
Energie zusammen mit den politischen Kontroversen, die er während 
seines Pensums als Publizist für die New York Maßeinheit des 
ftp zeugte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Partie de la gestion d'avancement des travaux de 
nouvelle affaire (WPA), le projet fédéral de théâtre (ftp) était 
une indication de la largeur de ce programme. Les gouvernements,
y compris celui des Etats-Unis, avaient longtemps été les patrons 
importants des arts, mais le soutien de nouvelle affaire de l'art 
était sans précédent dans la vie politique américaine. Comme
les autres projets d'arts de nouvelle affaire, le ftp a traité des 
efforts créateurs en tant que travail ; il a employé des fonds
de gouvernement pour louer les acteurs sans emploi, mains d'étape, et
les dramaturges peut-être mieux connus pour son satire politique 
incisive et présentations innovatrices, le ftp ont représenté 
réellement un intervalle beaucoup plus large d'activité. Ses 
productions ont inclus des classiques du répertoire excessif par des 
dramaturges tels qu'Euripide et Shakespeare ; jeux de langue étrangère
; et drames contemporains. Dans une entrevue faite en 1978
par Elizabeth C. Stevens, Milton Meltzer s'est rappelé l'énergie 
vibrante et créatrice avec les polémiques politiques des 
lesquelles il était témoin pendant son travail assigné en tant que 
publiciste pour l'unité de New York du ftp.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Parte da administração do progresso de trabalhos
de negócio novo (WPA), o projeto federal do theatre (ftp) era uma 
indicação da largura desse programa. Os governos, including 
aquele dos estados unidos, tinham sido por muito tempo patrons 
importantes das artes, mas a sustentação do negócio novo para a 
arte era unprecedented na vida política americana. Como os 
outros projetos das artes do negócio novo, o ftp tratou esforços 
creativos como o trabalho; usou fundos do governo empregar 
atores unemployed, mãos do estágio, e os playwrights conhecidos 
talvez melhor para seus satire político trenchant e apresentações 
inovativas, o ftp representaram realmente uma escala muito mais larga 
da atividade. Suas produções incluíram clássicos do 
repertoire dramático por playwrights como Euripides e Shakespeare; 
jogos da extrangeiro-língua; e dramas contemporary. 
Em uma entrevista feita em 1978 por Elizabeth C. Stevens, Milton
Meltzer recordou a energia vibrant, creativa junto com as 
controvérsias políticas que testemunhou durante seu stint como um 
publicist para a unidade de New York do ftp.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Parte della gestione di progresso degli impianti 
del nuovo affare (WPA), il progetto federale del teatro (ftp) era 
un'indicazione della larghezza di quel programma. I governi, 
compreso quello del unito Dichiara, lungamente erano stati 
patroni importanti delle arti, ma il sostegno di nuovo affare l'arte 
era senza precedente nella vita politica americana. Come gli 
altri progetti di arti di nuovo affare, il ftp ha trattato le 
attività creative come lavoro; ha usato i fondi monetari di 
governo per assumere gli attori disoccupati, mani della fase ed i 
playwrights conosciuti forse il bene per il relativi satire politico 
trenchant e presentazioni innovarici, il ftp realmente hanno 
rappresentato una gamma molto più vasta di attività. Le 
relative produzioni hanno incluso i classici del repertorio drammatico
da tali playwrights come Euripides e Shakespeare; giochi di 
straniero-linguaggio; e drammi contemporanei. In 
un'intervista fatta in 1978 da Elizabeth C. Stevens, Milton Meltzer si
è ricordato dell'energia vibrant e creativa con le polemiche 
politiche che ha testimoniato durante il suo stint come publicist per 
l'unità de New York del ftp.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μέρος της διοίκησης προόδου εργασιών της νέας 
διαπραγμάτευσης (WPA), το ομοσπονδιακό έργο θεάτρων (FTP) 
ήταν μια ένδειξη του εύρους εκείνου του προγράμματος. Οι 
κυβερνήσεις, συμπεριλαμβανομένου αυτού των Ηνωμένων Πολιτειών, 
ήταν από καιρό σημαντικοί προστάτες των τεχνών, αλλά η νέα 
υποστήριξη διαπραγμάτευσης για την τέχνη ήταν πρωτοφανής στην 
αμερικανική πολιτική ζωή. Όπως τα άλλα νέα προγράμματα 
τεχνών διαπραγμάτευσης, οι αντιμετωπισμένες FTP δημιουργικές 
προσπάθειες ως εργασία  χρησιμοποίησε τα κυβερνητικά 
κεφάλαια για να μισθώσει τους άνεργους δράστες, σκηνικά χέρια, 
και οι θεατρικοί συγγραφείς ίσως που ήταν γνωστοί καλύτερα για 
την οξεία πολιτική σάτυρα και τις καινοτόμες παρουσιάσεις του, το
FTP αντιπροσώπευσαν πραγματικά ένα πολύ ευρύτερο φάσμα της 
δραστηριότητας. Οι παραγωγές της περιέλαβαν τους κλασικούς 
του δραματικού ρεπερτορίου από τέτοιους θεατρικούς συγγραφείς 
όπως Euripides και Shakespeare  ξένος-γλωσσικά 
παιχνίδια  και σύγχρονα δράματα. Σε μια συνέντευξη που
γίνεται το 1978 από Elizabeth C. Stevens, Milton 
Meltzer ρεμεμψερεδ η δονούμενη, δημιουργική ενέργεια μαζί με 
τις πολιτικές διαμάχες που βεβαίωσε κατά τη διάρκεια του ορίου 
του ως πολιτικό αρθρογράφο για τη μονάδα της Νέας Υόρκης του 
FTP.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Parte de la administración del progreso de 
trabajos del nuevo reparto (WPA), el proyecto federal del teatro (ftp)
era una indicación de la anchura de ese programa. Los 
gobiernos, incluyendo el de los Estados Unidos, habían sido de largo 
patrón importantes de los artes, pero la ayuda del nuevo reparto para
el arte era sin precedente en vida política americana. Como los
otros proyectos de los artes del nuevo reparto, el ftp trató 
esfuerzos creativos como trabajo; utilizó fondos del gobierno 
para emplear a agentes parados, manos de la etapa, y los dramaturgos 
conocidos quizás lo más mejor posible para su sátira política 
mordaz y presentaciones innovadoras, el ftp representaron realmente un
rango mucho más amplio de la actividad. Sus producciones 
incluyeron obras clásicas del repertorio dramático de los 
dramaturgos tales como Euripides y Shakespeare; juegos del no 
nativo-lenguaje; y dramas contemporáneos. En una 
entrevista hecha en 1978 por Elizabeth C. Stevens, Milton Meltzer 
recordó la energía vibrante, creativa junto con las controversias
políticas que él atestiguó durante su restricción como publicista 
para la unidad de Nueva York del ftp.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086351</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107306</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/it-was-a-wildly-exciting-time-milton-meltzer-remembers-the-new-deals-federal-theatre-project</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
