<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103790</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103790</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207050</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Financial Aid for Students</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Finanzielles Hilfsmittel für Kursteilnehmer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Aide financière pour des étudiants</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dae (dispositivo automático de entrada) 
financeiro para estudantes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sussidio finanziario agli allievi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οικονομική ενίσχυση για τους σπουδαστές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ayuda financiera para los estudiantes</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a place you can find help for every state of the financial aid process, whether you're in school or out of school. The site helps you apply for financial aid over the Internet and find out about scholarships, college costs, and college admissions information. It is also a gateway to other funding resources.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist ein Platz, den Sie Hilfe für jeden Zustand 
des finanziellen Helferprozesses finden können, ob Sie in der Schule 
oder außerschulisch sind. Die Site-Hilfen, die Sie finanzielles
Hilfsmittel über dem Internet beantragen und über Gelehrsamkeiten 
herausfinden, Hochschulkosten und Hochschulaufnahmeinformationen. 
Es ist auch eine Gateway zu anderen finanzierenbetriebsmitteln.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un endroit que vous pouvez trouver l'aide pour
chaque état du processus financier d'aide, si vous êtes à l'école 
ou extrascolaire. Les aides de site que vous sollicitez l'aide 
financière au-dessus de l'Internet et découvrez au sujet des 
bourses, coûts d'université, et information d'admissions 
d'université. C'est également un Gateway à d'autres 
ressources de placement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um lugar que você pode encontrar a ajuda para 
cada estado do processo financeiro do dae (dispositivo automático de 
entrada), se você é na escola ou fora da escola. As ajudas que
do local você se aplica para o dae (dispositivo automático de 
entrada) financeiro sobre o Internet e se encontra para fora sobre 
scholarships, custos da faculdade, e informação das admissões da 
faculdade. É também um Gateway a outros recursos financiando.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un posto che potete trovare l'aiuto per l'ogni 
per dichiarare del processo finanziario del sussidio, se siete a
scuola o extrascolastico. Gli aiuti che del luogo fate domanda 
per il sussidio finanziario sopra il Internet e che scoprite circa le 
borse, costi dell'università e le informazioni di ammissioni 
dell'università. È egualmente un Gateway ad altre risorse 
costituenti un fondo per.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια θέση που μπορείτε να βρείτε τις οδηγίες για
κάθε κατάσταση της οικονομικής διαδικασίας ενίσχυσης, εάν είστε
στο σχολείο ή από το σχολείο. Η περιοχή σας βοηθά να 
υποβάλετε αίτηση για την οικονομική ενίσχυση μέσω του Διαδικτύου
και να ανακαλύψετε για τις υποτροφίες, τις δαπάνες κολλεγίων, και 
τις πληροφορίες αποδοχών κολλεγίων. Είναι επίσης μια πύλη 
σε άλλα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς χρηματοδότησης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un lugar que usted puede encontrar la ayuda 
para cada estado del proceso financiero del asistente, si usted está 
en escuela o extraescolar. Las ayudas del sitio que usted 
solicita ayuda financiera sobre el Internet y que descubre sobre 
becas, costes de la universidad, e información de las admisiones de 
la universidad. Es también un Gateway a otros recursos de 
financiamiento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207050</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103790</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/financial-aid-for-students</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
