<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103749</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103749</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205931</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Fiddle Tunes of the Old Frontier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geige Melodien der alten Grenze</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Airs de violon de la vieille frontière</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tunes do fiddle da fronteira velha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arie del fiddle di vecchia frontiera</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το βιολί συντονίζει των παλαιών συνόρων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Consonancias del violín de la vieja frontera</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is a collection of 184 original sound recordings of traditional fiddle tunes performed by Henry Reed of Glen Lyn, Virginia, and recorded by folklorist Alan Jabbour. The tunes represent the music, history, and spirit of Virginia's Appalachian frontier. The site also offers musical transcriptions with descriptive notes on tune histories and musical features and an illustrated essay about Reed's life, art, and influence.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine Ansammlung von 184 ursprünglichen 
Tonaufnahmen der traditionellen Geige Melodien, die von Henry Reed von
Glen Lyn, Virginia durchgeführt werden und vom Folkloristen Alan 
Jabbour gespeichert sind. Die Melodien stellen die Musik, die 
Geschichte und den Geist von Virginias Appalachian Grenze dar. 
Die Site bietet auch musikalische Übertragungen mit 
beschreibenden Anmerkungen über Melodie Geschichten und musikalische 
Merkmale und einem erläuterten Versuch über das Leben, kunst und 
Einfluß des REED an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est une collection de 184 enregistrements sonores 
initiaux des airs traditionnels de violon exécutés par Henry Reed de
gorge Lyn, la Virginie, et enregistrés par le folkloriste 
Alan Jabbour. Les airs représentent la musique, 
l'histoire, et l'esprit de la frontière appalachienne de la Virginie.
Le site offre également les transcriptions musicales avec des 
notes descriptives sur des histoires d'air et des dispositifs musicaux
et un essai illustré au sujet de la vie, de l'art, et de l'influence 
du roseau.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é uma coleção de 184 gravações sadias 
originais dos tunes tradicionais do fiddle executados por Henry 
Lingüeta do glen Lyn, Virgínia, e gravados pelo folklorist Alan 
Jabbour. Os tunes representam a música, o history, e o 
espírito da fronteira appalachian de Virgínia. O local oferece
também transcrições musicais com notas descritivas em histories do 
tune e em características musicais e um essay ilustrado sobre a vida,
a arte, e a influência da lingüeta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è una collezione di 184 registrazioni del suono 
originali delle arie tradizionali del fiddle effettuate da Henry Reed 
del glen Lyn, la Virginia e registrate dal folklorist Alan Jabbour. 
Le arie rappresentano la musica, la storia e lo spirito della 
frontiera appalachian della Virginia. Il luogo egualmente offre 
le trascrizioni musicali con le note descrittive sui dati storici di 
aria e sulle caratteristiche musicali e un saggio illustrato circa 
vita, l'arte e l'influenza della canna.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι μια συλλογή 184 αρχικών υγιών καταγραφών του
παραδοσιακού βιολιού συντονίζει αποδοθείς από Henry Reed 
Glen Lyn, Βιρτζίνια, και καταγραμμένος από folklorist 
Alan Jabbour. Οι τόνοι αντιπροσωπεύουν τη μουσική, την 
ιστορία, και το πνεύμα των της όξινης απορροής συνόρων της 
Βιρτζίνια. Η περιοχή προσφέρει επίσης τις μουσικές 
μεταγραφές με τις περιγραφικές σημειώσεις για τις ιστορίες τόνου 
και τα μουσικά χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα και ένα διευκρινισμένο 
δοκίμιο για τη ζωή, την τέχνη, και την επιρροή του καλάμου.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es una colección de 184 grabaciones originales de
sonidos de las consonancias tradicionales del violín realizadas por 
Henry Reed de la cañada Lyn, Virginia, y registradas por el 
folklorist Alan Jabbour. Las consonancias representan la 
música, la historia, y el alcohol de la frontera apalache de 
Virginia. El sitio también ofrece transcripciones musicales con
notas descriptivas sobre historias de la consonancia y 
características musicales y un ensayo ilustrado sobre la vida, el 
arte, y la influencia de la caña.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205931</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103749</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/fiddle-tunes-of-the-old-frontier</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
