<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107474</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107474</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087293</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Devil to Tempt and a Corrupt Heart to Deceive," John Dane Battles Life's Temptations, ca. 1670s.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein zu reizen Teufel und ein verdorbenes Inneres 
zum zu betrügen," Versuchungen des John Däne-Schlacht-Lebens, ca. 
1670s.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un diable à tenter et un coeur altéré à 
tromper," les tentations de la vie de batailles de Danois de John, ca.
1670s.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um diabo a tempt e um coração corrupt a 
iludir-se," temptations da vida das batalhas do dinamarquês de John, 
ca. 1670s.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un diavolo da tentare e un cuore corrotto da 
ingannare," tentazioni della vita di battaglie del danese del John, 
ca. 1670s.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένας διάβολος που βάζουν στον πειρασμό και μια 
διεφθαρμένη καρδιά για να εξαπατήσει," Temptations John 
Dane Battles Life's, περίπου 1670s.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un diablo a tentar y un corazón corrupto a 
engañar," tentaciones de la vida de las batallas del danés de Juan, 
ca. 1670s.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">John Dane, a tailor, was born in Berkhampstead, England, around 1612. In the late 1630s, which he recollects here as a period of "a great coming to New England," he and his family emigrated to Ipswich, Massachusetts. He died in Ipswich in 1684. Dane's parents, like many Puritan parents, raised their children to carry what historian Philip Greven calls an "inner disciplinarian" within their own consciences at all times. Dane's mother reminded him: "Go where you will, God will find you out." In this narrative, Dane, who always remembered her warning, related the temptations he faced over the course of his life--to steal, to accept the advances of women, to avoid church--and the prices he negotiated with an all-seeing God. (The spelling of this selection has been regularized to make it easier to read.)</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">John Däne, ein Schneider, war in Berkhampstead, England, 
herum 1612 geboren. Im späten 1630s das er hier als Periode 
"eines großen Kommens nach Neu-England bedenkt," wanderten er und 
seine Familie nach Ipswich, Massachusetts aus. Er starb in 
Ipswich 1684. Eltern des Dänen, wie viele puritanische Eltern, 
hoben ihre Kinder an, um zu tragen, was Historiker Philip Greven einen
"inneren Disciplinarian" innerhalb ihrer eigenen Gewissenhaftigkeit 
ständig nennt. Mutter des Dänen erinnerte ihn: ", wohin 
Sie werden, gehen Gott herausfindet Sie." In dieser Darstellung 
stand Däne, der sich immer an ihr WARNING erinnerte, die Versuchungen
in Verbindung, die er über dem Kurs seiner Lebensdauer -- stehlen, 
die Fortschritte der Frauen annehmen, um Kirche zu vermeiden -- und 
über der Preise gegenüberstellte, er mit einem all-sehenden Gott 
verhandelte. (die Rechtschreibung dieser Auswahl ist reguliert 
worden, um sie einfacher zu bilden zu lesen.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Danois de John, un tailleur, est né dans 
Berkhampstead, Angleterre, autour 1612. Vers la fin de 1630s, 
qu'il rappelle ici comme période "de grand venir en Nouvelle 
Angleterre," lui et sa famille ont émigré à Ipswich, le 
Massachusetts. Il est mort à Ipswich en 1684. Les parents
du Danois, comme beaucoup de parents puritains, ont élevé leurs 
enfants pour porter ce que l'historien Philip Greven appelle "un 
disciplinaire intérieur" dans leurs propres consciences à tout 
moment. La mère du Danois l'a rappelé : "vont où vous ,
Dieu vous découvrira." Dans ce récit, le Danois, qui s'est 
toujours rappelé son avertissement, a rapporté les tentations qu'il 
a faites face au-dessus du cours de sa vie -- pour voler, pour 
recevoir les avances des femmes, pour éviter l'église -- et des prix
il était en pourparlers avec Dieu tout-voyant. (l'épellation 
de cette sélection a été régularisée pour la faciliter pour 
lire.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O dinamarquês de John, um alfaiate, foi carregado em 
Berkhampstead, Inglaterra, ao redor 1612. No 1630s atrasado, que
recorda aqui como um período "de uma vinda grande a Nova Inglaterra,"
e sua família emigrated a Ipswich, Massachusetts. Morreu em 
Ipswich em 1684. Os pais do dinamarquês, como muitos pais 
puritan, levantaram suas crianças para carregar o que o historian 
Philip Greven se chama "um disciplinarian interno" dentro de seus 
próprios consciences em todas as vezes. A matriz do 
dinamarquês lembrou-o: "vai a aonde você , o deus 
encontrá-lo-á para fora." Nesta narrativa, o dinamarquês, que
recordou sempre seu aviso, relacionou os temptations que enfrentou 
sobre o curso de sua vida -- para roubar, para aceitar os avanços das
mulheres, para evitar a igreja -- e dos preços negociou com um deus 
todo-vendo. (a soletração desta seleção regularized para a 
fazer mais fácil de ler.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il danese del John, un sarto, è stato sopportato in 
Berkhampstead, Inghilterra, intorno 1612. Verso la fine di 
1630s, che ricorda qui come periodo "di un venire grande in Nuova 
Inghilterra," lui e la sua famiglia hanno emigrato ad Ipswich, 
Massachusetts. È morto a Ipswich in 1684. I genitori del 
danese, come molti genitori puritan, hanno alzato i loro bambini per 
trasportare che cosa lo storico Philip Greven chiama "un 
disciplinarian interno" all'interno della loro propria coscienza 
sempre. La madre del danese gli ha ricordato: "va dove, il
dio li scoprirà." In questa descrizione, il danese, che si è 
ricordato sempre del suo avvertimento, ha riferito le tentazioni che 
ha affrontato sopra il corso della sua vita -- rubare, accettare gli 
avanzamenti delle donne, per evitare chiesa -- e dei prezzi ha 
negoziato con un dio tutto-vedente. (l'ortografia di questa 
selezione è stata regolarizzata per renderla più facile leggere.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Ιοχν Dane, ένας ράφτης, γεννήθηκε σε 
Berkhampstead, Αγγλία, περίπου 1612. Προς το τέλος 
1630s, που ανακαλεί εδώ ως περίοδο "μεγάλου ερχομού στη Νέα 
Αγγλία," αυτός και η οικογένειά του μετανάστευσαν στο Ίπσουιτς, 
Μασαχουσέτη. Πέθανε στο Ίπσουιτς σε 1684, γονείς του 
Δανού, όπως πολλούς πουριτανούς γονείς, ανέθρεψε τα παιδιά τους
για να φέρει τι ο ιστορικός Philip Greven καλεί "εσωτερικός 
disciplinarian" μέσα στις συνειδήσεις τους πάντα. Η 
μητέρα του Δανού υπενθύμισε σε τον: "Πηγαίνετε όπου, ο 
Θεός θα σας ανακαλύψει." Σε αυτό το αφήγημα, ο Δανός, που 
θυμήθηκε πάντα την προειδοποίησή της, αφορούσε τους πειρασμούς 
αντιμετώπισε κατά τη διάρκεια της ζωής του -- για να κλέψει, για 
να αποδεχθεί τις προόδους των γυναικών, για να αποφύγουν την 
εκκλησία -- και των τιμών που διαπραγματεύτηκε με έναν 
όλος-βλέποντας Θεό. (Η ορθογραφία αυτής της επιλογής
έχει συστηματοποιηθεί για να το καταστήσει ευκολότερο να 
διαβάσει.)</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El danés de Juan, personalización, nació en 
Berkhampstead, Inglaterra, alrededor 1612. En el último 1630s, 
que él recuerda aquí como período "de gran venir a Nueva 
Inglaterra," él y su familia emigraron a Ipswich, 
Massachusetts. Él murió en Ipswich en 1684. Los padres 
del danés, como muchos padres puritan, criaron a sus niños para 
llevar lo que llama el historiador Philip Greven un "disciplinarian 
interno" dentro de sus propias conciencias siempre. La madre del
danés lo recordó: "va a adonde usted , el dios le 
descubrirá." En esta narrativa, el danés, que recordó siempre
su alerta, relacionó las tentaciones que él hizo frente sobre el 
curso de su vida -- robar, validar los avances de mujeres, para evitar
la iglesia -- y de los precios él negoció con un dios todo-que 
vei'a. (el deletreo de esta selección se ha regularizado para 
hacerla más fácil leer.)</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087293</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107474</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-devil-to-tempt-and-a-corrupt-heart-to-deceive-john-dane-battles-lifes-temptations-ca-1670s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
