<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108663</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108663</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206510</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Omaha Indian Arts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Omaha Inder-Künste</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts d'Indien d'Omaha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes Do Indian De Omaha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti Dell'Indiano De Omaha</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ινδικές τέχνες της Ομάχα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes Del Indio De Omaha</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers a sampling of traditional Omaha Indian music. The sound recordings include wax cylinder recordings made in the 1890s, as well as songs and spoken-word segments from the 1983 Omaha harvest celebration pow-wow, segments from an interview with an Omaha elder in 1983, songs and speeches from a performance by members of the Hethu'shka Society in 1985, and portions of an interview with an Omaha musician in 1999. Photos, fieldnotes, and more from the 1983 pow-wow are included.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">bietet ein Musterstück der traditionellen Omaha 
Indermusik an. Die Tonaufnahmen schließen die 
Wachszylinderaufnahmen ein, die im 1890s, sowie Liede und Sprechenwort
Segmente vom Omaha Ernte-Feier Kriegsgefangen-Wimmern 1983, Segmente 
von einem Interview mit einem Omaha Ältesten 1983, Liede und Reden 
von einer Leistung mit Bauteilen der Hethu'shka Gesellschaft 1985 und 
Teile eines Interviews mit einem Omaha Musiker 1999 gebildet werden. 
Fotos, fieldnotes und mehr vom Kriegsgefangen-Wimmern 1983 sind 
enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">offre un prélèvement de la musique 
traditionnelle d'Indien d'Omaha. Les enregistrements sonores 
incluent des enregistrements de cylindre de cire faits dans le 1890s, 
comme des chansons et des segments de parler-mot à partir du 
prisonnier de guerre-défaut de la reproduction sonore 1983 de 
célébration de moisson d'Omaha, des segments à partir d'une 
entrevue avec un aîné d'Omaha en 1983, des chansons et des discours 
à partir d'une exécution par des membres de la société de 
Hethu'shka en 1985, et des parties d'une entrevue avec un musicien 
d'Omaha en 1999. Les photos, les fieldnotes, et plus du 
prisonnier de guerre-défaut de la reproduction sonore 1983 sont 
inclus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oferece uma amostragem da música tradicional do 
indian de Omaha. As gravações sadias incluem as gravações do
cilindro da cera feitas no 1890s, assim como canções e segmentos da 
fal-palavra do prisioneiro de guerra-pow-wow 1983 do celebration da 
colheita de Omaha, segmentos de uma entrevista com uma pessoa idosa de
Omaha em 1983, canções e discursos de um desempenho por membros da 
sociedade de Hethu'shka em 1985, e parcelas de uma entrevista com um 
músico de Omaha em 1999. As fotos, os fieldnotes, e mais do 
prisioneiro de guerra-pow-wow 1983 são incluídos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">offre un campione della musica tradizionale 
dell'indiano de Omaha. Le registrazioni del suono includono le 
registrazioni del cilindro della cera fatte nel 1890s, come pure le 
canzoni e segmenti di parl-parola dalla prigioniero di 
guerra-distorsione di velocità 1983 di celebrazione della raccolta de
Omaha, segmenti da un'intervista con un elder de Omaha in 1983, 
canzoni e discorsi dalle prestazioni dai membri della società di 
Hethu'shka in 1985 e parti di un'intervista con un musicista de 
Omaha in 1999. Le foto, i fieldnotes e più dalla prigioniero di
guerra-distorsione di velocità 1983 sono inclusi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσφέρει μια δειγματοληψία της παραδοσιακής ινδικής 
μουσικής της Ομάχα. Οι υγιείς καταγραφές περιλαμβάνουν τις 
καταγραφές κυλίνδρων κεριών που γίνονται στο 1890s, καθώς 
επίσης και τα τραγούδια και τα τμήματα μνήμης μιλώ-λέξης από 
την ποω-καταπληκτική επιτυχία εορτασμού συγκομιδών της Ομάχα του 
1983, τα τμήματα μνήμης από μια συνέντευξη με μια Ομάχα 
παλαιότερη το 1983, τα τραγούδια και τις ομιλίες από μια 
απόδοση από τα μέλη της κοινωνίας του Hethu το 1985, και τις
μερίδες μιας συνέντευξης με έναν μουσικό της Ομάχα σε 1999, 
φωτογραφίες, fieldnotes, και περισσότεροι από την 
ποω-καταπληκτική επιτυχία του 1983 συμπεριλαμβάνονται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece un muestreo de la música tradicional del 
indio de Omaha. Las grabaciones de sonidos incluyen las 
grabaciones del cilindro de la cera hechas en el 1890s, tan bien como 
canciones y los segmentos de la hablar-palabra de la prisionero de 
guerra-ululacio'n 1983 de la celebración de la cosecha de Omaha, los 
segmentos de una entrevista con una anciano de Omaha en 1983, las 
canciones y los discursos de un funcionamiento de los miembros de la 
sociedad de Hethu'shka en 1985, y las porciones de una entrevista con 
un músico de Omaha en 1999. Las fotos, los fieldnotes, y más 
de la prisionero de guerra-ululacio'n 1983 son incluidos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206510</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108663</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/omaha-indian-arts</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
