<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108427</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108427</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206222</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">NRCS Soils</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">NRCS Boden</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sols de NRCS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Solos de NRCS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Terreni di NRCS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χώματα NRCS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Suelos de NRCS</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">includes soil surveys for each state, a manual for surveying soil, an urban soil primer for homeowners and local planning boards, and tools for educators -- lessons and information on soil taxonomy (the 12 orders of soil), fundamental concepts about soil, soil biology, and soil risks and hazards.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">schließt Bodenübersichten für jeden Zustand, 
ein Handbuch für überblickenboden, eine städtische Bodenzündkapsel
für Eigenheimbesitzer und lokale Planungsstellen und Hilfsmittel für
Erzieher -- Lektionen und Informationen über Bodentaxonomie (die 12 
Ordnungen des Bodens), grundlegende Konzepte über Boden, 
Bodenbiologie und Bodengefahren und -gefahren ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">inclut des enquêtes de sol pour chaque état, un 
manuel pour le sol examinant, une amorce urbaine de sol pour des 
propriétaires d'une maison et des panneaux de planification locaux, 
et des outils pour des éducateurs -- des leçons et l'information sur
la taxonomie de sol (les 12 commandes du sol), des concepts 
fondamentaux au sujet de sol, biologie de sol, et risques et risques 
de sol.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">inclui exames do solo para cada estado, um manual 
para o solo examinando, um primer urbano do solo para homeowners e 
placas de planeamento locais, e ferramentas para educadores -- 
lições e informação no taxonomy do solo (as 12 ordens do solo), 
conceitos fundamentais sobre o solo, a biologia do solo, e os riscos e
os perigos do solo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">include le indagini del terreno per ciascuno 
dichiarano, un manuale per terreno d'esame, un iniettore urbano 
del terreno per i proprietari di abitazione e bordi locali di 
progettazione e strumenti per gli educatori -- lezioni e le 
informazioni su tassonomia del terreno (i 12 ordini di terreno), 
concetti fondamentali circa terreno, biologia del terreno e rischi e 
rischi del terreno.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιλαμβάνει τις χαρτογραφήσεις εδάφους για κάθε 
κράτος, ένα εγχειρίδιο για την έρευνα του χώματος, έναν αστικό 
εδαφολογικό εγχυτήρα για τους ιδιοκτήτες σπιτιού και τους 
τοπικούς προγραμματίζοντας πίνακες, και τα εργαλεία για τους 
εκπαιδευτικούς -- μαθήματα και πληροφορίες για την εδαφολογική 
ταξονομία (οι 12 κατατάξεις του χώματος), θεμελιώδεις έννοιες 
για το χώμα, την εδαφολογική βιολογία, και τους εδαφολογικούς 
κινδύνους και τους κινδύνους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">incluye las encuestas sobre el suelo para cada 
estado, un manual para el suelo que examina, una cartilla urbana del 
suelo para los dueños de una casa y las tarjetas de hojas de 
operación (planning) locales, y las herramientas para los educadores 
-- las lecciones e información sobre la taxonomía del suelo (las 12 
pedidos del suelo), los conceptos fundamentales sobre suelo, biología
del suelo, y los riesgos y los peligros del suelo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206222</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108427</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nrcs-soils</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
