<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108702</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108702</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086494</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Music and milking time.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Musik und melkenzeit.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Musique et temps de traire.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Música e tempo ordenhar.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Musica e tempo di mungitura.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χρόνος μουσικής και αρμέγματος.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Música y tiempo del ordeño.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Radio and other popular entertainments, like movies, created a truly national popular culture during the 1920s. Pausing to tune in to his favorite program, this farmer represents an extreme example of radio's broad popularity during the 1920s. For rural Americans, radios not only delivered music and sports but also vital information on commodity prices and weather reports. While they linked rural residents to the rest of the country, radio broadcasts and movie theaters also provided a vehicle for advertising and a spur for consumer culture.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Radio und andere populäre Unterhaltungen, wie Filme, 
erstellten eine wirklich nationale populäre Kultur während der 
zwanziger Jahre, die pausieren, um zu seinem Lieblingsprogramm innen 
zu justieren, dieser Landwirt, darstellt ein extremes Beispiel der 
ausgedehnten Popularität des Radios während der zwanziger Jahre. 
Zu landwirtschaftlichen Amerikanern, gelieferter Musik der 
Radios nicht nur und Sport aber auch lebenswichtiger Information über
Rohstoffpreise und Wetterreports. Während sie 
landwirtschaftliche Bewohner mit dem Rest des Landes banden, stellten 
Radiosendungen und Filmtheater auch einen Träger für das 
Bekanntmachen und einen Sporn für Verbraucherkultur zur Verfügung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La radio et d'autres divertissements populaires, comme des
films, ont créé une culture populaire véritablement nationale 
pendant les années 20 faisant une pause pour accorder dedans à son 
programme préféré, ce fermier représente un exemple extrême de la
large popularité de la radio pendant les années 20. Pour les 
Américains ruraux, la musique de radios non seulement et les sports 
fournis mais également l'information essentielle sur des cours de 
matières premières et survivent à à des états. Tandis 
qu'ils joignaient les résidants ruraux au reste du pays, les 
émissions de radio et les théâtres de film ont également fourni un
véhicule pour annoncer et une dent pour la culture du consommateur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O rádio e outros entertainments populares, como filmes, 
criaram uma cultura popular verdadeiramente nacional durante os 1920s.
que pausam para ajustar dentro a seu programa favorito, este 
fazendeiro representam um exemplo extremo da popularidade larga do 
rádio durante os 1920s. Para americanos rurais, a música dos 
rádios não somente e esportes entregados mas também a informação 
vital em preços de producto e em relatórios do tempo. Quando 
ligaram residentes rurais ao descanso do país, as transmissões do 
rádio e os teatros do filme forneceram também um veículo anunciando
e um dente reto para a cultura do consumidor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La radio ed altri intrattenimenti popolari, come i 
film, hanno creato una coltura popolare vero nazionale durante 
gli anni 20 che fanno una pausa per sintonizzare dentro al suo 
programma favorito, questo coltivatore rappresenta un esempio estremo 
di vasta popolarità della radio durante gli anni 20. Per gli 
Americani rurali, la musica delle radio non soltanto e gli sport 
trasportati ma anche le informazioni vitali sui prezzi dei prodotti e 
sui rapporti del tempo. Mentre hanno collegato i residenti 
rurali al resto del paese, le radiodiffusioni della radio ed i teatri 
di film egualmente hanno fornito un veicolo per la pubblicità 
e un dente cilindrico per la coltura del consumatore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ραδιόφωνο και άλλες δημοφιλείς ψυχαγωγίες, όπως 
τους κινηματογράφους, δημιούργησαν έναν αληθινά εθνικό δημοφιλή 
πολιτισμό κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '20 που σταματά για 
να συντονίζουν μέσα στο αγαπημένο πρόγραμμά του, αυτός ο 
αγρότης αντιπροσωπεύει ένα ακραίο παράδειγμα της ευρείας 
δημοτικότητας του ραδιοφώνου κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του 
'20. Για αγροτικούς Αμερικανούς, την παραδοθείσα μουσική 
ραδιοφώνων όχι μόνο και τον αθλητισμό αλλά και τις ζωτικής 
σημασίας πληροφορίες για τις τιμές προϊόντων και τις καιρικές 
εκθέσεις. Ενώ σύνδεσαν τους αγροτικούς κατοίκους με το 
υπόλοιπο της χώρας, οι ραδιο ραδιοφωνικές μεταδόσεις και οι 
κινηματογράφοι παρείχαν επίσης ένα όχημα για τη διαφήμιση και 
ένα κέντρισμα για τον καταναλωτικό πολιτισμό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La radio y otras hospitalidades populares, como 
películas, crearon una cultura popular verdaderamente nacional 
durante los años 20 que se detenían brevemente para templar adentro 
a su programa preferido, este granjero representa un ejemplo extremo 
del amplio renombre de la radio durante los años 20. Para los 
americanos rurales, la música de las radios no solamente y los 
deportes entregados pero también la información vital sobre precios 
de materia e informes del tiempo. Mientras que conectaron a 
residentes rurales al resto del país, las difusiones de la radio y 
los teatros de la película también proporcionaron a un vehículo 
para anunciar y a un estímulo para la cultura del consumidor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086494</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108702</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/music-and-milking-time</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
