<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103404</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103404</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206939</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Lunar Plant Growth Chamber</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mondbetriebswachstum-Raum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chambre Lunaire de Croissance de Plantes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Câmara Lunar Do Crescimento De Planta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alloggiamento Lunare Di Sviluppo Di Pianta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σεληνιακή αίθουσα αύξησης εγκαταστάσεων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Compartimiento Lunar Del Crecimiento vegetal</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">invites students to design chambers for growing plants on the moon. (Plants may be used to supplement meals of astronauts during space exploration.) Teacher guides include lessons on providing light and water for the plants, choosing plant species, exploring the moon, and designing, building, and evaluating plant growth chambers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">lädt Kursteilnehmer ein, Räume für wachsende 
Betriebe auf dem Mond zu konzipieren. (Betriebe können benutzt 
werden, um Mahlzeiten der Astronauten während der Platzerforschung zu
ergänzen.) Lehreranleitungen schließen Lektionen auf dem Zur 
Verfügung stellen des Lichtes und des Wassers für die Betriebe, 
wählende Betriebssorte ein und erforschen den Mond und das 
Konzipieren, das Aufbauen und die auswertenden Betriebswachstumräume.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">invite des étudiants à concevoir des chambres 
pour les usines croissantes sur la lune. (des usines peuvent 
être employées pour compléter des repas des astronautes pendant 
l'exploration de l'espace.) Les guides de professeur incluent 
des leçons sur fournir la lumière et l'eau pour les usines, 
espèces de choix d'usine, explorant la lune, et concevoir, 
construire, et les chambres d'évaluation de croissance de plantes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">convida estudantes projetar câmaras para plantas 
crescentes na lua. (as plantas podem ser usadas suplementar 
refeições dos astronautas durante a exploração do espaço.) 
As guias do professor incluem lições em fornecer a luz e a 
água para as plantas, espécie escolhendo da planta, explorando a 
lua, e o projeto, construir, e câmaras de avaliação do crescimento 
de planta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">invita gli allievi a progettare gli alloggiamenti 
per le piante crescenti sulla luna. (piante possono essere usate
per completare i pasti degli atronauti durante l'esplorazione dello 
spazio.) Le guide dell'insegnante includono le lezioni sul 
fornire la luce e l'acqua per le piante, specie di scelta della 
pianta, esplorando la luna e la progettazione, la costruzione e gli 
alloggiamenti di valutazione di sviluppo di pianta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προσκαλεί τους σπουδαστές για να σχεδιάσει τις 
αίθουσες για την ανάπτυξη των εγκαταστάσεων στο φεγγάρι. (Οι
εγκαταστάσεις μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν για να συμπληρώσουν τα 
γεύματα των αστροναυτών κατά τη διάρκεια της διαστημικής 
εξερεύνησης.) Οι οδηγοί δασκάλων περιλαμβάνουν τα μαθήματα 
στην παροχή του φωτός και του ύδατος για τις εγκαταστάσεις, την 
επιλογή των ειδών εγκαταστάσεων, την εξερεύνηση του φεγγαριού, 
και το σχεδιασμό, την οικοδόμηση, και την αξιολόγηση των αιθουσών 
αύξησης εγκαταστάσεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">invita a estudiantes que diseñen los 
compartimientos para las plantas crecientes en la luna. (las 
plantas se pueden utilizar para suplir comidas de astronautas durante 
la exploración del espacio.) Las guías del profesor incluyen 
lecciones en proporcionar a la luz y al agua para las plantas, especie
de la planta que elige, explorando la luna, y diseñar, la 
construcción, y compartimientos de evaluación del crecimiento 
vegetal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206939</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103404</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/lunar-plant-growth-chamber</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
