<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103846</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103846</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086275</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Cannot and Will Not Cut My Conscience to Fit This Year's Fashions": Lillian Hellman Refuses to Name Names</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ich kann nicht und werde nicht meine 
Gewissenhaftigkeit schneiden, um diesjährige Art und Weise zu 
passen": Lillian Hellman lehnt ab, Namen zu benennen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"je ne peux pas et ne couperai pas ma conscience 
pour adapter des modes de cette année" : Lillian Hellman refuse
de nommer des noms</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"eu não posso e não corto meu conscience para 
caber formas deste ano": Lillian Hellman recusa nomear nomes</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"non posso e non taglierò la mia coscienza per 
misura le mode relative a quest'anno": Lillian Hellman rifiuta 
di chiamare i nomi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"δεν μπορώ και δεν θα κόψω τη συνείδησή μου για να 
εγκαταστήσω τις φετινές μόδεσ": Το Lillian Hellman 
αρνείται να ονομάσει τα ονόματα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no puedo y no cortaré mi conciencia para caber 
maneras relativas a este año": Lillian Hellman rechaza nombrar 
nombres</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC) held hearings in 1947 on Communist activity in Hollywood. Ten writers and directors were held in contempt when they refused to answer questions regarding their political affiliations or beliefs. They later served prison terms after the Supreme Court in April 1950 turned down their appeal that such questioning violated their First Amendment rights. Hearings began again in March 1951, While almost half of those testifying from the entertainment industry informed on their colleagues, others like playwright and screenwriter Lillian Hellman invoked the Fifth Amendment protection against self-incrimination. This route insured that they would not be hired for future work in the industry. In the following letter to HUAC's chairman, Hellman offered to testify as to her own activities if she would not be forced to inform on others. When the Committee refused her request, she took the Fifth and was blacklisted.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Haus-Ausschuß für Un-Amerikanische 
Aktivitäten (HUAC) hielt Hörfähigkeiten 1947 auf kommunistischer 
Aktivität in Hollywood an. 10 Verfasser und Direktoren wurden 
in der Verachtung angehalten, als sie ablehnten, die Fragen betreffend
sind ihre politischen Verbindungen oder Glauben zu beantworten. 
Sie dienten später Gefängnisbezeichnungen, nachdem das 
Höchste Gericht im April 1950 unten ihren Anklang drehte, daß 
solches Ausfragen ihre erste Änderung Rechte verletzte. 
Hörfähigkeiten fingen wieder im März 1951, während sich fast
Hälfte von denen, die von der Unterhaltung Industrie bezeugen, auf 
ihren Kollegen informierte, andere wie Stückeschreiber an und 
Drehbuchautor Lillian Hellman rief den fünfte Änderung Schutz gegen
Selbst-incrimination hervor. Dieser Weg versicherte, daß sie 
nicht für zukünftige Arbeit in der Industrie angestellt würden. 
Im folgenden Zeichen zum Vorsitzenden HUACs, bot Hellman an, 
hinsichtlich ihrer eigenen Aktivitäten zu bezeugen, wenn sie nicht 
erzwungen würde, sich auf anderen zu informieren. Als der 
Ausschuß ihren Antrag ablehnte, nahm sie das Fünftel und wurde auf 
die schwarze Liste gesetzt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le comité de Chambre des activités 
Un-Américaines (HUAC) a tenu des auditions en 1947 sur l'activité 
communiste dans Hollywood. Dix auteurs et directeurs ont été 
tenus au mépris quand ils ont refusé de répondre à des questions 
concernant leurs affiliations ou croyance politiques. Ils plus 
tard ont servi des limites de prison après que la cour suprême en 
avril 1950 ait tourné vers le bas leur appel qu'une telle 
interrogation a violé leurs droites de premier amendement. Les 
auditions ont commencé encore en mars 1951, alors que presque la 
moitié de ceux témoignant de l'industrie de divertissement informait
sur leurs collègues, d'autres comme le dramaturge et le scénariste 
Lillian Hellman a appelé la protection du cinquième amendement 
contre l'auto-incrimination. Cet itinéraire a assuré qu'ils ne 
seraient pas loués pour les travaux futurs dans l'industrie. 
Dans la lettre suivante au Président de HUAC, Hellman a offert 
de témoigner quant à ses propres activités si elle ne serait pas 
forcée d'informer sur d'autres. Quand le Comité a refusé sa 
demande, elle a pris le cinquième et a été mise sur la liste noire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O comitê da casa nas atividades Un-Americanas 
(HUAC) prendeu hearings em 1947 na atividade comunista em Hollywood. 
Dez escritores e diretores foram prendidos no contempt quando 
recusaram responder às perguntas a respeito de sua afiliações ou 
opinião política. Serviram mais tarde a termos da prisão 
depois que a corte suprema em abril 1950 girou para baixo sua 
apelação que tal questionar violated suas direitas da primeira 
emenda. Os hearings começaram outra vez em março 1951, quando 
quase a metade daquelas que testifying da indústria de entertainment 
informou em seus colegas, outros como o playwright e o screenwriter 
Lillian Hellman invocou a proteção da quinta emenda de encontro ao 
self-incrimination-incrimination. Esta rota segurou que não 
estariam empregados para o trabalho futuro na indústria. Na 
seguinte letra ao presidente de HUAC, Hellman ofereceu testify a 
respeito de suas próprias atividades se não fosse forçada a 
informar em outra. Quando o comitê recusou seu pedido, fêz 
exame do fifth e foi posta.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il comitato della Camera delle attività 
ONU-Americane (HUAC) ha tenuto le udienze in 1947 su attività 
comunista in Hollywood. Dieci produttori e direttori sono stati 
tenuti nel contempt quando hanno rifiutato di rispondere alle domande 
per quanto riguarda le loro affiliazioni o credenza politiche. 
Più successivamente hanno servito i termini della prigione dopo
che la Corte suprema in aprile 1950 girasse giù il loro appello che 
tale interrogazione ha violato i loro diritti di prima correzione. 
Le udienze hanno cominciato ancora nel mese di marzo del 1951, 
mentre quasi la metà di quelle che testimoniano dall'industria di 
intrattenimento ha informato sui loro colleghe, altri come il 
playwright e lo screenwriter Lillian Hellman ha invocato la protezione
di quinta correzione contro l'auto-incrimination. Questo 
itinerario ha assicurato che non sarebbero assunti per lavori futuri 
nell'industria. Nella seguente lettera al presidente del HUAC, 
Hellman ha offerto di testimoniare quanto alle sue proprie attività 
se non fosse costretta ad informare su altre. Quando il comitato
ha rifiutato la sua richiesta, ha preso il fifth ed è stata messa in.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Επιτροπή Βουλών των αντιαμερικανικών δραστηριοτήτων 
(HUAC) πραγματοποίησε τις ακροάσεις το 1947 για την 
κομμουνιστική δραστηριότητα σε Hollywood. Δέκα συγγραφείς
και σκηνοθέτες κρατήθηκαν στην περιφρόνηση όταν αρνήθηκαν να 
απαντήσουν στις ερωτήσεις σχετικά με τους πολιτικές 
συνεταιρισμούς ή τις πεποιθήσεις τους. Εξυπηρέτησαν 
αργότερα τις θητείες φυλακών αφότου γύρισε κάτω το ανώτατο 
δικαστήριο τον Απρίλιο του 1950 την έκκλησή τους ότι τέτοια 
επερώτηση παραβίασε τα πρώτα δικαιώματα τροποποιήσεών τους. 
Οι ακροάσεις άρχισαν πάλι τον Μάρτιο του 1951, ενώ 
σχεδόν των μισοί από εκείνους που πιστοποιούν από τη βιομηχανία
ψυχαγωγίας που ενημερώθηκε για τους συναδέλφους τους, άλλοι όπως 
το θεατρικό συγγραφέα και screenwriter Lillian Hellman 
κάλεσαν την πέμπτη προστασία τροποποιήσεων ενάντια στην 
μόνος-ενοχοποίηση. Αυτή η διαδρομή ασφάλισε ότι δεν θα 
μισθώνονταν για τη μελλοντική εργασία στη βιομηχανία. Στην 
ακόλουθη επιστολή στον πρόεδρο HUAC, Hellman πρόσφερε να 
πιστοποιήσει ως προς τις δραστηριότητές της εάν δεν θα 
αναγκαζόταν να ενημερώσει για άλλες. Όταν η Επιτροπή 
αρνήθηκε το αίτημά της, πήρε το πέμπτο και βάλθηκε στη μαύρη 
λίστα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El comité de la casa sobre las actividades 
Un-Americanas (HUAC) llevó a cabo audiencias en 1947 en actividad 
comunista en Hollywood. Sostuvieron a diez programas de 
escritura y directores en desprecio cuando rechazaron contestar a 
preguntas con respecto sus afiliaciones o creencia políticas. 
Sirvieron más adelante términos de la prisión después de que
el Tribunal Supremo en abril 1950 diera vuelta abajo a su súplica que
el tal preguntar violó las sus derechas de primera enmienda. 
Las audiencias comenzaron otra vez en marcha de 1951, mientras 
que casi la mitad de ésas que atestiguaban de la industria de 
hospitalidad informó en sus colegas, otros como dramaturgo y el 
guionista Lillian Hellman invocó la protección de la quinto enmienda
contra el uno mismo-incrimination. Esta ruta aseguró que los no
emplearían para el trabajo futuro en la industria. En la carta 
siguiente al presidente de HUAC, Hellman ofreció atestiguar en cuanto
a sus propias actividades si la no forzarían informar en otras. 
Cuando el comité rechazó su petición, ella tomó el fifth y 
fue puesta.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086275</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103846</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-cannot-and-will-not-cut-my-conscience-to-fit-this-years-fashions-lillian-hellman-refuses-to-name-names</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
