<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105315</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105315</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087282</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Clear Signal to Officials of the White South: 'Go Back to Your Old Ways'": Vernon Jordan Argues Against the Nixon Administration's Voting Rights Proposal</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein freies Signal zu den Beamten des weißen 
Südens: ' gehen Sie zurück zu Ihren alten Methoden ": 
Vernon Jordanien argumentiert gegen den der Nixon wählende 
Recht-Antrag Leitung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un signal clair aux fonctionnaires des 
Sud blancs : 'allez de nouveau à vos vieilles voies ":
Vernon Jordanie discute contre la proposition du droit de vote 
de la gestion de Nixon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um sinal desobstruído aos oficiais do sul 
branco: ' vá para trás a suas maneiras velhas ": Vernon 
Jordão discute de encontro à proposta das direitas votando da 
administração de Nixon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un segnale libero ai funzionari del sud bianco: 
'vada di nuovo ai vostri vecchi modi ": Vernon Giordano 
parla contro la proposta di diritti di voto della gestione di Nixon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένα σαφές σήμα στους ανώτερους υπαλλήλους του 
άσπρου νότου: "Επιστρέψτε στους παλαιούς τρόπους σασ" ": 
Βερνόν Ιορδανία μιλά ενάντια στην πρόταση δικαιωμάτων 
ψήφου της κυβέρνησης Nixon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"una señal clara a los funcionarios del sur 
blanco: ' vaya de nuevo a sus viejas maneras ": Vernon 
Jordania discute contra la oferta de los derechos al voto de la 
administración de Nixon</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Voting Rights Act of 1965--called "the most successful civil rights law in the nation's history" by Rev. Theodore M. Hesburgh, chairman of the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights--was enacted in order to force Southern states and localities to allow all citizens of voting age to vote in public elections. Although the 15th Amendment, ratified in 1870, guaranteed citizens the right to vote regardless of race, discriminatory requirements, such as literacy tests, disenfranchised many African Americans in the South. In 1965, following the murder of a voting rights activist by an Alabama sheriff's deputy and the subsequent attack by state troopers on a massive protest march in Selma, President Lyndon B. Johnson pressed Congress to pass a voting rights bill with "teeth". The Act, signed into law on August 6, applied to states or counties where fewer than half of the citizens of voting age were registered in 1964--Alabama, Georgia, Louisiana, Mississippi, South Carolina, Virginia, and numerous counties in North Carolina. For these areas, the law banned literacy tests, appointed Federal examiners to oversee election procedures, and, according to the Act's controversial Section 5, required approval by the U.S. Attorney General of future changes to election laws. In 1969, a Senate subcommittee held hearings to discuss extending the Act. In the following statement, Vernon E. Jordan strongly argued against a House bill, advocated by the Nixon Administration, that proposed to extend coverage to the entire country and replace Section 5 with an oversight mechanism more amenable to the white South. Ultimately, on June 22, 1970, President Richard M. Nixon signed into law a bill that extended the Act's provisions, including Section 5, for five additional years, and in addition, lowered the voting age throughout the country to 18.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die wählende Recht-Tat von 1965 -- benannt "das 
erfolgreichste Zivilrecht-Gesetz in der Geschichte der Nation" durch 
Rev. Theodore M. Hesburgh, Vorsitzender der VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Kommission auf Zivilrechten -- wurde verordnet, um südliche Zustände
und Stellen zu erzwingen, um allen Bürgern des wählenden Alters zu 
erlauben, in den allgemeinen Wahlen zu wählen. Obgleich die 15.
Änderung, bestätigt 1870, Bürgern das Recht, unabhängig davon 
Rennen zu wählen garantierte, entrechteten diskriminierende 
Anforderungen, wie Bildungsgradtests, viele afrikanische Amerikaner im
Süden. 1965 dem Mord an einem Aktivisten der wählenden Rechte 
vom Abgeordneten eines Alabama Polizeichefs und am folgenden Angriff 
von den Zustand troopers folgend auf einem massiven Protestmärz in 
Selma, betätigte Präsident Lyndon B. Johnson Kongreß, einen Gesetz 
der wählenden Rechte mit "den Zähnen" zu verabschieden. Die 
Tat, unterzeichnet in Gesetz an August 6, traf auf Zustände oder 
Grafschaften, in denen weniger als Hälfte der Bürger des wählenden 
Alters 1964 registriert wurden -- Alabama, Georgia, Louisiana, 
Mississippi, Südcarolina, Virginia und zahlreiche Grafschaften in 
Nord-Carolina zu. Für diese Bereiche verbot das Gesetz die 
Bildungsgradtests, ernannt Bundesprüfer, um Wahlprozeduren zu 
beaufsichtigen, und, entsprechend dem umstrittenen Kapitel 5 der Tat, 
ändert benötigte Zustimmung durch den VEREINIGTE STAATEN 
Generalstaatsanwalt von Zukunft zu den Wahlgesetzen. 1969 hielt 
eine Senatunterausschuß Hörfähigkeiten an, um das Ausdehnen der Tat
zu behandeln. In der folgenden Anweisung argumentierte Vernon E.
Jordanien stark gegen eine Hausrechnung, befürwortet durch die Nixon 
Leitung, die vorschlug, Dichte auf das gesamte Land auszudehnen und 
Kapitel 5 mit einer Aufsichteinheit zu ersetzen, die dem weißen 
Süden zugänglicher ist. Schließlich an Juni 22, 1970, 
Präsident Richard M. Nixon unterzeichnete in Gesetz, das, eine 
Rechnung, die die Bestimmungen der Tat, einschließlich Kapitel 5, 
für fünf zusätzliche Jahre und zusätzlich ausdehnte, das wählende
Alter in dem Land bis 18 senkte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Loi de droit de vote de 1965 -- appelé "la 
plus réussie loi de droits civiques dans l'histoire de la nation" par
M. Hesburgh, Président d'Rev. Theodore de la Commission des 
ETATS-UNIS sur des droits civiques -- a été décrétée afin de 
forcer les états et les localités méridionaux pour permettre à 
tous les citoyens d'âge de vote de voter dans des élections 
publiques. Bien que le 15ème amendement, ratifié en 1870, ait 
garanti des citoyens la droite de voter indépendamment de la course, 
les conditions discriminatoires, telles que des essais d'instruction, 
ont privé des droits civiques beaucoup d'Américains africains dans 
les Sud. En 1965, suivant le meurtre d'un activiste de 
droit de vote du député d'un shérif de l'Alabama et de l'attaque 
ultérieure des soldats de la cavalerie d'état sur une march de protestation 
massive dans Selma, le Président Lyndon B. Johnson a appuyé le 
congrès passer une facture de droit de vote avec des "dents". 
La Loi, signée dans la loi août 6, s'est appliquée aux états
ou aux comtés où moins que la moitié des citoyens de l'âge de vote
ont été enregistrés en 1964 -- l'Alabama, la Géorgie, la 
Louisiane, le Mississippi, la Caroline du sud, la Virginie, et 
de nombreux comtés en Caroline du nord. Pour ces zones, la
loi a interdit des essais d'instruction, désignés les examinateurs 
fédéraux pour surveiller des procédures d'élection, et, selon la 
section controversée 5 de l'acte, l'approbation exigée par le 
général de mandataire des ETATS-UNIS du futur change en des lois 
d'élection. En 1969, un sous-comité de sénat a tenu des 
auditions pour discuter étendre l'acte. Dans le rapport 
suivant, E. Jordanie de Vernon a fortement discuté contre une facture
de Chambre, préconisé par la gestion de Nixon, qui a proposé 
d'étendre à l'assurance le pays entier et de substituer la section 5
avec un mécanisme d'inadvertance plus favorable aux Sud 
blancs. Finalement, 22 juin 1970, le Président Richard M. 
Nixon a signé dans la loi que une facture qui a étendu les 
dispositions de l'acte, y compris la section 5, pendant cinq années 
supplémentaires, et en outre, a abaissé l'âge de vote dans tout le 
pays à 18.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O ato das direitas votando de 1965 -- chamado "a 
lei a mais bem sucedida das direitas civis no history da nação" por 
M. Hesburgh de Rev. Theodore, presidente do commission de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS em direitas civis -- foi decretado a fim forçar estados e 
localities do sul para permitir que todos os cidadãos da idade 
votando votem em eleições públicas. Embora a 1ä emenda, 
ratificada em 1870, garantisse cidadãos a direita votar não obstante
a raça, as exigências discriminatory, tais como testes do literacy, 
disenfranchised muitos americanos africanos no sul. Em 1965, 
seguindo o assassinato de uma activista das direitas votando pelo 
deputado de um sheriff de Alabama e do ataque subseqüente por 
troopers do estado em um março de protesto maciço em Selma, o 
presidente Lyndon B. Johnson pressionou o congress passar uma conta 
das direitas votando com os "dentes". O ato, assinado na lei 
agosto em 6, aplicou-se aos estados ou aos condados onde menos do que 
a metade dos cidadãos da idade votando foram registadas em 1964 -- 
Alabama, Geórgia, Louisiana, Mississippi, carolina sul, Virgínia, e 
condados numerosos em North.carolina. Para estas áreas, a lei 
proibiu os testes do literacy, apontados examinadores federais para 
oversee procedimentos da eleição, e, de acordo com a seção 
controversa 5 do ato, a aprovaçã0 requerida pelo general de advogado
de ESTADOS UNIDOS do futuro muda às leis da eleição. Em 1969,
uma subcomissão do senate prendeu hearings para discutir estender o 
ato. Na seguinte indicação, o E. Jordão de Vernon discutiu 
fortemente de encontro a uma conta da casa, advogada pela 
administração de Nixon, que propôs estender a cobertura ao país 
inteiro e substituir a seção 5 com um mecanismo do oversight mais 
amenable ao sul branco. Finalmente, junho em 22, 1970, 
presidente Richard M. Nixon assinou na lei que uma conta que 
estendesse as provisões do ato, including a seção 5, por cinco anos
adicionais, e além, abaixou a idade votando durante todo o país a 
18.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I diritti di voto una Legge di 1965 -- chiamato 
"la legge più riuscita di diritti civili nella storia della nazione" 
dal M. Hesburgh, presidente dell'Rev. Theodore della Commissione degli
STATI UNITI sui diritti civili -- è stata promulgata per forzare del 
sud dichiara e località per permettere che tutti i cittadini 
dell'età di voto votino nelle elezioni pubbliche. Anche se la 
quindicesima che correzione, ratificata in 1870, ha garantito i 
cittadini la destra votare senza riguardo alla corsa, i requisiti 
discriminatori, quali le prove di literacy, disenfranchised molti 
Americani africani nel sud. In 1965, seguendo l'omicidio di un 
attivista di diritti di voto dal delegato e dall'attacco successivo
dello sheriff dell'Alabama vicino dichiari i troopers su un 
procedere di protesta voluminoso in Selma, congresso premuto Johnson 
del presidente Lyndon B. per passare una fattura di diritti di voto 
con "i denti". La Legge, firmata in legge il 6 agosto, si è 
applicata a dichiara o contee in cui meno della metà dei 
cittadini dell'età di voto sono stati registrati in 1964 -- 
l'Alabama, la Georgia, la Luisiana, il Mississippi, Carolina del Sud, 
la Virginia e contee numerose in North.carolina. Per queste 
zone, la legge ha vietato le prove di literacy, nominate ispettori 
federali per sorvegliare le procedure di elezione e, secondo la parte 
discutibile 5 della Legge, l'approvazione richiesta da parte del 
General di avvocato degli STATI UNITI di futuro cambia alle leggi di 
elezione. In 1969, un sottocomitato del senato ha tenuto le 
udienze per discutere l'estensione della Legge. Nella seguente 
istruzione, il E. Giordano di Vernon ha parlato fortemente contro una 
fattura della Camera, sostenuta tramite la gestione di Nixon, che ha 
proposto di ampliare il riempimento fino l'intero paese e di 
sostituire la parte 5 con un meccanismo di svista più favorevole al 
sud bianco. Infine, il 22 giugno 1970, il presidente Richard M. 
Nixon ha firmato in legge che una fattura che ha esteso le 
disposizioni della Legge, compreso la parte 5, per cinque anni 
supplementari ed in più, ha abbassato l'età di voto durante il paese
a 18.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο νόμος δικαιωμάτων ψήφου του 1965 -- αποκαλούμενος
"επιτυχέστερο νόμο αστικών δικαιωμάτων στην ιστορία του έθνουσ" 
από την αναθ. Theodore Μ. Hesburgh, πρόεδρος της ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΉΣ
Επιτροπής στα αστικά δικαιώματα -- θεσπίστηκε προκειμένου να 
αναγκαστούν τα νότιες κράτη και οι τοποθεσίες για να επιτρέψει σε
όλους τους πολίτες της ψηφοφορίας της ηλικίας για να ψηφίσει στις
δημόσιες εκλογές. Αν και η 15$η τροποποίηση, που επικυρώθηκε
το 1870, εγγυήθηκε στους πολίτες το δικαίωμα να ψηφίσει 
ανεξάρτητα από τη φυλή, οι μεροληπτικές απαιτήσεις, όπως οι 
δοκιμές βασικής εκπαίδευσης, πολλοί αφρικανικοί Αμερικανοί στο 
νότο. Το 1965, μετά από τη δολοφονία ενός ενεργού 
στελέχους δικαιωμάτων ψήφου από τον αναπληρωτή ενός της 
Αλαμπάμα σερίφη και της επόμενης επίθεσης από τους κρατικούς 
στρατιώτες ιππικού σε μια ογκώδη διαμαρτυρία Μάρτιος σε Selma,
ο Πρόεδρος Lyndon B. Johnson πάτησε το συνέδριο για να 
ψηφίσει ένα νομοσχέδιο δικαιωμάτων ψήφου με "τα δόντια". Ο
νόμος, που υπογράφηκε στο νόμο σχετικά με στις 6 Αυγούστου, 
ίσχυσε για τα κράτη ή τους νομούς όπου λιγότεροι από τους 
μισούς από τους πολίτες της ψηφοφορίας της ηλικίας καταχωρήθηκαν
το 1964 -- Αλαμπάμα, Γεωργία, Λουιζιάνα, Μισισιπής, νότια 
Καρολίνα, Βιρτζίνια, και πολυάριθμοι νομοί στη βόρεια Καρολίνα. 
Για αυτές τις περιοχές, ο νόμος απαγόρευσε τις δοκιμές 
βασικής εκπαίδευσης, που διορίστηκαν τους ομοσπονδιακούς 
εξεταστές για να επιτηρήσει τις διαδικασίες εκλογής, και, σύμφωνα
με την αμφισβητούμενη παράγραφο 5 του νόμου, απαίτησε την έγκριση
από τον ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΟ γενικό εισαγγελέα των μελλοντικών αλλαγών 
στους νόμους εκλογής. Το 1969, μια υποεπιτροπή Συγκλήτου 
οργάνωσε τις ακροάσεις για να συζητήσει την επέκταση του νόμου. 
Στην ακόλουθη δήλωση, Βερνόν E. Ιορδανία μίλησε έντονα 
ενάντια σε έναν λογαριασμό σπιτιών, που υποστηρίχτηκε από την 
κυβέρνηση Nixon, η οποία πρότεινε να επεκτείνει την κάλυψη τη 
σε ολόκληρη χώρα και να αντικαταστήσει την παράγραφο 5 με έναν 
μηχανισμό παράλειψης πιό υποκείμενο στον άσπρο νότο. 
Τελικά, στις 22 Ιουνίου ..1970, Πρόεδρος Richard 
M. Nixon υπέγραψε στο νόμο έναν λογαριασμό που επέκτεινε 
τις διατάξεις του νόμου, συμπεριλαμβανομένης της παραγράφου 5, για
πέντε πρόσθετα έτη, και επιπλέον, χαμήλωσε την ηλικία 
ψηφοφορίας σε όλη τη χώρα σε 18.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El acto de los derechos al voto de 1965 -- llamado
"la ley más acertada de las derechas civiles de la historia de la 
nación" por M. Hesburgh, presidente de Rev. Theodore de la Comisión 
de ESTADOS UNIDOS en las derechas civiles -- fue decretado para forzar
estados y lugares meridionales para permitir que todos los ciudadanos 
de la edad de votación voten en elecciones públicas. Aunque la
décimo quinta enmienda, ratificada en 1870, garantizó a ciudadanos 
la derecha de votar sin importar la raza, los requisitos 
discriminatorios, tales como pruebas de la instrucción, 
disenfranchised a muchos americanos africanos en el sur. En 
1965, siguiendo el asesinato de un activista de los derechos al voto 
del diputado de un sheriff de Alabama y del ataque subsecuente por 
troopers del estado contra una manifestación masiva en Selma, 
presidente Lyndon B. Johnson presionó a congreso aprobar una cuenta 
de los derechos al voto con los "dientes". El acto, firmado en 
ley de agosto el 6, se aplicó a los estados o a los condados en donde
menos que la mitad de los ciudadanos de la edad de votación fueron 
colocadas en 1964 -- Alabama, Georgia, Luisiana, Mississippi, Carolina
del Sur, Virginia, y los condados numerosos en Carolina del Norte. 
Para estas áreas, la ley prohibió las pruebas de la 
instrucción, designadas los examinadores federales para supervisar 
procedimientos de la elección, y, según la sección polémica 5 del 
acto, la aprobación requerida del general de abogado de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS del futuro cambia a los leyes de la elección. En 1969, 
un subcomité del senado llevó a cabo audiencias para discutir 
ampliar el acto. En la declaración siguiente, el E. Jordania de
Vernon discutió fuertemente contra una cuenta de la casa, abogada por
la administración de Nixon, que propuso ampliar cobertura al país 
entero y substituir la sección 5 por un mecanismo del descuido más 
favorable al sur blanco. En última instancia, 22 de junio de
1970, presidente Richard M. Nixon firmó en ley que una cuenta que 
extendió las provisiones del acto, incluyendo la sección 5, por 
cinco años adicionales, y además, bajó la edad de votación a 
través del país a 18.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087282</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105315</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-clear-signal-to-officials-of-the-white-south-go-back-to-your-old-ways-vernon-jordan-argues-against-the-nixon-administrations-voting-rights-proposal</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
