<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103555</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103555</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086945</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Great Debate: Gompers Versus Hillquit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Große Debatte: Gompers Gegen Hillquit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Grande Discussion : Gompers Contre 
Hillquit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O Debate Grande: Gompers Contra Hillquit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il Dibattito Grande: Gompers Contro 
Hillquit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μεγάλη συζήτηση: Gompers εναντίον 
Hillquit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El Gran Discusión: Gompers Contra Hillquit</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">At the turn of the 20th century, many socialists within the labor movement argued that unions should be an instrument of larger social transformation. Others, led by American Federation of Labor (AFL) President Samuel Gompers, believed that the labor movement should have more limited goals. In 1903 Gompers told socialist AFL members pushing for independent political action and public ownership of the means of production: "Economically, you are unsound; socially you are wrong; industrially you are an impossibility." In 1914, Gompers once again participated in a public debate over the larger goals of the labor movement. His opponent was Morris Hillquit, a Jewish immigrant lawyer and a leading figure in the Socialist Party in New York. Gompers and Hillquit had been called to testify before a special session of the U.S. Commission on Industrial Relations, set up by Congress to investigate the underlying causes of industrial strife in America.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">An der Jahrhundertwende 20., argumentierten viele 
Sozialisten innerhalb der Arbeiterbewegung, daß Anschlüße ein 
Instrument der größeren Sozialtransformation sein sollten. 
Andere, geführt durch American Federation des Arbeits (AFL) 
Präsidenten Samuel Gompers, glaubten, daß die Arbeiterbewegung haben
sollte Ziele begrenzt. Gompers 1903 erklärte sozialistische 
AFL Bauteile, die für unabhängige politische Tätigkeit und 
allgemeinen Besitz der Produktionsmittel drücken: "ökonomisch,
sind Sie nicht einwandfrei; sozial sind Sie falsch; 
industriell sind Sie eine Unmöglichkeit." 1914 nahm 
Gompers noch einmal an einer allgemeinen Debatte über den größeren 
Zielen der Arbeiterbewegung teil. Sein Konkurrent war Morris 
Hillquit, ein jüdischer einwandernder Rechtsanwalt und eine führende
Abbildung in der sozialistischen Partei in New York. 
Gompers und Hillquit waren benannt worden, um vor einer 
speziellen Sitzung der VEREINIGTE STAATEN Kommission auf industriellen
Beziehungen zwischen den Sozialpartnern zu bezeugen, aufgestellt von 
Congress, um die zugrundeliegenden Ursachen des industriellen Streits 
in Amerika nachzuforschen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">À la fin du 20ème siècle, beaucoup de 
socialistes dans le mouvement de travail ont argué du fait que les 
syndicats devraient être un instrument d'une plus grande 
transformation sociale. D'autres, mené par American Federation 
(AFL) du Président de travail Samuel Gompers, ont cru que le 
mouvement de travail devrait avoir plus limité des buts. En 
Gompers 1903 membres socialistes dits d'AFL poussant pour l'action 
politique indépendant et la propriété du public des moyens de 
production : "économiquement, vous êtes défectueux ; 
socialement vous avez tort ; industriellement vous êtes 
une impossibilité." En 1914, Gompers a participé de nouveau à
une discussion publique au-dessus des buts plus grands du mouvement de
travail. Son adversaire était Morris Hillquit, un avocat 
immigré juif et une principale figure en parti socialiste à New 
York. Gompers et Hillquit s'étaient appelés pour témoigner 
avant une session spéciale de la Commission des ETATS-UNIS sur des 
relations industrielles, ont installé par Congress pour étudier les 
causes fondamentales des différends industriels en Amérique.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na volta do 20o século, muitos socialists dentro 
do movimento labor discutiram que as uniões devem ser um instrumento 
da transformação social maior. Outros, conduzido por Americano
Federation (AFL) do presidente labor Samuel Gompers, acreditaram que o
movimento labor deve ter mais limitado objetivos. Em Gompers 
1903 membros socialist ditos de AFL que empurram para a ação 
política independente e a posse pública dos meios de produção: 
"economicamente, você é doentio; social você é errado;
industrial você é um impossibility." Em 1914, Gompers 
participou uma vez outra vez em um debate público sobre os objetivos 
maiores do movimento labor. Seu oponente era Morris Hillquit, um
advogado immigrant jewish e uma figura principal no partido socialist 
em New York. Gompers e Hillquit tinham sido chamados para 
testify antes de uma sessão especial do commission de ESTADOS UNIDOS 
em relações industriais, ajustada acima por Congress para investigar
as causas subjacentes do strife industrial em América.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Alla fine del ventesimo secolo, molti socialisti 
all'interno del movimento di lavoro hanno sostenuto che i sindacati 
dovrebbero essere uno strumento di più grande trasformazione sociale.
Altri, condotto da American Federation (AFL) del presidente 
Di lavoro Samuel Gompers, hanno creduto che il movimento di lavoro 
dovrebbe avere limitato gli obiettivi. In Gompers 1903 membri 
socialisti detti a di AFL che spingono per l'azione politica 
indipendente e la proprietà pubblica dei mezzi di produzione: 
"economicamente, siete difettosi; siete socialmente 
errati; siete su scala industriale un'impossibilità." A 
1914, Gompers ancora una volta ha partecipato ad un dibattito pubblico
sopra i più grandi obiettivi del movimento di lavoro. Il suo 
avversario era Morris Hillquit, un avvocato immigrato ebreo e una 
figura principale nel partito socialista a New York. Gompers e 
Hillquit erano stati chiamati per testimoniare prima di una sessione 
speciale della Commissione degli STATI UNITI sulle relazione 
industriali, hanno installato da Congress per studiare le cause 
di fondo di disputa industriale in America.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο γύρισμα του 20ού αιώνα, πολλοί σοσιαλιστές μέσα 
στη μετακίνηση εργασίας υποστήριξαν ότι οι ενώσεις πρέπει να 
είναι ένα όργανο του μεγαλύτερου κοινωνικού μετασχηματισμού. 
Αλλοι, που οδηγήθηκαν από την αμερικανική ομοσπονδία του 
Προέδρου Samuel Gompers εργασίας (AFL), εθεώρησαν ότι η 
μετακίνηση εργασίας πρέπει να έχει περιορισμένος τους στόχους. 
Το 1903 Gompers είπε στα σοσιαλιστικά μέλη AFL που 
ωθούν για την ανεξάρτητη πολιτική ενέργεια και τη δημόσια 
ιδιοκτησία των μέσων της παραγωγής: "Οικονομικά, είστε 
ασθενικοί  κοινωνικά κάνετε λάθος  βιομηχανικά είστε
ένα αδύνατο." Το 1914, Gompers άλλη μια φορά 
συμμετείχε σε μια δημόσια συζήτηση πέρα από τους μεγαλύτερους 
στόχους της μετακίνησης εργασίας. Ο αντίπαλός του ήταν 
Morris Hillquit, εβραϊκός που έχουν μεταναστεύσει δικηγόρος
και ένας κύριος αριθμός στο Σοσιαλιστικό Κόμμα στη Νέα Υόρκη. 
Το Gompers και Hillquit είχαν κληθεί για να 
πιστοποιήσουν πριν από μια ειδική περίοδο επικοινωνίας της 
ΑΜΕΡΙΚΑΝΙΚΗΣ Επιτροπής στις εργασιακές σχέσεις, που οργανώθηκε 
από το συνέδριο για να ερευνήσει τις ελλοχεύουσες αιτίες της 
βιομηχανικής σύγκρουσης στην Αμερική.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Al final del vigésimo siglo, muchos socialistas 
dentro del movimiento de trabajo discutieron que las uniones fueran un
instrumento de una transformación social más grande. Otros, 
conducido por american Federation (AFL) de presidente de trabajo 
Samuel Gompers, creyeron que el movimiento de trabajo debe tener 
limitado metas. En Gompers 1903 miembros socialistas dichos de 
AFL que empujan para la acción política independiente y la propiedad 
pública de los medios de la producción: "económicamente, 
usted es falso; usted es social incorrecto; usted es 
industrial una imposibilidad." En 1914, Gompers participó de 
nuevo en un discusión público sobre las metas más grandes del 
movimiento de trabajo. Su opositor era Morris Hillquit, abogado 
inmigrante judío y una figura principal en el partido socialista en 
Nueva York. Gompers e Hillquit habían sido llamados para 
atestiguar antes de una sesión especial de la Comisión de ESTADOS 
UNIDOS en relaciones laborales, instalada por Congress para investigar
las causas subyacentes de la distensión industrial en América.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086945</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103555</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-great-debate-gompers-versus-hillquit</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
