<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106623</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106623</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206584</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Central and Eastern Europe: Peace Corps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zentrale und Osteuropa: Friedenskorps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Central et l'Europe de l'Est : Corps de 
Paix</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Central e Europa Oriental: Corpo De Paz</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Centrale e l'Europa Orientale: Corpo 
di pace</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεντρική και Ανατολική Ευρώπη: Ειρήνη Σώμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Central y Europa Oriental: Cuerpo De Paz</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">provides lessons about stories, letters, and folk tales from experiences of Peace Corps volunteers in rural and urban areas of Central and Eastern Europe. Topics include folk tales, Macedonia, Romania, Bulgaria, fear of certain numbers, transition from a state-controlled system to a democracy, school in Ukraine, the importance of speaking another language, storks and cultural icons, and family traditions as macrocosms of larger cultures.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt Lektionen über Geschichten, Zeichen zur 
Verfügung, und Volksgeschichten von den Erfahrungen der 
Friedenskorpse erbietet sich in den landwirtschaftlichen und 
städtischen Bereichen der Zentrale und des Osteuropas freiwillig. 
Themen schließen Volksgeschichten, Mazedonien, Rumänien, 
Bulgarien, Furcht vor bestimmten Zahlen, Übergang von einem 
Zustand-kontrollierten System zu einer Demokratie, Schule in Ukraine, 
der Wert des Sprechens einer anderen Sprache, Störche und kulturellen
Ikonen und Familie Traditionen als macrocosms der größeren Kulturen 
ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">fournit des leçons au sujet des histoires, 
lettres, et les contes folkloriques des expériences des corps de paix
offre dans des régions rurales et urbaines de l'Europe centrale et 
orientale. Les sujets incluent des contes folkloriques, 
Macédoine, Roumanie, Bulgarie, la crainte de certains nombres, 
transition d'un système état-commandé à une démocratie, l'école 
en Ukraine, l'importance de parler langage, cigognes et des graphismes
culturels, et des traditions différents de famille comme macrocosms 
de plus grandes cultures.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">fornece lições sobre histórias, letras, e os 
tales populares das experiências de corpos de paz oferecem-se em 
áreas rurais e urbanas de central e de Europa Oriental. Os 
tópicos incluem tales populares, Macedonia, Romania, Bulgária, medo 
de determinados números, transição de um sistema estado-controlado 
a uma democracia, escola em Ucrânia, a importância de falar uma 
outra língua, cegonhas e ícones cultural, e tradições da família 
como macrocosms de culturas maiores.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">fornisce le lezioni circa le storia, lettere ed i 
racconti pieghi per esperienza nel Corpo di pace si offre 
volontariamente nelle aree urbane rurali e della centrale e 
dell'Europa Orientale. I soggetti includono i racconti pieghi, 
Macedonia, Romania, Bulgaria, timore di determinati numeri, 
transizione da un sistema ad una democrazia, scuola in Ucraina, 
l'importanza di dichiarare-controlled di parlare un altri linguaggio, 
cicogne ed icone culturali e tradizioni della famiglia come macrocosms
di più grandi colture.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρέχει τα μαθήματα για τις ιστορίες, επιστολές, και 
οι λαϊκές ιστορίες από την εμπειρία της ειρήνης προσφέρονται 
εθελοντικά Σώμα στις αγροτικές και αστικές περιοχές της 
Κεντρικής και Ανατολικής Ευρώπης. Τα θέματα περιλαμβάνουν 
τις λαϊκές ιστορίες, Μακεδονία, Ρουμανία, Βουλγαρία, φόβος 
ορισμένων αριθμών, μετάβαση από ένα ελεγχόμενο από το κράτος 
σύστημα σε μια δημοκρατία, σχολείο στην Ουκρανία, η σημασία μια 
άλλη γλώσσα, τους πελαργούς και τα πολιτιστικά εικονίδια, και τις
οικογενειακές παραδόσεις ως μακρόκοσμος των μεγαλύτερων 
πολιτισμών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">proporciona a lecciones sobre las historias, 
cartas, y los cuentos populares por experiencia de los cuerpos de paz 
se ofrecen voluntariamente en áreas rurales y urbanas de la central y
de Europa Oriental. Los asuntos incluyen los cuentos populares, 
Macedonia, Rumania, Bulgaria, miedo de ciertos números, transición 
de un sistema estado-controlado a una democracia, escuela en Ucrania, 
la importancia de hablar otro lenguaje, cigüeñas e iconos 
culturales, y tradiciones de la familia como macrocosms de culturas 
más grandes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206584</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106623</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/central-and-eastern-europe-peace-corps</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
