<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108532</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108532</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207135</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Battle of Glorieta Pass: A Shattered Dream</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Schlacht des Glorieta Durchlaufs: Ein 
Zerbrochener Traum</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La bataille du passage de Glorieta : Un 
Rêve Brisé</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A batalha da passagem de Glorieta: Um Sonho 
Quebrado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La battaglia del passaggio di Glorieta: Un 
Sogno Frantumato</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μάχη του περάσματος Glorieta: Ένα όνειρο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La batalla del paso de Glorieta: Un Sueño 
Roto</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">examines a Civil War battle known as the Gettysburg of the West. Texans invaded this mountain valley, intent on conquering New Mexico. Victory here would be a necessary prelude to detaching the western states from the Union and expanding the Confederacy to the Pacific Ocean. They were met by volunteers from Colorado along the canyon and ridge on 03/26, 1862. A three-day battle ensued, culminating in the Confederates retreating to Texas and the Confederate hopes of expanding west shattered.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">überprüft eine Bürgerkriegschlacht, die als das
Gettysburg des Westens bekannt ist. Texans drang diese 
Gebirgssenke, Absicht auf dem Erobern von von New-Mexico ein. 
Sieg hier würde eine notwendige Einleitung zum Abtrennen der 
westlichen Zustände vom Anschluß und zur Erweiterung der 
Konföderation zum pazifischen Ozean sein. Sie wurden von den 
Freiwilligern von Kolorado entlang der Schlucht und der Kante auf 
03/26, 1862 getroffen. Eine dreitägige Schlacht folgte und 
kulminierte in den Verbündeten, die zu Texas zurückziehen und in den
verbündeten Hoffnungen der Erweiterung des Westens zerbrochen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">examine une bataille de guerre civile connue sous 
le nom de Gettysburg de l'ouest. Les Texans ont envahi 
cette vallée de montagne, intention sur conquérir le 
Nouveau-Mexique. La victoire ici serait un prélude nécessaire 
à détacher les états occidentaux de l'union et à augmenter la 
confédération à l'océan pacifique. Ils ont été rencontrés
par des volontaires du Colorado le long de la gorge et de l'arête sur
03/26, 1862. Une bataille de trois jours s'est ensuivie, 
aboutissant aux confédérés retraitant au Texas et aux espoirs 
confédérés d'augmenter l'ouest brisés.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">examina uma batalha da guerra civil sabida como o 
Gettysburg do oeste. Texans invadiu este vale da montanha, 
intenção em conquistar Novo México. A vitória aqui seria um 
prelude necessário a destacar os estados ocidentais da união e a 
expandir o confederacy ao oceano pacífico. Foram encontrados 
com por voluntários de Colorado ao longo da garganta e do cume em 
03/26, 1862. Uma batalha three-day seguiu, culminando nos 
confederados que recuam a Texas e nas esperanças confederate de 
expandir o oeste quebradas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">esamina una battaglia di guerra civile conosciuta 
come il Gettysburg dell'ovest. Texans ha invaso questa valle 
della montagna, l'intenzione sulla conquista del Nuovo Messico. 
La vittoria qui sarebbe un preludio necessario a staccare 
l'occidentale dichiara dall'unione e dall'espansione del 
confederacy all'oceano pacifico. Sono stati venuti a contatto di
dai volontari da Colorado lungo il canyon e la cresta su 03/26, 1862. 
Una battaglia di tre giorni ha seguito, culminando nei 
confederati che si ritirano al Texas e nelle speranze confederate di 
espansione dell'ovest frantumate.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει μια μάχη εμφύλιου πολέμου γνωστή ως 
Gettysburg της δύσης. Το Texans εισέβαλε σε αυτήν την 
κοιλάδα βουνών, πρόθεση στην κατάκτηση του New Mexico. 
Η νίκη εδώ θα ήταν ένα απαραίτητο προοίμιο στην 
αποσύνδεση των δυτικών κρατών από την Ένωση και την επέκταση της
συνομοσπονδίας στον ειρηνικό ωκεανό. Καλύφτηκαν από τους 
εθελοντές από το Κολοράντο κατά μήκος του φαραγγιού και την 
κορυφογραμμή στο 03/26, 1862. Μια τριών ημερών μάχη 
ακολούθησε, καταλήγοντας με τους συμμάχους που υποχωρούν στο 
Τέξας και τις ομόσπονδες ελπίδες της επέκτασης της δύσης που 
καταστράφηκαν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">examina una batalla de la guerra civil conocida 
como el Gettysburg del oeste. Texans invadió este valle de la 
montaña, intento en la conquista de New México. La victoria 
aquí sería un preludio necesario a separar los estados occidentales 
de la unión y a ampliar el confederacy al Océano Pacífico. 
Fueron resueltos por los voluntarios de Colorado a lo largo de 
la barranca y del canto en 03/26, 1862. Una batalla de tres 
días sobrevino, culminando en los confederatos que retiraban a Tejas 
y las esperanzas confederadas de ampliar el oeste rotas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207135</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108532</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-battle-of-glorieta-pass-a-shattered-dream</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
