<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/528947953</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>528947953</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213219</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">World Wind</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Weltwind</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vent du Monde</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vento Do Mundo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Vento Del Mondo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παγκόσμιος αέρας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Viento Del Mundo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site features World Wind 1.3, a NASA Learning Technologies application that lets the user zoom from any satellite altitude into any place on Earth. It features 3D Engine, Blue Marble, Landsat 7, SRTM, Animated Earth, MODIS, GLOBE, Country &amp; State Borders, Place Names, Visual Tools and Landmark Set. The user can download World Wind, reference an online manual, post to an online forum, view screen shot examples from various satellites, and read press coverage about World Wind.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Situationsmerkmale Weltwind 1.3, eine die 
NASA erlernentechnologieanwendung, die den Benutzer zoom von jeder 
Satellitenhöhe in irgendeinen Platz auf Masse läßt. Sie 
kennzeichnet 3D Maschine, blauer Marmor, Landsat 7, SRTM, lebhafte 
Masse, MODIS, KUGEL, Land-u. Zustand-Ränder, Ortsnamen, 
Sichthilfsmittel und Grenzstein-Set. Der Benutzer kann Weltwind 
downloaden, ein Onlinehandbuch, Pfosten anzusprechen zu einem 
Onlineforum, schoß Ansichtbildschirm Beispiele von den verschiedenen 
Satelliten und las Pressedichte über Weltwind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce vent 1.3, une application d'étude du monde de 
dispositifs de site de technologies de la NASA qui laisse 
l'utilisateur bourdonner de n'importe quelle altitude satellite dans 
n'importe quel endroit sur terre. Elle comporte 3D le moteur, 
marbre bleu, Landsat 7, SRTM, terre animée, MODIS, GLOBE, cadres de 
pays et d'état, noms de lieu, outils visuels et positionnement de 
borne limite. L'utilisateur peut télécharger le vent du monde,
mettre en référence un manuel en ligne, poteau à un forum en ligne,
l'écran de vue a tiré des exemples de divers satellites, et a 
indiqué l'assurance de presse au sujet du vent du monde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este vento 1.3 do mundo das características de 
local, uma aplicação de aprendizagem das tecnologias da NASA que 
deixe o usuário zumbir de toda a altura satellite em qualquer lugar 
na terra. Caracteriza 3D o motor, mármore azul, Landsat 7, 
SRTM, terra animated, MODIS, GLOBO, beiras do país &amp; do estado, nomes
de lugar, ferramentas visuais e jogo do marco. O usuário pode 
download o vento do mundo, para reference um manual em linha, borne a 
um forum em linha, a tela da vista disparou em exemplos dos vários 
satélites, e leu a cobertura de imprensa sobre o vento do mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo vento 1.3, un'applicazione imparante del 
mondo delle caratteristiche di luogo di tecnologie della NASA che 
lascia l'utente zumare da tutta l'altezza satellite in qualunque posto
su terra. Caratterizza 3D il motore, marmo blu, Landsat 7, SRTM,
terra animata, MODIS, GLOBO, paese &amp; Dichiara i bordi, i nomi 
di luogo, gli strumenti visivi e l'insieme del limite. L'utente 
può trasferire il vento dal sistema centrale verso i satelliti del 
mondo, riferire un manuale in linea, alberino ad una tribuna in linea,
lo schermo di vista ha sparato gli esempi dai vari satelliti ed ha 
indicato l'accoglienza della stampa circa il vento del mondo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει τον παγκόσμιο αέρα 
1,3, μια εφαρμογή τεχνολογιών εκμάθησης της NASA που αφήνει 
το χρήστη να μεγεθύνει από οποιοδήποτε δορυφορικό ύψος σε 
οποιαδήποτε θέση στη γη. Χαρακτηρίζει την τρισδιάστατη 
μηχανή, το μπλε μάρμαρο, Landsat 7, SRTM, τη ζωντανεψοντη γη, 
MODIS, τα σύνορα ΣΦΑΙΡΏΝ, χώρας &amp; κράτους, τα ονόματα θέσεων,
τα οπτικά εργαλεία και το σύνολο ορόσημων. Ο χρήστης 
μπορεί να μεταφορτώσει τον παγκόσμιο αέρα, να παραπέμψει ένα σε 
απευθείας σύνδεση εγχειρίδιο, τη θέση σε ένα σε απευθείας 
σύνδεση φόρουμ, τα πυροβοληθέντα οθόνη παραδείγματα όψης από 
τους διάφορους δορυφόρους, και τη διαβασμένη κάλυψη Τύπου για τον
παγκόσμιο αέρα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este viento 1.3, una aplicación del mundo de las 
características de sitio de las tecnologías de la NASA que aprende 
que deja a utilizador enfocar de cualquier altitud basada en los 
satélites en cualquier lugar en la tierra. Ofrece 3D el motor, 
mármol azul, Landsat 7, SRTM, tierra animada, MODIS, GLOBO, fronteras
del país y del estado, topónimos, herramientas visuales y conjunto 
de la señal. El utilizador puede descargar el viento del mundo,
referirse a un manual en línea, poste a un foro en línea, la 
pantalla de la visión tiró a ejemplos de los varios satélites, y 
leyó cobertura de prensa sobre el viento del mundo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213219</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>528947953</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/world-wind</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
