<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108128</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108128</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212445</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Teaching with Models</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Unterricht mit Modellen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Enseignement avec des modèles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ensino com modelos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Insegnamento con i modelli</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διδασκαλία με τα μοντέλα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Enseñanza con los modelos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Starting Point Module contains information on teaching with models geoscience education. Modeling is fundamental to science, great for an interactive student-centered environment, and ideal for the Earth systems approach. Types of models include conceptual, physical analog, mathematical, statistical, and visualization. This page offers links, information and examples for all modeling types, including examples of different models for each geoscience discipline. This module is part of the Starting Point Collection: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses Ausgangspunkt-Modul enthält Informationen 
über das Unterrichten mit Modelle geoscience Ausbildung. Die 
Formung ist grundlegend zur Wissenschaft ideal, groß für eine 
interaktive Kursteilnehmer-zentrierte Umgebung, und für die Masse 
Systeme Annäherung. Typen der Modelle enthalten Begriffs-, 
körperliche Entsprechung, mathematisch, statistisch und 
Sichtbarmachung. Diese Seite bietet Links, Informationen und 
Beispiele für alle formentypen, einschließlich Beispiele der 
unterschiedlichen Modelle für jede geoscience Disziplin an. 
Dieses Modul ist ein Teil der Ausgangspunkt-Ansammlung: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce module de point de départ contient 
l'information sur enseigner avec l'éducation de geoscience de 
modèles. Modeler est fondamental à la science, grand pour un 
environnement étudiant-centré interactif, et idéal pour l'approche 
systématisée de la terre. Les types de modèles incluent 
l'analogue, mathématique conceptuel et physique, statistique, et la 
visualisation. Cette page offre des liens, l'information et des 
exemples pour tous les types modelants, y compris des exemples de 
différents modèles pour chaque discipline de geoscience. Ce 
module fait partie de la collection de point de départ : 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este módulo do ponto começar contem a 
informação em ensinar com instrução do geoscience dos modelos. 
Modelar é fundamental à ciência, grande para um ambiente 
estudante-centrado interativo, e ideal para a aproximação de 
sistemas da terra. Os tipos de modelos incluem o analog, 
matemático conceptual, físico, estatístico, e o visualization. 
Esta página oferece as ligações, a informação e os exemplos
para todos os tipos modelando, including exemplos de modelos 
diferentes para cada disciplina do geoscience. Este módulo é 
parte da coleção do ponto começar: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo modulo del punto di partenza contiene le 
informazioni sull'istruzione con la formazione di geoscience dei 
modelli. La modellistica è fondamentale alla scienza, grande 
per un ambiente allievo-centrato interattivo ed ideale per l'approccio
sistematico della terra. I tipi di modelli includono l'analogo, 
matematico concettuale e fisico, statistico e la visualizzazione. 
Questa pagina offre i collegamenti, le informazioni e gli esempi
per tutti i tipi modellanti, compreso gli esempi dei modelli 
differenti per ogni disciplina di geoscience. Questo modulo fa 
parte dell'accumulazione del punto di partenza: 
http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η ενότητα αφετηρίας περιέχει τις πληροφορίες για
τη διδασκαλία με την εκπαίδευση geoscience μοντέλων. Η 
διαμόρφωση είναι θεμελιώδης στην επιστήμη, μεγάλη για ένα 
διαλογικό σπουδαστής-κεντροθετημένο περιβάλλον, και το ιδανικό 
για την προσέγγιση γήινων συστημάτων. Οι τύποι μοντέλων 
περιλαμβάνουν εννοιολογικούς, φυσικούς αναλογικό, μαθηματικός, 
στατιστικός, και την απεικόνιση. Αυτή η σελίδα προσφέρει 
τις συνδέσεις, τις πληροφορίες και τα παραδείγματα για όλους τους 
τύπους διαμόρφωσης, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των παραδειγμάτων των 
διαφορετικών μοντέλων για κάθε πειθαρχία geoscience. 
Αυτή η ενότητα είναι μέρος της συλλογής αφετηρίας: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este módulo del punto de partida contiene la 
información sobre la enseñanza con la educación del geoscience de 
los modelos. El modelar es fundamental a la ciencia, grande para
un ambiente estudiante-centrado interactivo, e ideal para el 
acercamiento de sistemas de la tierra. Los tipos de modelos 
incluyen análogo, matemático conceptual, físico, estadístico, y la
visualización. Esta paginación ofrece conexiones, la 
información y los ejemplos para todos los tipos que modelan, 
incluyendo ejemplos de diversos modelos para cada disciplina del 
geoscience. Este módulo es parte de la colección del punto de 
partida: http://serc.carleton.edu/introgeo/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212445</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108128</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/teaching-with-models</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
