<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107013</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107013</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206164</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">National Center for Learning and Teaching in Nanoscale Science and Technology and Engineering</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nationale Mitte für das Lernen und das 
Unterrichten in der Nanoscale Wissenschaft und der Technologie und die
Technik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Centre national pour apprendre et enseigner en la 
Science et technologie de Nanoscale et machiner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Centro nacional para aprender e ensinar na 
ciência e na tecnologia de Nanoscale e projetar</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Centro nazionale per imparare e l'istruzione nella
scienza e nella tecnologia di Nanoscale e costruire</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εθνικό κέντρο για την εκμάθηση και τη διδασκαλία στην 
επιστήμη Nanoscale και την τεχνολογία και την εφαρμοσμένη 
μηχανική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Centro nacional para aprender y enseñar en la 
ciencia y la tecnología de Nanoscale y dirigir</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">offers summer professional development opportunities for teachers and online courses. One course, Introduction to Nanometer Scale, looks at strategies for controlling the structure of matter and real-world applications that use nanometer scale devices. What Can Electrons Do? examines properties of electrons and applications of electron microscopy in characterizing nano-scale materials.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">professionelle Gelegenheiten Entwicklung des 
Angebotsommers für Lehrer und Onlinekurse. Ein Kurs, Einleitung
in eine Nanometer-Skala, Blicke auf Strategien für die Steuerung der 
Struktur des Stoffes und der realistischen Anwendungen, die 
Nanometerskalaeinheiten benutzen. Was Können Elektronen Tun? 
überprüft Eigenschaften der Elektronen und Anwendungen der 
Elektronenmikroskopie, beim Kennzeichnen nano-stufen Materialien ein.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">occasions professionnelles de développement 
d'été d'offres pour des professeurs et des cours en ligne. Un 
cours, introduction à l'échelle de nanomètre, regards aux 
stratégies pour contrôler la structure de la matière et des 
applications réelles qui utilisent des dispositifs d'échelle de 
nanomètre. Que Les Électrons Peuvent-ils Faire ? examine
des propriétés des électrons et des applications de la microscopie 
électronique en caractérisant des matériaux de nano-scale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">oportunidades profissionais do desenvolvimento do 
verão das ofertas para professores e cursos em linha. Um curso,
introdução à escala do nanômetro, olhares nas estratégias para 
controlar a estrutura da matéria e das aplicações real-world que 
usam dispositivos da escala do nanômetro. Que Podem Os 
Elétrons Fazer? examina propriedades dos elétrons e as 
aplicações do microscopy de elétron em caracterizar nano-escalam 
materiais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">occasioni professionali di sviluppo di estate di 
offerte per gli insegnanti ed i corsi in linea. Un corso, 
introduzione alla scala di nanometro, sguardi alle strategie per 
gestire la struttura della materia e delle applicazioni nell'ambiente 
che utilizzano i dispositivi della scala di nanometro. Che cosa 
Possono Gli Elettroni Fare? esamina le proprietà degli 
elettroni e le applicazioni di microscopia elettronica nel 
caratterizzare nano-regolano i materiali.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ευκαιρίες θερινής επαγγελματικές ανάπτυξης προσφορών 
για τους δασκάλους και τις σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρές μαθημάτων.
Μια σειρά μαθημάτων, εισαγωγή στην κλίμακα Nanometer, 
εξετάζει τις στρατηγικές για τη δομή του θέματος και των 
πραγματικών εφαρμογών που χρησιμοποιούν τις συσκευές κλίμακας 
nanometer. Τι μπορούν τα ηλεκτρόνια να κάνουν; 
εξετάζει τις ιδιότητες των ηλεκτρονίων και των εφαρμογών της
μικροσκόπησης ηλεκτρονίων στο χαρακτηρισμό των υλικών 
νανο-κλίμακας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">oportunidades profesionales del desarrollo del 
verano de las ofertas para los profesores y los cursos en línea. 
Un curso, introducción a la escala del nanómetro, miradas en 
las estrategias para controlar la estructura de la materia y de las 
aplicaciones del mundo real que utilizan los dispositivos de la escala
del nanómetro. ¿Qué Pueden Los Electrones Hacer? examina
características de electrones y las aplicaciones de la microscopia 
electrónica en caracterizar nano-escalan los materiales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206164</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107013</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/national-center-for-learning-and-teaching-in-nanoscale-science-and-technology-and-engineering</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
