<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103862</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103862</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211445</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Order it up applet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bestellen Sie ihn herauf applet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Commandez-le vers le haut de l'applet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Requisite-o acima do applet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ordinilo sul applet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατάταξη αυτό επάνω applet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pídalo encima de applet</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Does any planet have a stronger magnetic field than Mars? Which planets have a greater mass than Jupiter? Which are denser? Which are larger? Users can find out while playing the Solar System Edition of Order It Up! Order it Up measures of size and scale help us understand the magnitude of objects. Once you get the planetary bodies in order, you can unscramble a space photograph.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Läßt irgendein Planet ein stärkeres magnetisches
als Mars auffangen? Welche Planeten haben eine 
grössere Masse als Jupiter? Welche sind dichter? Welche 
sind größer? Benutzer können herausfinden beim die 
Solarsystem Ausgabe der Ordnung oben spielen es! Bestellen Sie 
es herauf Masse der Größe und Skala helfen uns, die Größe der 
Nachrichten zu verstehen. Sobald Sie die planetarischen Körper 
in der Ordnung erhalten, können Sie unscramble eine Platzfotographie.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Est-ce que une planète a un champ magnétique plus
fort que Mars ? Quelles planètes ont une plus grande masse que 
Jupiter ? Quel est plus dense ? Quel est plus grand ? 
Les utilisateurs peuvent découvrir tout en jouant l'édition de
système solaire de la commande il vers le haut ! Commandez-le 
vers le haut des mesures de taille et l'échelle nous aident à 
comprendre l'importance d'objets. Une fois que vous obtenez les 
corps planétaires dans la commande, vous pouvez déchiffrer une 
photographie de l'espace.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Algum planeta tem um campo magnético mais forte do
que Marte? Que planetas têm uma massa mais grande do que 
Jupiter? Quais são mais densos? Quais são maiores? 
Os usuários podem encontrar para fora ao jogar a edição do 
sistema solar da ordem ele acima! Requisite-o acima das medidas 
do tamanho e a escala ajuda-nos compreender o valor dos objetos. 
Uma vez que você começa os corpos planetários em ordem, você
pode unscramble uma fotografia do espaço.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Del pianeta ha un campo magnetico più forte che 
Marte? Quali pianeti hanno una massa più grande che Jupiter? 
Quale sono più densi? Quale sono più grandi? Gli 
utenti possono scoprire mentre giocano l'edizione del sistema solare 
di ordine esso in su! Ordinilo sulle misure del formato e la 
scala li aiuta a capire la grandezza degli oggetti. Una volta 
che ottenete i corpi planetari nell'ordine, potete unscramble una 
fotografia dello spazio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οποιοσδήποτε πλανήτης έχει ένα ισχυρότερο μαγνητικό 
πεδίο από τον Αρη; Ποιοι πλανήτες έχουν μια μεγαλύτερη 
μάζα από Δία; Όποιοι είναι πυκνότεροι; Όποιοι 
είναι μεγαλύτεροι; Οι χρήστες μπορούν να ανακαλύψουν 
παίζοντας την έκδοση ηλιακών συστημάτων της κατάταξης αυτό 
επάνω! Η κατάταξη αυτό επάνω μέτρα του μεγέθους και της 
κλίμακας μας βοηθά να καταλάβουμε το μέγεθος των αντικειμένων. 
Μόλις πάρετε τους πλανητικούς οργανισμούς στην κατάταξη, 
μπορείτε unscramble μια διαστημική φωτογραφία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Planeta tiene un campo que Marte? ¿Qué 
planetas tienen una mayor masa que Júpiter? ¿Cuáles son más 
densos? ¿Cuáles son más grandes? ¡Los utilizadores 
pueden descubrir mientras que juegan la edición de la Sistema Solar 
de la orden él para arriba! Pídalo encima de medidas de la 
talla y la escala nos ayuda a entender la magnitud de objetos. 
Una vez que usted consiga los cuerpos planetarios en orden, 
usted puede descifrar una fotografía del espacio.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211445</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103862</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/order-it-up-applet</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
