<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107278</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107278</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1037366505</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A History Bursting With Telling: Asian Americans in Washington State</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Geschichte, die Mit Dem Sagen Birst: 
Asiatische Amerikaner im Staat Washington</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une Histoire Éclatant Avec Le dire : 
Américains asiatiques dans l'état de Washington</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um History Que Estoura Com Dizer: Americanos 
asian no estado de Washington</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una Storia Che Scoppia Con Dire: Gli 
Americani asiatici a Washington Dichiarano</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια ιστορία που εκρήγνυται με την αφήγηση: 
Ασιατικοί Αμερικανοί στο κράτος της Ουάσιγκτον</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una Historia Que reparte Con Decir: 
Americanos asiáticos en el estado de Washington</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Washington is a mosaic made of different peoples coming together to create new lives in a new land. The Asian American experience is part of this mosaic. The documents that accompany this essay demonstrate how Chinese, Japanese, and Filipinos came to Washington, struggled against discrimination, labored to earn their living, and created distinctive cultures and identities. These documents chronicle, in a small way, how some Asian immigrants became Asian Americans.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Washington ist ein Mosaik, das von den 
unterschiedlichen Völkern gebildet wird, die zusammen kommen, neue 
Lebensdauern in einem neuen Land zu erstellen. Die asiatische 
amerikanische Erfahrung ist ein Teil dieses Mosaiks. Die 
Dokumente, die diesen Versuch begleiten, zeigen, wie chinesisch, 
japanisch und Filipinos nach Washington kam, gekämpft gegen die 
Unterscheidung, bearbeitet, um ihr Leben zu erwerben und erstellte 
unterscheidende Kulturen und Identitäten. Chronik dieser 
Dokumente, in einer kleinen Methode, wie einige asiatische Immigranten
asiatische Amerikaner wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Washington est une mosaïque faite de différents 
peuples venant ensemble pour créer les nouvelles vies dans une 
nouvelle terre. L'expérience américaine asiatique fait partie 
de cette mosaïque. Les documents qui accompagnent cet essai 
démontrent comment chinois, japonais, et des Philippins est venu à 
Washington, lutté contre la discrimination, travaillée pour gagner 
leur vie, et les cultures et les identités distinctives créées. 
Chronique de ces documents, d'une petite voie, comment quelques 
immigrés asiatiques sont devenus les Américains asiatiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Washington é um mosaic feito dos povos diferentes
que vêm junto criar vidas novas em uma terra nova. A 
experiência americana asian é parte deste mosaic. Os originais
que acompanham este essay demonstram como chinês, japonês, e 
filipinos veio a Washington, esforçado de encontro à 
discriminação, trabalhada para ganhar sua vida, e culturas e 
identidades distintivas criadas. Chronicle destes originais, em 
uma maneira pequena, como alguns immigrants asian se transformaram 
americanos asian.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Washington è un mosaico fatto della gente 
differente che viene insieme creare le nuove vite in una nuova terra. 
L'esperienza americana asiatica fa parte di questo mosaico. 
I documenti che accompagnano questo saggio dimostrano quanto 
cinese, giapponese e filipinos è venuto a Washington, lottata 
contro distinzione, lavorata per guadagnare la loro vita e colture ed 
identità distintive create. Chronicle di questi documenti, in 
un piccolo modo, come alcuni immigranti asiatici sono diventato 
Americani asiatici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Ουάσιγκτον είναι ένα μωσαϊκό φιαγμένο από 
διαφορετικούς λαούς που ενώνονται να δημιουργήσει τις νέες ζωές 
σε ένα νέο έδαφος. Η ασιατική αμερικανική εμπειρία είναι 
μέρος αυτού του μωσαϊκού. Τα έγγραφα που συνοδεύουν αυτό 
το δοκίμιο καταδεικνύουν πώς τα κινέζικα, Ιάπωνες, και 
Φιλιππίνοι ήρθαν στην Ουάσιγκτον, κατά της διάκρισης, που 
εργάστηκε για να κερδίσει τη διαβίωσή τους, και δημιούργησαν τους
διακριτικούς πολιτισμούς και τις ταυτότητες. Αυτά τα 
έγγραφα εξιστορούν κατά γράμμα, με έναν μικρό τρόπο, πώς 
μερικοί ασιατικοί μετανάστες έγιναν ασιατικοί Αμερικανοί.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Washington es un mosaico hecho de diversa gente 
que viene junto crear nuevas vidas en una pista nueva. La 
experiencia americana asiática es parte de este mosaico. Los 
documentos que acompañan este ensayo demuestran cómo es chino, 
japonés, y los filipinos vino a Washington, luchado contra la 
discriminación, trabajada para ganar su vida, y las culturas y las 
identidades distintivas creadas. Chronicle de estos documentos, 
de una manera pequeña, cómo algunos inmigrantes asiáticos hicieron 
americanos asiáticos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1037366505</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107278</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/a-history-bursting-with-telling-asian-americans-in-washington-state</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
