<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103387</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103387</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209899</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Circumcircle of a Regular Polygon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Circumcircle eines regelmäßigen Polygons</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Circumcircle d'un polygone régulier</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Circumcircle de um polygon regular</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Circumcircle di un poligono normale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Circumcircle ενός κανονικού πολυγώνου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Circumcircle de un polígono regular</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that show the properties of a circumcircle of a polygon. The applet shows a regular polygon where the user can drag the vertices to reshape it and alter the number of sides. As the polygon is being varied, the circumcircle is shown, passing through all vertices. The text describes two ways to calculate the radius of the circumcircle, depending on what you are given to start. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die die Eigenschaften eines circumcircle eines Polygons 
zeigen. Der applet zeigt einem regelmäßigen Polygon, wo der 
Benutzer die Gipfel schleppen kann, um ihn umzugestalten und die Zahl 
Seiten zu ändern. Während das Polygon verändert wird, wird 
das circumcircle gezeigt und überschreitet durch alle Gipfel. 
Der Text beschreibt zwei Möglichkeiten, zu errechnen den Radius
des circumcircle, abhängig von, was Ihnen zum Anfang gegeben werden. 
Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit einem 
Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch im 
Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui montrent les propriétés d'un circumcircle d'un polygone. 
L'applet montre à un polygone régulier où l'utilisateur peut 
traîner les sommets pour le restructurer et pour modifier le nombre 
de côtés. Pendant que le polygone est changé, le circumcircle
est montré, passant par tous les sommets. Le texte décrit deux
voies de calculer le rayon du circumcircle, selon ce que vous êtes 
donné au début. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille de 
plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. 
Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut 
lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison 
ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
mostrem as propriedades de um circumcircle de um polygon. O 
applet mostra a um polygon regular onde o usuário pode arrastar os 
vertices para reshape o e alterar o número dos lados. Enquanto 
o polygon está sendo variado, o circumcircle é mostrado, passando 
com todos os vertices. O texto descreve duas maneiras calcular o
raio do circumcircle, dependendo de o que você é dado ao começo. 
O applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso 
com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de 
aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na 
HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. 
Este recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook 
da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
mostrano le proprietà di un circumcircle di un poligono. Il 
applet mostra ad un poligono normale dove l'utente può trascinare i 
vertici per rimodellarlo ed alterare il numero di lati. Mentre 
il poligono sta variando, il circumcircle è indicato, passante con 
tutti i vertici. Il testo descrive due modi calcolare il raggio 
del circumcircle, secondo che cosa siete dati all'inizio. Il 
applet può essere ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con 
un proiettore dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, 
allievo può accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o 
nella libreria senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa 
risorsa è un componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della 
geometria di riferimento aperto di per la matematica a 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
εμφανίζουν τις ιδιότητες ενός circumcircle ενός πολυγώνου. 
Το applet εμφανίζει κανονικό πολύγωνο όπου ο χρήστης 
μπορεί να σέρει vertices για να το αναδιαμορφώσει και να 
αλλάξει τον αριθμό πλευρών. Δεδομένου ότι το πολύγωνο 
ποικίλλεται, το circumcircle εμφανίζεται, περνώντας μέσω όλα 
vertices. Το κείμενο περιγράφει δύο τρόπους να 
υπολογιστεί η ακτίνα του circumcircle, ανάλογα με αυτό που σας 
δίνεται στην έναρξη. Το Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο 
πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. 
Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει 
πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι
ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. 
Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του 
ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math 
διαλογικού σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
muestran las características de un circumcircle de un polígono. 
El applet muestra a polígono regular donde el utilizador puede 
arrastrar las cimas para restructurarlo y para alterar el número de 
caras. Mientras que se está variando el polígono, el 
circumcircle se muestra, pasando con todas las cimas. El texto 
describe dos maneras de calcular el radio del circumcircle, 
dependiendo de lo que le dan al comienzo. El applet se puede 
agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209899</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103387</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/circumcircle-of-a-regular-polygon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
