<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107732</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107732</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200652</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Biodiversity stuff to do: Endangered!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Biodiversitymaterial zum zu tun: Gefährdet!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Substance de biodiversité à faire : Mis en
danger !</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Material do biodiversity a fazer: Posto em 
perigo!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Roba di biodiversity da fare: Messo!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ουσία βιοποικιλότητας για να κάνει: 
Διακυβευμένος!</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Materia de la biodiversidad a hacer: ¡Puesto en
peligro!</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This Ology game site contains rules and a board for a board game dealing with extinction, particularly the modern biodiversity crisis. The players need to read endangered species facts from the board to answer questions on the spaces that they land in so that they can progress. Users can follow links to what to do and materials needed for the game.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Ologyspielsite enthält Richtlinien und ein Brett 
für ein Brettspiel, das Löschung, besonders die moderne 
Biodiversitykrise beschäftigt. Die Spieler müssen gefährdete 
Sortetatsachen vom Brett lesen, um Fragen über die Platz zu 
beantworten, die sie innen landen, damit sie weiterkommen können. 
Benutzer können Links zu was zu tun und zu den Materialien 
folgen benötigten für das Spiel.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site de jeu d'ology contient des règles et un panneau 
pour un jeu de panneau traitant l'extinction, en particulier la crise 
moderne de biodiversité. Les joueurs doivent lire des faits mis
en danger d'espèces du panneau pour répondre à des questions 
sur les espaces qu'ils débarquent dedans de sorte qu'ils puissent 
progresser. Les utilisateurs peuvent suivre des liens à quoi 
faire et aux matériaux ont eu besoin pour le jeu.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local do jogo do ology contem réguas e uma placa 
para um jogo de placa que trata da extinção, particularmente a crise
moderna do biodiversity. Os jogadores necessitam ler fatos 
postos em perigo da espécie da placa para responder a perguntas nos 
espaços que aterram dentro de modo que possam progredir. Os 
usuários podem seguir as ligações a o que fazer e aos materiais 
necessitaram para o jogo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo del gioco del ology contiene le regole e un 
bordo per un gioco che si occupa dell'estinzione, specialmente 
la crisi moderna del bordo di biodiversity. I giocatori 
devono leggere i fatti in pericolo di specie dal bordo per 
rispondere alle domande sugli spazi che atterrano dentro in moda da 
poterli progredire. Gli utenti possono seguire i collegamenti 
che cosa fare ed a materiali hanno avuto bisogno di per il gioco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παιχνιδιών Ology περιέχει τους 
κανόνες και έναν πίνακα για ένα παιχνίδι πινάκων που εξετάζει 
την εξάλειψη, ιδιαίτερα η σύγχρονη κρίση βιοποικιλότητας. 
Οι φορείς πρέπει να διαβάσουν τα διακυβευμένα γεγονότα 
ειδών από τον πίνακα στις ερωτήσεις απάντησης στα διαστήματα που
προσγειώνονται έτσι ώστε μπορούν να προχωρήσουν. Οι 
χρήστες μπορούν να ακολουθήσουν τις συνδέσεις με αυτά που να 
κάνουν και τα υλικά χρειάστηκαν για το παιχνίδι.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio del juego del ology contiene a reglas y a 
tarjeta para un juego de tarjeta que se ocupa de la extinción, 
determinado la crisis moderna de la biodiversidad. Los jugadores 
necesitan leer hechos puestos en peligro de la especie de la tarjeta 
para contestar a preguntas sobre los espacios que aterrizan adentro de
modo que puedan progresar. Los utilizadores pueden seguir 
conexiones qué hacer y a los materiales necesitaron para el juego.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770200652</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107732</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/biodiversity-stuff-to-do-endangered</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
