<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106618</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106618</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206539</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Trail of Tears: The Forced Relocation of the Cherokee Nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Spur der Risse: Die vorverlegte 
Verschiebung der Cherokee Nation</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La traînée des larmes : Le réadressage 
obligatoire de la nation cherokee</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A fuga dos rasgos: O relocation forçado da 
nação cherokee</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La traccia delle rotture: Rilocazione 
forzata della nazione cherokee</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ίχνος των δακρύων: Η αναγκασμένη 
επαναμετάθεση του τσερόκι έθνους</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El rastro de rasgones: La realocación 
forzada de la nación cherokee</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells about the removal of the Cherokee Nation from their ancestral homeland (NC, TN, GA, AL) to Indian Territory (now Oklahoma). After passage of the Indian Removal Act and the discovery of gold on Cherokee lands (1830), about 100,000 American Indians living between the original 13 states and the Mississippi River were relocated to Oklahoma. The trails they followed came to be known as the Trail of Tears.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt über den Abbau der Cherokee Nation von 
ihrer ancestral Heimaten (NC, TN, GA, AL) zur indischen Gegend (jetzt 
Oklahoma). Nachdem Durchgang der indischen Abbau-Tat und der 
Entdeckung des Goldes auf Cherokee Ländern (1830), ungefähr 100.000 
Indianer, die zwischen den Vorlage 13 Zuständen und dem Mississippi 
Fluß leben, zu Oklahoma verlagert wurden. Die Spuren, die sie 
folgten, kamen, als die Spur der Risse bekannt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit au sujet du déplacement de la nation cherokee
de leur patrie héréditaire (OR, TN, GA, AL) au territoire indien 
(maintenant l'Oklahoma). Après que le passage de l'acte indien 
de déplacement et de la découverte de l'or sur les terres cherokee 
(1830), environ 100.000 Indiens d'Amerique vivant entre les états de 
l'original 13 et le fleuve du Mississippi aient été replacés à 
l'Oklahoma. Les traînées qu'elles ont suivies sont venues pour
être connues comme traînée des larmes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz sobre a remoção da nação cherokee de seu 
homeland ancestral (NC, TN, GA, AL) ao território indian (agora 
Oklahoma). Depois que a passagem do ato indian da remoção e da
descoberta do ouro nas terras cherokee (1830), aproximadamente 100.000
indians americanos que vivem entre os estados do original 13 e o rio 
de Mississippi relocated a Oklahoma. As fugas que seguiram 
vieram ser sabidas como a fuga dos rasgos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice a circa la rimozione della nazione cherokee 
dalla loro patria ancestral (NC, TN, GA, AL) al territorio 
indiano (ora Oklahoma). Dopo che il passaggio della Legge 
indiana di rimozione e la scoperta di oro sulle terre cherokee (1830),
circa 100.000 indiani americani che vivono fra l'originale 13 
dichiari ed il fiume del Mississippi è stato riassegnato ad 
Oklahoma. Le tracce che hanno seguito sono venuto essere 
conosciute come la traccia delle rotture.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει για την απομάκρυνση του τσερόκι έθνους από την 
προγονική πατρίδα τους (NC, TN, GA, Al) στο ινδικό 
έδαφος (τώρα Οκλαχόμα). Μετά από τη μετάβαση του ινδικού 
νόμου αφαίρεσης και την ανακάλυψη του χρυσού στα τσερόκι εδάφη 
(1830), περίπου 100.000 αμερικανικοί Ινδοί που ζουν μεταξύ 
των αρχικών 13 κρατών και του ποταμού του Μισισιπή 
επανεντοπίστηκαν στην Οκλαχόμα. Τα ίχνη που ακολούθησαν 
ήρθαν να μαθευτούν ως ίχνος των δακρύων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">habla del retiro de la nación cherokee de su 
patria ancestral (NC, TN, GA, AL) al territorio indio (ahora 
Oklahoma). Después de que volvieran a poner el paso del acto 
indio del retiro y del descubrimiento del oro en las pistas cherokee 
(1830), a cerca de 100.000 indios americanos que vivían entre los 
estados de la original 13 y el río de Mississippi a Oklahoma. 
Los rastros que siguieron vinieron ser conocidos como el rastro 
de rasgones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206539</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106618</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-trail-of-tears-the-forced-relocation-of-the-cherokee-nation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
