<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107171</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107171</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086817</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Shall the Fundamentalists Win?": Defending Liberal Protestantism in the 1920s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"sollen Sie der Fundamentalist-Gewinn?": 
Verteidigendes liberales Protestantism in den zwanziger Jahren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">" la victoire de fondamentalistes?" : 
Protestantisme libéral défendant dans les années 20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"deva a vitória dos fundamentalistas?": 
Protestantism liberal defendendo nos 1920s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"la vittoria di Fondamentalisti?": Protestantism 
liberale difendente negli anni 20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Οι φανατικοί οπαδοί θα κερδίσουν;": Υπεράσπιση 
του φιλελεύθερου Προτεσταντισμού στη δεκαετία του '20</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">" el triunfo de los fundamentalistas?": 
Protestantism liberal que defiende en los años 20</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Urban as well as rural Americans flocked to fundamentalist and evangelical churches in the 1920s. "Liberal" Protestants sought to reconcile faith and science and to slow what they saw as the reactionary tendencies of fundamentalism. Harry Emerson Fosdick's influential 1922 sermon, "Shall the Fundamentalists Win?," called for an open-minded, intellectual, and tolerant "Christian fellowship." Though the sermon cost him his post at New York's First Presbyterian Church, his views represented those of an influential Protestant minority, and Fosdick enjoyed a long career at Riverside Church, built for him by John D. Rockefeller. Following the Scopes trial and a well-publicized scandal involving well-known pastor Aimee Semple McPherson and a mysterious lover, fundamentalists began to lose the prominence they enjoyed in the 1920s. But religious fundamentalism would remain a vital political force in American life.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Städtisch sowie die landwirtschaftlichen 
Amerikaner geschart zu den fundamentalistischen und evangelischen 
Kirchen in den zwanziger Jahren. "liberale" Protestanten 
suchten, Glauben und Wissenschaft zu versöhnen und zu verlangsamen, 
was sie als die Reaktionärtendenzen des Fundamentalismus sahen. 
Harry Emerson Fosdicks einflußreiche Predigt 1922, "soll die 
Fundamentalisten gewinnen?," verlangt öffnen-gekümmert, einen 
Intellektuellen und ein tolerantes "christliches Stipendium." 
Zwar kostete die Predigt ihm seinen Pfosten New York an der 
ersten presbyterianischen Kirche, stellten seine Ansichten die einer 
einflußreichen protestierenden Minorität dar, und Fosdick genoß 
eine lange Karriere an der Flußufer-Kirche, aufgebaut für ihn von 
John D. Rockefeller. Nach dem Bereichversuch und einem 
gut-publizierten Skandal, die weithin bekannten Pastor Aimee Semple 
McPherson und ein geheimnisvoller Geliebter mit einbeziehen, fingen 
Fundamentalisten an, den Vorsprung zu verlieren, den sie in den 
zwanziger Jahren genossen. Aber frommer Fundamentalismus würde 
eine lebenswichtige politische Kraft in der amerikanischen Lebensdauer
bleiben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Urbain aussi bien que les Américains ruraux 
assemblés aux églises fondamentalistes et évangéliques dans les 
années 20. les protestants "libéraux" ont recherché à 
réconcilier la foi et la science et à ralentir ce qu'ils ont vu 
comme tendances réactionnaires de fondamentalisme. Le sermon 
1922 influent de Harry Emerson Fosdick, " les fondamentalistes gagnent
?," nécessité ouvrir-occupé, un intellectuel, et "une 
camaraderie chrétienne tolérante." Cependant le sermon lui a 
coûté son poteau à la première église presbytérienne de New 
York, ses vues ont représenté ceux d'une minorité protestante 
influente, et Fosdick a apprécié une longue carrière à l'église 
de rive, construite pour lui par John D. Rockefeller. Après 
l'épreuve de portées et un scandale bien-donné de la publicité 
faisant participer le pasteur bien connu Aimee Semple McPherson et un 
amoureux mystérieux, les fondamentalistes ont commencé à détruire 
la proéminence qu'ils ont appréciée dans les années 20. Mais
le fondamentalisme religieux demeurerait une force politique 
essentielle dans la vie américaine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Urbano as.well.as os americanos rurais reunidos às
igrejas fundamentalistas e evangelical nos 1920s. os protestants
"liberais" procuraram reconcile a fé e a ciência e retardar o que 
viram como as tendências reactionary do fundamentalism. O 
sermon 1922 influential de Harry Emerson Fosdick, "deve os 
fundamentalistas ganha?," chamado para abr-ocupado, um 
intelectual, e "um fellowship christian tolerante." Though o 
sermon custou-lhe seu borne na primeira igreja presbyterian de New 
York, suas vistas representaram aquelas de um minority protestant 
influential, e Fosdick apreciou uma carreira longa na igreja do 
riverside, construída para ele por John D. Rockefeller. Depois 
da experimentação dos espaços e de um scandal bem-well-publicized 
que envolvem pastor well-known Aimee Semple McPherson e um amante 
misterioso, os fundamentalistas começaram a perder o prominence que 
apreciaram nos 1920s. Mas o fundamentalism religioso 
remanesceria uma força política vital na vida americana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Urbano così come gli Americani rurali affollati al
fondamentalista ed alle chiese evangelical negli anni 20. i 
protestants "liberali" hanno cercato di riconciliare la fede e la 
scienza e di ritardare che cosa hanno visto come le tendenze 
reactionary del fondamentalismo. Il sermon influente 1922 del 
Harry Emerson Fosdick, "i Fondamentalisti vince?," richiesto 
apr-occupato di, un intellettuale e "un fellowship cristiano 
tollerante." Comunque il sermon gli ha costato il suo alberino 
alla prima chiesa presbyterian de New York, i suoi punti di vista 
hanno rappresentato quelli di una minoranza protestante influente e 
Fosdick ha goduto una carriera lunga alla chiesa della riva del fiume,
costruita per lui da John D. Rockefeller. A seguito della prova 
di portate e di uno scandalo bene-divulg che fanno partecipare il 
pastor ben noto Aimee Semple McPherson e un amante mysterious, i 
fondamentalisti hanno cominciato a perdere la protuberanza che hanno 
goduto negli anni 20. Ma il fondamentalismo religioso rimarrebbe
una forza politica vitale nella vita americana.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αστικοί καθώς επίσης και αγροτικοί Αμερικανοί 
συγκεντρώθηκαν στις θεμελιωτούσες και εβαγγελικές εκκλησίες στη 
δεκαετία του '20. _ "φιλελεύθεροσ" Προτεσταντς επιδιώκω να 
συμφιλιώνω πίστη και επιστήμη και να επιβραδύνω τι αυτός 
βλέπω ως ο αντιδραστικός τάση φονταμενταλισμός. Το 
επιδρόν το 1922 κήρυγμα Harry Emerson Fosdick's, "οι 
φανατικοί οπαδοί θα κερδίσει;," απαιτημένος μια 
απροκατάληπτη, διανοητική, και ανεκτική "χριστιανική υποτροφία." 
Εν τούτοις το κήρυγμα του κόστισε τη θέση του στην πρώτη 
Πρεσβυτεριανή εκκλησία της Νέας Υόρκης, οι όψεις του 
αντιπροσώπευσαν εκείνους μιας επιδρούσας προτεσταντικής 
μειονότητας, και Fosdick απόλαυσε μια μακροχρόνια σταδιοδρομία 
στην εκκλησία όχθεων ποταμού, που χτίστηκε για τον από John 
D. Rockefeller. Μετά από τη δοκιμή πεδίων και ένα 
καλά-κοινοποιημένο σκάνδαλο που περιλαμβάνουν το γνωστό πάστορα 
Aimee Semple McPherson και έναν μυστήριο εραστή, οι 
φανατικοί οπαδοί άρχισαν να χάνουν την προεξοχή που απόλαυσαν 
στη δεκαετία του '20. Αλλά ο θρησκευτικός φονταμενταλισμός 
θα παρέμενε μια ζωτικής σημασίας πολιτική δύναμη στην 
αμερικανική ζωή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Urbano así como los americanos rurales reunidos a 
las iglesias fundamentalistas y evangélicas en los años 20. 
los protestants "liberales" intentaron reconciliar la fe y la 
ciencia y retardarse lo que vieron como las tendencias reaccionarias 
del fundamentalismo. El sermón influyente 1922 de Harry Emerson
Fosdick, " los fundamentalistas gana?," llamado para abrir-haber
importado, un intelectual, y una "beca cristiana tolerante." Sin
embargo el sermón le costó su poste en la primera iglesia 
presbyterian de Nueva York, sus opiniones representaron los de una 
minoría protestante influyente, y Fosdick gozó de una carrera larga 
en la iglesia de la orilla, construida para él por Juan D. 
Rockefeller. Después del ensayo de los alcances y de un 
escándalo bien-publicado que implicaban a pastor bien conocido 
Aimee Semple McPherson y amante misterioso, los fundamentalistas 
comenzaron a perder la prominencia que gozaron en los años 20. 
Pero el fundamentalismo religioso seguiría siendo una fuerza 
política vital en vida americana.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086817</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107171</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/shall-the-fundamentalists-win-defending-liberal-protestantism-in-the-1920s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
