<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105016</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105016</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086401</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Learning on the Piece-Rate Plan": Economist Thorstein Veblen Attacks the Commercialization of Knowledge</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", erlernend auf dem Stück-Kinetik Plan": 
Wirtschaftswissenschaftler Thorstein Veblen nimmt die 
Kommerzialisierung des Wissens in Angriff</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"apprenant sur le plan de Morceau-Cadence" : 
L'économiste Thorstein Veblen attaque la commercialisation de 
la connaissance</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"aprendendo na planta da Parte-Taxa": O 
economista Thorstein Veblen ataca o commercialization do conhecimento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"imparando sul programma di Parte-Tasso": 
L'economista Thorstein Veblen attaca la commercializzazione di 
conoscenza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μαθαίνοντας στο σχέδιο κομμάτι-ποσοστού": Ο 
οικονομολόγος Thorstein Veblen επιτίθεται στην 
εμπορευματοποίηση της γνώσης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"aprendiendo en el plan de la Pedazo-Tarifa": 
El economista Thorstein Veblen ataca la comercialización del 
conocimiento</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The history of American higher education reflects a long struggle between faculty and the business and political interests typically assembled on the governing boards of universities and colleges. By World War I, university and college faculty had become professionalized, governed by organized bodies that set general standards for promotion and tenure as well as for ethical conduct and for accuracy in research and scholarship. Assisted by organizations like the American Association of University Professors (AAUP), faculty had acquired a substantial degree of autonomy and authority over the conduct of their own business. But academics remained subject to both economic and political pressures, pressures that exploded during World War I era loyalty crusades. Thorstein Veblen's 1918 essay "The Higher Learning" accused American academics of capitulating to business. Veblen, a noted economist and social critic, argued that the pursuit of knowledge should answer to higher priorities than the pursuit of money, and that it demanded freedom of expression and thought. In American higher learning, Veblen thought, the interests of politics were so like the interests of business that the two had merged, leaving professors doubly vulnerable to intimidation.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Geschichte der amerikanischen höherer 
Ausbildung reflektiert einen langen Kampf zwischen Lehrkörper und den
Geschäfts- und politischen Interessen, die gewöhnlich auf den 
regelnbrettern der Universitäten und der Hochschulen zusammengebaut 
werden. Durch den Ersten Weltkrieg, war Universitäts- und 
Hochschulfähigkeit professionalized geworden, geregelt durch 
organisierte Körper, die allgemeine Standards für Förderung und 
Besitz sowie für ethische Führung und für Genauigkeit in der 
Forschung und in der Gelehrsamkeit einstellten. Unterstützt 
durch Organisationen mögen Sie die amerikanische Verbindung der 
Universitätsprofessoren (AAUP), Lehrkörper hatte erworben einen 
erheblichen Grad Autonomie und Berechtigung über der Führung ihres 
eigenen Geschäfts. Aber Akademiker geblieben abhängig von 
ökonomischem und politischem Druck, Druck, der während der 
Weltkriegära-Loyalitätkreuzzüge explodierte. Thorstein 
Veblens 1918 Versuch "das höhere Lernen" beschuldigte Amerikaner 
Akademiker vom Kapitulieren zum Geschäft. Veblen, ein 
beachteter Wirtschaftswissenschaftler und Sozialkritiker, 
argumentiert, daß die Verfolgung des Wissens auf höhere Prioritäten
als die Verfolgung des Geldes antworten sollte und daß sie Freiheit 
des Ausdruckes und des Gedankens verlangte. Im amerikanischen 
höheren Lernen waren Veblen Gedanke, die Interessen von Politiken so 
wie die Interessen des Geschäfts, die die zwei gemergt hatten und 
ließen Professoren doppelt verletzbar zur Einschüchterung.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'histoire de l'éducation plus élevée 
américaine reflète une longue lutte entre le corps enseignant et les
intérêts d'affaire et politiques typiquement assemblés sur les 
conseils de direction des universités et des universités. Par 
la Première Guerre Mondiale, la faculté d'université et 
d'université était devenue professionalized, régi par les corps 
organisés qui ont fixé des normes générales pour la promotion et 
la tenure aussi bien que pour la conduite morale et pour l'exactitude 
dans la recherche et la bourse. Aidé par des organismes aimez 
l'association américaine des professeurs d'université (AAUP), corps 
enseignant avait saisi un degré substantiel d'autonomie et 
d'autorité au-dessus de la conduite de leurs propres affaires. 
Mais les universitaires sont restés sujet aux pressions 
économiques et politiques, les pressions qui ont éclaté pendant les
croisades de fidélité d'ère de Première Guerre Mondiale. 
L'essai de Thorstein Veblen 1918 "l'étude plus élevée" accuse
des universitaires américains de la capitulation aux affaires. 
Veblen, un économiste remarquable et critique social, argués 
du fait que la poursuite de la connaissance devrait répondre à des 
priorités plus élevées que la poursuite de l'argent, et qu'elle a 
exigé la liberté d'expression et de pensée. Dans l'étude 
plus élevée américaine, la pensée de Veblen, les intérêts de la 
politique étaient ainsi comme les intérêts des affaires que les 
deux avaient fusionnés, laissant des professeurs doublement 
vulnérables à l'intimidation.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O history da instrução mais elevada americana 
reflete um esforço longo entre a faculdade e os interesses do 
negócio e os políticos montados tipicamente nas placas governando 
das universidades e das faculdades. Pelo world.war.i, a 
faculdade da universidade e da faculdade tinha-se tornado 
professionalized, governado pelos corpos organizados que ajustaram 
padrões gerais para o promotion e o tenure as.well.as para a conduta 
ética e para a exatidão na pesquisa e no scholarship. Ajudado 
por organizações goste da associação americana dos professores da 
universidade (AAUP), faculdade tinha adquirido um grau substancial de 
autonomia e de autoridade sobre a conduta de seu próprio negócio. 
Mas o academics remanesceu sujeito  às pressões econômicas e 
políticas, as pressões que explodiram durante crusades da lealdade 
da era do world.war.i. O essay de Thorstein Veblen 1918 "a 
aprendizagem mais elevada" acusa o academics americano de capitulating
ao negócio. Veblen, um economista notável e crítico social, 
discutidos que a perseguição do conhecimento deve responder a umas 
prioridades mais elevadas do que a perseguição do dinheiro, e que 
exijiu a liberdade da expressão e do pensamento. Na 
aprendizagem mais elevada americana, o pensamento de Veblen, os 
interesses da política era assim como os interesses do negócio que 
os dois tinham fundido, deixando professores dobro vulneráveis à 
intimidação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La storia di istruzione superiore americana 
riflette una lotta lunga fra la facoltà e gli interessi politici e di
affare montati tipicamente sui bordi governanti delle 
università e delle università. Dal world.war.i, la facoltà 
dell'università e dell'università era diventato professionalized, 
governato dagli enti organizzati che hanno regolato gli standard 
generali per la promozione ed il possesso così come per comportamento
etico e per esattezza nella ricerca e nella borsa. Aiutato dalle
organizzazioni gradisca l'associazione americana dei professori 
dell'università (AAUP), facoltà aveva acquistato un grado notevole 
di autonomia e di autorità sopra il comportamento del loro proprio 
commercio. Ma il academics è rimasto conforme sia alle 
pressioni economiche che politiche, pressioni che hanno esploso 
durante i crusades di lealtà di era di world.war.i. Il saggio 
di Thorstein Veblen 1918 "più alto imparare" accusa il academics 
americano di capitulating al commercio. Veblen, un economista 
celebre e critico sociale, sostenuti che l'inseguimento di conoscenza 
dovrebbe rispondere a alle nette priorità che l'inseguimento di soldi
e che ha richiesto la libertà dell'espressione e del pensiero. 
Nell'più alto imparare americano, il pensiero di Veblen, gli 
interessi delle politiche era così come gli interessi del commercio 
che i due avevano fuso, lascianti i professori doppiamente vulnerabili
all'intimidazione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιστορία της αμερικανικής τριτοβάθμιας εκπαίδευσης 
απεικονίζει μια μακροχρόνια προσπάθεια μεταξύ της σχολής και των 
πολιτικών ενδιαφερόντων επιχειρήσεων και που συγκεντρώνονται 
χαρακτηριστικά στα κυβερνητικά συμβούλια των πανεπιστημίων και των
κολλεγίων. Από τον παγκόσμιο πόλεμο Ι, το πανεπιστήμιο και 
η σχολή κολλεγίων είχαν γίνει, κυβερνημένος από τους 
οργανωμένους οργανισμούς που καθόρισαν τα γενικά πρότυπα για την 
προώθηση και τη διάρκεια αξιώματος καθώς επίσης και για την 
ηθική συμπεριφορά και για την ακρίβεια στην έρευνα και την 
υποτροφία. Βοηθημένη από τις οργανώσεις όπως την 
αμερικανική ένωση των πανεπιστημιακών καθηγητών (AAUP), η 
σχολή είχε αποκτήσει έναν ουσιαστικό βαθμό αυτονομίας και 
αρχής πέρα από τη συμπεριφορά της επιχείρησής τους. Αλλά 
οι ακαδημαϊκοί παρέμειναν υπαγόμενοι και στις οικονομικές και 
πολιτικές πιέσεις, πιέσεις που εξερράγησαν κατά τη διάρκεια του 
παγκόσμιου πολέμου Ι τις σταυροφορίες πίστης εποχής. Το 
1918 Veblen Thorstein δοκιμάζει "τους υψηλότερους 
μαθαίνοντασ" κατηγορούμενους αμερικανικούς ακαδημαϊκούς της 
συνθηκολόγησης στην επιχείρηση. Το Veblen, ένας 
σημειωμένος οικονομολόγος και ένας κοινωνικός κριτικός, 
υποστήριξαν ότι η αναζήτηση της γνώσης πρέπει να απαντήσει στις 
πιό υψηλές προτεραιότητες από την αναζήτηση των χρημάτων, και 
ότι απαίτησε την ελευθερία της έκφρασης και της σκέψης. 
Στην αμερικανική υψηλότερη εκμάθηση, σκέψη Veblen, τα 
ενδιαφέροντα της πολιτικής ήταν έτσι όπως τα ενδιαφέροντα της 
επιχείρησης που τα δύο είχαν συγχωνεύσει, αφήνοντας τους 
καθηγητές διπλά τρωτούς στον εκφοβισμό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La historia de la educación más alta americana 
refleja una lucha larga entre la facultad y los intereses del negocio 
y políticos ensamblados típicamente en las tarjetas que gobiernan de
universidades y de universidades. Por Primera Guerra Mundial, la
facultad de la universidad y de la universidad se había convertido 
professionalized, gobernado por los cuerpos ordenados que fijaron los 
estándares generales para la promoción y el arrendamiento así como 
para conducta ética y para la exactitud en la investigación y la 
beca. Asistido por organizaciones tenga gusto de la asociación 
americana de los profesores de la universidad (AAUP), facultad había 
adquirido un grado substancial de autonomía y de autoridad sobre la 
conducta de su propio negocio. Pero el académico permanecía 
conforme a las presiones económicas y políticas, las presiones que 
estallaron durante cruzadas de la lealtad de la era de la Primera 
Guerra Mundial. El ensayo de Thorstein Veblen 1918 "el aprender 
más alto" acusa el académico americano de la capitulación al 
negocio. Veblen, un economista conocido y crítico social, 
discutidos que la búsqueda del conocimiento debe contestar a 
prioridades más altas que la búsqueda del dinero, y que exigió la 
libertad de la expresión y del pensamiento. En aprender más 
alto americano, el pensamiento de Veblen, los intereses de políticas 
era tan como los intereses del negocio que los dos habían combinado, 
dejando profesores doble vulnerables a la intimidación.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086401</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105016</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/learning-on-the-piece-rate-plan-economist-thorstein-veblen-attacks-the-commercialization-of-knowledge</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
