<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107275</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107275</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201892</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">European Rulers of the 1st Millennium AD</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Europäische Tabellierprogramme der 1. Jahrtausend
ANZEIGE</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Grilles de tabulation européennes de la 1ère 
ANNONCE de millénium</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Réguas européias do 1o ANÚNCIO do millennium</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Righelli europei del primo ANNUNCIO di millennio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ευρωπαϊκοί κυβερνήτες της ΑΓΓΕΛΙΑΣ της 1$ης χιλιετίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Reglas europeas del 1r ANUNCIO del milenio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is a gapfill quiz. The idea behind the quiz is to help a player acquire an overview of European history through looking at some of the leaders that have shaped Europe's history. The project is far from complete and so far only includes leaders up to the tenth century. Anyone who wishes to edit this quiz is free to do so. The information about the leaders has largely come from wikipedia. All I have done is cut and paste the page then edit it down to an even briefer description of the leader's life, and then chosen words from the description to use for the gapfill.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist ein gapfill Quiz. Die Idee hinter
dem Quiz ist, einem Spieler zu helfen, einen Überblick über 
europäische Geschichte durch das Betrachten einige der Führer zu 
erwerben, die Geschichte Europas geformt haben. Das Projekt ist 
weit von komplettes und enthält bis jetzt nur Führer bis zum zehnten
Jahrhundert. Jedermann, das diesen Quiz bearbeiten möchte, ist 
frei, so zu tun. Die Informationen über die Führer sind groß 
vom wikipedia gekommen. Aller, den ich getan habe, ist Schnitt 
und Paste die Seite bearbeiten dann sie unten zu einer sogar kürzeren
Beschreibung der Lebensdauer des Führers und dann gewählte Wörter 
von der Beschreibung, um für das gapfill zu verwenden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est un jeu de gapfill. L'idée derrière 
le jeu est d'aider un joueur à saisir une vue d'ensemble de 
l'histoire européenne en regardant certaines des amorces qui ont 
formé l'histoire de l'Europe. Le projet est loin de complet et 
inclut jusqu'ici seulement des amorces jusqu'au dixième siècle. 
N'importe qui qui souhaite éditer ce jeu est libre pour faire 
ainsi. Les informations sur les amorces sont en grande partie 
venues du wikipedia. Tout que j'ai fait est découpage et le 
déplacement la page éditent alors elle vers le bas à une 
description encore plus courte de la vie de l'amorce, et des mots 
alors choisis de la description pour utiliser pour le gapfill.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este é um quiz do gapfill. A idéia atrás 
do quiz é ajudar a um jogador adquirir uma vista geral do history 
europeu com olhar alguns dos líderes que deram forma ao history de 
Europa. O projeto é longe de completo e inclui assim distante 
somente líderes até o décimo século. Qualquer um que deseja 
editar este quiz está livre fazer assim. A informação sobre 
os líderes veio pela maior parte do wikipedia. Tudo que eu fiz 
é corte e a pasta a página edita então a para baixo a uma 
descrição mesmo mais breve da vida do líder, e palavras então 
escolhidas da descrição para usar-se para o gapfill.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è un quiz del gapfill. L'idea dietro 
il quiz è aiutare un giocatore ad acquistare una descrizione di 
storia europea through guardando alcuni dei capi che hanno 
modellato la storia dell'Europa. Il progetto è lontano da 
completo e finora soltanto include i capi fino al decimo 
secolo. Chiunque che desideri stampare questo quiz è libero 
fare così. Le informazioni sui capi in gran parte sono 
venuto dal wikipedia. Tutto che abbia fatto è taglio e la colla
la pagina allora stampa esso giù ad una descrizione ancora più 
sommaria della vita del capo e le parole allora scelte dalla 
descrizione per usare per il gapfill.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι ένας διαγωνισμός γνώσεων gapfill. 
Η ιδέα πίσω από το διαγωνισμό γνώσεων είναι να ενισχυθεί 
ένας φορέας να αποκτήσει μια επισκόπηση της ευρωπαϊκής ιστορίας
μέσω της εξέτασης μερικούς από τους ηγέτες που έχουν 
διαμορφώσει την ιστορία της Ευρώπης. Το πρόγραμμα είναι 
μακριά από πλήρη και μέχρι τώρα μόνο περιλαμβάνει τους ηγέτες 
μέχρι το δέκατο αιώνα. Καθένας που επιθυμεί να επιμεληθεί 
αυτόν τον διαγωνισμό γνώσεων είναι ελεύθερος να κάνει έτσι. 
Οι πληροφορίες για τους ηγέτες έχουν προέλθει κατά ένα 
μεγάλο μέρος από το wikipedia. Όλος έχω κάνει είμαι 
cut-$l*and-$l*paste η σελίδα κατόπιν επιμελούμαι το κάτω σε μια
ακόμα συνοπτικότερη περιγραφή της ζωής του ηγέτη, και τις έπειτα
επιλεγμένες λέξεις από την περιγραφή που χρησιμοποιεί για το 
gapfill.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esto es un concurso del gapfill. La idea 
detrás del concurso es ayudar a un jugador a adquirir una 
descripción de la historia europea con mirar a algunos de los 
arranques de cinta que han formado la historia de Europa. El 
proyecto está lejos de completo e incluye hasta ahora solamente a 
arranques de cinta hasta el décimo siglo. Cualquier persona que
desea corregir este concurso está libre hacer tan. La 
información sobre los arranques de cinta ha venido en gran parte de 
wikipedia. Todo lo que he hecho es corte y la goma la 
paginación entonces corrige la abajo a una descripción incluso más 
abreviada de la vida del arranque de cinta, y palabras entonces 
elegidas de la descripción para utilizar para el gapfill.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GARETH LEE
FN:GARETH LEE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201892</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107275</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/european-rulers-of-the-1st-millennium-ad</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
