<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/172881187</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>172881187</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209974</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Energy Technology</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Energie-Technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Technologie D'Énergie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tecnologia Da Energia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tecnologia Di Energia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ενεργειακή τεχνολογία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tecnología De la Energía</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This course looks at all forms that energy exists. It explains how energy is used in: transport, agriculture, industry, commerce and households. It describes how energy is stored using storage systems such as: battery, flywheels, compressed air, chemical energy systems and pumped storage. This course explains the problem of depletion of energy resources. It describes the environmental damage associated with the use of fossil fuels, acid rains, dangers posed by leaded fuels, oil spills, gas leaks and explosions, water pollution caused by poorly managed coal mines, and air pollution. It describes the environmental damage associated with the use of fuelwood, uranium, hydro-power plants and wind. It also explains possible solutions to the energy-related problems. </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser Kurs betrachtet alle Formulare, daß 
Energie existiert. Erklärt er, wie Energie in verwendet wird: 
Transport, Landwirtschaft, Industrie, Handel und Haushalte. 
Beschreibt er, wie Energie mit Speichersystemen wie gespeichert 
wird: Batterie, Schwungräder, komprimierte Luft, Systeme der 
chemischen Energie und gepumpte Speicherung. Dieser Kurs 
erklärt das Problem Entleerung der Energiebetriebsmittel. Er 
beschreibt die Klimabeschädigung, die mit dem Gebrauch von 
Fossilbrennstoffen, saure Regen, die Gefahren verbunden ist, die durch
verbleite Kraftstoffe aufgeworfen werden, Öl verschüttet.wird, 
Gasleckstellen und -explosionen, die Wasserverunreinigung, die durch 
schlecht gehandhabte Kohlengruben verursacht werden, und 
Luftverschmutzung. Er beschreibt die Klimabeschädigung, die mit
dem Gebrauch des Brennholzes, des Urans, der Hydro-powerbetriebe und 
des Winds verbunden ist. Er erklärt auch mögliche Lösungen 
den energiebezogenen Problemen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce cours regarde toutes les formes que l'énergie 
existe. Il explique dans comment de l'énergie est utilisée : 
transport, agriculture, industrie, commerce et ménages. 
Il décrit tels que comment de l'énergie est enregistrée en 
utilisant des systèmes de mémoire : batterie, volants, air 
comprimé, systèmes d'énergie chimique et mémoire pompée. Ce
cours explique le problème de l'épuisement des ressources 
énergétiques. Il décrit les dommages environnementaux liés 
à l'utilisation des combustibles fossiles, pluies acides, dangers 
posés par les carburants plombés, huile se renverse, fuite et 
explosions de gaz, pollution de l'eau provoquée par les mines de 
houille mal contrôlées, et pollution atmosphérique. Il 
décrit les dommages environnementaux liés à l'utilisation du bois 
de chauffage, de l'uranium, des usines d'hydro-électricité et du 
vent. Il explique également les solutions possibles aux 
problèmes énergétiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este curso olha todos os formulários que a 
energia existe. Explica em como a energia é usada: 
transporte, agricultura, indústria, comércio e casas. 
Descreve como a energia é armazenada usando sistemas do 
armazenamento tais como: bateria, volantes, ar comprimido, 
sistemas de energia química e armazenamento bombeado. Este 
curso explica o problema do depletion de recursos de energia. 
Descreve os danos ambientais associados com o uso de 
combustíveis fossil, chuvas ácidas, perigos posed por combustíveis 
leaded, óleo derrama, escape e explosões do gás, poluição da 
água causada por minas de carvão deficientemente controladas, e 
poluição de ar. Descreve os danos ambientais associados com o 
uso do fuelwood, do urânio, das plantas do hydro-power e do vento. 
Explica também soluções possíveis aos problemas 
energy-related.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo corso guarda tutte le forme che l'energia 
esiste. Spiega come l'energia è usata in: trasporto, 
agricoltura, industria, commercio e famiglie. Descrive come 
l'energia è memorizzata usando i sistemi di memorizzazione come: 
batteria, volani, aria appiattita, sistemi energetici chimici e 
memoria pompata. Questo corso spiega il problema di svuotamento 
delle risorse energetiche. Descrive danni ambientali connessi 
con l'uso dei combustibili fossili, pioggie acide, pericoli proposti 
dai combustibili al piombo, olio si rovescia, perdite ed esplosioni 
del gas, inquinamento dell'acqua causato dalle miniere di carbone male
gestite ed inquinamento atmosferico. Descrive danni ambientali 
connessi con l'uso di legna, di uranio, delle piante di idropotenza e 
del vento. Egualmente spiega le soluzioni possibili ai problemi 
energetici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων εξετάζει όλες τις μορφές ότι
η ενέργεια υπάρχει. Εξηγεί πώς η ενέργεια χρησιμοποιείται 
σε: μεταφορά, γεωργία, βιομηχανία, εμπόριο και οικογένειες.
Περιγράφει πώς η ενέργεια καταχωρείται χρησιμοποιώντας τα 
συστήματα αποθήκευσης όπως: μπαταρία, σφόνδυλοι, 
συμπιεσμένος αέρας, χημικά ενεργειακά συστήματα και αντλημένη 
αποθήκευση. Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων εξηγεί το πρόβλημα της 
μείωσης των ενεργειακών στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς. Περιγράφει 
την περιβαλλοντική ζημία που συνδέεται με τη χρήση των 
απολιθωμένων καυσίμων, όξινες βροχές, κίνδυνοι που τίθενται από
τα μολυβδούχα καύσιμα, διαρροές πετρελαίου, διαρρέει αέριο 
και εκρήξεις, ρύπανση των υδάτων που προκαλούνται από τα κακώς 
διοικούμενα ορυχεία άνθρακα, και ατμοσφαιρική ρύπανση. 
Περιγράφει την περιβαλλοντική ζημία που συνδέεται με τη 
χρήση των καυσόξυλων, του ουράνιου, των εγκαταστάσεων 
υδρενέργειας και του αέρα. Εξηγεί επίσης τις πιθανές 
λύσεις στα σχετικά με την ενέργεια προβλήματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este curso mira todas las formas que existe la 
energía. Explica en cómo la energía se utiliza: 
transporte, agricultura, industria, comercio y casas. 
Describe tales como cómo se salva la energía usando sistemas 
del almacenaje: batería, ruedas volantes, aire comprimido, 
sistemas de energía química y almacenaje bombeado. Este curso 
explica el problema del agotamiento de los recursos energéticos. 
Describe el daño ambiental asociado al uso de los combustibles 
fósiles, lluvias ácidas, peligros planteados por los combustibles 
plomados, aceite se derrama, los escapes y las explosiones del gas, 
contaminación del agua causada por las minas de carbón mal 
manejadas, y contaminación atmosférica. Describe el daño 
ambiental asociado al uso de la leña, del uranio, de las plantas de 
la hidroelectricidad y del viento. También explica soluciones 
posibles a los problemas energéticos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209974</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>172881187</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/energy-technology</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
