<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104546</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104546</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205318</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">You Decide: Should the US adopt a single-payer, Universal Health Care Plan?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sie Entscheiden: Sollten die US einen 
EinzelnSingle-payer, Universalgesundheitspflege-Plan annehmen?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vous Décidez : Les USA devraient-ils 
adopter un simple-débiteur, plan universel de santé ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Você Decide-se: Devem os E. U. adotar um 
único-single-payer, planta universal do cuidado de saúde?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Decidete: Dovrebbero gli Stati Uniti 
adottare un singolo-debitore, programma universale di sanità?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αποφασίζετε: Θα έπρεπε οι ΗΠΑ να υιοθετήσουν 
έναν ενιαίος-πληρωτή, καθολικό σχέδιο υγειονομικής περίθαλψης;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Usted Decide: ¿Deben los E.E.U.U. adoptar a 
un solo-pagador, plan universal del cuidado médico?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This educational guide focuses on health care issues in the US and whether or not it would be beneficial to adopt a single-payer, universal health care plan. Students are invited to examine the arguments on both sides of the debate, developing critical thinking skills as they work through the activities. Students will learn how to support their arguments with evidence and reason. It is expected that at the end of this guide students will determine where they stand on this controversial issue.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese pädagogische Anleitung konzentriert auf 
Gesundheitspflegeausgaben in den US und ob oder nicht ihn vorteilhaft 
seien Sie, einen EinzelnSingle-payer anzunehmen, Universalim 
gesundheitspflegeplan. Kursteilnehmer werden eingeladen, die 
Argumente auf beiden Seiten der Debatte zu überprüfen und entwickeln
kritische denkende Fähigkeiten, während sie durch die Aktivitäten 
arbeiten. Kursteilnehmer erlernen, wie man ihre Argumente mit 
Beweis und Grund unterstützt. Es wird erwartet, daß am Ende 
dieser Anleitung Kursteilnehmer feststellen, wo sie zu diesem 
umstrittenen Punkt stehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce guide éducatif se concentre sur des questions de 
santé aux USA et si eux soyez salutaire pour adopter un 
simple-débiteur, le plan universel de santé. Des étudiants 
sont invités à examiner les arguments des deux côtés de la 
discussion, développant des qualifications de pensée critiques 
pendant qu'ils travaillent par les activités. Les étudiants 
apprendront comment supporter leurs arguments avec l'évidence et la 
raison. On s'attend à ce qu'à l'extrémité de ce guide les 
étudiants déterminent où ils se tiennent sur cette question 
controversée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta guia educacional focaliza em edições do cuidado de 
saúde nos E. U. e se ou não eles seja benéfico adotar um 
único-single-payer, na planta universal do cuidado de saúde. 
Os estudantes estão convidados examinar os argumentos em ambos 
os lados do debate, desenvolvendo habilidades pensando críticas 
enquanto trabalham com as atividades. Os estudantes aprenderão 
como suportar seus argumentos com evidência e razão. Espera-se
que na extremidade desta guia os estudantes determinarão onde estão 
nesta edição controversa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa guida educativa mette a fuoco sulle edizioni di 
sanità negli Stati Uniti e se o non esso sia favorevole da adottare 
un singolo-debitore, il programma universale di sanità. Gli 
allievi sono invitati ad esaminare gli argomenti da entrambi i lati 
del dibattito, sviluppanti le abilità pensanti critiche mentre 
lavorano con le attività. Gli allievi impareranno come 
sostenere i loro argomenti con prova e motivo. È previsto che 
all'estremità di questa guida allievi determinino dove si levano in 
piedi su questa edizione discutibile.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο εκπαιδευτικός οδηγός εστιάζει στα ζητήματα 
υγειονομικής περίθαλψης στις ΗΠΑ και εάν θα ήταν ή όχι 
ευεργετικό να υιοθετηθεί ένας ενιαίος-πληρωτής, καθολικό σχέδιο
υγειονομικής περίθαλψης. Οι σπουδαστές καλούνται για να 
εξετάσουν τα ορίσματα και στις δύο πλευρές της συζήτησης, που 
αναπτύσσει τις κρίσιμες δεξιότητες σκέψης όπως λειτουργούν μέσω
των δραστηριοτήτων. Οι σπουδαστές θα μάθουν πώς να 
υποστηρίξουν τα ορίσματά τους με τα στοιχεία και το λόγο. 
Αναμένεται ότι στο τέλος αυτού του οδηγού οι σπουδαστές θα
καθορίσουν όπου στέκονται σε αυτό το αμφισβητούμενο ζήτημα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta guía educativa se centra en ediciones del cuidado 
médico en los E.E.U.U. y si o no ellos sea beneficioso adoptar a un 
solo-pagador, el plan universal del cuidado médico. Se invita a
los estudiantes que examinen los argumentos en ambas caras del 
discusión, desarrollando habilidades de pensamiento críticas 
mientras que trabajan con las actividades. Los estudiantes 
aprenderán cómo utilizar sus argumentos con evidencia y razón. 
Se espera que en el extremo de esta guía los estudiantes se 
determinen dónde están parados en esta edición polémica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205318</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104546</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/you-decide-should-the-us-adopt-a-single-payer-universal-health-care-plan</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
