<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105601</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105601</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205817</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Ragtime</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ragtime</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ragtime</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ragtime</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ragtime</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εήδος μουσικής τζαζ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ragtime</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents sheet music, essays, and video and sound clips related to ragtime. This distinctly American music appeared (in its published form) during the mid-1890s mainly in the South and Midwest, spread across the U.S. and to Europe, and influenced early jazz styles. Learn about Scott Joplin, one of the best known ragtime players. Hear segments of his classic Maple Leaf Rag, which helped spread the ragtime craze. See more than 100 pieces of sheet music.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschenke bedecken Musik, Versuche und die 
Bildschirm- und Tonclips, die auf ragtime in Verbindung gestanden 
werden. Diese deutlich amerikanische Musik erschien (in seiner 
erschienenen Form) während des mid-1890s hauptsächlich im Süden und
im Mittelwesten, Verbreitung über den VEREINIGTEN STAATEN und zu 
Europa und beeinflußte frühe Jazzarten. Erlernen Sie über 
Scott Joplin, einer der besten bekannten ragtime Spieler. Hören
Sie Segmente seines klassischen Ahornholz-Blatt-Lappens, die halfen, 
den ragtime Verrücktheit zu verbreiten. Sehen Sie mehr als 100 
Stücke Blattmusik.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les présents couvrent la musique, les essais, et 
les clips de vidéo et de bruit liés au ragtime. Cette musique 
distinctement américaine est apparue (sous son forme éditée) 
pendant le mid-1890s principalement dans les Sud et le 
Midwest, diffusion à travers les ETATS-UNIS et vers l'Europe, et a 
influencé des modèles tôt de jazz. Renseignez-vous sur 
Scott Joplin, un des meilleurs joueurs connus de ragtime. 
Entendez les segments de son chiffon classique de feuille de 
érable, qui ont aidé à écarter la manie de ragtime. Voir les
plus de 100 morceaux de musique de feuille.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os presentes sheet a música, os essays, e os 
grampos do vídeo e do som relacionados ao ragtime. Esta música
distintamente americana apareceu (em seu formulário publicado) 
durante o mid-1890s principalmente no sul e no Midwest, propagação 
através dos ESTADOS UNIDOS e a Europa, e influenciou estilos 
adiantados do jazz. Aprenda sobre Scott Joplin, um dos mais 
melhores jogadores conhecidos do ragtime. Ouça os segmentos de 
seu pano clássico da folha do bordo, que ajudaram espalhar a mania do
ragtime. Veja mais de 100 partes de música da folha.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">i presenti rivestono la musica, i saggi e le clip 
del suono e del video relative a ragtime. Questa musica 
distintamente americana è comparso (nella relativa forma pubblicata) 
durante il mid-1890s pricipalmente nel sud e nel Midwest, diffusione 
attraverso gli STATI UNITI e ad Europa ed ha influenzato gli stili 
iniziali di jazz. Impari circa Scott Joplin, uno dei giocatori 
del ragtime conosciuti migliori. Senta i segmenti del suo panno 
classico del foglio dell'acero, che hanno contribuito a spargere la 
mania del ragtime. Veda più di 100 parti di musica del foglio.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τη μουσική φύλλων, τα δοκίμια, και τους 
τηλεοπτικούς και υγιείς συνδετήρες σχετικούς με το εήδο μουσικής
τζαζ. Αυτή η ευδιάκριτα αμερικανική μουσική εμφανίστηκε (με
δημοσιευμένη μορφή του) κατά τη διάρκεια τα μέσα της 1890s 
κυρίως στο νότο και midwest, διέδωσε στις ΗΠΑ και στην Ευρώπη, 
και επηρέασε τις πρόωρες μορφές τζαζ. Μάθετε για Scott 
Joplin, ένας από τους καλύτερα γνωστούς φορείς εήδων 
μουσικής τζαζ. Ακούστε τα τμήματα μνήμης του κλασικού 
κουρελιού φύλλων σφενδάμνου του, το οποίο βοήθησε να διαδώσει 
την τρέλα εήδων μουσικής τζαζ. Δείτε περισσότερα 
από 100 κομμάτια της μουσικής φύλλων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los presentes cubren música, ensayos, y los clips
del vídeo y del sonido relacionados con el ragtime. Esta 
música distintamente americana apareció (en su forma publicada) 
durante el mid-1890s principalmente en el sur y el Cercano oeste, 
extensión a través de los ESTADOS UNIDOS y a Europa, e influenció 
estilos tempranos del jazz. Aprenda sobre Scott Joplin, uno de 
los mejores jugadores conocidos del ragtime. Oiga los segmentos 
de su trapo clásico de la hoja del arce, que ayudaron a separar la 
manía del ragtime. Vea más de 100 pedazos de música de la 
hoja.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205817</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105601</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/ragtime-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
