<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103824</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103824</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202640</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Pliny and the Eruption of Mt. Vesuvius</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Pliny und die Eruption von Millitorr Vesuvius</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pliny et l'éruption du millitorr Vesuvius</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pliny e o eruption de Mt. Vesuvius</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Pliny ed il eruption del Mt. Vesuvius</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πλίνιος και η έκρηξη του όρους Βεζούβιος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Pliny y la erupción de Mt. Vesuvius</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The purpose of this lesson is to use earth science concepts--from volcanology--to explain to students studying the letter of Pliny the Younger to the historian Tacitus how Mt. Vesuvius erupted in AD 79. Students will study and demonstrate mastery of the eruption and its historical impact through a webquest on Pompeii, reading of an articles with appropriate content-area reading support, participation in interactive lecture, writing of a journal entry about life in Pompeii at the time of the eruption, oral presentations on life in Pompeii, reviewing of the grammatical functions of all tenses of participles, and using a rubric to evaluate a video on Pompeii to be used for instruction.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Zweck dieser Lektion ist, 
Geowissenschaftkonzepte zu verwenden -- vom volcanology -- um den 
Kursteilnehmern zu erklären, die das Zeichen von Pliny das jüngere 
zum Historiker Tacitus studieren, wie Millitorr Vesuvius in ANZEIGE 79
ausbrach. Kursteilnehmer studieren und demonstrieren 
Beherrschung der Eruption und seiner historischen Auswirkung durch ein
webquest auf Pompeji, Ablesen von Artikel mit passendem Inhalt-Bereich
Lesesupport, Teilnahme am interaktiven Vortrag, Schreiben eines 
Journaleintrags über das Leben in Pompeji zu der Zeit der Eruption, 
Munddarstellungen auf dem Leben in Pompeji, dem Wiederholen der 
grammatischen Funktionen aller Tempora Partizipien und dem Verwenden 
einer Rubrik, um einen Bildschirm auf für Anweisung verwendet zu 
werden Pompeji auszuwerten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but de cette leçon est d'employer des concepts
de science de la terre -- du volcanology -- pour expliquer aux 
étudiants étudiant la lettre de Pliny le plus jeune à l'historien 
Tacitus comment le millitorr Vesuvius a éclaté dans l'ANNONCE 79. 
Les étudiants étudieront et démontreront la maîtrise de 
l'éruption et de son impact historique par un webquest sur Pompeii, 
lecture de l'des articles avec le support approprié de lecture de 
contenu-zone, la participation à la conférence interactive, 
l'écriture d'une écriture comptable au sujet de la vie à Pompeii au
moment de l'éruption, les présentations orales la vie à Pompeii, 
passer en revue des fonctions grammaticales de tous les temps des 
participes, et employer une rubrique pour évaluer un vidéo sur 
Pompeii à utiliser pour l'instruction.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A finalidade desta lição é usar conceitos da 
ciência de terra -- do volcanology -- explicar aos estudantes que 
estudam a letra de Pliny o mais novo ao historian Tacitus como o Mt. 
Vesuvius erupted no ANÚNCIO 79. Os estudantes estudarão e 
demonstrarão o mastery do eruption e de seu impacto histórico com um
o mais webquest em Pompeii, leitura do artigos com sustentação 
apropriada da leitura da índice-área, participação no lecture 
interativo, escrita de uma entrada de jornal sobre a vida em Pompeii 
na altura do eruption, apresentações orais na vida em Pompeii, rever
das funções gramaticais de todos os tempos dos participles, e usar 
um rubric avaliar um vídeo em Pompeii a ser usado para a instrução.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Lo scopo di questa lezione è usare i concetti di 
scienze della terra -- dal volcanology -- per spiegare agli allievi 
che studiano la lettera di Pliny il più giovane allo storico Tacitus 
come il Mt. Vesuvius ha scoppiato in ANNUNCIO 79. Gli 
allievi studeranno e dimostreranno la padronanza del eruption e del 
relativo effetto storico con un più webquest su Pompeii, lettura 
dell'articoli con il supporto adatto della lettura di soddisfare-zona,
la partecipazione alla conferenza interattiva, la scrittura di 
un'entrata di giornale circa vita a Pompeii ai tempi del eruption, le 
presentazioni orali sulla vita a Pompeii, la riesaminazione delle 
funzioni grammaticali di tutti i tempi dei participi ed usando una 
rubrica per esaminare un video su Pompeii da usare per istruzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο σκοπός αυτού του μαθήματος είναι να χρησιμοποιηθούν
γήινη επιστήμη οι έννοιες -- από την ηφαιστειολογία -- που 
εξηγούν στους σπουδαστές που μελετούν την επιστολή του Πλίνιου 
στον ιστορικό Τάκιτος πώς το όρος Βεζούβιος εξερράγη στους 
σπουδαστές ΑΓΓΕΛΙΏΝ 79. θα μελετήσει και θα καταδείξει την 
κυριότητα της έκρηξης και του ιστορικού αντίκτυπού του μέσω 
ενός pjo' ωεψquεστ στην Πομπηία, ανάγνωση άρθρα με την 
κατάλληλη υποστήριξη ανάγνωσης ικανοποιημένος-περιοχής, τη 
συμμετοχή στη διαλογική διάλεξη, το γράψιμο μιας εισόδου 
περιοδικών για τη ζωή στην Πομπηία κατά την διάρκεια της 
έκρηξης, προφορικές παρουσιάσεις στη ζωή στην Πομπηία, την 
αναθεώρηση των γραμματικών λειτουργιών όλων των χρόνων των 
μετοχών, και τη χρησιμοποίηση μιας ρουμπρίκας για να αξιολογήσει 
ένα βίντεο στην Πομπηία που χρησιμοποιείται για την οδηγία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El propósito de esta lección es utilizar 
conceptos de la geología -- de volcanology -- para explicar a los 
estudiantes que estudian la carta de Pliny el más joven al 
historiador Tacitus cómo el Mt. Vesuvius entró en erupción en el 
ANUNCIO 79. Los estudiantes estudiarán y demostrarán la 
maestría de la erupción y de su impacto histórico con un la ma's 
webquest en Pompeii, lectura de los artículos con la ayuda apropiada 
de la lectura del contenido-a'rea, la participación en conferencia 
interactiva, la escritura de una entrada de diario sobre vida en 
Pompeii a la hora de la erupción, presentaciones orales el vida en 
Pompeii, el repaso de las funciones gramaticales de todos los tiempos 
de participios, y usar una rúbrica para evaluar un vídeo en Pompeii 
que se utilizará para la instrucción.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GREGORY KING-OWEN
FN:GREGORY KING-OWEN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202640</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103824</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/pliny-and-the-eruption-of-mt-vesuvius</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
