<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107668</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107668</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087354</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"A Youngster Needs a Knowledge of the Present": A Popular Magazine Urges Tolerance for the Distractions of Youth</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"ein Knabe benötigt ein Wissen des 
Geschenkes": Eine populäre Zeitschrift drängt auf Toleranz 
für die Ablenkungen von Jugend</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"un jeune a besoin d'une connaissance du présent"
: Un magasin populaire pousse la tolérance pour les 
distractions de la jeunesse</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"um jovem necessita um conhecimento do presente": 
Um compartimento popular incita a tolerância para os 
distractions da juventude</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"un giovanotto ha bisogno di una conoscenza del 
presente": Uno scomparto popolare sollecita la tolleranza per le
distrazioni della gioventù</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ένας νεαρός χρειάζεται γνώση του παρόντοσ": 
Ένα δημοφιλές περιοδικό ωθεί την ανοχή για τις αποσπάσεις 
της προσοχής της νεολαίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"un joven necesita un conocimiento del presente": 
Un compartimiento popular impulsa la tolerancia para las 
distracciones de la juventud</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In the 1950s, parents, educators, religious leaders, and moralists expressed intense concern over the perceived harmful effects of modern life on the nation's youth. This concern was not new, however. Fears of corrupting influences on youth have periodically flooded the public discourse, from child-rearing tomes of the antebellum period to congressional hearings in the 1950s on media and juvenile delinquency. The following editorial from 1950, in the popular magazine Collier's, offered one perspective on the potential harm of such youthful indiscretions as radio programs, phonograph records, Western movies, and comic books and advocated tolerance for youth-oriented popular culture.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In den fünfziger Jahren drückten Eltern, 
Erzieher, fromme Führer und Moralisten intensiven Interesse 
Überschuß die wahrgenommenen schädlichen Effekte der modernen 
Lebensdauer auf der Jugend der Nation aus. Dieses Interesse war 
nicht, jedoch neu. Furcht vor Verderbeneinflüssen auf Jugend 
hat regelmäßig die allgemeine Darlegung, von Kind-aufrichtenden 
Tomes der antebellum Periode zu den Kongreßhörfähigkeiten in den 
fünfziger Jahren auf Media und jugendlicher Gesetzesverletzung 
überschwemmt. Der folgende Leitartikel von 1950, im populären 
Zeitschrift Colliers, bot eine Perspektive auf dem möglichen Schaden 
solcher jugendlicher Indiskretionen wie Radioprogramme, 
Plattenspielersätze, westliche Filme und komische Bücher an und 
befürwortete Toleranz für Jugend-orientierte populäre Kultur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En années 50, les parents, les éducateurs, les 
amorces religieuses, et les moralistes ont exprimé l'excédent 
intense de souci les effets nocifs perçus de la vie moderne sur la 
jeunesse de la nation. Ce souci n'était pas nouveau, cependant.
Les craintes des influences d'altèration sur la jeunesse ont 
périodiquement inondé le discours public, des tomes 
d'enfant-élevage de la période d'avant-guerre aux auditions 
congressionnelles dans les années 50 sur des medias et la 
délinquance juvénile. L'éditorial suivant de 1950, dans le 
magasin populaire Collier, a offert une perspective sur le mal 
potentiel de telles indiscrétions jeunes comme les programmes par 
radio, les enregistrements de phonographe, les films occidentaux, et 
les livres comiques et a préconisé la tolérance pour la culture 
populaire jeunesse-orientée.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nos 1950s, os pais, os educadores, os líderes 
religiosos, e os moralists expressaram o excesso intenso do interesse 
os efeitos prejudiciais percebidos da vida moderna na juventude da 
nação. Este interesse não era novo, entretanto. Os 
medos de influências corrupting na juventude inundaram 
periòdicamente o discurso público, dos tomes criança-elevando do 
período antebellum aos hearings congressionais nos 1950s em media e 
no delinquency juvenile. O seguinte editorial de 1950, no 
collier popular do compartimento, ofereceu um perspective no dano 
potencial de indiscretions jovens como os programas de rádio, os 
registros do fonógrafo, filmes ocidentais, e livros comic e advogou a
tolerância para a cultura popular juventude-orientada.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Negli anni 50, i genitori, gli educatori, i 
capi religiosi ed i moralisti hanno espresso l'eccedenza 
intensa di preoccupazione gli effetti nocivi percepiti di vita moderna
sulla gioventù della nazione. Questa preoccupazione non era 
nuova, tuttavia. I timori delle influenze di corruzione sulla 
gioventù hanno sommerso periodicamente il discorso pubblico, dai tomi
d'elevazione del periodo antebellum alle udienze congressuali negli 
anni 50 sui media e sulla delinquenza giovanile. Il seguente 
editoriale da 1950, nel collier popolare dello scomparto, ha offerto 
una prospettiva sul danno potenziale di tali indiscretions youthful 
come i programmi radiofonici, i record del fonografo, i film 
occidentali ed i libri comic ed ha sostenuto la tolleranza per coltura
popolare gioventù-orientata.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στη δεκαετία του '50, οι γονείς, οι εκπαιδευτικοί, οι 
θρησκευτικοί ηγέτες, και moralists εξέφρασαν την έντονη 
ανησυχία σχετικά με τα αντιληπτά επιβλαβή αποτελέσματα της 
σύγχρονης ζωής στη νεολαία του έθνους. Αυτή η ανησυχία δεν
ήταν νέα, εντούτοις. Οι φόβοι τις επιρροές στη νεολαία 
έχουν πλημμυρίσει περιοδικά τη δημόσια ομιλία, από τους τόμους 
παιδί-εκτροφής της προπολεμικής περιόδου στις του Κογκρέσου 
ακροάσεις στη δεκαετία του '50 στα μέσα και τη νεανική 
εγκληματικότητα. Το ακόλουθο κύριο άρθρο από το 1950, 
του δημοφιλούς ανθρακωρύχου περιοδικών, πρόσφερε μια προοπτική 
στην πιθανή ζημιά τέτοιων νεανικών αδιακρισιών όπως τα ραδιο 
προγράμματα, τα αρχεία φωνογράφων, τους δυτικούς κινηματογράφους,
και τα κωμικά βιβλία και υποστήριξε την ανοχή για τον 
νεολαία-προσανατολισμένο στον δημοφιλή πολιτισμό.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En los años 50, los padres, los educadores, los 
arranques de cinta religiosos, y los moralistas expresaron el 
excedente intenso de la preocupación los efectos dañosos percibidos 
de la vida moderna en la juventud de la nación. Esta 
preocupación no era nueva, sin embargo. Los miedos de las 
influencias de la corrupción en la juventud han inundado 
periódicamente el discurso público, de los tomos niño-que se 
alzaban del período antebellum a las audiencias del congreso en los 
años 50 en media y delincuencia juvenil. El editorial siguiente
a partir de 1950, en el collier popular del compartimiento, ofreció 
una perspectiva en el daño potencial de las indiscreciones jóvenes 
tales como los programas de radio, los expedientes del fonógrafo, las
películas occidentales, y los libros cómicos y abogó la tolerancia 
para la cultura popular juventud-orientada.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087354</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107668</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-youngster-needs-a-knowledge-of-the-present-a-popular-magazine-urges-tolerance-for-the-distractions-of-youth</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
