<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105590</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105590</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086166</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"For Six Nights and Five Days We Never Left That Line for More than Five Minutes:" Cynthia Long Recalls Applying for an Electrician Apprenticeship</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"für sechs Nächte und fünf Tage ließen wir nie
diese Zeile für mehr als fünf Minuten:" Cynthia lange 
Rückrufe, die eine Elektriker-Lehre beantragen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"pour six nuits et cinq jours nous n'avons jamais 
laissé cette ligne pendant plus de cinq minutes :" Longs 
rappels de Cynthia s'appliquant pour un apprentissage d'électricien</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"para seis noites e cinco dias nós nunca deixamos
essa linha por mais de cinco minutos:" Recordações longas de 
Cynthia que aplicam-se para um apprenticeship do eletricista</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"per sei notti e cinque giorni non abbiamo 
lasciato mai quella riga per più di cinque minuti:" Richiami 
lunghi della Cynthia che fanno domanda per un apprendistato 
dell'elettricista</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Για έξι νύχτες και πέντε ημέρες δεν αφήσαμε ποτέ 
εκείνη την γραμμή για περισσότερο από πέντε λεπτά:" 
Θ*Θυντχηα Long Recalls Applying για μια μαθητεία 
ηλεκτρολόγων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"para seis noches y cinco días nunca dejamos esa 
línea por más de cinco minutos:" Memorias largas de Cynthia 
que solicitan un aprendizaje del electricista</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The women's movement of the 1970's sent shockwaves into every recess of American life. Women organized to seek enforcement of the ban on sex discrimination included in the 1964 Civil Rights Act, demanded equal pay at work, and sought access to non-traditional jobs, from which women had long been barred. After becoming dissatisfied with the low pay and lack of opportunities in traditional women's office jobs, Cynthia Long overcame the opposition of the union and male workers to seek training as a construction electrician. In 1978, she was one of the first women to gain access to a union apprenticeship program in New York City, where she continued to face opposition and harassment from male supervisors and co-workers.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Bewegung der Frauen der siebziger Jahre 
sendete Shockwaves in jede Aussparung der amerikanischen Lebensdauer. 
Die Frauen, die organisiert werden, um Durchführung des Verbots
auf der Geschlechtunterscheidung zu suchen eingeschlossen ist in den 
1964 Zivilrechten, fungieren, verlangte gleiche Bezahlung an der 
Arbeit und gesuchter Zugriff zu den nicht traditionelen Jobs, von 
denen Frauen lang abgehalten worden waren. Nachdem sie mit der 
niedrigen Bezahlung und dem Mangel an Gelegenheiten in den Bürojobs 
der traditionellen Frauen unzufrieden gemacht geworden war, überwand 
Cynthia lang die Opposition der Anschluß- und Mannesarbeiter, um 
Training als Aufbauelektriker zu suchen. 1978 war sie eine der 
ersten Frauen, zum zu einem Anschlußlehreprogramm in New York City 
Zutritt zu erhalten, in dem sie fortfuhr, Opposition und Belästigung 
von den männlichen Überwachungsprogrammen und von den Mitarbeitern 
gegenüberzustellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le mouvement des femmes des années 70 a envoyé 
des ondes de choc dans chaque cavité de vie américaine. Les 
femmes organisées pour rechercher l'application de l'interdiction de 
la discrimination de sexe incluse dans les 1964 droits civiques 
agissent, égalité de salaires exigée au travail, et accès 
recherché aux travaux non traditionnels, desquels des femmes avaient 
été longtemps empêchées. Après être devenu mécontente 
avec le bas salaire et manque d'occasions dans les travaux du bureau 
des femmes traditionnelles, Cynthia a longtemps surmonté l'opposition
des ouvriers des syndicats et de mâle pour rechercher la formation en
tant qu'électricienne de construction. En 1978, elle était 
l'une des premières femmes à accéder à un programme 
d'apprentissage des syndicats à New York City, où elle a continué 
à faire face à l'opposition et au harcèlement des superviseurs et 
des collègues mâles.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O movimento das mulheres dos 1970's emitiu 
shockwaves em cada rebaixo da vida americana. As mulheres 
organizadas para procurar o enforcement da proibição na 
discriminação de sexo incluída nas 1964 direitas civis agem, 
pagamento igual exijido no trabalho, e acesso procurado aos trabalhos 
non-traditional, de que as mulheres tinham sido barradas por muito 
tempo. Após tornar-se descontentada com o pagamento e a falta 
baixos das oportunidades em trabalhos do escritório das mulheres 
tradicionais, Cynthia superou por muito tempo a oposição dos 
trabalhadores da união e do macho para procurar o treinamento como um
eletricista da construção. Em 1978, era uma das primeiras 
mulheres para ganhar o acesso a um programa do apprenticeship da 
união em New York City, onde continuou a enfrentar a oposição e o 
harassment dos supervisores e dos colegas de trabalho masculinos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il movimento delle donne degli anni 70 ha 
trasmesso gli shockwaves in ogni incavo di vita americana. Le 
donne organizzate per cercare l'applicazione del divieto di 
discriminazione in base al sesso inclusa nei 1964 diritti civili si 
comportano, parità salariale richiesta sul lavoro ed accesso cercato 
ai lavori non tradizionali, da cui le donne lungamente erano state 
escluse. Dopo essere stato insoddisfatta con la paga e la 
mancanza basse di occasioni nei lavori dell'ufficio delle donne 
tradizionali, Cynthia lungamente ha sormontato l'opposizione degli 
operai del maschio e del sindacato per cercare l'addestramento come 
elettricista della costruzione. In 1978, era una delle prime 
donne da accedere ad un programma di apprendistato del sindacato a New
York City, in cui ha continuato ad affrontare l'opposizione ed il 
harassment dai soprintendenti e dai colleghe maschii.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το κίνημα των γυναικών της δεκαετίας του '70 έστειλε 
shockwaves σε κάθε κοιλότητα της αμερικανικής ζωής. Οι 
γυναίκες που οργανώθηκαν για να επιδιώξουν την επιβολή της 
απαγόρευσης στις διακρίσεις λόγω φύλου που περιλήφθηκαν στο νόμο
αστικών δικαιωμάτων του 1964, απαίτησαν την ίση αμοιβή στην 
εργασία, και επιδίωξαν την πρόσβαση στις μη παραδοσιακές 
εργασίες, από τις οποίες οι γυναίκες ήταν φραγμένων από καιρό.
Μετά από να γίνει δυσαρεστημένη με τη χαμηλές αμοιβή στις 
εργασίες γραφείων και την έλλειψη ευκαιριών των παραδοσιακών 
γυναικών, η Cynthia Long υπερνίκησε την αντίθεση της ένωσης 
και των ανδρών εργαζόμενοι για να επιδιώξει την κατάρτιση ως 
ηλεκτρολόγο κατασκευής. Το 1978, ήταν μια από τις πρώτες
γυναίκες για να αποκτήσει πρόσβαση σε ένα πρόγραμμα μαθητείας 
ένωσης στην πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης, όπου συνέχισε να 
αντιμετωπίζει την αντίθεση και την παρενόχληση από τους 
αρσενικούς επόπτες και τους συναδέλφους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El movimiento de las mujeres de los años 70 
envió ondas de choque en cada receso de la vida americana. Las 
mujeres ordenadas para buscar la aplicación de la interdicción en la
discriminación de sexo incluida en las 1964 derechas civiles actúan,
igualdad de salario exigida en el trabajo, y acceso buscado a los 
trabajos no tradicionales, de los cuales habían barrado a las mujeres
de largo. Después de el descontentarse con la paga y la 
carencia bajas de oportunidades en los trabajos de la oficina de las 
mujeres tradicionales, Cynthia superó de largo la oposición de los 
trabajadores de la unión y del varón para buscar el entrenamiento 
como electricista de la construcción. En 1978, ella era una de 
las primeras mujeres a acceder a un programa del aprendizaje de la 
unión en New York City, en donde ella continuó haciendo frente a la 
oposición y al hostigamiento de los supervisores y de los compañeros
de trabajo masculinos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086166</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105590</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/for-six-nights-and-five-days-we-never-left-that-line-for-more-than-five-minutes-cynthia-long-recalls-applying-for-an-electrician-apprenticeship</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
