<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103768</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103768</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086102</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Dressmaker and Former Slave Elizabeth Keckley (ca.1818-1907), Tells How She Gained Her Freedom, 1868.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Damenschneiderin und ehemaliges Sklavenelizabeth 
Keckley (ca.1818-1907), erklärt, wie sie ihre Freiheit gewann, 1868.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La couturière et l'ancien Elizabeth 
Slave Keckley (ca.1818-1907), dit comment elle a gagné sa 
liberté, 1868.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A costureira e Elizabeth slave anterior Keckley 
(ca.1818-1907), dizem como ganhou sua liberdade, 1868.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il sarto da donna ed Elizabeth slave precedente 
Keckley (ca.1818-1907), dice come ha guadagnato la sua libertà, a 
1868.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η μοδίστρα και ο προηγούμενος σκλάβος Elizabeth 
Keckley (ca.1818-1907), λένε πώς κέρδισε την ελευθερία της, 
1868.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La modista y Elizabeth auxiliar anterior Keckley 
(ca.1818-1907), dice cómo ella ganó su libertad, 1868.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Elizabeth Hobbs Keckley was born around 1818 in Virginia, a slave of the Burwell family. At fourteen she was loaned to the Rev. Robert Burwell, her master's son, who lived in North Carolina. There she gave birth to her son George, the product of an unwanted encounter with a white man. After several unhappy years with Robert Burwell and his family, Keckley was sent to live in St. Louis with Anne Burwell Garland, a married daughter of the Burwells. In this selection from her 1868 memoir  Behind the Scenes , Keckley describes how she bought her freedom from the Garland family, a process that was completed in November 1855. Her sincere efforts to live within slavery's rules are striking and indicate how deeply the slave system's practices and values permeated both the black and white cultures of the South. After her emancipation Keckley earned her living as a dressmaker in Washington, D.C.; she died there in poverty in 1907.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Elizabeth Hobbs Keckley wurde um 1818 in Virginia, ein 
Sklave der Burwell Familie getragen. Bei vierzehn Rev. Robert 
Burwell, Sohn wurde sie ihr Meisters ausgeliehen, der in Nord-Carolina
wohnte. Dort gab sie ihrem Sohn George, das Produkt Geburt eines
unerwünschten Treffens mit einem weißen Mann. Nach einigen 
unglücklichen Jahren mit Robert Burwell und seine Familie, wurde 
Keckley gesendet, um in St. Louis mit Anne Burwell Girlande, eine 
verheiratete Tochter des Burwells zu wohnen. In dieser Auswahl 
von ihrer Abhandlung 1868 hinter den Szenen, beschreibt Keckley, wie 
sie ihre Freiheit von der Girlandefamilie kaufte, ein Prozeß, der im 
November 1855 durchgeführt wurde. Ihre aufrichtigen 
Bemühungen, innerhalb der Richtlinien der Sklaverei zu leben schlagen
und anzuzeigen an, wie tief die Praxis und die Werte des Untersystems 
die schwarzen und weißen Kulturen des Südens durchdrangen. 
Nach ihrer Emanzipation erwarb Keckley ihr Leben als 
Damenschneiderin in Washington, Gleichstrom; sie starb dort in 
der Armut 1907.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Elizabeth Hobbs Keckley a été soutenu autour de 1818 
en Virginie, un slave de la famille de Burwell. À 
quatorze elle a été prêtée à Rev. Robert Burwell, le fils de son 
maître, qui a habité en Caroline du nord. Là elle a 
donné naissance à son fils George, le produit d'une rencontre 
non désirée avec un homme blanc. Après plusieurs années 
malheureuses avec Robert Burwell et sa famille, Keckley a été 
envoyé pour habiter à St Louis avec la guirlande d'Anne Burwell, une
fille mariée du Burwells. Dans cette sélection à partir de 
son mémoire 1868 dans les coulisses, Keckley décrit comment elle a 
acheté son absence de la famille de guirlande, un processus qui a 
été complété en novembre 1855. Ses efforts sincères de 
vivre dans les règles de l'esclavage frappent et d'indiquer comment 
profondément les pratiques en matière slaves et les valeurs 
du système ont imprégné les cultures noires et blanches des 
Sud. Après son émancipation Keckley a gagné sa vie 
en tant que couturière à Washington, C.C ; elle est morte là 
dans la pauvreté en 1907.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Elizabeth Hobbs Keckley foi carregado em torno de 1818 em 
Virgínia, um escravo da família de Burwell. Em quatorze foi 
emprestada ao Rev. Robert Burwell, o filho do seu mestre, que viveu em
North.carolina. Lá deu o nascimento a seu filho George, o 
produto de um encontro não desejado com um homem branco. Após 
diversos anos infelizes com Robert Burwell e sua família, Keckley foi
emitido para viver em St. Louis com o garland de Anne Burwell, uma 
filha casada do Burwells. Nesta seleção de seu memoir 1868 
atrás das cenas, Keckley descreve como comprou sua liberdade da 
família do garland, um processo que seja terminado em novembro 1855. 
Seus esforços sincere viver dentro das réguas do slavery 
estão golpeando e indicar como profundamente as práticas e os 
valores de sistema slave permeated  as culturas pretas e brancas do 
sul. Após seu emancipation Keckley ganhou sua vida como uma 
costureira em Washington, C.C.; morreu lá na pobreza em 1907.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Elizabeth Hobbs Keckley è stato sopportato verso 1818 
nella Virginia, uno schiavo della famiglia di Burwell. A 
quattordici è stata prestata all'Rev. Robert Burwell, figlio del suo 
supervisore, che ha vissuto in North.carolina. Là ha dato alla 
luce al suo figlio George, il prodotto di un incontro indesiderabile 
con un uomo bianco. Dopo parecchi anni infelici con Robert 
Burwell e la sua famiglia, Keckley è stato trasmesso per vivere a St.
Louis con il garland del Anne Burwell, una figlia sposata del 
Burwells. In questa selezione dalla sua memoria 1868 dietro le 
scene, Keckley descrive come ha comprato la sua libertà dalla 
famiglia del garland, un processo che è stato realizzato nel mese di 
novembre del 1855. I suoi sforzi sinceri vivere all'interno 
delle regole dello slavery stanno colpendo ed indicare quanto 
profondamente le pratiche ed i valori del sistema slave hanno pervaso 
sia le colture nere che bianche del sud. Dopo la sua 
emancipazione Keckley ha guadagnato la sua vita come sarto da donna in
Washington, DC; è morto là nella povertà in 1907.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θ*Εληζαψετχ Hobbs Keckley ήταν γεννημένα περίπου 
1818 στη Βιρτζίνια, ένας σκλάβος της οικογένειας Burwell. 
Σε δεκατέσσερα ήταν δανεισμένη στην αναθ. Robert 
Burwell, γιος του κυρίου της, ο οποίος έζησε στη βόρεια 
Καρολίνα. Εκεί γέννησε στο γιο της George, το προϊόν 
μιας ανεπιθύμητης σύγκρουσης με ένα λευκό άτομο. Μετά από
αρκετά δυστυχισμένα έτη με Robert Burwell και την 
οικογένειά του, Keckley στάλη για να ζήσει στο ST Louis 
με την Anne Burwell Garland, μια παντρεμένη κόρη του 
Burwells. Σε αυτήν την επιλογή από τα απομνημονεύματα 
1868 της πίσω από τις σκηνές, Keckley περιγράφει πώς 
αγόρασε την ελευθερία της από την οικογένεια γιρλαντών, μια 
διαδικασία που ολοκληρώθηκε τις 1855, Νοεμβρίου Οι 
ειλικρινείς προσπάθειές της να ζήσει μέσα στους κανόνες της 
σκλαβιάς είναι εντυπωσιακές και δείχνουν πόσο βαθειά οι 
πρακτικές και οι τιμές του συστήματος σκλάβων διαπέρασαν και τους
μαύρους και άσπρους πολιτισμούς του νότου. Μετά από την 
χειραφέτηση της Keckley την κέρδισε που ζει ως μοδίστρα στην 
Ουάσιγκτον, ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ  πέθανε εκεί στην ένδεια το 
1907.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Elizabeth Hobbs Keckley fue llevado alrededor de 1818 en 
Virginia, un esclavo de la familia de Burwell. En catorce le 
prestaron al Rev. Roberto Burwell, el hijo de su amo, que vivió en 
Carolina del Norte. Allí ella dio a luz a su hijo George, el 
producto de un encuentro indeseado con un hombre blanco. 
Después de varios años infelices con Roberto Burwell y su 
familia, Keckley fue enviado para vivir en St. Louis con el garland de
Anne Burwell, hija casada del Burwells. En esta selección de su
memoria 1868 detrás de las escenas, Keckley describe cómo ella 
compró su libertad de la familia del garland, un proceso que fue 
terminado en noviembre de 1855. Sus esfuerzos sinceros de vivir 
dentro de las reglas de la esclavitud pulso y de indicar cómo 
profundamente las prácticas y los valores del sistema auxiliar 
impregnaron las culturas negras y blancas del sur. Después de 
su emancipación Keckley ganó su vida como modista en Washington, 
C.C.; ella murió allí en pobreza en 1907.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086102</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103768</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/dressmaker-and-former-slave-elizabeth-keckley-ca-1818-1907-tells-how-she-gained-her-freedom-1868</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
