<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103868</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103868</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086159</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Five generations on Smith's plantation, Beaufort, South Carolina."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"fünf Erzeugungen auf Plantage Smith, Beaufort, 
Südcarolina."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"cinq générations sur la plantation de Smith, 
Beaufort, Caroline du sud."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"cinco gerações na plantação de Smith, 
Beaufort, carolina sul."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"cinque generazioni sulla piantagione dello Smith,
Beaufort, Carolina del Sud."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Πέντε γενεές στη φυτεία Smith, Beaufort, νότια 
Καρολίνα."</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"cinco generaciones en la plantación de Smith, 
Beaufort, Carolina del Sur."</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This African-American family was photographed in 1862 after Union forces captured the Sea Island coastal area of South Carolina. One of four photographs taken by Timothy O'Sullivan of the J. J. Smith plantation, this picture was subsequently exhibited at Alexander Gardner's Washington, D.C., photography gallery in September 1863. In contrast to this Beaufort, South Carolina, family the history of the slave family was usually characterized by constant efforts by enslaved African Americans to maintain continuity in the face of forced break-ups and sales (exemplified in the naming of children to mark lineage).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Familie wurde 1862 
fotografiert, nachdem Anschlußkräfte den Seeinselküstenbereich von 
Südcarolina erfaßten. Eine von vier Fotographien, die von 
Timothy O'Sullivan der J. J. Smith Plantage, diese Abbildung genommen 
wurden, wurde nachher in Alexander Gardners Washington, Gleichstrom, 
Fotographie Galerie im September 1863 ausgestellt. Im Gegensatz 
zu diesem Beaufort wurde Südcarolina, Familie die Geschichte der 
Sklavenfamilie normalerweise durch konstante Bemühungen durch 
versklavte afrikanische Amerikaner, Durchgang angesichts der 
vorverlegten Abbrüche und der Verkäufe beizubehalten gekennzeichnet 
(illustriert im Benennen der Kinder zur Markierung Abstammung).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette famille afro-américaine a été photographiée en 1862
après que les forces des syndicats aient capturé la région 
côtière d'île de mer de la Caroline du sud. Une de 
quatre photographies prises par Timothy o'Sullivan de la plantation de
J. J. Smith, cette image a été ultérieurement montrée à 
Washington d'Alexandre Gardner, C.C, galerie de photographie en 
septembre 1863. Contrairement à ce Beaufort, la Caroline 
Du sud, famille l'histoire de la famille slave a été 
habituellement caractérisée par des efforts constants par les 
Américains africains asservis de mettre à jour la continuité face 
aux dissolutions obligatoires et aux ventes (exemplifiées dans nommer
des enfants à la lignée de marque).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta família Africano-Americana foi fotografada em 1862 
depois que as forças da união capturaram a área litoral do console 
do mar de carolina sul. Uma de quatro fotografias feitas exame 
por Timothy O'Sullivan da plantação de J. J. Smith, este retrato foi
exibido subseqüentemente em Washington de Alexander Gardner, C.C., 
galeria da fotografia em setembro 1863. No contraste a este 
Beaufort, carolina sul, família o history da família slave foi 
caracterizado geralmente por esforços constantes por americanos 
africanos enslaved manter a continuidade na cara de break-ups 
forçados e das vendas (exemplified em nomear das crianças ao lineage
da marca).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa famiglia Africano-Americana è stata fotografata in
1862 dopo che le forze del sindacato bloccassero la zona costiera 
dell'isola del mare di Carolina del Sud. Una di quattro 
fotografie prese da Timothy O'Sullivan della piantagione del J. J. 
Smith, questa immagine successivamente è stata esibita a Washington 
del Alexander Gardner, DC, galleria di fotographia nel mese di 
settembre del 1863. Contrariamente a questo Beaufort, Carolina 
del Sud, famiglia la storia della famiglia slave è stata 
caratterizzata solitamente dagli sforzi costanti dagli Americani 
africani asserviti effettuare la continuità di fronte ai break-ups 
forzati ed alle vendite (esemplificati nel chiamare dei bambini al 
lineage del contrassegno).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η αφρικανικός-αμερικανική οικογένεια 
φωτογραφίστηκε το 1862 αφότου συνέλαβαν οι δυνάμεις ένωσης την
παράκτια περιοχή νησιών θάλασσας της νότιας Καρολίνας. Η 
μια από τέσσερις φωτογραφίες που λήφθηκαν από timothy 
O'Sullivan της φυτείας Θ*ι. Θ*ι. Smith, αυτή η εικόνα 
εκτέθηκε στη συνέχεια στην Ουάσιγκτον του Αλεξάνδρου Gardner's,
ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ, στοά φωτογραφίας τον Σεπτέμβριο του 1863. 
Σε αντίθεση με αυτό το Beaufort, η νότια Καρολίνα, 
οικογένεια η ιστορία της οικογένειας σκλάβων χαρακτηρίστηκε 
συνήθως από τις σταθερές προσπάθειες από υποδουλωμένους 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς να διατηρηθεί η συνοχή παρά τις 
αναγκασμένες αποσυνθέσεις και τις πωλήσεις (που εξηγούνται στην 
ονομασία των παιδιών στην καταγωγή σημαδιών).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fotografiaron a esta familia Africano-Americana en 1862 
después de que las fuerzas de la unión capturaran el área costera 
de la isla del mar de Carolina del Sur. Una de cuatro 
fotografías tomadas por Timothy ÓSullivan de la plantación de J. J.
Smith, este cuadro fue exhibido posteriormente en Washington de 
Alexander Gardner, C.C., galería de la fotografía en septiembre de 
1863. En contraste con este Beaufort, Carolina del Sur, familia 
la historia de la familia auxiliar fue caracterizado generalmente por 
esfuerzos constantes de los americanos africanos esclavizados de 
mantener continuidad en la cara de desintegraciones forzadas y de 
ventas (ejemplificadas en el nombramiento de niños al linaje de la 
marca).</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086159</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103868</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/five-generations-on-smiths-plantation-beaufort-south-carolina</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
