<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108013</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108013</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087214</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Welcome back.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Willkommen zurück.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bienvenue en arrière.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Boa vinda para trás.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Benvenuto indietro.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ευπρόσδεκτη πλάτη.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Recepción detrás.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During World War II, housing construction came to a virtual standstill. The return of millions of servicemen to civilian life in 1945 set off a national housing crisis, followed by a construction boom. Although other New Deal and wartime housing programs emphasized rental apartments in close proximity to workplaces, the post-war building boom focused on single residence suburban development. Prodded by builders like William Levitt, the government underwrote low-interest loans that made it possible for working people to own their own homes in the suburbs, once a domain reserved for the well-to-do. Those Federal Housing Authority loans, however, deepened racial and class divisions across metropolitan America, since the FHA refused to write mortgage loans in cities and allowed its loan holders to enforce restrictive covenants barring Jews and African Americans from buying homes in certain areas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des Zweiten Weltkrieges kam die Unterbringung des
Aufbaus zu einem virtuellen Stillstand. Die Rückkehr der 
Millionen Soldaten zur Zivillebensdauer in Set 1945 weg von 
einer nationalen Gehäusekrise, gefolgt von einer 
Aufbauhochkonjunktur. Obgleich andere neues Abkommen- und 
Kriegwohnungsbauprogramme Mietwohnungen in der nahen Nähe zu den 
Arbeitsplätzen hervorhoben, konzentrierte die 
Nachkriegsgebäudehochkonjunktur auf Vorstadtentwicklung des einzelnen
Wohnsitzes. Stieß durch Erbauer wie William Levitt, die 
Regierung unterschrieb niedrigverzinsliche Darlehen, denen es für 
Arbeitsleute zu besitzen ihre eigenen Häuser in den Vororten 
ermöglichte, einmal ein Gebiet, das für gut-zu- aufgehoben wurde. 
Jene Bundesgehäuse-Berechtigung Darlehen jedoch vertieften 
rassisches und klassifizieren Abteilungen über Metropolitanamerika, 
da das FHA, das abgelehnt wurde, um Pfandbriefdarlehen in Städte zu 
schreiben und seine Hypothekare, um einschränkende Vereinbarungen 
außer Juden und afrikanischen Amerikanern von kaufenden Häusern in 
bestimmten Bereichen zu erzwingen erlaubt war.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant la deuxième guerre mondiale, loger la 
construction est venu à un arrêt virtuel. Le retour des 
millions de soldats à la vie civile dans le positionnement 1945 outre
d'une crise nationale de logement, suivis d'une perche de 
construction. Bien que d'autres nouvelle programmes de logement 
d'affaire et de temps de guerre aient souligné les appartements de 
location dans la proximité étroite aux lieux de travail, la 
construction en plein essor d'après-guerre s'est concentrée sur le 
développement suburbain de résidence simple. A poignardé par 
des constructeurs comme William Levitt, le gouvernement a garanti les 
prêts de faible intérêt aux lesquels l'a rendu possible aux personnes 
travaillantes possèdent leurs propres maisons dans les banlieues, une
fois un domaine réservé pour bien-à-. Ces prêts fédéraux 
d'autorité de logement, cependant, ont approfondi racial et classent 
des divisions à travers l'Amérique métropolitaine, puisque le FHA 
refusé pour écrire des prêts hypothécaires dans les villes et 
permis ses supports de prêt pour imposer les engagements restrictifs 
excepté des juifs et des Américains africains des maisons achetantes
dans certaines zones.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante a segunda guerra mundial, abrigar a construção 
veio a uma paralisação virtual. O retorno dos milhões dos 
recrutas à vida civil no jogo 1945 fora de uma crise nacional da 
carcaça, seguidos por um crescimento da construção. Embora 
outros programas de carcaça do negócio novo e do wartime 
emfatizassem apartamentos rental na proximidade próxima aos 
workplaces, o crescimento de edifício post-war focalizou no 
desenvolvimento suburbano da única residência. Prodded por 
construtores como William Levitt, o governo subscreveu os empréstimos
low-interest a que fêz possível para povos trabalhando possuem suas 
próprias HOME nos suburbs, uma vez um domínio reservado para 
bem-à-. Aqueles empréstimos federais da autoridade da 
carcaça, entretanto, aprofundaram racial e classificam divisões 
através de América metropolitana, desde que o FHA recusado escrever 
empréstimos de mortgage nas cidades e permitido seus suportes de 
empréstimo para reforçar convénios restritivos exceto jews e 
americanos africanos das HOME de compra em determinadas áreas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante la seconda guerra mondiale, alloggiare la 
costruzione è venuto ad una fermata virtuale. Il ritorno di 
milioni di tecnici di manutenzione a vita civile nell'insieme 1945 
fuori di una crisi nazionale dell'alloggiamento, seguiti da un'asta 
della costruzione. Anche se altri nuovo programmi di 
alloggiamento di wartime e di affare hanno dato risalto agli 
appartamenti locativi nella prossimità vicina ai posti di lavoro, 
l'asta di costruzione del dopoguerra ha messo a fuoco su sviluppo 
suburbano della singola residenza. Prodded dai costruttori come 
William Levitt, il governo ha sottoscritto i prestiti low-interest a 
che lo ha permesso per la gente lavorante possiedono le loro proprie 
sedi nella periferia, una volta un settore riservato al bene-$$$-. 
Quei prestiti federali di autorità dell'alloggiamento, 
tuttavia, hanno approfondito razziale e classificano le divisioni 
attraverso l'America metropolitana, poiché il FHA ha rifiutato di 
scrivere i prestiti ipotecari in città e che ha permesso che i 
relativi supporti di prestito facessero rispettare i patti restrittivi
eccetto gli ebrei e gli Americani africani dalle sedi d'acquisto in 
determinate zone.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του παγκόσμιου πολέμου ΙΙ, η 
κατασκευή κατοικίας ήρθε σε ένα εικονικό σταμάτημα. Η 
επιστροφή των εκατομμυρίων servicemen στην πολιτική ζωή στο 
σύνολο του 1945 από μια εθνική κρίση κατοικίας, που 
ακολουθούνται από έναν βραχίονα κατασκευής. Αν και άλλα 
νέα διαπραγμάτευση και εν καιρώ πολέμου προγράμματα κατοικίας 
υπογράμμισαν τα διαμερίσματα ενοικίου στη στενή εγγύτητα στους 
εργασιακούς χώρους, ο μεταπολεμικός βραχίονας οικοδόμησης 
εστίασε στην ενιαία προαστιακή ανάπτυξη κατοικιών. 
Σπρωγμένη από τους οικοδόμους όπως William Levitt, η 
κυβέρνηση ασφάλισε τα με χαμηλό επιτόκιο δάνεια που το 
κατέστησαν πιθανό για τους εργαζόμενους ανθρώπους να είναι 
κύριοι των σπιτιών τους στα προάστια, μόλις μια δικτυακή 
γειτονιά που διατηρείται για τον ευκατάστατο. Εκείνα τα 
ομοσπονδιακά δάνεια αρχής κατοικίας, εντούτοις, εμβάθυναν τα 
φυλετικά και τμήματα κλάσης σε ολόκληρη τη μητροπολιτική 
Αμερική, δεδομένου ότι το FHA αρνήθηκε να γράψει τα ενυπόθηκα
δάνεια στις πόλεις και επέτρεψε στους κατόχους δανείου του για να
επιβάλει τα περιοριστικά συμβόλαια που φράζουν τους Εβραίους και 
αφρικανικούς Αμερικανούς από την αγορά των σπιτιών σε ορισμένες 
περιοχές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante la Segunda Guerra Mundial, contener la 
construcción vino a una parada virtual. La vuelta de millones 
de mecánicos a la vida civil en el conjunto 1945 de una crisis 
nacional de la cubierta, seguidos por un auge de la construcción. 
Aunque otros nuevo programas de cubierta del reparto y del 
tiempo de guerra acentuaron los apartamentos de alquiler en proximidad
cercana a los lugares de trabajo, el auge de edificio de la posguerra 
se centró en el desarrollo suburbano de la sola residencia. 
Pinchó por los constructores como Guillermo Levitt, el gobierno
subscribió los préstamos de bajo interés a los cuales hizo posible 
para la gente de trabajo poseen sus propios hogares en los suburbios, 
un dominio reservado para bien-a- una vez. Esos préstamos 
federales de la autoridad de la cubierta, sin embargo, profundizaron 
racial y clasifican las divisiones a través de América 
metropolitana, puesto que el FHA rechazado para escribir préstamos de
hipoteca en ciudades y no prohibido sus sostenedores de préstamo para
hacer cumplir los convenios restrictivos salvo judíos y americanos 
africanos de hogares que compraban en ciertas áreas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087214</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108013</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/welcome-back</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
