<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105431</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105431</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202531</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Community in the Classroom: Part 2 (Cooperative Planning)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gemeinschaft im Klassenzimmer: Teil 2 
(Kooperative Planung)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Communauté dans la salle de classe : 
Partie 2 (Planification Coopérative)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Comunidade na sala de aula: Parte 2 
(Planeamento Cooperativo)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Comunità nell'aula: Parte 2 (Progettazione 
Cooperativa)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινότητα στην τάξη: Μέρος 2 (συνεταιρισμός που 
προγραμματίζει)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Comunidad en la sala de clase: Parte 2 
(Hojas de operación (planning) Cooperativas)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This series of lessons is designed to help develop a sense of classroom community through use of group goal-setting, decision-making, brainstorming, peer feedback, positive reinforcement, and positive peer pressure. The lessons will help students create and maintain a supportive environment for learning. Part 1 focused on goal-setting process and practice. In Part 2, students will apply knowledge of the goal-setting process by cooperatively creating a plan to work on group goals.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Reihe Lektionen ist konzipiert, um zu 
helfen, eine Richtung der Klassenzimmergemeinschaft durch Gebrauch von
Gruppe Ziel-Einstellung, Beschlußfassung, Geistesstörung, 
Gleichfeedback, positiver Verstärkung und positivem Gleichdruck zu 
entwickeln. Die Lektionen willen helfen Kursteilnehmern, eine 
unterstützende Umgebung für das Lernen zu erstellen und 
beizubehalten. Zerteilen Sie 1 gerichtet auf 
Ziel-einstellenprozeß und Praxis. In Teil 2, wenden 
Kursteilnehmer Wissen des Ziel-einstellenprozesses an, indem sie 
kooperativ einen Plan an der Arbeit über Gruppe Ziele erstellen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette série de leçons est conçue pour aider à 
développer un sens de la communauté de salle de classe par 
l'utilisation du but-réglage de groupe, de la prise de décision, de 
la séance de réflexion, du feedback de pair, du renfort positif, et 
de la pression positive de pair. Les leçons veulent aident des 
étudiants à créer et mettre à jour un environnement de support 
pour l'étude. Pièce 1 concentré sur le processus et la 
pratique deréglage. Dans la partie 2, les étudiants 
appliqueront la connaissance du processus deréglage en créant 
coopérativement un plan au travail sur des buts de groupe.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta série das lições é projetada ajudar 
desenvolver um sentido da comunidade da sala de aula com o uso do 
objetivo-ajuste do grupo, da tomada de decisão, do brainstorming, do 
feedback do par, do reforço positivo, e da pressão positiva do par. 
As lições querem ajudam a estudantes criar e manter um 
ambiente de suporte para aprender. Peça 1 focalizado no 
processo e na prática deajuste. Na parte 2, os estudantes 
aplicarão o conhecimento do processo deajuste cooperativa criando uma
planta ao trabalho em objetivos do grupo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa serie di lezioni è destinata per 
contribuire a sviluppare un senso della Comunità dell'aula con uso di
obiettivo-regolazione del gruppo, di risoluzione, di "brainstorming", 
di risposte del pari, del rinforzo positivo e della pressione positiva
del pari. Le lezioni vogliono aiutano gli allievi a creare ed 
effettuare un ambiente di appoggio per imparare. Parte 1 messo a
fuoco sul processo e sulla pratica diregolazione. Nella parte 2,
gli allievi applicheranno la conoscenza del processo diregolazione in 
cooperazione creando un programma a lavoro sugli obiettivi del gruppo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων έχει ως σκοπό να βοηθήσει να 
αναπτύξει μια αίσθηση της κοινότητας τάξεων μέσω της χρήσης της 
στόχος-τιμής τών παραμέτρων ομάδας, της λήψης αποφάσεων, του 
"brainstorming", της όμοιας ανατροφοδότησης, της θετικής 
ενίσχυσης, και της θετικής όμοιας πίεσης. Τα μαθήματα θα 
βοηθήσουν τους σπουδαστές να δημιουργήσουν και να διατηρήσουν ένα
ενθαρρυντικό περιβάλλον για την εκμάθηση. Το μέρος 1 
εστίασε στην στόχος-τιμή τών παραμέτρων της διαδικασίας και της 
πρακτικής. Στο μέρος 2, οι σπουδαστές θα εφαρμόσουν τη 
γνώση της στόχος-θέτοντας διαδικασίας με συνεταιριστικά να 
δημιουργήσουν ένα σχέδιο για να εργαστούν στους στόχους ομάδας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta serie de lecciones se diseña para ayudar a 
desarrollar un sentido de la comunidad de la sala de clase con el uso 
de meta-fijar del grupo, de la toma de decisión, de la reunión de 
reflexión, del feedback del par, del refuerzo positivo, y de la 
presión positiva del par. Las lecciones quieren ayudan a 
estudiantes a crear y a mantener un ambiente de apoyo para aprender. 
Pieza 1 centrado en proceso y práctica meta-que fijan. En
la parte 2, los estudiantes aplicarán el conocimiento del proceso 
meta-que fija cooperativo creando un plan al trabajo sobre metas del 
grupo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAT NYSTROM
FN:PAT NYSTROM
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202531</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105431</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/community-in-the-classroom-part-2-cooperative-planning</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
