<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108764</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108764</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087250</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Working for My Benefits:" Brenda Steward Describes the Work Experience Program (WEP) in New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">", arbeitend für meinen Nutzen:" Brenda 
Verwalter beschreibt das Arbeit Erfahrung Programm (WEP) in New 
York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"travaillant pour mes avantages :" 
L'administrateur de Brenda décrit le programme d'expérience 
professionnelle (WEP) à New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"trabalhando para meus benefícios:" O 
steward de Brenda descreve o programa da experiência de trabalho 
(WEP) em New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"funzionando per i miei benefici:" 
L'amministratore di Brenda descrive il programma di esperienza 
di lavoro (WEP) a New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Εργαζόμενος για τα οφέλη μου:" Ο διαχειριστής 
Brenda περιγράφει το πρόγραμμα επαγγελματικής εμπειρίας 
(WEP) στην πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"trabajando para mis ventajas:" El 
administrador de Brenda describe el programa de la experiencia 
profesional (WEP) en New York City</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the 1960's and 1970's welfare reform movements from the left sought to increase benefits and expand community power, but in 1996 critics from the right passed the federal Welfare Reform Act to limit the program by imposing time-limits and restrictions on welfare benefits. In New York City, the Work Experience Program (WEP), or workfare, initiated in conjunction with the 1996 act, required welfare recipients to "pay off" their welfare benefits by working menial jobs for the city at well below minimum wage. Participants in the program do not receive wages, but simply continue to receive their welfare benefits. In addition, the program confines people who often have skills to do mindless, unskilled work while they are deprived of basic rights such as the right to unionize. Brenda Steward is a WEP worker who has been working with WEP Workers Together to demand improvements to the program.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während der sechziger Jahre und siebziger Jahre 
Wohlfahrt Reformbewegungen vom links suchte, Nutzen zu erhöhen und 
Gemeinschaftsenergie zu erweitern, aber in 1996 Kritikern vom Recht 
führte die Bundeswohlfahrt Verbesserung-Tat, um das Programm durch 
imposing Time-limits und Beschränkungen auf Wohlfahrt Nutzen zu 
begrenzen. In New York City initialisieren das Arbeit Erfahrung 
Programm (WEP) oder das workfare, in Verbindung mit der Tat 1996, 
benötigte Wohlfahrt Empfänger "zahlen weg" ihren Wohlfahrt Nutzen, 
indem sie menial Jobs für die Stadt an gut unterhalb des minimalen 
Lohnes bearbeiten. Teilnehmer an das Programm empfangen nicht 
Löhne, aber fahren einfach fort, ihren Wohlfahrt Nutzen zu empfangen.
Zusätzlich begrenzt das Programm Leute, die häufig die 
Fähigkeiten haben, zum der geistlosen, unerfahrenen Arbeit zu 
erledigen, während sie Grundrechte wie das Recht unionize beraubt 
werden. Brenda Verwalter ist ein WEP Arbeiter, der mit WEP 
Arbeitern zusammen gearbeitet hat, um Verbesserungen zum Programm zu 
verlangen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant les mouvements de réforme d'assistance 
sociale des années 60 et des années 70 de la gauche a recherché à 
augmenter des avantages et à augmenter la puissance de la 
communauté, mais dans 1996 critiques de la droite a passé l'acte 
fédéral de réforme d'assistance sociale pour limiter le programme 
par des délais et des restrictions imposants aux avantages 
d'assistance sociale. À New York City, le programme 
d'expérience professionnelle (WEP), ou le workfare, lance en même 
temps que l'acte 1996, les destinataires exigés d'assistance sociale 
"payent hors fonction" leurs avantages d'assistance sociale en 
travaillant les travaux serviles la ville à bien au-dessous du 
salaire minimum. Les participants au programme ne reçoivent pas
des salaires, mais continuent simplement à recevoir leurs avantages 
d'assistance sociale. En outre, le programme confine les 
personnes qui ont souvent des qualifications pour effectuer le travail
étourdi et non qualifié tandis qu'elles sont privées des droits 
fondamentaux tels que la droite de se syndiquer. 
L'administrateur de Brenda est un ouvrier de WEP qui avait 
travaillé avec des ouvriers de WEP ensemble pour exiger des 
améliorations au programme.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante os movimentos de reforma do bem-estar dos 
1960's e dos 1970's da esquerda procurou aumentar benefícios e 
expandir a potência da comunidade, mas em 1996 críticos da direita 
passou o ato federal da reforma do bem-estar para limitar o programa 
por time-limits e por limitações imponentes em benefícios de 
bem-estar. Em New York City, o programa da experiência de 
trabalho (WEP), ou o workfare, inicíam conjuntamente com o ato 1996, 
receptores requeridos do bem-estar "pagam fora" seus benefícios de 
bem-estar trabalhando trabalhos menial pela cidade em bem abaixo do 
salário mínimo. Os participants no programa não recebem 
salários, mas continuam simplesmente a receber seus benefícios de 
bem-estar. Além, o programa confina os povos que têm 
frequentemente as habilidades para fazer o trabalho mindless, inábil 
quando forem privadas de direitas básicas tais como a direita 
unionize. O steward de Brenda é um trabalhador de WEP que 
esteja trabalhando com trabalhadores de WEP junto para exijir 
melhorias ao programa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante i movimenti di riforma di assistenza 
sociale degli anni 70 e degli anni 60 dalla parte di sinistra ha 
cercato di aumentare i benefici ed espandere l'potenza della 
Comunità, ma in 1996 critici dalla destra ha passato la Legge 
federale di riforma di assistenza sociale per limitare il programma 
dai limiti di tempo e dalle limitazioni imponenti sulle prestazioni 
sociali. A New York City, il programma di esperienza di lavoro 
(WEP), o il workfare, inizia insieme con l'atto 1996, destinatari 
richiesti di assistenza sociale "paga fuori" le loro prestazioni 
sociali funzionando i lavori menial la città a bene sotto lo 
stipendio minimo. I partecipanti al programma non ricevono gli 
stipendi, ma semplicemente continuano a ricevere le loro prestazioni 
sociali. In più, il programma limita la gente che ha spesso 
abilità per fare il lavoro mindless e non qualificato mentre sono 
private dei diritti di base quale la destra unionize. 
L'amministratore di Brenda è un operaio di WEP che sta 
lavorando insieme con gli operai di WEP per richiedere i miglioramenti
al programma.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '60 και της 
δεκαετίας του '70 τα κινήματα κοινωνικής πρόνοιας από το 
αριστερό επιδίωξαν να αυξήσουν τα οφέλη και να επεκτείνουν την 
κοινοτική δύναμη, αλλά το 1996 οι κριτικοί από το δικαίωμα 
πέρασαν τον ομοσπονδιακό νόμο κοινωνικής πρόνοιας για να 
περιορίσουν το πρόγραμμα με την επιβολή των προθεσμιών και των 
περιορισμών στα οφέλη ευημερίας. Στην πόλη της Νέας 
Υόρκης, το πρόγραμμα επαγγελματικής εμπειρίας (WEP), ή 
workfare, που αρχίζει από κοινού με την πράξη του 1996, τους
απαραίτητους παραλήπτες ευημερίας για "να πληρώσει μακριά" τα 
οφέλη ευημερίας τους δουλεύοντας τις menial εργασίες για την 
πόλη αρκετά κάτω από το βασικό μισθό. Οι συμμετέχοντες 
στο πρόγραμμα δεν λαμβάνουν τις αμοιβές, αλλά απλά συνεχίζουν να
λαμβάνουν τα οφέλη ευημερίας τους. Επιπλέον, το πρόγραμμα 
περιορίζει τους ανθρώπους που έχουν συχνά τις δεξιότητες για να 
κάνουν την απρόσεκτη, ανειδίκευτη εργασία ενώ στερούνται από τα
βασικά δικαιώματα όπως το δικαίωμα να οργανώσουν σε συνδικάτο. 
Ο διαχειριστής Brenda είναι εργαζόμενος WEP που έχει 
συνεργαστεί με τους εργαζομένους WEP για να απαιτήσει μαζί τις 
βελτιώσεις στο πρόγραμμα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante los movimientos de reforma del bienestar 
de los años 60 y de los años 70 de la izquierda intentó aumentar 
ventajas y ampliar potencia de la comunidad, pero en 1996 críticos de
la derecha pasó el acto federal de la reforma del bienestar para 
limitar el programa por time-limits y restricciones imponentes en 
ventajas de bienestar. En New York City, el programa de la 
experiencia profesional (WEP), o el workfare, inició conjuntamente 
con el acto 1996, los recipientes requeridos del bienestar "paga 
apagado" sus ventajas de bienestar trabajando los trabajos menial la 
ciudad en bien debajo de salario mínimo. Los participantes en 
el programa no reciben salarios, sino continúan simplemente 
recibiendo sus ventajas de bienestar. Además, el programa 
confina a gente que tiene a menudo habilidades para hacer el trabajo 
mindless, inexperto mientras que se privan de derechos fundamentales 
tales como la derecha unionize. El administrador de Brenda es un
trabajador de WEP que ha estado trabajando con los trabajadores de WEP
junto para exigir mejoras al programa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087250</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108764</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/working-for-my-benefits-brenda-steward-describes-the-work-experience-program-wep-in-new-york-city</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
