<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107240</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107240</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205478</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">NASA's Rocket to the Moon</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rakete der NASAS zum Mond</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La fusée de la NASA à la lune</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Foguete da NASA à lua</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Razzo della NASA alla luna</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πύραυλος της NASA στο φεγγάρι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Cohete de la NASA a la luna</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">QUEST gets the details on NASA's plan to crash a rocket into the moon in an effort to locate evidence of water. This educator guide provides activities to assist teachers with the use of the video segment in their classrooms and provides suggestions for additional educator resources offered in the Bay Area related to the study of the moon.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">SUCHE erhält die Details über Plan der NASAS, 
eine Rakete in den Mond in einer Bemühung zu zerschmettern, Beweis 
des Wassers zu lokalisieren. Diese Erzieheranleitung versieht 
Aktivitäten zu den Vorlage Lehrern mit dem Gebrauch von dem 
videosegment in ihren Klassenzimmern und stellt Vorschläge für die 
zusätzlichen Erzieherbetriebsmittel zur Verfügung, die im 
Bucht-Bereich angeboten werden, der auf der Studie des Mondes in 
Verbindung gestanden wird.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La RECHERCHE obtient les détails sur le plan de 
la NASA de tomber en panne une fusée dans la lune dans un effort de 
localiser l'évidence de l'eau. Ce guide d'éducateur fournit 
des activités aux professeurs d'aide en utilisation du segment visuel
dans leurs salles de classe et fournit des suggestions pour les 
ressources supplémentaires d'éducateur offertes dans la région de 
compartiment liée à l'étude de la lune.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O QUEST começa os detalhes na planta da NASA 
deixar de funcionar um foguete na lua em um esforço encontrar a 
evidência da água. Esta guia do educador fornece atividades 
aos professores da assistência com o uso do segmento video em suas 
salas de aula e fornece sugestões para os recursos adicionais do 
educador oferecidos na área da baía relacionada ao estudo da lua.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La RICERCA convince i particolari sul programma 
della NASA a arrestare un razzo nella luna in uno sforzo individuare 
la prova di acqua. Questa guida dell'educatore fornisce le 
attività agli insegnanti di aiuto l'uso di video segmento nelle loro 
aule e fornisce i suggerimenti per le risorse supplementari 
dell'educatore offerte nella zona della baia relativa allo studio 
della luna.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ΑΝΑΖΗΤΗΣΗ παίρνει τις λεπτομέρειες στο σχέδιο της 
NASA για να συντρίψει έναν πύραυλο στο φεγγάρι σε μια 
προσπάθεια να βρεθούν τα στοιχεία του ύδατος. Αυτός ο 
οδηγός εκπαιδευτικών παρέχει τις δραστηριότητες για να βοηθήσει 
τους δασκάλους με τη χρήση του τηλεοπτικού τμήματος μνήμης στις 
τάξεις τους και παρέχει τις προτάσεις για τα πρόσθετα στοιχεία 
συμπεριφοράς εκπαιδευτικών που προσφέρονται στην περιοχή κόλπων 
σχετική με τη μελέτη του φεγγαριού.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La BÚSQUEDA consigue los detalles en el plan de 
la NASA estrellar un cohete en la luna en un esfuerzo de localizar la 
evidencia del agua. Esta guía del educador proporciona a 
actividades a los profesores de la ayuda del uso del segmento video en
sus salas de clase y proporciona a las sugerencias para los recursos 
adicionales del educador ofrecidos en el área de la bahía 
relacionada con el estudio de la luna.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205478</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107240</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nasas-rocket-to-the-moon</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
