<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105818</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105818</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206638</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Web de Anza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Web de Anza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Web de Anza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Web de Anza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Web de Anza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Web de Anza</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Web de Anza</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is an interactive environment for studying Spain's exploration and colonization of Alta California (1774-1776). Diaries and letters (available in both English and Spanish), maps and trail routes, drawing and photos all recreate a living timeline of the past and provide primary documents and multimedia resources covering Juan Bautista de Anza's two expeditions to what would become San Francisco.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ist eine interaktive Umgebung für das Studieren 
von von Erforschung und von von Besiedlung Spaniens von Alta 
Kalifornien (1774-1776). Die Tagebücher und Zeichen (vorhanden 
auf englisches und spanisch), Karten und Hinteralle wege, Zeichnung 
und Fotos erstellen ein lebendes timeline der Vergangenheit neu und 
stellen Primärdokumente und die Multimediabetriebsmittel, die Juan 
Bautista de Anzas zwei Expeditionen umfassen zu zur Verfügung, was 
San Francisco werden würde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est un environnement interactif pour étudier 
l'exploration et la colonisation de l'Espagne d'Alta la Californie 
(1774-1776). Les agendas et les lettres (disponibles dans 
anglais et espagnol), les cartes et les itinéraires de traînée, le 
schéma et les photos tous recréent une chronologie vivante du passé
et fournissent les documents primaires et les ressources de 
multimédia couvrant des expéditions de Juan Bautista de 
Anza's deux à ce qui deviendrait San Francisco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é um ambiente interativo para estudar a 
exploração e a colonização de Spain de Alta Califórnia 
(1774-1776). Os diários e as letras (disponíveis  em inglês e
em espanhol), os mapas e as rotas da fuga, o desenho e as fotos todos 
recreiam um timeline vivo do passado e fornecem originais preliminares
e os recursos dos multimedia que cobrem expedições de Juan Bautista 
de Anza dois a o que se transformaria San Francisco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è un ambiente interattivo per studiare 
l'esplorazione e la colonizzazione della Spagna di Alta la California 
(1774-1776). I diari e le lettere (disponibili sia in inglese 
che in spagnolo), i programmi e gli itinerari della traccia, 
l'illustrazione e le foto tutti ricreano un timeline vivente 
dell'esperienza e forniscono i documenti primari e le risorse di 
multimedia che riguardano le spedizioni del Juan Bautista de Anza due 
a che cosa si transformerebbe in in San Francisco.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">είναι ένα διαλογικό περιβάλλον για τη μελέτη της 
εξερεύνησης και της αποίκισης της Ισπανίας Alta Καλιφόρνια 
(1774-1776). Τα ημερολόγια και οι επιστολές (διαθέσιμα και
στα αγγλικά και σε ισπανικά), οι χάρτες και οι διαδρομές ιχνών, 
το σχέδιο και οι φωτογραφίες όλοι αναδημιουργούν μια υπόδειξη ως 
προς το χρόνο διαβίωσης του προηγούμενου και παρέχουν τα αρχικά 
έγγραφα και τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς πολυμέσων που καλύπτουν 
Juan bautista δύο αποστολές de Anza's σε αυτό που θα 
γινόταν Σαν Φρανσίσκο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es un ambiente interactivo para estudiar la 
exploración y la colonización de España de Alta California 
(1774-1776). Los diarios y las cartas (disponibles en inglés y 
español), las correspondencias y las rutas del rastro, el gráfico y 
las fotos todas reconstruyen un timeline vivo del pasado y 
proporcionan a documentos primarios y a los recursos de las 
multimedias que cubren a expediciones de Juan Bautista de Anza dos a 
qué se convirtió en San Francisco.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206638</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105818</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/web-de-anza</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
