<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107820</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107820</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086993</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Momentum Was Catching On:" Lillian Roberts Describes Organizing Hospital Workers in New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Das Momentum War Anziehend An:" Lillian 
Roberts beschreibt, Krankenhaus-Arbeiter zu organisieren in New York 
City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"L'Élan Était allumé Contagieux :" 
Lillian Roberts décrit organiser des ouvriers d'hôpital à New
York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O Momentum Era Catching Sobre:" Lillian 
Roberts descreve organizar trabalhadores do hospital em New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"La Quantità di moto Era Catching Sopra:" 
Lillian Roberts descrive organizzare gli operai dell'ospedale a 
New York City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η ορμή επίανε σε:" Το Lillian Roberts 
περιγράφει την οργάνωση των εργαζομένων νοσοκομείων στην πόλη της
Νέας Υόρκης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"El Ímpetu Era Catching Encendido:" Lillian
Roberts describe el ordenar de trabajadores del hospital en New York 
City</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Municipal workers led a wave of strikes that made the 1960_s and early 1970_s a highpoint for organized labor militancy in New York City. Teachers, social workers, sanitation workers, and parks employees all fought to improve work conditions, low-paying wage scales, and to reform the city_s social services. Lillian Roberts arrived in New York in 1965 to organize low-paid and often disrespected hospital workers for American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees (AFSCME). At the time, AFSCME was competing with the Teamsters to represent the health workers, and the struggle was intense enough for Roberts to carry a brick in her purse. An African-American woman who had grown up on welfare in Chicago, Roberts proved adept at organizing hospital workers, many of whom were African-American women. She and AFSCME prevailed, paving the way for their local D.C. 37 to become the dominant New York municipal union.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Städtische Arbeiter führten eine Welle der 
Schläge, die das 1960_s und das frühe 1970_s ein highpoint für 
organisierten Arbeitsmilitancy in New York City bildeten. 
Lehrer, Sozialarbeiter, Hygienearbeiter und Parkangestellte 
kämpften ganz, um Arbeit Zustände zu verbessern und niedrig-zahlten 
Lohnskalen, und die city_s Sozialeinrichtungen zu verbessern. 
Lillian Roberts kam in New York 1965 an, um die 
niedrig-zahlenden und häufig respektlos behandelten 
Krankenhausarbeiter für amerikanische Vereinigung des Zustandes, der 
Grafschaft und der städtischen Angestellten (AFSCME) zu organisieren.
Zur Zeit konkurrierte AFSCME mit dem Teamsters, um die 
Gesundheit Arbeiter darzustellen, und der Kampf war genug intensiv, 
damit Roberts einen Ziegelstein in ihrem Geldbeutel trägt. Eine
Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Frau, die auf Wohlfahrt in Chicago 
aufgewachsen war, Roberts prüfte Adepten an organisierenden 
Krankenhausarbeitern, viele von, waren wem Afrikanisch-Amerikanische 
Frauen. Sie und AFSCME herschten vor und pflasterten die Methode
für ihren lokalen Gleichstrom 37, der dominierende New York 
städtische Anschluß zu werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les ouvriers municipaux ont mené une vague des 
grèves qui ont fait le 1960_s et le 1970_s tôt un sommet pour le
militantisme de travail organisé à New York City. Les 
professeurs, les ouvriers sociaux, les ouvriers d'hygiène, et les 
employés de parcs ont tout combattu pour améliorer des états de 
travail, bas-payant des échelles des salaires, et pour reformer les 
services sociaux de city_s. Lillian Roberts est arrivé à New 
York en 1965 pour organiser les ouvriers sous-payé et souvent 
traités sans respect d'hôpital pour la fédération américaine de 
l'état, du comté, et des employés municipaux (AFSCME). 
Lorsque, AFSCME concurrençait le Teamsters pour représenter le
personnel sanitaire, et la lutte étaient assez intenses pour que 
Roberts porte une brique dans sa bourse. Une femme afro-américaine
qui avait grandi sur le bien-être Chicago, Roberts a prouvé l'adepte
aux ouvriers d'organisation d'hôpital, beaucoup de qui étaient les 
femmes afro-américaines. Elle et AFSCME ont régné, préparant le
terrain pour leur dc local 37 de devenir l'union municipale dominante 
de New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os trabalhadores municipais conduziram a uma onda 
das batidas que fizeram o 1960_s e o 1970_s adiantado um highpoint 
para o militancy labor organizado em New York City. Os 
professores, os trabalhadores sociais, os trabalhadores do sanitation,
e os empregados dos parques lutaram toda para melhorar condições do 
trabalho, baixo-pagando escalas de salário, e para reformar os 
serviços sociais dos city_s. Lillian Roberts chegou em New York
em 1965 para organizar trabalhadores baixo-pagos e frequentemente 
disrespected do hospital para o federation americano do estado, do 
condado, e dos empregados municipais (AFSCME). Então, AFSCME 
estava competindo com o Teamsters para representar os trabalhadores de
saúde, e o esforço eram intensos bastante para que Roberts carregue 
um tijolo em sua bolsa. Uma mulher Africano-Americana que 
crescesse acima no bem-estar em Chicago, Roberts provou o adept nos 
trabalhadores organizando do hospital, muitos de quem eram mulheres 
Africano-Americanas. E AFSCME prevaleceram, pavimentando a 
maneira para sua C.C. local 37 transformar-se a união municipal 
dominante de New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gli operai comunali hanno condotto un'onda dei 
colpi che hanno fatto il 1960_s ed il 1970_s iniziale un highpoint per
militanza di lavoro organizzata a New York City. Gli 
insegnanti, gli operai sociali, gli operai di risanamento e gli 
impiegati dei parchi interamente hanno combattuto per migliorare gli 
stati del lavoro, basso-pagando le scale di stipendio e per riformare 
i servizi sociali dei city_s. Lillian Roberts è arrivato a New 
York in 1965 per organizzare basso-low-paid e gli operai spesso 
disrespected dell'ospedale per federazione americana di 
Dichiarano, contea ed impiegati comunali (AFSCME). Quando, 
AFSCME stava competendo al Teamsters per rappresentare gli operai di 
salute e la lotta erano abbastanza intensi affinchè Roberts 
trasportino un mattone in sua borsa. Una donna 
Africano-Americana che si era sviluppata in su su benessere in 
Chicago, Roberts ha dimostrato il adept agli operai d'organizzazione 
dell'ospedale, molti di chi erano donne Africano-Americane. Lei 
ed AFSCME sono prevalso, aprendo la strada per il loro dc locale 37 
transformarsi in nell'unione comunale dominante de New York.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι δημοτικοί εργαζόμενοι οδήγησαν ένα κύμα των 
απεργιών που έκανε το 1960_s και το πρόωρο 1970_s μια κορυφή
για την οργανωμένη μαχητικότητα εργασίας στην πόλη της Νέας 
Υόρκης. Οι δάσκαλοι, οι κοινωνικοί λειτουργοί, οι 
εργαζόμενοι υγιεινής, και οι υπάλληλοι όλοι πάρκων πάλεψαν για 
να βελτιώσουν τους όρους εργασίας, χαμηλός-πληρώνοντας τις 
κλίμακες αμοιβών, και για να μεταρρυθμίσουν τις κοινωνικές 
υπηρεσίες city_s. Το Lillian Roberts έφθασε στη Νέα 
Υόρκη το 1965 για να οργανώσει χαμηλόμισθο και συχνά οι 
εργαζόμενοι νοσοκομείων για την αμερικανική ομοσπονδία του 
κράτους, του νομού, και των δημοτικών υπαλλήλων (AFSCME). 
Στο χρόνο, AFSCME ανταγωνιζόταν με το Teamsters για να 
αντιπροσωπεύσει τους εργαζομένους στον ιατρικό κλάδο, και η 
προσπάθεια ήταν αρκετά έντονη για Roberts για να φέρει ένα 
τούβλο στο πορτοφόλι της. Μια αφρικανικός-αμερικανική 
γυναίκα που είχε μεγαλώσει στην ευημερία στο Σικάγο, Roberts 
αποδείχθηκε έμπειρη στην οργάνωση των εργαζομένων νοσοκομείων, 
πολλοί από τους οποίους ήταν αφρικανικός-αμερικανικές γυναίκες.
Αυτή και AFSCME επικράτησαν, προετοιμάζω το έδαφος για το
τοπικό ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ τους 37 για να γίνουν η κυρίαρχη 
δημοτική ένωση της Νέας Υόρκης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los trabajadores municipales condujeron una onda 
de las huelgas que hicieron el 1960_s y el 1970_s temprano un 
highpoint para la militancia de trabajo ordenada en New York City. 
Los profesores, los trabajadores sociales, los trabajadores del 
saneamiento, y los empleados de los parques lucharon todo para mejorar
condiciones del trabajo, bajo-pagando escalas de salario, y para 
reformar los servicios sociales de los city_s. Lillian Roberts 
llegó en Nueva York en 1965 para ordenar a trabajadores bajo-pagados 
y a menudo disrespected del hospital para la federación americana del
estado, del condado, y de los empleados municipales (AFSCME). 
Cuando, AFSCME competía con el Teamsters para representar los 
ayudantes de sanidad, y la lucha eran bastante intensos para que 
Roberts lleve un ladrillo en su monedero. Una mujer 
Africano-Americana que había crecido para arriba en bienestar en 
Chicago, Roberts probó a adepto en los trabajadores de ordenación 
del hospital, muchos de quién eran mujeres Africano-Americanas. 
Ella y AFSCME prevalecieron, pavimentando la manera para su dc 
local 37 de hacer la unión municipal dominante de Nueva York.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086993</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107820</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-momentum-was-catching-on-lillian-roberts-describes-organizing-hospital-workers-in-new-york-city</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
