<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104866</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104866</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206690</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology Education</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie-Ausbildung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et éducation de technologie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e instrução da tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza ed educazione di tecnologia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκπαίδευση επιστήμης και τεχνολογίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y educación de la tecnología</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">includes booklets on cells, genes, health, chemistry, and medicines. The booklets explore advances in the development and delivery of drugs, links between genes and diseases, how genes work, the body's reaction to medicines, and the hundreds of thousands of molecules that perform specialized functions inside the fundamental unit of life (the cell). One booklet, The Structures of Life, features stories designed to inspire young people to consider careers in biomedical research.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">enthält Broschüren auf Zellen, Genen, 
Gesundheit, Chemie und Medizin. Die Broschüren erforschen 
Fortschritte in der Entwicklung und in der Anlieferung der Drogen, 
Links zwischen Genen und Krankheiten, wie Gene arbeiten, die Reaktion 
des Körpers zur Medizin und die Hunderte von Tausenden Molekülen, 
die fachkundige Funktionen innerhalb der grundlegenden Maßeinheit des
Lebens durchführen (die Zelle). Eine Broschüre, die Strukturen
des Lebens, kennzeichnet die Geschichten, die konzipiert sind, um 
junge Leute anzuspornen, Karrieren in der biomedizinischen Forschung 
zu betrachten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">inclut des livrets sur des cellules, des gènes, 
la santé, la chimie, et des médecines. Les livrets explorent 
des avances dans le développement et la livraison des drogues, des 
liens entre les gènes et les maladies, comment les gènes 
fonctionnent, la réaction du corps aux médecines, et les centaines 
de milliers de molécules qui exécutent des fonctions spécialisées 
à l'intérieur de l'unité fondamentale de la vie (la cellule). 
Un livret, les structures de la vie, comporte des histoires 
conçues pour inspirer les jeunes considérer des carrières dans la 
recherche biomédicale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">inclui livretos em pilhas, em genes, em saúde, em
chemistry, e em medicinas. Os livretos exploram avanços no 
desenvolvimento e na entrega das drogas, ligações entre genes e 
doenças, como os genes trabalham, a reação do corpo às medicinas, 
e as centenas dos milhares das moléculas que executam funções 
especializadas dentro da unidade fundamental da vida (a pilha). 
Um livreto, as estruturas da vida, caracteriza as histórias 
projetadas inspirar povos novos considerar carreiras na pesquisa 
biomedical.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">include i libretti sulle cellule, sui geni, sulla 
salute, sulla chimica e sulle medicine. I libretti esplorano gli
avanzamenti nello sviluppo e nella consegna delle droghe, i 
collegamenti fra i geni e le malattie, come i geni funzionano, la 
reazione del corpo alle medicine e le centinaia delle migliaia delle 
molecole che effettuano le funzioni specializzate all'interno 
dell'unità fondamentale di vita (la cellula). Un libretto, le 
strutture di vita, caratterizza le storia destinate per ispirare i 
giovani considerare le carriere nella ricerca biomedica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιλαμβάνει τα βιβλιάρια στα κύτταρα, τα γονίδια, την
υγεία, τη χημεία, και τα φάρμακα. Τα βιβλιάρια ερευνούν τις
προόδους στην ανάπτυξη και την παράδοση των φαρμάκων, τις 
συνδέσεις μεταξύ των γονιδίων και των ασθενειών, πώς τα γονίδια 
λειτουργούν, η αντίδραση του σώματος στα φάρμακα, και τις 
εκατοντάδες χιλιάδες των μορίων που εκτελούν τις εξειδικευμένες 
λειτουργίες μέσα στη θεμελιώδη μονάδα της ζωής (το κύτταρο). 
Ένα βιβλιάριο, οι δομές της ζωής, χαρακτηρίζει τις 
ιστορίες με σκοπό να εμπνεύσουν τους νέους για να εξετάσει τις 
σταδιοδρομίες στη βιοϊατρική έρευνα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">incluye los libretes en las células, los genes, 
salud, química, y medicinas. Los libretes exploran avances en 
el desarrollo y la salida de drogas, conexiones entre los genes y las 
enfermedades, cómo los genes trabajan, la reacción del cuerpo a las 
medicinas, y los centenares de millares de moléculas que realicen 
funciones especializadas dentro de la unidad fundamental de la vida 
(la célula). Un librete, las estructuras de la vida, ofrece las
historias diseñadas para inspirar a gente joven que considere 
carreras en la investigación biomédica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206690</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104866</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/science-and-technology-education</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
