<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103237</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103237</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206132</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Kids Corner Endangered Species Program</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zicklein Bringen Gefährdetes Sorte-Programm In 
Verlegenheit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Gosses Acculent Le Programme Mis en danger 
d'Espèces</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os Miúdos Encurralam O Programa Posto em perigo 
Da Espécie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I Capretti Accantonano Il Programma In pericolo Di
Specie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Διακυβευμένο πρόγραμμα ειδών κατσικιών γωνία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Los Cabritos Arrinconan Programa Puesto en peligro
De la Especie</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">helps students and teachers find information on threatened and endangered species. In addition to providing fact sheets, activities, and suggestions about what kids can do to help, the site links to the Endangered Species Program website, where you'll find descriptions and images of threatened and endangered species, announcements of additions to the lists of threatened and endangered species, and information on programs and activities.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Hilfen Kursteilnehmer und Lehrer finden 
Informationen über bedrohte und gefährdete Sorte. Zusätzlich 
zum Zur Verfügung stellen der Tatsache Blätter, können Aktivitäten
und Vorschläge über was kids, tun, um, die Site-Links zur 
gefährdeten Sorte-Programmweb site zu helfen, in der Sie 
Beschreibungen und Bilder der bedrohten und gefährdeten Sorten, 
Ansagen von Hinzufügung zu den Listen der bedrohten und gefährdeten 
Sorten finden, und Informationen über Programme und Aktivitäten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les étudiants et les professeurs d'aides trouvent
l'information sur des espèces menacées et mises en danger. 
En plus de prévoir des fiches documentaires , les activités, 
et les suggestions au sujet de ce qui badine peuvent faire pour aider,
les liens de site au site Web mis en danger de programme 
d'Espèces, où vous trouverez des descriptions et des images des 
espèces menacées et mises en danger, annonces des ajouts aux 
listes d'espèces menacées et mises en danger, et l'information 
sur des programmes et des activités.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">os estudantes e os professores das ajudas 
encontram a informação na espécie ameaçada e posta em perigo. 
Além a fornecer folhas do fato, as atividades, e as sugestões 
sobre o que caçoa podem fazer para ajudar, as ligações do local ao 
Web site posto em perigo do programa da espécie, onde você 
encontrará descrições e imagens das espécies ameaçadas e postas 
em perigo, anúncios das adições às listas de espécies ameaçadas 
e postas em perigo, e informação em programas e em atividades.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">gli allievi e gli insegnanti di aiuti trovano le 
informazioni sulla specie minacciata ed in pericolo. Oltre che 
fornire i fogli di fatto, le attività ed i suggerimenti circa che 
cosa scherza possono fare per aiutare, i collegamenti del luogo al Web
site in pericolo di programma di specie, dove troverete le descrizioni
e le immagini delle specie minacciate ed in pericolo, annunci delle 
aggiunte alle liste delle specie minacciate ed in pericolo e le 
informazioni sui programmi e sulle attività.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">οι σπουδαστές και οι δάσκαλοι οδηγιών βρίσκουν τις 
πληροφορίες για τα απειλητικά και απειλούμενα υπό εξαφάνιση 
είδη. Εκτός από την παροχή των ενημερωτικών δελτίων, των 
δραστηριοτήτων, και των προτάσεων για αυτά που τα κατσίκια 
μπορούν να κάνουν για να βοηθήσουν, οι συνδέσεις περιοχών με το 
διακυβευμένο ιστοχώρο προγράμματος ειδών, όπου θα βρείτε τις 
περιγραφές και τις εικόνες των απειλητικών και απειλούμενων υπό 
εξαφάνιση ειδών, ανακοινώσεις των προσθηκών στους καταλόγους 
απειλητικών και απειλούμενων υπό εξαφάνιση ειδών, και 
πληροφοριών για τα προγράμματα και τις δραστηριότητες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">los estudiantes y los profesores de las ayudas 
encuentran la información sobre especie amenazada y puesta en 
peligro. Además de proporcionar a las hojas del hecho, las 
actividades, y las sugerencias sobre qué embroma pueden hacer para 
ayudar, las conexiones del sitio al Web site puesto en peligro del 
programa de la especie, en donde usted encontrará descripciones e 
imágenes de las especies amenazadas y puestas en peligro, avisos de 
adiciones a las listas de especies amenazadas y puestas en peligro, e 
información sobre programas y actividades.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206132</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103237</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/kids-corner-endangered-species-program</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
