<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/212792407</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>212792407</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211524</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Periodic Table</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Periodische Tabelle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tableau Périodique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tabela Periódica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tabella Periodica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιοδικός πίνακας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Vector Periódico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A reference and instruction for scientists of all levels. What chemistry software package would be complete without a periodic table? The actual use of this applet in the classroom is quite simple. Simply click on the desired element and data as well as a graphical plot of electron configurations will be displayed. This particular version shows the electronic configuration of the element in the panel on the right. Future versions of this applet will show relative atomic sizes, electronegativities and other periodic trends, as well as extensive atomic data.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Referenz und eine Anweisung für 
Wissenschaftler aller Stufen. Welches Chemieanwendungspaket 
würde ohne eine periodische Tabelle komplett sein? Der 
tatsächliche Gebrauch dieses applet im Klassenzimmer ist ziemlich 
einfach. Klicken Sie einfach an das gewünschte Element und die 
Daten, sowie ein graphischer Plot der Elektronkonfigurationen 
angezeigt wird. Diese bestimmte Version zeigt die elektronische 
Konfiguration des Elements im Panel auf dem Recht. Zukünftige 
Versionen dieses applet zeigen relative Atomgrößen, 
electronegativities und andere periodische Tendenzen, sowie 
umfangreiche Atomdaten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une référence et une instruction pour des 
scientifiques de tous les niveaux. Quel progiciel de chimie 
serait complet sans table périodique ? L'utilisation réelle de
cet applet dans la salle de classe est tout à fait simple. 
Simplement le clic sur l'élément et les données 
désirés aussi bien qu'un traçage graphique des configurations 
d'électron sera affiché. Cette version particulière montre la
configuration électronique de l'élément dans le panneau du côté 
droit. Les futures versions de cet applet montreront des tailles
atomiques relatives, electronegativities et d'autres tendances 
périodiques, aussi bien que des données atomiques étendues.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma referência e uma instrução para cientistas 
de todos os níveis. Que pacote de software do chemistry estaria
completo sem uma tabela periódica? O uso real deste applet na 
sala de aula é completamente simples. Estale simplesmente sobre
o elemento e os dados desejados assim como um lote gráfico de 
configurações do elétron será indicado. Esta versão 
particular mostra a configuração eletrônica do elemento no painel 
na direita. As versões futuras deste applet mostrarão tamanhos
atômicos relativos, electronegativities e outras tendências 
periódicas, as.well.as dados atômicos extensivos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un riferimento e un'istruzione per gli scienziati 
di tutti i livelli. Che pacchetto di programmi di chimica 
sarebbe completo senza una tabella periodica? L'uso reale di 
questo applet nell'aula è abbastanza semplice. Scatti 
semplicemente sopra l'elemento ed i dati voluti come pure un diagramma
grafico delle configurazioni dell'elettrone sarà visualizzato. 
Questa versione particolare mostra la configurazione elettronica
dell'elemento nel pannello a destra. Le versioni future di 
questo applet mostreranno i formati atomici relativi, 
electronegativities ed altre tendenze periodiche, così come i vasti 
dati atomici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια αναφορά και μια οδηγία για τους επιστήμονες όλων 
των επιπέδων. Ποιο πακέτο λογισμικού χημείας θα ήταν 
πλήρης χωρίς έναν περιοδικό πίνακα; Η πραγματική χρήση 
αυτού του applet στην τάξη είναι αρκετά απλή. Απλά 
χτυπήστε στο επιθυμητά στοιχείο και τα στοιχεία καθώς επίσης και
μια γραφική πλοκή των διαμορφώσεων ηλεκτρονίων θα παρουσιαστεί. 
Αυτή η ιδιαίτερη έκδοση εμφανίζει ηλεκτρονική διαμόρφωση 
του στοιχείου στην επιτροπή στο δικαίωμα. Οι μελλοντικές 
εκδόσεις αυτού του applet θα εμφανίσουν τα σχετικά ατομικά 
μεγέθη, τα electronegativities και άλλες περιοδικές τάσεις, 
καθώς επίσης και εκτενή ατομικά στοιχεία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una referencia y una instrucción para los 
científicos de todos los niveles. ¿Qué paquete de software de 
la química sería completa sin un vector periódico? El uso 
real de este applet en la sala de clase es absolutamente simple. 
Haga clic simplemente encendido el elemento y los datos deseados
tan bien como un diagrama gráfico de las configuraciones del 
electrón será visualizado. Esta versión determinada muestra 
la configuración electrónica del elemento en el panel a la derecha. 
Las versiones futuras de este applet mostrarán las tallas 
atómicas relativas, electronegativities y otras tendencias 
periódicas, así como datos atómicos extensos.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CHEMISTRY COLLECTIVE
FN:CHEMISTRY COLLECTIVE
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211524</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>212792407</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/periodic-table</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
