<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108302</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108302</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212384</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Mars Student Imaging Project (MSIP)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mars Kursteilnehmer-Belichtung Projekt (MSIP)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Projet de Formation image D'Étudiant de Mars 
(MSIP)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Projeto Da Imagem latente Do Estudante De Marte 
(MSIP)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Progetto Di Formazione immagine Dell'Allievo Del 
Marte (MSIP)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πρόγραμμα απεικόνισης σπουδαστών του Αρη (MSIP)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Proyecto De la Proyección de imagen Del 
Estudiante De Marte (MSIP)</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website features NASA and Arizona State University's Mars Education Program, which offers students the opportunity to be involved in authentic Mars research. Students and teachers are able to perform an in-depth analysis of a site on Mars using the THEMIS visible wavelength camera onboard the Mars Odyssey spacecraft. The website features everything that is necessary for teams of students in grades 5 through college sophomore level to participate in this project, including activity formats, curriculum, downloads, and applications.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site kennzeichnet Programm Ausbildung 
Mars die NASA und Arizona-der Landesuniversität, das Kursteilnehmern 
die Gelegenheit anbietet, in authentische Mars Forschung mit 
einbezogen zu werden. Kursteilnehmer und Lehrer können, eine 
eingehende Analyse einer Sites auf Mars mit der THEMIS sichtbaren 
Wellenlängekamera an Bord des Mars Odysseeraumfahrzeugs 
durchzuführen. Die Web site kennzeichnet alles, das notwendig 
für Teams der Kursteilnehmer in Graden 5 durch 
HochschulCollege-Student im 2. Jahrstufe ist, um an diesem Projekt, einschließlich 
Aktivität Formate, Lehrplan, Downloads und Anwendungen teilzunehmen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web comporte le programme d'éducation de 
Mars de l'université de l'Etat de la NASA et de l'Arizona, qui donne 
à des étudiants l'occasion d'être impliqué dans la recherche 
authentique de Mars. Les étudiants et les professeurs peuvent 
exécuter une analyse détaillée d'un site sur Mars en utilisant 
l'appareil-photo visible de longueur d'onde de THEMIS à bord du 
vaisseau spatial d'odyssée de Mars. Le site Web comporte tout 
qui est nécessaire pour des équipes d'étudiants dans les 
catégories 5 par le niveau d'étudiant en deuxième année 
d'université pour participer à ce projet, y compris des formats 
d'activité, le programme d'études, des téléchargements, et des 
applications.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site caracteriza o programa da 
instrução de Marte de universidade de estado da NASA e do arizona, 
que oferece a estudantes a oportunidade de ser envolvido na pesquisa 
authentic de Marte. Os estudantes e os professores podem  
executar uma análise in-depth de um local em Marte usando a câmera 
visível do wavelength de THEMIS onboard a nave espacial do odyssey de
Marte. O Web site caracteriza tudo que é necessário para 
equipes dos estudantes nas classes 5 através do nível do estudante 
de segundo ano de universidade da faculdade para participar neste 
projeto, including formatos da atividade, curriculum, downloads, e 
aplicações.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site caratterizza la NASA e l'Arizona 
Dichiara il programma di formazione del Marte dell'università,
che offre ad allievi l'opportunità di partecipare alla ricerca 
autentica del Marte. Gli allievi e gli insegnanti possono 
effettuare un'analisi approfondita di un luogo su Marte usando la 
macchina fotografica visibile di lunghezza d'onda di THEMIS a bordo 
della nave spaziale di odyssey del Marte. Il Web site 
caratterizza tutto che sia necessario per le squadre di allievi nei 
gradi 5 attraverso il livello del sophomore dell'università da 
partecipare a questo progetto, compreso i formati di attività, il 
programma di studi, i trasferimenti dal sistema centrale verso i 
satelliti e le applicazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος χαρακτηρίζει το πρόγραμμα 
εκπαίδευσης του Αρη του πανεπιστημίου της NASA και κράτους της 
Αριζόνα, το οποίο προσφέρει στους σπουδαστές την ευκαιρία που 
περιλαμβάνεται στην αυθεντική έρευνα του Αρη. Οι σπουδαστές
και οι δάσκαλοι είναι σε θέση να εκτελέσουν μια σε βάθος ανάλυση
μιας περιοχής στον Αρη χρησιμοποιώντας την ορατή φωτογραφική 
μηχανή μήκους κύματος THEMIS επί του διαστημικού σκάφους 
οδύσσειας του Αρη. Ο ιστοχώρος χαρακτηρίζει όλα που είναι 
απαραίτητα για τις ομάδες των σπουδαστών στους βαθμούς 5 μέσω του
επιπέδου δευτεροετών φοιτητών κολλεγίων για να συμμετέχουν σε 
αυτό το πρόγραμμα, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των μορφών δραστηριότητας,
πρόγραμμα σπουδών, μεταφορτώνουν, και εφαρμογές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site ofrece el programa de la educación 
de Marte de la universidad de estado de la NASA y del Arizona, que 
ofrece a estudiantes la oportunidad de estar implicado en la 
investigación auténtica de Marte. Los estudiantes y los 
profesores pueden realizar un análisis profundizado de un sitio en 
Marte usando la cámara fotográfica visible de la longitud de onda de
THEMIS onboard la nave espacial de la odisea de Marte. El Web 
site ofrece todo que sea necesario para los equipos de estudiantes en 
los grados 5 a través de nivel del estudiante de segundo año de la 
universidad participar en este proyecto, incluyendo formatos de la 
actividad, plan de estudios, transferencias directas, y aplicaciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212384</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108302</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/syllabus-technology-for-higher-education</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
