<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103260</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103260</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206477</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Elections</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wahlen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Élections</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Eleições</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Elezioni</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εκλογές</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Elecciones</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">looks at American political parties of the past, presidential inaugurations, images of presidents and first ladies, our first uniform election day, political cartoons by Herbert Block (Herblock) and Pat Oliphant, the 1877 electoral commission created by Congress to resolve the disputed presidential election of 1876, the 19th and 24th amendments (ending the poll tax and giving women the right to vote), and the Nixon-Kennedy debates.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Blicke auf amerikanische politische Parteien
der letzten, Präsidenteneinweihungen, Bilder der Präsidenten und der
ersten Damen, unser erster konstanter Wahltag, politische Karikaturen 
durch Herbert Block (Herblock) und Klaps Oliphant, die Wahlkommission 
1877 erstellt von Congress, um die diskutierte Präsidentenwahl von 
1876 zu beheben, die 19. und 24. Änderungen (die Gemeindeabgabe 
beendend und Frauen das Recht gebend zu wählen) und die Nixon-Kennedy
Debatten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">regards aux parties politiques américaines des 
inaugurations passées et présidentielles, les images des présidents
et les premières dames, notre premier jour d'élection uniforme, les 
dessins animés politiques par Herbert Block (Herblock) et le 
tapotement Oliphant, la commission 1877 électorale créée par 
Congress pour résoudre l'élection présidentielle contestée de 
1876, les 19èmes et 24èmes amendements (terminant l'impôt local et 
donnant à femmes le droit de voter), et les discussions de 
Nixon-Kennedy.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">olhares em partidos políticos americanos dos 
inaugurations passados, presidenciais, imagens dos presidentes e as 
primeiras senhoras, nosso primeiro dia de eleição uniforme, cartoons
políticos por Herbert Obstrução (Herblock) e pat Oliphant, o 
commission 1877 electoral criado por Congress para resolver a 
eleição presidencial disputada de 1876, as 19as e 2âs emendas (que 
terminam o imposto de votação e que dão a mulheres a direita 
votar), e os debates de Nixon-Kennedy.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">sguardi ai partiti politici americani delle 
inaugurazioni passate e presidenziali, immagini dei presidenti e prime
signore, il nostro primo giorno di elezione dell'uniforme, fumetti 
politici da Herbert Block (Herblock) e picchiettio Oliphant, la 
commissione elettorale 1877 creata da Congress per risolvere 
l'elezione presidenziale disputata di 1876, le diciannovesime e 
ventiquattresime correzioni (che concludono la tassa di scrutinio e 
che danno a donne la destra votare) ed i dibattiti di Nixon-Kennedy.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εξετάζει τα αμερικανικά πολιτικά κόμματα του 
παρελθόντος, προεδρικές εγκαινιάσεις, εικόνες των Προέδρων και 
των πρώτων κυριών, η πρώτη ομοιόμορφη ημέρα εκλογής μας, 
πολιτικά κινούμενα σχέδια από Herbert Block (Herblock) 
και Pat Oliphant, η εκλογική επιτροπή 1877 που 
δημιουργείται από το συνέδριο για να επιλύσει τη συζητημένη 
προεδρική εκλογή 1876, τις 19$ες και 24$ες τροποποιήσεις (που 
τελειώνουν τον κεφαλικό φόρο και που δίνουν στις γυναίκες το 
δικαίωμα να ψηφίσει), και τις συζητήσεις νηξον- Kennedy.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">miradas en los partidos políticos americanos de 
las inauguraciones últimas, presidenciales, imágenes de presidentes 
y primeras señoras, nuestro primer día de elección del uniforme, 
historietas políticas de Herberto Block (Herblock) y palmadita 
Oliphant, la comisión electoral 1877 creada por Congress para 
resolver la elección presidencial disputada de 1876, las 
diecinueveavo y 24tas enmiendas (que terminan el impuesto de encuesta 
y que dan a mujeres la derecha de votar), y los discusiones de 
Nixon-Kennedy.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206477</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103260</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/elections</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
