<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107755</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107755</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213194</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Winogradsky Column Unit: Chemical and Physical Change</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Winogradsky Spalte-Maßeinheit: Chemikalie 
und körperliche Änderung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Unité De Colonne de Winogradsky : Produit 
chimique et changement physique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Unidade Da Coluna De Winogradsky: Produto 
químico e mudança física</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Unità Della Colonna Di Winogradsky: 
Prodotto chimico e cambiamento fisico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μονάδα στηλών Winogradsky: Χημική και φυσική 
αλλαγή</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Unidad De la Columna De Winogradsky: 
Producto químico y cambio físico</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This two-part activity leads Physical Science students, grades 8-12, to explore chemical change using Winogradsky Columns. Part 1 constructs student concepts concerning chemical and physical changes. Part 2 asks students to compare physical versus chemical changes and observe chemical changes in a Winogradsky Column, and teaches them to build their own column. It includes the following student pages: introductory lesson, Winogradsky Column lesson, challenge your thinking activity sheet, how to make a Winogradsky Column, how to create an observation journal, and journal evaluation sheet.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese zweiteilige Aktivität führt körperliche 
Wissenschaft Kursteilnehmer, Grade 8-12, chemische Umwandlung mit 
Winogradsky Spalten zu erforschen. Der Teil 1 konstruiert die 
Kursteilnehmerkonzepte hinsichtlich sind der Chemikalie- und 
Systemteständerungen. Der Teil 2 bittet Kursteilnehmer, 
Systemtest gegen chemische Umwandlungen zu vergleichen und chemische 
Umwandlungen in einer Winogradsky Spalte zu beobachten und 
unterrichtet sie, ihre eigene Spalte aufzubauen. Er enthält die
folgenden Kursteilnehmerseiten: einleitende Lektion, Winogradsky
Spaltelektion, fordern Ihr denkendes Aktivität Blatt heraus, wie man 
eine Winogradsky Spalte bildet, wie man ein Beobachtung Journal- und 
Journalauswertungsblatt herstellt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette activité en deux parties mène les 
étudiants physiques de la Science, catégories 8-12, à explorer le 
changement chimique en utilisant des colonnes de Winogradsky. La
partie 1 construit des concepts d'étudiant au sujet des changements 
de produit chimique et d'examen médical. La partie 2 demande à
des étudiants de comparer l'examen médical contre les changements 
chimiques et d'observer les changements chimiques dans une colonne de 
Winogradsky, et les enseigne à construire leur propre colonne. 
Elle inclut les pages suivantes d'étudiant : la leçon 
préliminaire, leçon de colonne de Winogradsky, défient votre 
feuille de pensée d'activité, comment faire une colonne de 
Winogradsky, comment créer une feuille de journal d'observation, et 
d'évaluation de journal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta atividade two-part conduz a estudantes 
físicos da ciência, classes 8-12, explorar a mudança química 
usando colunas de Winogradsky. A parte 1 constrói os conceitos 
do estudante a respeito das mudanças do produto químico e do exame. 
A parte 2 pede que os estudantes comparem o exame contra 
mudanças químicas e observem mudanças químicas em uma coluna de 
Winogradsky, e ensina-as construir sua própria coluna. Inclui 
as seguintes páginas do estudante: a lição introdutória, 
lição da coluna de Winogradsky, desafia sua folha pensando da 
atividade, como fazer uma coluna de Winogradsky, como criar uma folha 
do jornal da observação, e da avaliação do jornal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa attività in due parti conduce gli allievi 
fisici di scienza, gradi 8-12, esplorare il cambiamento chimico usando
le colonne di Winogradsky. La parte 1 costruisce i concetti 
dell'allievo riguardo ai cambiamenti di fisico medica e del prodotto 
chimico. La parte 2 chiede agli allievi di confrontare il fisico
medica contro i cambiamenti chimici e di osservare i cambiamenti 
chimici in una colonna di Winogradsky e li insegna costruire la loro 
propria colonna. Include le seguenti pagine dell'allievo: 
la lezione introduttiva, lezione della colonna di Winogradsky, 
sfida il vostro foglio pensante di attività, come fare una colonna di
Winogradsky, come creare un foglio del giornale di osservazione e di 
valutazione del giornale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η διμερής δραστηριότητα οδηγεί τους φυσικούς 
σπουδαστές επιστήμης, βαθμολογεί 8-12, για να ερευνήσει τη 
χημική αλλαγή χρησιμοποιώντας τις στήλες Winogradsky. Το 
μέρος 1 κατασκευάζει τις έννοιες σπουδαστών σχετικά με τις 
χημικές και φυσικές αλλαγές. Το μέρος 2 ζητά από τους 
σπουδαστές για να συγκρίνει τις φυσικές εναντίον χημικές αλλαγές
και να παρατηρήσει τις χημικές αλλαγές σε μια στήλη 
Winogradsky, και τους διδάσκει για να χτίσει τη στήλη τους. 
Περιλαμβάνει τις ακόλουθες σελίδες σπουδαστών: το 
εισαγωγικό μάθημα, μάθημα στηλών Winogradsky, προκαλεί το 
φύλλο δραστηριότητας σκέψης σας, πώς να κάνει μια στήλη 
Winogradsky, πώς να δημιουργήσει ένα φύλλο περιοδικών 
παρατήρησης, και αξιολόγησης περιοδικών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta actividad bipartita conduce a estudiantes 
físicos de la ciencia, grados 8-12, a explorar el cambio químico 
usando las columnas de Winogradsky. La parte 1 construye 
conceptos del estudiante referentes a cambios del producto químico y 
de la comprobación. La parte 2 pide que los estudiantes 
comparen la comprobación contra cambios químicos y que observen 
cambios químicos en una columna de Winogradsky, y los enseña a 
construir su propia columna. Incluye las paginaciones siguientes
del estudiante: la lección introductoria, lección de la 
columna de Winogradsky, desafía su hoja de pensamiento de la 
actividad, cómo hacer una columna de Winogradsky, cómo crear una 
hoja del diario de la observación, y de la evaluación del diario.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:YEVGENY PEVZNER
FN:YEVGENY PEVZNER
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:SHARYN ANNETTE SHELTON
FN:SHARYN ANNETTE SHELTON
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:WESTMINSTER COLLEGE GREAT SALT LAKE PROJECT
FN:WESTMINSTER COLLEGE GREAT SALT LAKE PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213194</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107755</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/winogradsky-column-unit-chemical-and-physical-change</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
