<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103453</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103453</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087263</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">ZeroBio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">ZeroBio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">ZeroBio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">ZeroBio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ZeroBio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ZeroBio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ZeroBio</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Welcome to zeroBio! This is a website for high school science students. You'll find a variety of interactive quizzes, games and puzzles to practice what you're learning in Grade 9 Science, Grade 11 Biology and Grade 12 Biology. There are also some specific student resources for each course. All of the quizzes and games and stuff have grade flags or other symbols like the ones below to help you choose the right content for your course.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Willkommen zum zeroBio! Dieses ist eine Web 
site für High School Wissenschaft Kursteilnehmer. Sie finden 
eine Vielzahl der interaktiven Quizen, der Spiele und der 
Puzzlespiele, um zu üben, was Sie der Wissenschaft in des Grad-9 
erlernen, Biologie 11 ordnen und Biologie 12 ordnen. Es gibt 
auch einige spezifische Kursteilnehmerbetriebsmittel für jeden Kurs. 
Alle Quizen und die Spiele und Material haben 
Gradmarkierungsfahnen oder andere Symbole wie die unten, zum Sie zu 
helfen, den rechten Inhalt für Ihren Kurs zu wählen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Bienvenue au zeroBio ! C'est un site Web pour
des étudiants de la science de lycée. Vous trouverez une 
variété de jeux, de jeux et de puzzles interactifs pour pratiquer ce
que vous apprenez en la Science de la catégorie 9, évaluez la 
biologie 11 et évaluez la biologie 12. Il y a également 
quelques ressources spécifiques d'étudiant pour chaque cours. 
Tous les jeux et jeux et la substance ont des indicateurs de 
catégorie ou d'autres symboles comme ceux ci-dessous pour vous aider 
à choisir le bon contenu pour votre cours.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Boa vinda ao zeroBio! Este é um Web site 
para estudantes da ciência da High School. Você encontrará 
uma variedade de quizzes, de jogos e de enigmas interativos para 
praticar o que você está aprendendo na ciência da classe 9, 
classifica a biologia 11 e classifica a biologia 12. Há também
alguns recursos específicos do estudante para cada curso. Todos
os quizzes e jogos e o material têm bandeiras da classe ou outros 
símbolos como esses abaixo para lhe ajudar escolher o índice direito
para seu curso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Benvenuto allo zeroBio! Ciò è un Web site 
per gli allievi di scienza della High School. Troverete una 
varietà di quiz, di giochi e di puzzle interattivi per esercitarsi in
che cosa state imparando nella scienza del grado 9, classificate la 
biologia 11 e classificate la biologia 12. Ci sono egualmente 
alcune risorse specifiche dell'allievo per ogni corso. Tutti i 
quiz ed i giochi ed il roba hanno le bandierine del grado o 
altri simboli come quei sotto per aiutarli a scegliere il giusto 
soddisfare per il vostro corso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υποδοχή σε zeroBio! Αυτό είναι ένας 
ιστοχώρος για τους σπουδαστές επιστήμης γυμνασίου. Θα 
βρείτε ποικίλους διαλογικούς διαγωνισμοους γνώσεων, παιχνίδια και
οι γρίφοι στην πρακτική τι μαθαίνετε στο βαθμό 9 την επιστήμη, 
βαθμολογούν τη βιολογία 11 και το βαθμό 12 η βιολογία. 
Υπάρχουν επίσης μερικά συγκεκριμένα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς 
σπουδαστών για κάθε σειρά μαθημάτων. Όλα τα διαγωνισμοοι 
γνώσεων και παιχνίδια και η ουσία έχουν τις σημαίες βαθμού ή 
άλλα σύμβολα όπως αυτά για να σας βοηθήσουν κατωτέρω να 
επιλέξετε το σωστό περιεχόμενο για τη σειρά μαθημάτων σας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Recepción al zeroBio! Esto es un Web site 
para los estudiantes de la ciencia de la High School secundaria. 
Usted encontrará una variedad de concursos, de juegos y de 
rompecabezas interactivos para practicar lo que usted está 
aprendiendo en ciencia del grado 9, califica la biología 11 y 
califica la biología 12. Hay también algunos recursos 
específicos del estudiante para cada curso. Todos los concursos
y los juegos y la materia tienen indicadores del grado u otros 
símbolos como los abajo para ayudarle a elegir el contenido derecho 
para su curso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087263</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103453</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/zerobio</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
