<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103363</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103363</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086992</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"The Moment That The Snows Are Melted The Indian Women Begin Their Work": Iroquois Women Work the Fields</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Der Moment, Daß Der Schnee Geschmolzen Wird, 
Fangen Die Indischen Frauen Ihre Arbeit" An: Irokese, den Frauen
bearbeiten, Fängt auf</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Le Moment Que Les Neige Sont fondues Les Femmes 
Indiennes Commencent Leur Travail" : Les femmes de Iroquois 
travaillent les zones</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"O Momento Que As Neves Estão derretidas As 
Mulheres Indian Começam Seu Trabalho": As mulheres do iroquois 
trabalham os campos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Il Momento Che Le Nevi Sono fuse Le Donne Indiane 
Cominciano Il Loro Lavoro": Le donne del iroquois lavorano i 
campi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Η στιγμή ότι τα χιόνια λειώνουν οι ινδικές γυναίκες
αρχίζουν την εργασία τουσ": Iroquois οι γυναίκες 
απασχολούνται στα πεδία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"El Momento Que Las Nieves Están derretidas Las 
Mujeres Indias Comienzan Su Trabajo": Las mujeres del iroquois 
trabajan los campos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Indian people of the Eastern Woodlands (northeastern North America) followed a seasonal schedule of hunting, fishing, gathering wild food, and the cultivation of crops. They relied upon cultivated crops such as corn, beans, and squash for much of their food. Men primarily provided the meat and fish, while women were responsible for supplying cultivated vegetables along with wild berries, nuts, and fruit. While men helped clear the fields, women did the planting, weeding, and harvesting in the warm months. Many European observers remarked upon what they saw as drudgery inflicted upon Indian women. However, Joseph-Franois Lafitau, a Jesuit missionary and writer, was also a keen ethnographic observer of the details of Iroquois life. In this account, he noted the similarities between farm women's work in Europe and among the Iroquois.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Indische Leute des östlichen Waldlandes 
(nordöstliches Nordamerika) folgten einem Saisonzeitplan von Jagd, 
von Fischen, Versammlung von wilder Nahrung und von Bearbeitung der 
Getreide. Sie bauten auf bebaute Getreide wie Mais, Bohnen und 
Kürbis für viel ihrer Nahrung. Männer stellten hauptsächlich
das Fleisch und die Fische zur Verfügung, während Frauen für das 
Angeben des bebauten Gemüses zusammen mit wilden Beeren, Muttern und 
Frucht verantwortlich waren. Während Männer klar halfen, 
fängt, Frauen tat das Errichten, das Säubern und das Ernten
in den warmen Monaten auf. Viele europäische Beobachter 
erwähnten nach, was sie als Schufterei zugefügt nach indischen 
Frauen sahen. Jedoch war Joseph-Franois Lafitau, ein 
Jesuitmissionar und Verfasser, auch ein scharfer ethnographischer 
Beobachter der Details des Irokeselebens. In diesem Konto 
beachtete er die Ähnlichkeiten zwischen Arbeit der Bauernhoffrauen in
Europa und unter dem Irokesen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les  indiens des régfions boisées orientales 
(Amérique du nord du nord-est) ont suivi un programme saisonnier 
de la chasse, de la pêche, de la nourriture sauvage de rassemblement,
et de la culture des collectes. Ils ont compté lors des 
collectes cultivées telles que le maïs, les haricots, et la courge 
pour beaucoup de leur nourriture. Les hommes ont principalement 
fourni la viande et les poissons, alors que les femmes étaient 
responsables de fournir les légumes cultivés avec les baies, les 
écrous, et le fruit sauvages. Tandis que les hommes aidaient 
clairement les zones, les femmes ont fait la plantation, le sarclage, 
et la moisson en mois chauds. Beaucoup d'observateurs européens
ont remarqué sur ce qu'ils ont vu comme servitude infligée sur les 
femmes indiennes. Cependant, Joseph-Franois Lafitau, un 
missionnaire de jésuite et auteur, était également un observateur 
ethnographique vif des détails de la vie de Iroquois. Dans ce 
compte, il a noté les similitudes entre le travail des femmes de 
ferme en Europe et parmi le Iroquois.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os povos indian das florestas orientais (America do
Norte do nordeste) seguiram uma programação seasonal da caça, da 
pesca, do alimento selvagem do recolhimento, e do cultivation das 
colheitas. Confiaram em colheitas cultivadas tais como o milho, 
os feijões, e o squash para muito de seu alimento. Os homens 
forneceram primeiramente a carne e os peixes, quando as mulheres eram 
responsáveis para fornecer vegetais cultivados junto com bagas, 
porcas, e a fruta selvagens. Quando os homens ajudaram 
claramente aos campos, as mulheres fizeram plantar, remover ervas 
daninhas, e colher nos meses mornos. Muitos observadores 
europeus observaram em cima de o que viram como o drudgery inflicted 
em cima das mulheres indian. Entretanto, Joseph-Franois Lafitau,
um missionário do jesuit e escritor, era também um observador 
ethnographic afiado dos detalhes da vida do iroquois. Neste 
cliente, anotou as similaridades entre o trabalho das mulheres da 
fazenda em Europa e entre o iroquois.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La gente indiana dei terreni boscosi orientali 
(America del Nord di nordest) ha seguito un programma stagionale di 
cercare, pescando, riuniscendo l'alimento selvaggio e la
coltura dei raccolti. Ha contato sui raccolti coltivati quali 
mais, i fagioli e la zucca per molto del loro alimento. Gli 
uomini soprattutto hanno fornito alla carne ed ai pesci, mentre le 
donne erano responsabili del fornire le verdure coltivate con le 
bacche, i dadi e la frutta selvaggi. Mentre gli uomini hanno 
aiutato chiaramente i campi, le donne hanno fatto la piantatura, la 
sarchiatura e la raccolta nei mesi caldi. Molti osservatori 
europei hanno rilevato su che cosa hanno visto come drudgery inflitto 
sulle donne indiane. Tuttavia, Joseph-Franois Lafitau, un 
missionario del jesuit e produttore, era egualmente un osservatore 
ethnographic acuto dei particolari di vita del iroquois. In 
questo cliente, ha notato le somiglianze fra il lavoro delle donne 
dell'azienda agricola in Europa e fra il iroquois.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι ινδικοί λαοί των ανατολικών δασωδών περιοχών 
(βορειοανατολική Βόρεια Αμερική) ακολούθησαν ένα εποχιακό 
πρόγραμμα του κυνηγιού, αλιεύοντας, συλλέγοντας τα άγρια 
τρόφιμα, και την καλλιέργεια των συγκομιδών. Στηρίχθηκαν 
επάνω στις καλλιεργημένες συγκομιδές όπως το καλαμπόκι, τα 
φασόλια, και η κολοκύνθη για ένα μεγάλο μέρος των τροφίμων τους.
Οι άνδρες παρείχαν πρώτιστα το κρέας και τα ψάρια, ενώ οι 
γυναίκες ήταν αρμόδιες για την παροχή των καλλιεργημένων 
λαχανικών μαζί με τα άγρια μούρα, τα καρύδια, και τα φρούτα. 
Ενώ οι άνδρες που ενισχύθηκαν να καθαρίσουν τα πεδία, 
γυναίκες έκαναν τη φύτευση, βοτανίζοντας, και συγκομίζοντας στους
θερμούς μήνες. Πολλοί ευρωπαϊκοί παρατηρητές παρατήρησαν 
επάνω σε αυτό που εβλέίδαν ως μόχθο που επιβλήθηκε επάνω 
στις ινδικές γυναίκες. Εντούτοις, Joseph- Franois 
Lafitau, ένας ιεραπόστολος Jesuit και ένας συγγραφέας, ήταν
επίσης έντονος εθνογραφικός παρατηρητής των λεπτομερειών 
iroquois της ζωής. Σε αυτόν τον απολογισμό, σημείωσε τις 
ομοιότητες μεταξύ της εργασίας των αγροτικών γυναικών στην 
Ευρώπη και μεταξύ iroquois.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La gente india de los arbolados del este 
(Norteamérica del noreste) siguió un horario estacional de la caza, 
de la pesca, del alimento salvaje de la reunión, y de la cultivación
de cosechas. Ella confió en cosechas cultivadas tales como 
maíz, habas, y calabaza para mucho de su alimento. Los hombres 
proporcionaron sobre todo a la carne y a los pescados, mientras que 
las mujeres eran responsables de proveer vehículos cultivados junto 
con bayas, tuercas, y fruta salvajes. Mientras que los hombres 
ayudaron claramente a los campos, las mujeres hicieron plantar, 
escardar, y cosechar en los meses calientes. Muchos observadores
europeos comentaron sobre lo que vieron como servidumbre infligida 
sobre mujeres indias. Sin embargo, Jose'-Franois Lafitau, 
misionario del jesuit y programa de escritura, era también un 
observador etnográfico afilado de los detalles de la vida del iroquois.
En esta cuenta, él observó las semejanzas entre el trabajo de 
las mujeres de la granja en Europa y entre el iroquois.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086992</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103363</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-moment-that-the-snows-are-melted-the-indian-women-begin-their-work-iroquois-women-work-the-fields</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
