<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106861</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106861</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211526</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Periodic Table of the Elements</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Periodische Tabelle der Elemente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Tableau périodique des éléments</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tabela periódica dos elementos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tabella periodica degli elementi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιοδικός πίνακας των στοιχείων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Vector periódico de los elementos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site presents an interactive periodic table that provides information about each element including its description, uses, occurrence, and role in biological processes. For instructors, the site features five comprehensive teaching packets which include teachers' guides, student pages, background materials, maps, and other student activities. The complete packets are available for a fee, but some of the learning activities can be downloaded for free. The site also provides links to other lessons, activities, and a 'homework help' area that includes a photo gallery and encyclopedic index of common minerals.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site stellt eine interaktive periodische 
Tabelle dar, die Informationen über jedes Element einschließlich 
seine Beschreibung, Gebrauch, Auftreten und Rolle in den biologischen 
Prozessen liefert. Für Ausbilder die Situationsmerkmale fünf 
komplette unterrichtende Pakete, welche Anleitungen der Lehrer, 
Kursteilnehmerseiten, Hintergrundmaterialien, Karten und andere 
Kursteilnehmeraktivitäten einschließen. Die kompletten Pakete 
sind für eine Gebühr vorhanden, aber einige der Lernenaktivitäten 
können für freies downloadet werden. Die Site stellt auch 
Links zu anderen Lektionen, zu den Aktivitäten und zu einem ' 
Heimarbeit Hilfe ' Bereich zur Verfügung, der eine Fotogalerie und 
einen enzyklopädischen Index der geläufigen Mineralien einschließt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site présente une table périodique 
interactive qui fournit des informations au sujet de chaque élément 
comprenant sa description, utilisations, occurrence, et rôle dans des
processus biologiques. Pour des instructeurs, les dispositifs de
site cinq paquets d'enseignement complets ce qui incluent les guides 
des professeurs, les pages d'étudiant, les matières de base, les 
cartes, et d'autres activités d'étudiant. Les paquets complets
sont disponibles pour des honoraires, mais une partie de l'étude peut
être téléchargée pour libre. Le site fournit également des 
liens à d'autres leçons, à activités, et à une zone 'd'aide de 
travail 'qui inclut une galerie de photo et un incrément 
encyclopédique des minerais communs.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local apresenta uma tabela periódica 
interativa que forneça a informação sobre cada elemento including 
seus descrição, usos, ocorrência, e papel em processos biológicos.
Para instrutores, as características de local cinco pacotes 
ensinando detalhados quais incluem guias dos professores, páginas do 
estudante, materiais de fundo, mapas, e outras atividades do 
estudante. Os pacotes completos estão disponíveis para uma 
taxa, mas algumas das atividades de aprendizagem podem downloaded para
livre. O local fornece também as ligações a outras lições, 
a atividades, e ' a uma área da ajuda do homework ' que inclua uma 
galeria da foto e um deslocamento predeterminado encyclopedic de 
minerais comuns.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo presenta una tabella periodica 
interattiva che fornisce le informazioni su ogni elemento compreso la 
relativi descrizione, usi, caso e ruolo nei processi biologici. 
Per gli istruttori, le caratteristiche di luogo cinque pacchetti
d'istruzione completi quale includono le guide degli insegnanti, le 
pagine dell'allievo, i materiali di base, i programmi ed altre 
attività dell'allievo. I pacchetti completi sono disponibili 
per una tassa, ma alcune delle attività imparanti possono essere 
trasferite per libero. Il luogo egualmente fornisce i 
collegamenti ad altre lezioni, ad attività e 'ad una zona di aiuto di
lavoro 'che include una galleria della foto e un indice enciclopedico 
dei minerali comuni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή παρουσιάζει έναν διαλογικό περιοδικό 
πίνακα που παρέχει τις πληροφορίες για κάθε στοιχείο 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της περιγραφής, των χρήσεων, του περιστατικού,
και του ρόλου του στις βιολογικές διαδικασίες. Για τους 
εκπαιδευτικούς, η περιοχή χαρακτηρίζει πέντε περιεκτικά πακέτα 
διδασκαλίας που περιλαμβάνουν τους οδηγούς των δασκάλων, τις 
σελίδες σπουδαστών, τα υλικά υποβάθρου, τους χάρτες, και άλλες 
δραστηριότητες σπουδαστών. Τα πλήρη πακέτα είναι διαθέσιμα
έναντι αμοιβής, αλλά μερικές από τις δραστηριότητες εκμάθησης 
μπορούν να μεταφορτωθούν δωρεάν. Η περιοχή παρέχει επίσης 
τις συνδέσεις με άλλα μαθήματα, τις δραστηριότητες, και μια 
περιοχή "οδηγιών εργασίασ" που περιλαμβάνει μια στοά φωτογραφιών
και ένα εγκυκλοπαιδικό ευρετήριο των κοινών μεταλλευμάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio presenta un vector periódico 
interactivo que proporcione a la información sobre cada elemento 
incluyendo su descripción, aplicaciones, ocurrencia, y papel en 
procesos biológicos. Para los instructores, las 
características de sitio cinco paquetes de enseñanza comprensivos 
cuáles incluyen las guías de los profesores, las paginaciones del 
estudiante, los materiales de base, las correspondencias, y otras 
actividades del estudiante. Los paquetes completos están 
disponibles para un honorario, pero algunas de las actividades que 
aprenden se pueden descargar para libre. El sitio también 
proporciona a conexiones a otras lecciones, a actividades, y ' a un 
área de la ayuda de la preparación ' que incluya una galería de la 
foto y un índice enciclopédico de minerales comunes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211526</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106861</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/periodic-table-of-the-elements-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
