<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106879</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106879</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087200</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"We No Longer Control Our Resources": Donna Koons Kingsley Describes the Struggle of Trinidad's Oilfield Workers</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Wir Steuern Nicht mehr Unsere Betriebsmittel": 
Donna Koons Kingsley beschreibt den Kampf der Ölfeld-Arbeiter 
Trinidads</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Nous Ne contrôlons Plus Nos Ressources" : 
Donna Koons Kingsley décrit la lutte des ouvriers du gisement 
de pétrole du Trinidad</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Nós Nenhum Controle Mais longo Nossos Recursos":
Donna Koons Kingsley descreve o esforço de trabalhadores do 
oilfield de Trinidad</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Più Non gestiamo Le Nostre Risorse": Donna
Koons Kingsley descrive la lotta degli operai del giacimento di 
petrolio della Trinidad</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν ελέγχουμε πλέον τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς μασ": 
Το Donna Koons Kingsley περιγράφει την προσπάθεια των
εργαζομένων πετρελαιοφόρων περιοχών του Τρινιδάδ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Nosotros Ningún Control Más largo Nuestros 
Recursos": Donna Koons Kingsley describe la lucha de los 
trabajadores del campo petrolífero de Trinidad</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A slew of international financial crises in the early 1990's, including collapses in Mexico, Southeast Asia, and Russia, highlighted the important influence international lending organizations such as the International Monetary Fund (IMF) and the World Bank had over economic decisions in the developing world. Often in cooperation with local elites, these bodies have forced countries to respond to debt crises by privatizing public industries and utilities, in many cases selling these public resources to foreign companies. Workers and citizens of developing countries often view these policies as a new form of colonialism. In this excerpt, Donna Koons Kingsley, a public relations officer of the Oilfield Workers Trade Union, describes workers' reactions to the process of privatization in Trinidad and Tobago.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Durchlauf internationale Finanzkrisen in den 
frühen neunziger Jahren, einschließlich Einstürze in Mexiko, 
Südostasien und Rußland, markierte die internationalen 
Leihorganisationen des wichtigen Einflusses wie Internationale 
Währungsfonds(IWF) und die Weltbank hatte ökonomische 
übermäßigentscheidungen in der sich entwickelnden Welt. 
Häufig in Zusammenarbeit mit lokalen Auslesen, haben diese 
Körper Länder erzwungen, um auf Schuldkrisen zu reagieren, indem sie
allgemeine Industrien und die Hilfsprogramme privatisierten und in 
vielen Fällen diese allgemeinen Betriebsmittel an 
Auslandsgesellschaften verkauften. Arbeiter und Bürger der 
Entwicklungsländer sehen häufig diese politischen Richtlinien als 
neues Formular von Kolonialismus an. In diesem Excerpt 
beschreibt Donna Koons Kingsley, ein Öffentlichkeitsarbeitoffizier 
der Ölfeld-Arbeiter-Gewerkschaft, Reaktionen der Arbeiter zum Prozeß
der Privatisierung in Trinidad und in Tobago.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un saut de papier de crises financières 
internationales au début des années 90, y compris des effondrements 
au Mexique, Asie du Sud-Est, et la Russie, a mis en valeur les 
organismes de prêt internationaux d'influence importante tels que le 
Fonds monétaire international (FMI) et la banque mondiale a eu des 
décisions économiques finies dans le monde en voie de 
développement. Souvent en coopération avec les élites 
locales, ces corps ont forcé des pays pour répondre aux crises de 
dette en privatisant des industries publiques et des utilitaires, dans
beaucoup de cas vendant ces ressources publiques aux compagnies 
étrangères. Les ouvriers et les citoyens des pays en voie de 
développement visualisent souvent ces politiques comme nouvelle forme
du colonialisme. Dans cet extrait, Donna Koons Kingsley, un 
responsable des relations publiques du syndicat d'ouvriers de gisement
de pétrole, décrit les réactions des ouvriers au processus de la 
privatisation en Trinité-et-Tabago.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um pântano de crises financeiras internacionais 
nos 1990's adiantados, including colapsos em México, Ásia do 
sudeste, e Rússia, destacou as organizações emprestando 
internacionais da influência importante tais como o fundo monetary 
internacional (IMF) e o banco de mundo teve decisões econômicas 
excedentes no mundo tornando-se. Frequentemente na cooperação 
com os elites locais, estes corpos forçaram países para responder 
às crises do débito privatizando indústrias e utilidades públicas,
em muitos casos que vendem estes recursos públicos às companhias 
extrangeiras. Os trabalhadores e os cidadãos de países 
tornando-se vêem frequentemente estas políticas como um formulário 
novo do colonialism. Neste excerpt, Donna Koons Kingsley, um 
oficial de relações públicas da união de comércio dos 
trabalhadores do oilfield, descreve reações dos trabalhadores ao 
processo do privatization em trinidad e em tobago.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un pantano delle crisi finanziarie internazionali 
nell'inizio degli anni 90, compreso i crolli nel Messico, Asia 
sudorientale e la Russia, ha evidenziato le organizzazioni prestarici 
internazionali di influenza importante quale il Fondo monetario 
internazionale (FMI (fondo monetario internazionale)) e la Banca
del mondo ha avuta decisioni economiche eccessive nel mondo di 
sviluppo. Spesso in collaborazione con le elite locali, questi 
corpi hanno forzato i paesi per rispondere alle crisi di debito 
privatizzando le industrie pubbliche ed i programmi di utilità, in 
molti casi vendenti questi fondi pubblici alle aziende straniere. 
Gli operai ed i cittadini dei pæsi in via di sviluppo osservano 
spesso queste politiche come nuova forma del colonialismo. In 
questo brano, Donna Koons Kingsley, un ufficiale di pubbliche 
relazioni del sindacato degli operai del giacimento di petrolio, 
descrive le reazioni degli operai al processo di privatizzazione nei 
Trinità e Tobago.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γυρίστε των διεθνών οικονομικών κρίσεων στις αρχές 
της δεκαετίας του '90, συμπεριλαμβανομένων των καταρρεύσεων στο 
Μεξικό, τη Νοτιοανατολική Ασία, και τη Ρωσία, έδωσε έμφαση στους
σημαντικούς διεθνείς δανείζοντας οργανισμούς επιρροής όπως το 
διεθνές νομισματικό Ταμείο (ΔΝΤ) και η Παγκόσμια Τράπεζα είχε 
πέρα από τις οικονομικές αποφάσεις στον αναπτυσσόμενο κόσμο. 
Συχνά σε συνεργασία με τα τοπικά elites, αυτοί οι 
οργανισμοί έχουν αναγκάσει τις χώρες για να αποκριθούν στις 
κρίσεις χρέους με την ιδιωτικοποίηση των δημόσιων βιομηχανιών και
των βοηθημάτων, πωλώντας σε πολλές περιπτώσεις αυτά τα δημόσια 
στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς στις ξένες επιχειρήσεις. Οι 
εργαζόμενοι και οι πολίτες των αναπτυσσόμενων χωρών εμφανίζουν 
συχνά αυτές τις πολιτικές ως νέα μορφή της αποικιοκρατίας. 
Σε αυτό το απόσπασμα, Donna Koons Kingsley, ένας 
ανώτερος υπάλληλος δημόσιων σχέσεων του συνδικάτου εργαζομένων 
πετρελαιοφόρων περιοχών, περιγράφει τις αντιδράσεις των 
εργαζομένων στη διαδικασία της ιδιωτικοποίησης στο Τρινιδάδ και 
Τομπάγκο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una ciénaga de crisis financieras internacionales
en los años 90 tempranos, incluyendo derrumbamientos en México, Asia
suroriental, y Rusia, destacó las organizaciones de préstamos 
internacionales de la influencia importante tales como el Fondo 
Monetario Internacional (el FMI) y el banco mundial tenía decisiones 
económicas excesivas en el mundo que se convertía. A menudo en
la cooperación con élites locales, estos cuerpos han forzado países
para responder a las crisis de la deuda privatizando industrias 
públicas y los utilitarios, en muchos casos vendiendo estos recursos 
públicos a las compañías no nativas. Los trabajadores y los 
ciudadanos de países en vías de desarrollo opinión a menudo estas 
políticas como nueva forma de colonialismo. En este extracto, 
Donna Koons Kingsley, oficial de relaciones públicas del sindicato de
los trabajadores del campo petrolífero, describe las reacciones de 
los trabajadores al proceso de la privatización en Trinidad y 
Trinidad y Tobago.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087200</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106879</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/we-no-longer-control-our-resources-donna-koons-kingsley-describes-the-struggle-of-trinidads-oilfield-workers</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
