<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106338</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106338</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086215</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Harvest Land": A Lyrical Critique of John Farmer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ernte-Land": Eine Lyrical Kritik des John 
Landwirts</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Terre de Moisson" : Une critique lyrique de
fermier de John</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Da "Terra Colheita": Uma crítica lyrical do
fazendeiro de John</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Terra Della Raccolta": Una valutazione 
lyrical del coltivatore del John</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Έδαφος συγκομιδών": Μια λυρική κριτική John 
Farmer</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Pista De la Cosecha": Una crítica lírica 
del granjero de Juan</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In 1915, the Industrial Workers of the World (IWW) established a branch union, the Agricultural Workers' Organization (AWO). The AWO organized temporary harvesters, known as "harvest stiffs," in railroad yards, migrant camps, and shelters. At its height in 1917 the AWO had more than 70,000 members, but like the IWW it was undermined by President Woodrow Wilson's wartime attack on dissent and by local vigilante organizations. The AWO, like its parent organization, used folksongs, stories, and poetry to spread its message to migrants. One such song, "Harvest Land," by "TD and H," first appeared in the  Little Red Songbook , a free booklet that IWW members regularly distributed to organizers and workers. Like most IWW songs, it set satirical lyrics to popular or traditional tunes, in this case "Beulah Land." "Harvest Land" attacked "John Farmer" for recruiting laborers with false promises, and it urged workers to withhold their labor until they received better wages.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">1915 stellten die industriellen Arbeiter der Welt 
(IWW) einen Zweiganschluß, die landwirtschaftlichen Organisation der 
Arbeiter her (AWO). Das AWO organisierte die temporären 
Erntemaschinen, bekannt als "Ernte stiffs," in den Eisenbahnyards, in 
den Wander- Lagern und in den Schutz. Auf seiner Höhe in 1917 
hatte das AWO mehr als 70.000 Bauteile, aber wie das IWW wurde es 
durch Präsident Woodrow Wilson Kriegangriff auf 
Meinungsverschiedenheit und durch lokale vigilante Organisationen 
untergraben. Das AWO, wie seine Elternteilorganisation, 
verwendete folksongs, Geschichten und Poesie, um seine Meldung zu den 
Wanderern zu verbreiten. Ein solches Lied, "Ernte-Land," durch 
"TD und H," erschienen zuerst im kleinen roten Songbook, eine freie 
Broschüre, die IWW Bauteile regelmäßig auf Organisatoren und 
Arbeiter verteilten. Wie die meisten IWW Liede stellte es 
satirical Lyriken auf die populären oder traditionellen 
Melodien, in diesem Fall "Beulah Land." ein "Ernte-Land" griff 
"John Landwirt" für einziehende Arbeiter mit falschen Versprechungen 
an, und es drängte Arbeiter, ihre Arbeit zurückzuhalten, bis sie 
bessere Löhne empfingen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En 1915, les ouvriers industriels du monde (IWW) 
ont établi une union de branchement, l'organisation des ouvriers 
agricoles (AWO). L'AWO a organisé les moissonneuses 
provisoires, connues sous le nom de "stiffs de moisson," dans des 
yards de chemin de fer, des camps migrateurs, et des abris. À 
sa taille dans 1917 l'AWO a eu plus de 70.000 membres, mais comme 
l'IWW il a été miné par attaque de temps de guerre du Président 
Woodrow Wilson sur la dissidence et par des organismes locaux de 
surveillant. L'AWO, comme sa organisation mère, a employé des 
folksongs, des histoires, et la poésie pour écarter son message aux 
migrants. Une telle chanson, "terre de moisson," par "TD et H," 
sont apparues la première fois dans le petit Songbook rouge, un 
livret libre que les membres d'IWW ont régulièrement distribué aux 
organisateurs et aux ouvriers. Comme la plupart des chansons 
d'IWW, il a placé le lyrique satirique aux airs populaires ou 
traditionnels, dans ce cas-ci "terre de Beulah." la "terre de 
moisson" a attaqué le "fermier de John" pour les travailleurs 
recruteurs avec des promesses fausses, et elle a invité des ouvriers 
à retenir leur travail jusqu'à ce qu'ils aient reçu de meilleurs 
salaires.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Em 1915, os trabalhadores industriais do mundo 
(IWW) estabeleceram uma união da filial, a organização dos 
trabalhadores agriculturais (AWO). O AWO organizou os harvesters
provisórios, sabidos como da "stiffs colheita," em jardas da estrada 
de ferro, em acampamentos emigrantes, e em abrigos. Em sua 
altura em 1917 o AWO teve mais de 70.000 membros, mas como o IWW 
undermined pelo ataque do wartime do presidente Woodrow Wilson no 
dissent e por organizações locais do vigilante. O AWO, como 
sua organização de pai, usou folksongs, histórias, e poesia 
espalhar sua mensagem aos emigrantes. Umas tais canção, da 
"terra colheita," por "TD e por H," apareceram primeiramente no 
Songbook vermelho pequeno, um livreto livre que os membros de IWW 
distribuíssem regularmente aos organizers e aos trabalhadores. 
Como a maioria de canções de IWW, ajustou lyrics satirical aos
tunes populares ou tradicionais, neste caso de "terra Beulah." 
da "a terra colheita" atacou de "o fazendeiro John" para 
laborers recrutando com promessas falsas, e incitou trabalhadores 
reter seu trabalho até que receberam salários melhores.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In 1915, i lavoratori dell'industria del mondo 
(IWW) hanno stabilito un'unione del ramo, l'organizzazione degli 
operai agricoli (AWO). Il AWO ha organizzato le mietitrici 
provvisorie, conosciute come "gli stiffs della raccolta," nelle iarde 
della ferrovia, negli accampamenti migratori e nei ripari. Alla 
relativa altezza in 1917 il AWO ha avuto più di 70.000 membri, ma 
come il IWW è stato insidiato tramite l'attacco di wartime del 
presidente Woodrow Wilson a dissenso e dalle organizzazioni locali del
vigilante. Il AWO, come la relativa organizzazione di genitore, 
ha usato i folksongs, le storia e la poesia per spargere il relativo 
messaggio ai migranti. Una tali canzone, "terra della raccolta,"
"da TD e dalla H," in primo luogo sono comparso nel Songbook rosso 
piccolo, un libretto libero che i membri di IWW hanno distribuito 
regolarmente agli organizzatori ed agli operai. Come la maggior 
parte delle canzoni di IWW, ha regolato i lyrics satirical alle arie 
popolari o tradizionali, in questo caso "terra di Beulah." "la 
terra della raccolta" ha attacato "il coltivatore del John" per i 
lavoratori di reclutamento con le promesse false ed ha invitato gli 
operai a ritenere il loro lavoro fino a che non ricevessero gli 
stipendi migliori.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το 1915, οι βιομηχανικοί εργάτες του κόσμου (IWW)
καθιέρωσαν μια ένωση κλάδων, η οργάνωση των γεωργικών 
εργαζομένων (AWO). Το AWO οργάνωσε τις προσωρινές 
θεριστικές μηχανές, γνωστές ως "συγκομιδή stiffs," στα 
ναυπηγεία σιδηροδρόμου, τα αποδημητικά στρατόπεδα, και τα 
καταφύγια. Στο ύψος του το 1917 το AWO είχε 
περισσότερα από 70.000 μέλη, αλλά όπως το IWW υπονομεύθηκε
από την εν καιρώ πολέμου επίθεση Προέδρου Woodrow Wilson's 
στη διαφωνία και από τις τοπικές οργανώσεις vigilante. Το
AWO, όπως την οργάνωση γονέων του, χρησιμοποίησε folksongs, 
ιστορίες, και ποίηση για να διαδώσει το μήνυμά του στους 
μετανάστες. Ένα τέτοιο τραγούδι, "έδαφος συγκομιδών," από
"το TD και το χ," αρχικά εμφανίστηκε στο μικρό κόκκινο 
Songbook, ένα ελεύθερο βιβλιάριο που τα μέλη IWW διένειμαν 
τακτικά στους διοργανωτές και τους εργαζομένους. Όπως τα 
περισσότερα τραγούδια IWW, έθεσε τα σατυρικά λυρικά ποιήματα 
στους δημοφιλείς ή παραδοσιακούς τόνους, σε αυτήν την περίπτωση 
"έδαφος Beulah." Το "έδαφος συγκομιδών" επιτέθηκε "σε 
John Farmer" για τη στρατολόγηση των laborers με τις 
ψεύτικες υποσχέσεις, και ώθησε τους εργαζομένους για να 
παρακρατήσει την εργασία τους έως ότου έλαβαν τις καλύτερες 
αμοιβές.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En 1915, los trabajadores industriales del mundo 
(IWW) establecieron una unión de la ramificación, la organización 
de los trabajadores agrícolas (AWO). El AWO ordenó las 
máquinas segadores temporales, conocidas como "stiffs de la cosecha,"
en yardas del ferrocarril, campos migratorios, y abrigos. En su 
altura en 1917 el AWO tenía más de 70.000 miembros, pero como el IWW
fue minado por ataque del tiempo de guerra de presidente Woodrow 
Wilson contra la disensión y por organizaciones locales del 
vigilante. El AWO, como su organización de padre, utilizó 
folksongs, historias, y poesía para separar su mensaje a los 
nómadas. Una tal canción, "pista de la cosecha," por "TD y H,"
primero aparecieron en el pequeño Songbook rojo, un librete libre que
los miembros de IWW distribuyeron regularmente a los organizadores y a
los trabajadores. Como la mayoría de las canciones de IWW, 
fijó las líricas satíricas a las consonancias populares o 
tradicionales, en este caso "pista de Beulah." la "pista de la 
cosecha" atacó a "granjero de Juan" para los trabajadores de 
reclutamiento con promesas falsas, e impulsó a trabajadores retener 
su trabajo hasta que recibieron salarios mejores.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086215</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106338</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/harvest-land-a-lyrical-critique-of-john-farmer</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
