<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103518</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103518</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201673</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Faraday's Electromagnetic Lab</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Faraday Elektromagnetisches Labor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le Laboratoire Électromagnétique de Faraday</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Laboratório Eletromagnético De Faraday</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Laboratorio Elettromagnetico Del Faraday</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ηλεκτρομαγνητικό εργαστήριο του Faraday</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Laboratorio Electromágnetico De Faraday</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play with a bar magnet and coils to learn about Faraday's law. Move a bar magnet near one or two coils to make a light bulb glow. View the magnetic field lines. A meter shows the direction and magnitude of the current. View the magnetic field lines or use a meter to show the direction and magnitude of the current. You can also play with electromagnets, generators and transformers!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>es</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie mit einem Stabmagneten und Spulen, um 
über Gesetz Faraday zu erlernen. Verschieben Sie einen 
Stabmagneten nahe ein oder zwei Spulen, um eine Glühlampe glühen zu 
lassen. Sehen Sie das magnetische auffangen Zeilen an. 
Ein Meßinstrument zeigt die Richtung und die Größe des 
Stromes. Sehen Sie das magnetische auffangen Zeilen 
oder benutzen ein Meßinstrument, um die Richtung und die Größe des 
Stromes zu zeigen an. Sie können mit Elektromagneten, 
Generatoren und Transformatoren auch spielen!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez avec une barre aimantée et des enroulements
pour se renseigner sur la loi de Faraday. Déplacez une barre 
aimantée près de un ou deux enroulements pour faire une ampoule 
rougeoyer. Visualisez les lignes de champ magnétique. Un 
mètre montre la direction et l'importance du courant. 
Visualisez les lignes de champ magnétique ou utilisez un mètre
pour montrer la direction et l'importance du courant. Vous 
pouvez également jouer avec des électro-aimants, des générateurs 
et des transformateurs !</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue com um ímã e as bobinas de barra para 
aprender sobre a lei de Faraday. Mova um ímã de barra perto de
uma ou dois bobinas para fazer um bulbo claro incandescer. Veja 
as linhas do campo magnético. Um medidor mostra o sentido e o 
valor da corrente. Veja as linhas do campo magnético ou use um 
medidor mostrar o sentido e o valor da corrente. Você pode 
também jogar com eletroímãs, geradores e transformadores!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc con un magnete e le bobine di barra per 
imparare circa legge del Faraday. Sposti un magnete di barra 
vicino ad una o due bobina per fare una lampadina emettere luce. 
Osservi le righe del campo magnetico. Un tester mostra il 
senso e la grandezza della corrente. Osservi le righe del campo 
magnetico o utilizzi un tester per mostrare il senso e la grandezza 
della corrente. Potete anche giocare con gli elettromagneti, i 
generatori ed i trasformatori!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδι με έναν μαγνήτη και τα πηνία ράβδων για να 
μάθει για το νόμο του Faraday. Κινήστε έναν μαγνήτη 
ράβδων κοντά σε ένα ή δύο πηνία για να κάνετε έναν ελαφρύ 
βολβό να καεί. Εμφανίστε τις γραμμές μαγνητικών πεδίων. 
Ένας μετρητής εμφανίζει την κατεύθυνση και μέγεθος του 
ρεύματος. Εμφανίστε τις γραμμές μαγνητικών πεδίων ή 
χρησιμοποιήστε έναν μετρητή για να εμφανίσετε την κατεύθυνση και 
μέγεθος του ρεύματος. Μπορείτε επίσης να παίξετε με τους 
ηλεκτρομαγνήτες, τις γεννήτριες και τους μετασχηματιστές!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegue con un imán y las bobinas de barra para 
aprender sobre la ley de Faraday. Mueva un imán de barra cerca 
de una o dos bobinas para hacer que una bombilla brilla intensamente. 
Opinión las líneas del campo magnético. Un contador 
muestra la dirección y la magnitud de la corriente. Opinión 
las líneas del campo magnético o utilice un contador para mostrar la
dirección y la magnitud de la corriente. ¡Usted puede también 
jugar con los electroimanes, los generadores y los transformadores!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201673</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103518</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/faraday-s-electromagnetic-lab</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
