<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105563</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105563</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205991</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Seeing Mathematics and Statistics ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sehen von von Mathematik und von von Statistiken?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Voir des mathématiques et des statistiques ?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vendo a matemática e os statistics?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Si vedano matematica e le statistiche?</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Να δει τα μαθηματικά και τις στατιστικές;</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Ver matemáticas y estadística?</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features a math curriculum, professional development for teachers, and software interactives. The interactives, available on the web, clarify key algebra concepts. They help students see connections between symbolic and graphic representations of quadratic functions, linear functions, piecewise linear functions, and more.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet einen Mathelehrplan, eine professionelle 
Entwicklung für Lehrer und Software interactives. Die 
interactives, die auf dem Web vorhanden sind, erklären 
Schlüsselalgebrakonzepte. Sie helfen Kursteilnehmern, 
Anschlüsse zwischen den symbolischen und graphischen Darstellungen 
der quadratischen Funktionen, der linearen Funktionen, der stückweise
linearen Funktionen und mehr zu sehen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte un programme d'études de maths, un 
développement professionnel pour des professeurs, et des interactives
de logiciel. Les interactives, disponibles sur le Web, 
clarifient les concepts principaux d'algèbre. Ils aident des 
étudiants à voir des connexions entre les représentations 
symboliques et graphiques des fonctions quadratiques, des fonctions 
linéaires, des fonctions par morceaux linéaires, et de plus.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza um curriculum do math, um desenvolvimento 
profissional para professores, e uns interactives do software. 
Os interactives, disponíveis no Web, esclarecem os conceitos 
chaves da álgebra. Ajudam a estudantes ver conexões entre 
respresentações simbólicas e gráficas de funções quadráticas, 
de funções lineares, de funções piecewise lineares, e de mais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza un programma di studi di per la matematica, 
uno sviluppo professionale per gli insegnanti ed i interactives del 
software. I interactives, disponibili sul Web, chiariscono i 
concetti chiave di algebra. Aiutano gli allievi a vedere i 
collegamenti fra le rappresentazioni simboliche e grafiche delle 
funzioni quadratiche, delle funzioni lineari, delle funzioni a tratti 
lineari e di più.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει ένα πρόγραμμα σπουδών math, 
επαγγελματική ανάπτυξη για τους δασκάλους, και τα interactives 
λογισμικού. Τα interactives, διαθέσιμα στον Ιστό, 
διευκρινίζουν τις βασικές έννοιες άλγεβρας. Βοηθούν τους 
σπουδαστές να δουν τις συνδέσεις μεταξύ των συμβολικών
και γραφικών αντιπροσωπεύσεων των δευτέρου βαθμού λειτουργιών, 
των γραμμικών λειτουργιών, τμηματικά των γραμμικών λειτουργιών, 
και περισσότερων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece un plan de estudios de la matemáticas, un 
desarrollo profesional para los profesores, e interactives del 
software. Los interactives, disponibles en el Web, clarifican 
los conceptos dominantes de la álgebra. Ayudan a estudiantes a 
ver conexiones entre las representaciones simbólicas y gráficas de 
funciones cuadráticas, de funciones lineares, de funciones por trozos
lineares, y más.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205991</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105563</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/seeing-mathematics-and-statistics</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
