<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108099</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108099</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086290</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"I Must Of Course Have Something Of My Own Before Many More Years Have Passed Over My Head": Sally Rice Leaves the Farm, 1838</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Ich Muß Etwas Von Meinen Selbst 
Selbstverständlich Haben, Bevor Viel mehr Jahre Über Meinen Kopf" 
Überschritten Haben: Sally Reis verläßt den Bauernhof, 1838</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Je Dois Naturellement Avoir Quelque chose de Mes 
Propres Avant que Beaucoup plus d'Années Aient passé Au-dessus de Ma
Tête" : Le riz de Sally part de la ferme, 1838</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Eu Devo Naturalmente Ter Algo Do Meus Próprios 
Antes que Muitos mais Anos Passem Sobre Minha Cabeça": O arroz 
de Sally sae da fazenda, 1838</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Devo Naturalmente Avere Qualcosa Dei Miei Propri 
Prima che Molti altri Anni Abbiano passato Sopra La Mia Testa": 
Il riso di Sally lascia il podere, 1838</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"πρέπει φυσικά να έχω κάτι του μου δικοί πριν από τα
πολλά περισσότερα έτη έχω περάσει πέρα από το κεφάλι μου": 
Θ*Σαλλυ Rice Leaves το αγρόκτημα, 1838</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Debo Por supuesto Tener Algo Mis El propios Antes
de que Muchos más Años Hayan pasado Sobre Mi Cabeza": El arroz
de Sally sale de la granja, 1838</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">From the rocky soil of Vermont's hill towns, many young men and women in the nineteenth century went looking for new opportunities. Often they made a series of moves between farm, factory, and city. Their leave-taking pitted the responsibilities of maintaining family farms against the new attractions of financial and social independence. Sally Rice, born in 1821 in Dover, Vermont, was typical. In 1838 she found work as a domestic servant in New York, not far over the border from her family's hardscrabble farm, securing for herself much valued wages and independence. Several years later she worked as a weaver in one of the many cotton mills that lined the Blackstone Valley of central Massachusetts and Connecticut. Her letters home to her mother and father in Vermont carefully weighed issues of family and independence, farm and factory life.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vom felsigen Boden der Hügelstädte Vermonts, 
gingen viele junge Männer und Frauen im 19.jahrhundert, nach neuen 
Gelegenheiten zu suchen. Häufig bildeten sie eine Serie von den
Bewegungen zwischen Bauernhof, Fabrik und Stadt. Ihr 
lassen-Nehmen bildete die Verantwortlichkeiten des Beibehaltens der 
Familie Bauernhöfe gegen die neuen Anziehungen der finanziellen und 
Sozialunabhängigkeit Löcher. Der Sally Reis, getragen 1821 in 
Dover, Vermont, war typisch. 1838 fand sie Arbeit als 
inländischer Bediensteter in New York, nicht weit über dem Rand vom 
hardscrabble Bauernhof ihrer Familie, sichernd für bewertete viel 
Löhne und Unabhängigkeit. Einige Jahre später arbeitete sie 
als Weber in einer der vielen Baumwollspinnereien, die die Blackstone 
Senke von zentralem Massachusetts und von Connecticut zeichneten. 
Sie die Zeichen, die zu ihrer Mutter und zu Vater in Vermont wog
Haupt sind sorgfältig, Ausgaben der Familie und des Unabhängigkeit-,
Bauernhof- und Fabriklebens.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Du sol rocheux des villes de la colline du 
Vermontn, beaucoup de jeunes hommes et femmes au dix-neuvième siècle
sont allés rechercher de nouvelles occasions. Souvent ils ont 
fait une série des mouvements entre la ferme, l'usine, et la ville. 
Leur laisser-prise a piqué les responsabilités de mettre à 
jour des fermes de famille contre les nouvelles attractions de 
l'indépendance financière et sociale. Le riz de Sally, soutenu
en 1821 à Douvres, Vermontn, était typique. En 1838 elle a 
trouvé le travail en tant que domestique domestique à New York, pas 
loin au-dessus du cadre de la ferme hardscrabble de sa famille, fixant
pour elle-même a beaucoup évalué des salaires et l'indépendance. 
Plusieurs ans après elle a travaillé en tant que tisserande 
dans une des nombreuses filatures de coton qui ont rayé la vallée de
Blackstone du Massachusetts et du Connecticut centraux. Elle des
lettres à la maison à sa mère et père au Vermontn a soigneusement 
pesé des issues de famille et de vie de l'indépendance, de ferme et 
d'usine.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Do solo rochoso de cidades do monte de Vermont, 
muitos homens novos e mulheres no décimo nono século foram procurar 
oportunidades novas. Frequentemente fizeram uma série dos 
movimentos entre a fazenda, a fábrica, e a cidade. Seu 
deix-fazer exame pitted as responsabilidades de manter fazendas da 
família de encontro às atrações novas da independência financeira
e social. O arroz de Sally, carregado em 1821 em Dôvar, 
Vermont, era típico. Em 1838 encontrou o trabalho como um 
empregado doméstico em New York, não distante sobre a beira da 
fazenda hardscrabble da sua família, fixando-se para herself avaliou 
muito salários e independência. Diversos anos mais tarde 
trabalhou como um weaver em um de muitos moinhos de algodão que 
alinharam o vale de Blackstone de Massachusetts e de Connecticut 
centrais. As letras home a seus matriz e pai em Vermont pesou 
com cuidado introduções da família e da vida da independência, da 
fazenda e da fábrica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dal terreno roccioso delle città della collina 
del Vermont, molti giovani e donne nel diciannovesimo secolo sono 
andato cercare le nuove occasioni. _ spesso fa un serie 
movimento fra podere, fabbrica, e città. La loro lasci-presa ha
scavato le responsabilità di effettuare i poderi della famiglia 
contro le nuove attrazioni di indipendenza finanziaria e sociale. 
Il riso di Sally, sopportato in 1821 a Dover, Vermont, era 
tipico. In 1838 ha trovato il lavoro come servo domestico a New 
York, non lontano sopra il bordo dal podere hardscrabble della sua 
famiglia, fissante per sè molto ha stimato gli stipendi e 
l'indipendenza. Parecchi anni più successivamente ha lavorato 
come tessitore in uno dei molti cotonifici che hanno allineato la 
valle di Blackstone di Massachusetts e di Connecticut centrali. 
Lei lettere domestiche alla suoi madre e padre nel Vermont ha 
pesato con attenzione le emissioni della famiglia e della vita di 
indipendenza, dell'azienda agricola e della fabbrica.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Από το δύσκολο χώμα των πόλεων λόφων του Βερμόντ, 
πολλοί νεαροί άνδρες και γυναίκες στο δέκατο έννατο αιώνα 
πήγαν τις νέες ευκαιρίες. Συχνά έκαναν μια σειρά κινήσεων
μεταξύ του αγροκτήματος, του εργοστασίου, και της πόλης. Η 
άδεια-λήψη τους κοίλανε τις ευθύνες τα οικογενειακά αγροκτήματα 
ενάντια στη νέα έλξη της οικονομικής και κοινωνικής 
ανεξαρτησίας. Η Sally Rice, γεννημένο το 1821 στο 
Ντόβερ, Βερμόντ, ήταν χαρακτηριστική. Το 1838 βρήκε την 
εργασία δεδομένου ότι ένας εσωτερικός υπάλληλος στη Νέα Υόρκη,
όχι μακριά πέρα από τα σύνορα από το hardscrabble αγρόκτημα 
της οικογένειάς της, που εξασφαλίζει για την εκτίμησε πολύ τις 
αμοιβές και την ανεξαρτησία. Αρκετά έτη αργότερα εργάστηκε
ως υφαντής σε ένας από τους πολλούς μύλους βαμβακιού που 
ευθυγράμμισαν την κοιλάδα Blackstone της κεντρικών Μασαχουσέτης
και του Κοννέκτικατ. Το σπίτι επιστολών της στη μητέρα και 
τον πατέρα της στο Βερμόντ ζύγισε προσεκτικά τα ζητήματα της 
οικογένειας και της ζωής ανεξαρτησίας, αγροκτημάτων και 
εργοστασίων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Del suelo rocoso de las ciudades de la colina de 
Vermont, muchos hombres jóvenes y mujeres en el diecinueveavo siglo 
fueron a buscar nuevas oportunidades. Hicieron a menudo una 
serie de movimientos entre la granja, la fábrica, y la ciudad. 
El su dejar-tomar marcó con hoyos las responsabilidades de 
mantener granjas de la familia contra las nuevas atracciones de la 
independencia financiera y social. El arroz de Sally, llevado en
1821 en Dover, Vermont, era típico. En 1838 ella encontró el 
trabajo como criado doméstico en Nueva York, no lejos sobre la 
frontera de la granja hardscrabble de su familia, asegurando para se 
valoró mucho salarios e independencia. Varios años más tarde 
ella trabajó como tejedor en una de las muchas fábricas de algodón 
que alinearon el valle de Blackstone de Massachusetts y de Connecticut
centrales. Ella las cartas caseras a su madre y padre en Vermont
pesó cuidadosamente aplicaciones la familia y la vida de la 
independencia, de la granja y de la fábrica.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086290</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108099</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/i-must-of-course-have-something-of-my-own-before-many-more-years-have-passed-over-my-head-sally-rice-leaves-the-farm-1838</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
