<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107190</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107190</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086063</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Debunking Intelligence Experts: Walter Lippmann Speaks Out</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Entlarvende Intelligenz-Experten: Walter 
Lippmann Spricht Heraus</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Experts en matière Démystifiants d'Intelligence 
: Walter Lippmann Parle Dehors</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Peritos Debunking Da Inteligência: Walter 
Lippmann Fala Para fora</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esperti Debunking Di Intelligenza: Walter 
Lippmann Parla Fuori</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εμπειρογνώμονες νοημοσύνης Debunking: Walter Lippmann Speaks Out</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Expertos Debunking De la Inteligencia: 
Walter Lippmann Habla Hacia fuera</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">"There is nothing about an individual as important as his IQ," declared psychologist Lewis M. Terman in 1922. To the extent that this is true, it is in large measure because of Terman himself and the opportunity that World War I afforded for the first widespread use of intelligence testing. The army's use of intelligence tests lent new credibility to the emerging profession of psychology, even as it sparked public debate about the validity of the tests and their implications for American democracy. The idea that experts could confidently assign a man to his proper place in the army--and by extension his place in life--suggested a kind of determinism that some found profoundly at odds with American democracy and its credo of upward mobility through hard work. Walter Lippmann, an influential political commentator and journalist, skewered the army intelligence tests in a series of six essays that appeared in the  New Republic  in 1922. He denounced as "nonsense" the claim that the average mental age of an American adult was fourteen years, and forcefully warned his readers of the danger of uncritical acceptance of IQ as destiny. He addressed the conditions of IQ testing, the possible biases of army intelligence tests, and the larger social problems raised by such classifications.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"es gibt nichts über eine Einzelperson, die," 
erklärter Psychologe Lewis M. Terman 1922 so wichtig ist wie sein IQ.
Soweit daß dieses zutreffend ist, ist es in großem Umfang 
wegen Terman selbst und der Gelegenheit, die der Erste Weltkrieg für 
den ersten weitverbreiteten Gebrauch von Intelligenzprüfung sich 
leistete. Der Gebrauch der Armee von Intelligenz prüft 
verliehene neue Glaubwürdigkeit zum auftauchenden Beruf von 
Psychologie, selbst als er allgemeine Debatte über die Gültigkeit 
der Tests und ihrer Implikationen für amerikanische Demokratie 
funkte. Die Idee, daß Experten einen Mann seinem korrekten 
Platz in der Armee sicher zuweisen konnten -- und durch Extension sein
Platz im Leben -- schlug eine Art Determinismus vor, die einige 
profund uneins mit amerikanischer Demokratie und seinem Credo von 
aufwärts Mobilität durch harte Arbeit fanden. Walter Lippmann,
ein einflußreicher politischer Kommentator und Journalist, spiaß die
Armeeintelligenztests in einer Reihe von sechs Versuchen auf, die in 
der neuen Republik 1922 erschienen. Er kündigte als "Unsinn" 
den Anspruch, daß das durchschnittliche Geistesalter eines 
amerikanischen Erwachsenen vierzehn Jahre war, und warnte stark seine 
Leser der Gefahr der unkritischen Abnahme von IQ als Schicksal. 
Er adressierte die Zustände der IQ Prüfung, die möglichen 
Vorspannungen der Armeeintelligenztests und die größeren 
Sozialprobleme, die durch solche Klassifikationen angehoben wurden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"il n'y a rien au sujet d'un individu aussi 
important que son Q.I.," psychologue avoué Lewis M. Terman en 1922. 
Dans la mesure où c'est vrai, il est dans une large mesure en 
raison de Terman lui-même et de l'occasion que la Première Guerre 
Mondiale a eus les moyens pour le premier usage répandu du test 
d'intelligence. L'utilisation de l'armée de l'intelligence 
teste la nouvelle crédibilité prêtée à la profession naissante de
la psychologie, même pendant qu'elle étincelait discussion publique 
au sujet de la validité des essais et de leurs implications pour la 
démocratie américaine. L'idée que les experts pourraient avec
confiance affecter un homme à son endroit approprié dans l'armée --
et par extension son endroit dans la vie -- a suggéré un genre de 
déterminisme que certains ont trouvé profondément à la chance avec
la démocratie américaine et son credo de mobilité ascendante 
par le travail dur. Walter Lippmann, un commentateur politique 
influent et journaliste, a embroché les essais d'intelligence 
d'armée dans une série de six essais qui sont apparus dans la 
nouvelle République en 1922. Il a dénoncé en tant que 
"contrôle par totalisation" la réclamation que l'âge mental moyen 
d'un adulte américain était de quatorze ans, et a avec force averti 
ses lecteurs du danger de l'acceptation non critique du Q.I. comme 
destin. Il a adressé les conditions du test de Q.I., les 
polarisations possibles des essais d'intelligence d'armée, et les 
problèmes sociaux plus grands soulevés par de telles 
classifications.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"não há nada sobre um indivíduo tão importante
quanto seu IQ," psicólogo declarado Lewis M. Terman em 1922. 
Até ao ponto em que isto é verdadeiro, está na medida grande 
por causa de Terman ele mesmo e na oportunidade que o world.war.i teve
recursos para para o primeiro uso difundido de testar da 
inteligência. O uso do exército da inteligência testa o 
credibility novo emprestado à profissão emergente do psychology, 
mesmo como ele acendeu debate público sobre a validez dos testes e de
suas implicações para a democracia americana. A idéia que os 
peritos poderiam confiàvel atribuir um homem a seu lugar apropriado 
no exército -- e pela extensão seu lugar na vida -- sugeriu um tipo 
do determinism que algumas encontrassem profundamente em 
probabilidades com democracia americana e seu credo da mobilidade 
ascendente através do trabalho duro. Walter Lippmann, um 
comentador político influential e journalist, skewered os testes da 
inteligência do exército em uma série de seis essays que apareceram
na república nova em 1922. Denounced como o "absurdo" a 
reivindicação que a idade mental média de um adulto americano era 
quatorze anos, e advertiu forcefully seus leitores do perigo da 
aceitação uncritical do IQ como o destiny. Dirigiu-se às 
condições de testar do IQ, às polarizações possíveis de testes 
da inteligência do exército, e aos problemas sociais maiores 
levantados por tais classificações.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"ci è niente circa un individuo importante quanto
il suo quoziente d'intelligenza," psicologo dichiarato Lewis M. Terman
in 1922. Anche se questo è allineare, è in una larga misura a 
causa di Terman egli stesso e dell'occasione che il world.war.i si è 
permesso per il primo uso molto diffuso di prova di intelligenza. 
L'uso dell'esercito di intelligenza verifica la nuova 
credibilità prestata alla professione d'emersione della psicologia, 
proprio mentre ha scintillato dibattito pubblico circa la validità 
delle prove e delle loro implicazioni per la democrazia americana. 
L'idea che gli esperti potrebbero assegnare con confidenza un 
uomo al suo posto adeguato nell'esercito -- e dall'estensione il suo 
posto nella vita -- ha suggerito un genere di determinismo che alcune 
hanno trovato profondamente in disaccordo con la democrazia americana 
ed il relativo credo di mobilità ascendente attraverso lavoro duro. 
Walter Lippmann, un commentatore politico influente e 
giornalista, ha infilzato le prove di intelligenza dell'esercito in 
serie di sei saggi che sono comparso nella nuova Repubblica in 1922. 
Ha denunciato come "assurdità" il reclamo che l'età mentale 
media di un adulto americano era di quattordici anni e validamente ha 
avvertito i suoi lettori del pericolo di accettazione non critica di 
quoziente d'intelligenza come destino. Ha richiamato gli stati 
di prova di quoziente d'intelligenza, le polarizzazioni possibili 
delle prove di intelligenza dell'esercito ed i più grandi problemi 
sociali sollevati tramite tali classificazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Δεν υπάρχει τίποτα για ένα άτομο τόσο σημαντικό 
όπως ο ΔΕΙΚΤΗΣ ΝΟΗΜΟΣΎΝΗΣ του," δηλωμένος ψυχολόγος Lewis Μ. 
Terman σε 1922, μέχρι το σημείο που αυτό ισχύει, αυτό 
είναι σε μεγάλο βαθμό λόγω Terman ο ίδιος και της ευκαιρίας 
που ο παγκόσμιος πόλεμος εγώ παρείχε για την πρώτη διαδεδομένη 
χρήση της δοκιμής νοημοσύνης. Η χρήση του στρατού των 
δοκιμών νοημοσύνης δάνεισε τη νέα αξιοπιστία στο αναδυόμενο 
επάγγελμα της ψυχολογίας, ακόμη και δεδομένου ότι προκάλεσε τη 
δημόσια συζήτηση για την ισχύ των δοκιμών και των επιπτώσεών 
τους στην αμερικανική δημοκρατία. Η ιδέα ότι οι 
εμπειρογνώμονες θα μπορούσαν με βεβαιότητα να διορίσουν ένα 
άτομο στην κατάλληλη θέση του στο στρατό -- και κατ' επέκταση η 
θέση του στη ζωή -- πρότεινε ένα είδος αιτιοκρατίας που μερικοί
βρήκαν βαθιά σε διαφωνία με την αμερικανική δημοκρατία και το 
credo ανοδικής κινητικότητάς του μέσω της σκληρής εργασίας. 
Walter Lippmann, ένας επιδρόντες πολιτικοί σχολιαστής
και ένας δημοσιογράφος, σούβλισαν τις δοκιμές νοημοσύνης στρατού
σε μία σειρά έξι δοκίμιων που εμφανίστηκαν στη νέα Δημοκρατία 
το 1922. Κατήγγειλε ως "αηδίεσ" την αξίωση ότι η μέση 
διανοητική ηλικία ενός αμερικανικού ενηλίκου ήταν δεκατέσσερα 
έτη, και προειδοποίησε δυνατά τους αναγνώστες του για τον κίνδυνο
της επιπόλαιας αποδοχής του ΔΕΙΚΤΗ ΝΟΗΜΟΣΎΝΗΣ ως πεπρωμένο. 
Εξέτασε τους όρους της δοκιμής ΔΕΙΚΤΗ ΝΟΗΜΟΣΎΝΗΣ, τις 
πιθανές πολώσεις των δοκιμών νοημοσύνης στρατού, και τα 
μεγαλύτερα κοινωνικά προβλήματα που προέκυψαν από τέτοιες 
ταξινομήσεις.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"no hay nada sobre un individuo tan importante 
como su índice de inteligencia," psicólogo declarado Lewis M. Terman
en 1922. Hasta el punto de esto sea verdad, está en la medida 
grande debido a Terman misma y la oportunidad que la Primera Guerra 
Mundial produjo para el primer uso extenso de la prueba de la 
inteligencia. El uso del ejército de la inteligencia prueba 
nueva credibilidad prestada a la profesión que emerge de la 
psicología, incluso como él chispeó discusión público sobre la 
validez de las pruebas y de sus implicaciones para la democracia 
americana. La idea que los expertos podrían asignar con 
confianza a un hombre a su lugar apropiado en el ejército -- y por la
extensión su lugar en vida -- sugirió una clase de determinismo que 
algo encontró profundo en desacuerdo con democracia americana y su 
credo de la movilidad ascendente a través de trabajo duro. 
Walter Lippmann, comentarista político influyente y periodista,
ensartó las pruebas de la inteligencia del ejército en una serie de 
seis ensayos que aparecieron en la nueva república en 1922. Él
denunci como "absurdo" la demanda que la edad mental media de un 
adulto americano era catorce años, y poderosamente advirtió a sus 
programas de lectura del peligro de la aceptación uncritical del 
índice de inteligencia como destino. Él trató las condiciones
de la prueba del índice de inteligencia, los diagonales posibles de 
las pruebas de la inteligencia del ejército, y los problemas sociales
más grandes suscitados por tales clasificaciones.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086063</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107190</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/debunking-intelligence-experts-walter-lippmann-speaks-out</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
