<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108005</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108005</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206312</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">NASAexplores</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">NASAexplores</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">NASAexplores</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">NASAexplores</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">NASAexplores</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">NASAexplores</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">NASAexplores</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents new lessons each week?including articles, learning activities, and background information for teachers and students?on topics related to space. Airport efficiency, motion sickness, housekeeping in space, the international space station, prevention of human error, seeing what can't be seen, asteroids, and use of light to speed recovery from illnesses are among the more than 30 topics. Lessons and materials support national education standards.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt den neuen Lektionen dar, die week?including
Artikel, Lernenaktivitäten und Hintergrundinformationen für Lehrer 
und die students?on Themen in Verbindung gestanden werden auf Platz 
jeden sind. Flughafen-Leistungsfähigkeit, Bewegung Krankheit, 
Haushaltung im Platz, die internationale Raumstation, die Verhinderung
des menschlichen Fehlers, das Sehen was nicht gesehen werden kann, die
Planetoide und der Gebrauch von Licht, Wiederanlauf von den 
Krankheiten zu beschleunigen gehören zu den mehr als 30 Themen. 
Lektionen und Materialien unterstützen 
Unterrichtswesenstandards.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente à de nouvelles leçons chaque les 
articles week?including, l'étude, et l'information de fond pour des 
professeurs et des sujets de students?on liés à l'espace. 
L'efficacité d'aéroport, la cinétose, le ménage dans 
l'espace, la station spatiale internationale, la prévention de 
l'erreur humaine, voir ce qui ne peut pas être vue, les asteroïdes, 
et l'utilisation de la lumière d'expédier la reprise des maladies 
sont parmi les plus de 30 sujets. Les leçons et les matériaux 
supportent des normes d'éducation nationale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta às lições novas cada artigos, 
atividades de aprendizagem, e a informação de fundo week?including 
para professores e tópicos do students?on relacionados ao espaço. 
A eficiência do aeroporto, a doença de movimento, as tarefas 
domésticas no espaço, a estação de espaço internacional, a 
prevenção do erro humano, ver o que não pode ser vista, os 
asteroids, e o uso da luz apressar a recuperação das doenças são 
entre os mais de 30 tópicos. As lições e os materiais 
suportam padrões da instrução nacional.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta a nuove lezioni ogni gli articoli 
week?including, le attività imparanti e le informazioni di base per 
gli insegnanti ed i soggetti dello students?on relativi a spazio. 
Il risparmio di temi dell'aeroporto, la cinetosi, il governo 
della casa nello spazio, la stazione di spazio internazionale, la 
prevenzione dell'errore umano, vedere che cosa non può essere vista, 
gli asteroidi e l'uso di luce accelerare il recupero dalle malattie 
sono fra i più di 30 soggetti. Le lezioni ed i materiali 
sostengono gli standard di formazione nazionale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τα νέα μαθήματα κάθε week?including 
άρθρα, δραστηριότητες εκμάθησης, και βασικές πληροφορίες για τους
δασκάλους και students?on θέματα σχετικά με το διάστημα. 
Η αποδοτικότητα αερολιμένων, η ασθένεια κινήσεων, η 
οικοκυρική στο διάστημα, ο διεθνής διαστημικός σταθμός, η 
πρόληψη του ανθρώπινου σφάλματος, να δουν τι δεν 
μπορεί να δει, asteroids, και η χρήση του φωτός στην
αποκατάσταση ταχύτητας από τις ασθένειες είναι μεταξύ των 
περισσότερων από 30 θεμάτων. Τα μαθήματα και τα υλικά 
υποστηρίζουν τα εθνικά πρότυπα εκπαίδευσης.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta a nuevas lecciones cada los artículos 
week?including, las actividades que aprenden, y la información de 
fondo para los profesores y los asuntos del students?on relacionados 
con el espacio. La eficacia del aeropuerto, la enfermedad de 
movimiento, las operacíones de entretenimiento en espacio, la 
estación espacial internacional, la prevención del error humano, ver
qué no puede ser vista, los asteroides, y el uso de la luz de 
apresurar la recuperación de enfermedades están entre los más de 30
asuntos. Las lecciones y los materiales utilizan estándares de 
la educación nacional.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206312</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108005</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/nasaexplores</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
