<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107522</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107522</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087295</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">A Family Corresponds: Polish Immigrants in the Early 20th century</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Eine Familie Entspricht: Polnische 
Immigranten im frühen 20. Jahrhundert</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Une Famille Correspond : Immigrés polonais 
en début du 20ème siècle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uma Família Corresponde: Immigrants 
poloneses no 20o século adiantado</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Una Famiglia Corrisponde: Immigranti 
polacchi nell'inizio del 20esimo secolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια οικογένεια αντιστοιχεί: Πολωνικοί μετανάστες
στις αρχές του 20ού αιώνα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Una Familia Corresponde: Inmigrantes polacos
en el vigésimo siglo temprano</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Many immigrants to the United States wrote letters back home. At the time they were written, the missives shaped the expectations of those who would soon make the same journey; today, they gave historians invaluable first-hand testimony of the immigrants' own experiences. These seventeen letters involved the children of a retired Polish farmer named Raczkowski. Adam Raczkowski went to the United States in 1904 with the financial assistance of his sister Helena Brylska [later Dabrowskis] and his brother Franciszek, who had both previously immigrated. He settled with his brother in Wilmington, Delaware, and obtained factory work. The letters included here cover the years 1904 to 1912 and were written between both Adam and Helena and their sister Teofila, who remained in Poland.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Viele Immigranten in die Vereinigten Staaten 
schrieben Zeichen rückseitiges Haus. Zu der Zeit als sie 
geschrieben wurden, formten die Sendschreiben die Erwartungen von 
denen, die bald die gleiche Reise bilden würden; heute gaben 
sie Historikern unschaetzbares aus erster Hand bezogenes Zeugnis 
eigener Erfahrungen der Immigranten. Diese siebzehn Zeichen 
bezogen die Kinder eines pensionierten polnischen Landwirts mit ein, 
der Raczkowski benannt wurde. Adam Raczkowski ging in die 
Vereinigten Staaten 1904 mit der finanziellen Unterstützung seiner 
Schwester Helena Brylska [ neueres Dabrowskis ] und sein Bruder 
Franciszek, der beide vorher hatte, wanderte ein. Er rechnete 
mit seinem Bruder in Wilmington, in Delaware und in erhaltener 
Fabrikarbeit ab. Die Zeichen, die hier eingeschlossen sind, 
umfassen die Jahre 1904 bis 1912 und wurden zwischen Adam und Helena 
und ihre Schwester Teofila geschrieben, die in Polen blieb.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Beaucoup d'immigrés vers les Etats-Unis ont 
écrit à des lettres la maison arrière. Lorsqu'ils ont été 
écrits, les missives ont formé les espérances de ceux qui feraient 
bientôt le même voyage ; aujourd'hui, ils ont donné à des 
historiens le témoignage de première main de valeur inestimable des 
propres expériences des immigrés. Ces dix-sept lettres ont 
fait participer les enfants d'un fermier polonais retraité nommé 
Raczkowski. Adam Raczkowski est allé aux Etats-Unis en 
1904 avec l'aide financière de sa soeur Helena Brylska [ plus défunt
Dabrowskis ] et son frère Franciszek, qui a eu tous les deux 
précédemment a immigré. Il a soldé le compte avec son frère
Wilmington, au Delaware, et travail obtenu d'usine. Les lettres 
incluses ici couvrent les années 1904 à 1912 et ont été écrites 
entre Adam et Helena et leur soeur Teofila, qui est restée en
Pologne.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Muitos immigrants aos estados unidos escreveram a 
letras a HOME traseira. Então foram escritos, os missives deram
forma às expectativas daqueles que fariam logo a mesma viagem; 
hoje, deram a historians o testimony first-hand invaluable de 
próprias experiências dos immigrants'. Estas dezessete letras 
envolveram as crianças de um fazendeiro polonês aposentado nomeado 
Raczkowski. Adam Raczkowski foi aos estados unidos em 1904 com o
auxílio financeiro de sua irmã Helena Brylska [ um Dabrowskis mais 
atrasado ] e seu irmão Franciszek, que teve ambos previamente 
immigrated. Estabeleciu-se com seu irmão em Wilmington, em 
Delaware, e no trabalho obtido da fábrica. As letras incluídas
aqui cobrem os anos 1904 a 1912 e foram escritas entre  Adam e Helena 
e sua irmã Teofila, que remanesceu em Poland.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Molti immigranti al unito Dichiara hanno 
scritto a lettere la sede posteriore. Quando sono stati scritti,
i missives hanno modellato le aspettative di coloro che presto farebbe
lo stesso viaggio; oggi, hanno dato a storici la testimonianza 
di prima mano inestimabile delle proprie esperienze degli immigranti. 
Queste diciassette lettere hanno fatto partecipare i bambini di 
un coltivatore polacco pensionato chiamato Raczkowski. Adam che 
Raczkowski è andato al unito Dichiara in 1904 con il concorso
finanziario della sua sorella Helena Brylska [ Dabrowskis successivo ]
ed il suo fratello Franciszek, che ha avuto precedentemente entrambi 
immigrated. Si è depositato con il suo fratello Wilmington, nel
Delaware ed il lavoro ottenuto della fabbrica. Le lettere 
incluse qui riguardano gli anni 1904 - 1912 e sono state scritte fra 
sia Adam che Helena e la loro sorella Teofila, che è rimasto in 
Polonia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολλοί μετανάστης στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες έγραψαν τις
επιστολές πίσω στο σπίτι. Στο χρόνο γράφτηκαν, τα 
missives διαμόρφωσαν τις προσδοκίες εκείνοι που θα έκαναν 
σύντομα το ίδιο ταξίδι  σήμερα, έδωσαν στους ιστορικούς 
την ανεκτίμητη από πρώτο χέρι κατάθεση της εμπειρίας των 
μεταναστών. Αυτές οι δεκαεπτά επιστολές περιέλαβαν τα 
παιδιά ενός συνταξιούχου πολωνικού αγρότη που ονομάστηκε 
Raczkowski. Θ*Αδαμ Raczkowski πήγε στις Ηνωμένες 
Πολιτείες το 1904 με χρηματοδοτική συνδρομή της αδελφής του 
Helena Brylska [ πιό πρόσφατο Dabrowskis ] και του 
αδελφού του Franciszek, οι οποίοι είχαν και τις δύο 
προηγουμένως μεταναστευμένος. Εγκατέστησε με τον αδελφό του 
σε Wilmington, Delaware, και έλαβε την εργασία εργοστασίων. 
Οι επιστολές συμπεριλαμβανόμενες εδώ καλύπτουν τα έτη 
1904 ως 1912 και γράφτηκαν και μεταξύ Adam και της 
Helena και της αδελφής τους Teofila, οι οποίοι παρέμειναν 
στην Πολωνία.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Muchos inmigrantes a los Estados Unidos 
escribieron a cartas el hogar posterior. Cuando les escribieron,
los missives formaron las expectativas de los que pronto harían el 
mismo viaje; hoy, dieron a historiadores el testimonio de 
primera mano inestimable de propias experiencias de los inmigrantes. 
Estas diecisiete cartas implicaron a niños de un granjero 
polaco jubilado nombrado Raczkowski. Adán Raczkowski fue a los 
Estados Unidos en 1904 con la ayuda financiera de su hermana Helena 
Brylska [ un Dabrowskis más último ] y su hermano Franciszek, que 
tenía ambos previamente immigrated. Él colocó con su hermano 
en Wilmington, Delaware, y trabajo obtenido de la fábrica. Las 
cartas incluidas aquí cubren los años 1904 a 1912 y fueron escritas 
entre Adán y Helena y su hermana Teofila, que permanecía en Polonia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087295</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107522</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/a-family-corresponds-polish-immigrants-in-the-early-20th-century</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
