<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103205</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103205</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206189</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Chandra X-ray Observatory</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Chandra Röntgenstrahl-Sternwarte</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Observatoire de Rayon X de Chandra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Obervatório Do Raio X De Chandra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Osservatorio Dei Raggi X Di Chandra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Των ακτίνων X παρατηρητήριο Chandra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Observatorio De la Radiografía De Chandra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features news and information about NASA's newest space telescope. As the world's most powerful X-rayobservatory, Chandra joins the Hubble Space Telescope and NASA's other observatories in a study of our universe, providing insights into the universe's structure and evolution. Visitors can track Chandra in orbit, watch live images from NASA-TV, and learn more about prior shuttle launch preparations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Merkmale Nachrichten und Informationen über 
neuesten Platz der NASAS schieben ineinander. Als 
leistungsfähigstes X-rayobservatory der Welt verbindet Chandra die 
anderen Sternwarten des Hubble Platz-Teleskops und der NASAS in einer 
Studie unseres Universums und stellt Einblicke in des die Struktur und
in Entwicklung Universums bereit. Besucher können Chandra in 
der Bahn aufspüren, Phasenbilder von NASA-TV überwachen, und mehr 
über vorherige Doppelventilkegelprodukteinführung Vorbereitungen 
erlernen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">les dispositifs nouvelles et information au sujet 
du plus nouvel espace de la NASA télescopent. En tant que 
X-rayobservatory le plus puissant du monde, Chandra joint 
observatoires de télescope et de NASA de l'espace de Hubble les 
autres dans une étude de notre univers, fournissant des 
perspicacités dans la structure et l'évolution de l'univers. 
Les visiteurs peuvent dépister Chandra en orbite, observer des 
images de phase de NASA-TV, et apprendre plus au sujet des 
préparations antérieures de lancement de navette.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">as características notícia e informação sobre o
espaço o mais novo da NASA encurtam. Como o X-rayobservatory o 
mais poderoso do mundo, Chandra junta obervatórios do telescópio e 
da NASA do espaço de Hubble os outros em um estudo de nosso universo,
fornecendo introspecções na estrutura e na evolução do universo. 
Os visitantes podem seguir Chandra na órbita, prestar atenção
a imagens vivas de NASA-TV, e aprender mais sobre preparações 
prévias do lançamento do shuttle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">le caratteristiche notizie e le informazioni circa 
il più nuovo spazio della NASA si infilano. Come 
X-rayobservatory più potente del mondo, Chandra unisce osservatori 
del telescopio e della NASA dello spazio di Hubble gli altri in uno 
studio del nostro universo, fornente le comprensioni nella struttura e
nello sviluppo dell'universo. Gli ospiti possono rintracciare 
Chandra in orbita, guardare le immagini in tensione da NASA-TV ed 
imparare più circa le preparazioni anteriori del lancio della spola.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ειδήσεις και πληροφορίες χαρακτηριστικών γνωρισμάτων 
για το νεώτερο διαστημικό τηλεσκόπιο της NASA. Σαν 
παγκόσμιο ισχυρότερο Χ- Rayobservatory, Chandra ενώνει τα 
διαστημικά άλλα παρατηρητήρια τηλεσκοπίων Hubble και της 
NASA σε μια μελέτη του κόσμου μας, που παρέχει τις ιδέες στη 
δομή και την εξέλιξη του κόσμου. Οι επισκέπτες μπορούν να 
ακολουθήσουν Chandra στην τροχιά, να προσέξουν τις ζωντανές 
εικόνες από την NASA-*TV, και να μάθουν περισσότερων για τις 
προγενέστερες προετοιμασίες έναρξης σαϊτών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">las características noticias e información sobre 
el más nuevo espacio de la NASA se telescopan. Como 
X-rayobservatory más de gran alcance del mundo, Chandra ensambla 
observatorios del telescopio y de la NASA del espacio de Hubble los 
otros en un estudio de nuestro universo, proporcionando a 
penetraciones en la estructura y la evolución del universo. Los
visitantes pueden seguir Chandra en órbita, mirar imágenes vivas de 
NASA-TV, y aprender más sobre preparaciones anteriores del 
lanzamiento de la lanzadera.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206189</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103205</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/chandra-x-ray-observatory</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
