<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103568</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103568</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087232</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">White sheets in Washington, D.C.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Weiße Blätter in Washington, Gleichstrom.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Feuilles blanches à Washington, C.C.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Folhas brancas em Washington, C.C..</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fogli bianchi in Washington, DC.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ασπρα φύλλα στην Ουάσιγκτον, ΣΥΝΕΧΈΣ ΡΕΎΜΑ</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Hojas blancas en Washington, C.C..</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Founded in 1915 and inspired by the Reconstruction-era organization of the same name, the second Ku Klux Klan shared with its nineteenth-century namesake a deep racism, a fascination with mystical regalia, and a willingness to use violence to silence its foes. It also professed anti-Catholicism and anti-Semitism as strongly as it affirmed racism. The secret" society had 3 million members during its heyday in the early 1920s; roughly half its members lived in metropolitan areas</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Gegründet 1915 und durch die Rekonstruktion-Ära 
Organisation des gleichen Namens angespornt, teilte das zweite Ku Klux
Klan mit seinem 19.-Jahrhundert namesake einen tiefen Rassismus, eine 
Faszination mit mystischem regalia und eine Bereitwilligkeit, 
Gewalttätigkeit zu verwenden, um seine Feinde zum Schweigen zu 
bringen. Es erklärte auch Anti-Katholizismus und Antisemitismus
so stark, wie es Rassismus bestätigte. Die geheime 
"Gesellschaft hatte 3 Million Bauteile während seiner Blütezeit 
in den frühen zwanziger Jahren; ungefähr lebte Hälfte seine 
Bauteil in den Metropolitanbereichen</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Fondé en 1915 et inspiré par l'organisation de 
Reconstruction-ère du même nom, le deuxième Ku Klux Klan a partagé
avec son homonyme de dix-neuvième-siècle un racisme profond, une 
fascination avec le régalia mystique, et une bonne volonté 
d'employer la violence pour amortir ses ennemis. Il également a
professé l'anti-Catholicisme et l'anti-sémitisme aussi fortement qu'il 
a affirmé le racisme. La "société secrète a eu 3 millions de
membres pendant son apogée au début des années 20 ; 
rudement la moitié de ses membres a vécu dans des zones 
métropolitaines</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Fundado em 1915 e inspirado pela organização da 
Reconstruction-era do mesmo nome, o segundo Ku Klux Klan compartilhou 
com seu namesake de décimo-século de um racism profundo, de um 
fascínio com o regalia mystical, e de um voluntariedade usar a 
violência silenciar seus foes. Professou também o 
anti-anti-Catholicism e o anti-Semitism tão fortemente quanto afirmou
o racism. A "sociedade secreta teve 3 milhão membros durante 
seu heyday nos 1920s adiantados; aproximadamente a metade dos 
seus membros viveu em áreas metropolitanas</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Fondato in 1915 ed ispirato dall'organizzazione di 
Ricostruzione-era dello stesso nome, il secondo Ku Klux Klan ha 
ripartito con il relativo namesake di diciannovesimo-secolo un 
razzismo profondo, un fascino per il regalia mystical e una 
compiacenza usare la violenza per fare tacere i relativi nemici.
Egualmente ha professato fortemente il anti-anti-Catholicism ed 
il anti-Semitism quanto ha affermato il razzismo. "la società 
segreta ha avuta 3 milione membri durante il relativo heyday 
nell'inizio degli anni 20; approssimativamente la metà dei 
relativi membri ha vissuto nelle aree metropolitane</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιδρυμένο το 1915 και εμπνευσμένο από την οργάνωση 
αναδημιουργία-εποχής του ίδιου ονόματος, το δεύτερο Ku Klux
Klan μοιράστηκε με το συνονόματο δέκατος-αιώνα του έναν βαθύ 
ρατσισμό, μια γοητεία με το μυστικό βασιλικό έμβλημα, και μια 
προθυμία να χρησιμοποιηθεί η βία για να κατασιγάσει τους εχθρούς 
του. Δήλωσε φανερά επίσης τον αντι-καθολικισμό και τον 
αντισημιτισμό τόσο έντονα όσο βεβαίωσε το ρατσισμό. Η 
μυστική "κοινωνία είχε 3 εκατομμύριο μέλη κατά τη διάρκεια του 
απόγειού της στις αρχές της δεκαετίας του '20  κατά 
προσέγγιση μισά από τα μέλη του έζησαν στις μητροπολιτικές 
περιοχές</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Fundado en 1915 e inspirado por la organización de la 
Reconstruccio'n-era del mismo nombre, el segundo Ku Klux Klan 
compartió con su namesake del diecinueveavo-siglo un racismo 
profundo, una fascinación con la regalía mystical, y una buena 
voluntad de utilizar violencia para silenciar a sus enemigos. 
También profesó contra-anti-Catholicism y anti-Semitism tan 
fuertemente como afirmó racismo. La "sociedad secreta tenía 3 
millones de miembros durante su apogeo en los años 20 tempranos; 
áspero la mitad de sus miembros vivió en áreas 
metropolitanas</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087232</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103568</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/white-sheets-in-washington-d-c</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
