<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108229</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108229</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206342</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Newspaper Pictorials: World War I Rotogravures</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zeitung Illustrierte: Erster 
Weltkriegrotogravures</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Graphiques de Journal : Rotogravures de 
Première Guerre Mondiale</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Pictorials Do Jornal: Rotogravures Do 
World.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Illustrazioni Del Giornale: Rotocalchi Di 
World.war.i</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εφημερίδα Pictorials: Παγκόσμιος πόλεμος Ι 
rotogravures</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Revistas ilustradas Del Periódico: 
Rotograbados De la Primera Guerra Mundial</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">presents images published from 1914-19 by two New York newspapers. The images, produced by a new rotogravure printing process, show events of the war alongside news and advertisements of the day. Essays discuss the origin of the war, costs of the war, President Wilson's 14 points, the armistice, military technology, the sinking of the Lusitania, pictures as propaganda, and the rotogravure process. A World War I timeline is included.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">stellt die Bilder dar, die von 1914-19 durch zwei 
New York Zeitungen veröffentlicht werden. Die Bilder, 
produziert durch einen druckenprozeß des neuen Rotogravure, zeigen 
Fälle des Krieges neben Nachrichten und der Reklameanzeigen des 
Tages. Versuche behandeln den Ursprung des Krieges, Kosten des 
Krieges, Präsident Wilsons 14 Punkte, der Waffenstillstand, 
militärische Technologie, das Sinken des Lusitania, Abbildungen als 
Propaganda und der Rotogravureprozeß. Ein Erster Weltkrieg 
timeline ist enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">présente des images éditées de 1914-19 par deux
journaux de New York. Les images, produites par un processus 
d'impression de nouvelle rotogravure, montrent des événements de la 
guerre à côté des nouvelles et des annonces du jour. Les 
essais discutent l'origine de la guerre, coûts de la guerre, 14 
points du Président Wilson, l'armistice, la technologie militaire, la
descente du Lusitania, images comme propagande, et processus de 
rotogravure. Une chronologie de Première Guerre Mondiale est 
incluse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">apresenta as imagens publicadas de 1914-19 por 
dois jornais de New York. As imagens, produzidas por um processo
imprimindo do rotogravure novo, mostram eventos da guerra ao lado da 
notícia e de propagandas do dia. Os essays discutem a origem da
guerra, custos da guerra, 14 pontos do presidente Wilson, o armistice,
tecnologia militar, afundar-se do Lusitania, retratos como o 
propaganda, e o processo do rotogravure. Um timeline do 
world.war.i é incluído.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">presenta le immagini pubblicate da 1914-19 da due 
giornali de New York. Le immagini, prodotte tramite un processo 
di stampa di nuovo rotocalco, mostrano gli eventi della guerra accanto
alle notizie e delle pubblicità del giorno. I saggi discutono 
l'origine della guerra, costi della guerra, 14 punti del presidente 
Wilson, il armistice, tecnologia militare, l'abbassamento del 
Lusitania, immagini come la propaganda ed il processo di rotocalco. 
Un timeline di world.war.i è incluso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">παρουσιάζει τις εικόνες που δημοσιεύονται από το 
1914-19 από δύο εφημερίδες της Νέας Υόρκης. Οι εικόνες,
που παράγονται με μια νέα rotogravure διαδικασία εκτύπωσης, 
εμφανίζουν γεγονότα του πολέμου παράλληλα με τις ειδήσεις και των
διαφημίσεων της ημέρας. Τα δοκίμια συζητούν την προέλευση 
του πολέμου, δαπάνες του πολέμου, 14 σημεία Προέδρου 
Wilson's, η ανακωχή, στρατιωτική τεχνολογία, η βύθιση του 
Lusitania, εικόνες ως προπαγάνδα, και rotogravure διαδικασία.
Ένας παγκόσμιος πόλεμος Ι υπόδειξη ως προς το χρόνο 
συμπεριλαμβάνεται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">presenta las imágenes publicadas a partir de 
1914-19 por dos periódicos de Nueva York. Las imágenes, 
producidas por un proceso de impresión del nuevo rotograbado, 
muestran los acontecimientos de la guerra junto a noticias y de los 
anuncios del día. Los ensayos discuten el origen de la guerra, 
costes de la guerra, 14 puntas de presidente Wilson, el armistice, 
tecnología militar, el hundirse del Lusitania, cuadros como 
propaganda, y el proceso del rotograbado. Un timeline de la 
Primera Guerra Mundial es incluido.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206342</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108229</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/newspaper-pictorials-world-war-i-rotogravures</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
