<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103223</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103223</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213043</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Volcanoes Loom as Sleeping Threat for Millions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vulkan-Webstuhl als Schlafendrohung für 
Millionen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Manche de volcans en tant que menace de sommeil 
pour des millions</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Tear dos vulcões como a ameaça dormir para 
milhões</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Telaio dei vulcani come minaccia di sonno per 
milioni</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αργαλειός ηφαιστείων ως απειλή ύπνου για τα 
εκατομμύρια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Telar de los volcanes como amenaza el dormir para 
millones</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This National Geographic news article from July 2002 describes world wide volcanic hazards. Due to the increasing population near dangerous volcanoes, the importance of volcanic monitoring and hazard prevention is essential. This article discusses the difficulty of educating residents about volcanic hazards and establishing programs to prevent disasters. The article also outlines several National Geographic television programs that relate to this topic. Users can also link to other National Geographic news stories, special news series and the main National Geographic site.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieser nationale geographische Nachrichten Artikel
von einem Juli 2002 beschreibt weltweite vulkanische Gefahren. 
Wegen der zunehmenden Bevölkerung nahe gefährlichen Vulkanen, 
des Wertes der vulkanischen Überwachung und der Gefahrverhinderung 
ist wesentlich. Dieser Artikel behandelt die Schwierigkeit des 
Erziehens der Bewohner über vulkanische Gefahren und des Herstellens 
von von Programmen, um Unfälle zu verhindern. Der Artikel 
umreißt auch einige nationale geographische Fernsehenprogramme, die 
auf diesem Thema in Verbindung stehen. Benutzer können mit 
anderen nationalen geographischen Nachrichten Geschichten, spezieller 
Nachrichten Serie und der nationalen geographischen hauptsächlichsite
auch binden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cet article géographique national de nouvelles à
partir de juillet 2002 décrit des risques volcaniques mondiaux. 
En raison de la population croissante près des volcans 
dangereux, de l'importance de la surveillance volcanique et de 
l'empêchement de risque est essentiel. Cet article discute la 
difficulté d'instruire des résidants au sujet des risques 
volcaniques et d'établir des programmes pour empêcher des 
désastres. L'article trace les grandes lignes également de 
plusieurs émissions télévisées géographiques nationales qui 
associent à ce sujet. Les utilisateurs peuvent également 
joindre à d'autres histoires géographiques nationales de nouvelles, 
séries spéciales de nouvelles et au site géographique national 
principal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este artigo geográfico nacional da notícia de 
julho 2002 descreve perigos vulcânicos largos do mundo. devido
à população crescente perto dos vulcões perigosos, à importância
da monitoração vulcânica e à prevenção do perigo é essencial. 
Este artigo discute a dificuldade de educar residentes sobre 
perigos vulcânicos e de estabelecer programas para impedir disastres.
O artigo esboça também diversos programas geográficos 
nacionais da televisão que se relacionam a este tópico. Os 
usuários podem também ligar às outras histórias geográficas 
nacionais da notícia, série especial da notícia e ao local 
geográfico nacional principal.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo articolo geografico nazionale di notizie da
luglio del 2002 descrive i rischi vulcanici in tutto il mondo. dovuto la popolazione aumentante vicino ai vulcani pericolosi, 
l'importanza di controllo vulcanico e la prevenzione di rischio è 
essenziale. Questo articolo discute la difficoltà di istruzione
dei residenti circa i rischi vulcanici e di stabilizzazione dei 
programmi per impedire i disastri. L'articolo egualmente 
descrive parecchi programmi televisivi geografici nazionali che si 
riferiscono a questo soggetto. Gli utenti possono anche 
collegarsi alle altra storia geografiche nazionali di notizie, serie 
speciale di notizie ed al luogo geografico nazionale principale.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό το εθνικό γεωγραφικό άρθρο ειδήσεων από τον 
Ιούλιο του 2002 περιγράφει τους παγκόσμιους ηφαιστειακούς 
κινδύνους. Λόγω στον αυξανόμενο πληθυσμό κοντά στα 
επικίνδυνα ηφαίστεια, η σημασία του ηφαιστειακών ελέγχου και της 
πρόληψης κινδύνου είναι ουσιαστική. Αυτό το άρθρο συζητά 
τη δυσκολία τους κατοίκους για τους ηφαιστειακούς κινδύνους και τα
προγράμματα για να αποτραπούν οι καταστροφές. Το άρθρο 
περιγράφει επίσης διάφορα εθνικά γεωγραφικά τηλεοπτικά 
προγράμματα που αφορούν αυτό το θέμα. Οι χρήστες μπορούν 
επίσης να συνδέσουν με άλλη εθνικές γεωγραφικές ιστορίες 
ειδήσεων, ειδική σειρά ειδήσεων και τη βασική εθνική γεωγραφική
περιοχή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este artículo geográfico nacional de las 
noticias a partir de julio de 2002 describe peligros volcánicos 
mundiales. debido a la población de aumento cerca de los 
volcanes peligrosos, a la importancia de vigilar volcánico y a la 
prevención del peligro es esencial. Este artículo discute la 
dificultad de educar a residentes sobre peligros volcánicos y de 
establecer programas para prevenir desastres. El artículo 
también contornea varios programas geográficos nacionales de la 
televisión que se relacionen con este asunto. Los utilizadores 
pueden también conectar a las otras historias geográficas nacionales
de las noticias, serie especial de las noticias y al sitio geográfico
nacional principal.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213043</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103223</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/volcanoes-loom-as-sleeping-threat-for-millions</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
