<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105252</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105252</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086243</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Holocaust or no holocaust, a woman's place is in . . .</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Holocaust oder kein holocaust, der Platz einer Frau
ist innen. . .</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Holocauste ou aucun holocauste, la place d'une 
femme est dedans. . .</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Holocaust ou nenhum holocaust, lugar de uma mulher
estão dentro. . .</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Non c'è Holocaust o nessun holocaust, posto della
donna dentro. . .</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το ολοκαύτωμα ή κανένα ολοκαύτωμα, η θέση μιας 
γυναίκας δεν είναι μέσα. ..</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Holocaust o no hay holocaust, el lugar de una 
mujer adentro. . .</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This illustration from the widely-circulated 1950 book  How to Survive an Atomic Bomb , which designated "appropriate" civil-defense jobs for men and women, reflected the contemporary labor market. While more women worked outside the home, they were largely confined to a female job ghetto, where wages were low, and prestige and opportunities for career advancement limited. Their subordination in the labor market coincided with a new postwar sexual ideology marked by rigidly defined gender roles that emphasized women's submissiveness and confinement to housework.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Abbildung vom breit-verteilten Buch 1950, wie man 
eine Atombombe, die "kennzeichnete, verwenden" Zivil-Verteidigung Jobs
für Männer und Frauen, reflektierte den zeitgenössischen 
Arbeitsmarkt überlebt. Während mehr Frauen außerhalb des 
Hauses arbeiteten, wurden sie groß auf einem weiblichen Jobgetto 
begrenzt, in dem Löhne niedrig waren, und Prestige und Gelegenheiten 
für Karrierezuführung begrenzten. Ihre Unterordnung im 
Arbeitsmarkt stimmte mit einer neuen sexuellen Nachkriegsideologie 
überein, die durch steif definierte Geschlechtrollen gekennzeichnet 
wurde, die submissiveness und Beschränkung der Frauen zur Hausarbeit 
hervorhoben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Cette illustration du livre 1950 large-circulé comment 
survivre une panne atomique, qui a indiqué "s'approprient" les 
travaux de la civil-défense pour les hommes et des femmes, a 
reflété le marché du travail contemporain. Tandis que plus de
femmes travaillaient en dehors de la maison, elles ont été en grande
partie confinées à un ghetto femelle du travail, où les salaires 
étaient bas, et le prestige et les occasions pour l'avancement de 
carrière ont limité. Leur subordination sur le marché du 
travail a coïncidé avec une nouvelle idéologie sexuelle 
d'après-guerre marquée par les rôles rigidement définis de genre 
qui ont souligné le submissiveness et l'emprisonnement des femmes aux
travaux domestiques.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta ilustração do livro 1950 largo-circulado como 
sobreviver uma bomba atômica, que designe "apropria" trabalhos da 
civil-defesa para homens e mulheres, refletiu o mercado labor 
contemporary. Quando mais mulheres trabalharam fora da HOME, 
foram confinadas pela maior parte a um ghetto fêmea do trabalho, onde
os salários fossem baixos, e o prestige e as oportunidades para o 
avanço da carreira limitaram. Seu subordination no mercado 
labor coincidiu com um ideology sexual postwar novo marcado pelos 
papéis rìgida definidos do gender que emfatizaram o submissiveness e
o confinamento das mulheres ao housework.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questa illustrazione dal libro largo-circolato 1950 come 
sopravvivere una bomba atomica, che ha indicato "appropria" i lavori 
della civile-difesa per gli uomini e le donne, ha riflesso il mercato 
di lavoro contemporaneo. Mentre più donne hanno lavorato 
fuori della sede, in gran parte sono state limitate ad un ghetto 
femminile di lavoro, in cui gli stipendi erano bassi ed il prestigio e
le occasioni per l'avanzamento di carriera hanno limitato. La 
loro subordinazione nel mercato di lavoro ha coinciso con una nuova 
ideologia sessuale dopoguerra contrassegnata dai ruoli rigidamente 
definiti di genere che hanno dato risalto al submissiveness ed alla 
relegazione delle donne a lavori domestici.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η απεικόνιση από το ευρέως-κυκλοφορημένο βιβλίο
του 1950 πώς να επιζήσει μιας ατομικής βόμβας, που υπέδειξε 
τις "κατάλληλεσ" αστικός-αμυντικές εργασίες για τους άνδρες και 
τις γυναίκες, απεικόνισε τη σύγχρονη αγορά εργασίας. Ενώ 
περισσότερες γυναίκες εργάστηκαν έξω από το σπίτι, 
περιορίστηκαν κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος σε ένα θηλυκό γκέτο 
εργασίας, όπου οι αμοιβές ήταν χαμηλές, και γόητρο και 
ευκαιρίες για την πρόοδο σταδιοδρομίας που περιορίστηκε. Η 
υπαγωγή τους στην αγορά εργασίας συνέπεσε με μια νέα 
μεταπολεμική σεξουαλική ιδεολογία που χαρακτηρίστηκε από τους 
άκαμπτα καθορισμένους ρόλους γένους που υπογράμμισαν το 
submissiveness και τον περιορισμό των γυναικών στα οικιακά.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esta ilustración del libro ancho-circulado 1950 cómo 
sobrevivir una bomba atómica, que señaló "se apropia" de los 
trabajos de la civil-defensa para los hombres y las mujeres, reflejó 
el mercado de trabajo contemporáneo. Mientras que más mujeres 
trabajaron fuera del hogar, las confinaron en gran parte a un ghetto 
femenino del trabajo, donde estaban bajos los salarios, y el prestigio
y las oportunidades para el adelanto de la carrera se limitaron. 
Su subordinación en el mercado de trabajo coincidió con una 
nueva ideología sexual de la posguerra marcada por los papeles 
rígido definidos del género que acentuaron el submissiveness y el 
confinamiento de las mujeres al quehacer doméstico.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086243</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105252</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/holocaust-or-no-holocaust-a-womans-place-is-in</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
