<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106294</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106294</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087421</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Bear Hunting in Tennessee: Davy Crockett Tells Tales, 1834</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bär Jagd in Tennessee: Davy Crockett 
Erklärt Geschichten, 1834</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chasse d'ours au Tennessee : Davy Crockett 
Indique Les Contes, 1834</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Caça do urso em Tennessee: Davy Crockett 
Diz Os Tales, 1834</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Orso che Cerca nel Tennessee: 
Davy Crockett Dice Ai Racconti, 1834</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αντέξτε στο Tennessee: Το Davy Crockett 
λέει τις ιστορίες, 1834</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Caza del oso en Tennessee: Davy Crockett 
Cuenta Los Cuentos, 1834</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">During the late-18th century, many southerners headed west, leaving older areas such as the Carolinas and Georgia; by 1790 more than 100,000 had moved into Kentucky and Tennessee. David Crockett was born in 1786 in East Tennessee. He fashioned a career as an Indian fighter, politician, and frontier humorist, using his mastery of the vernacular to spin tales on the campaign stump or in print. Crockett had many supposed life stories, but  A Narrative of the Life of David Crockett of the State of Tennessee , published in 1834, is believed to be Crockett's actual work (edited by Thomas Chilton). These excerpts about bear hunting in Tennessee emphasized Crockett's reputation as a great hunter and contributed to his legendary status even before his death at the Alamo in 1836.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Während des late-18th Jahrhunderts, vieler 
southerners vorangegangen West, ältere Bereiche wie das Carolinas und
das Georgia lassend; durch 1790 mehr als 100.000 hatte in 
Kentucky und in Tennessee bewogen. David Crockett wurde 1786 in 
Osttennessee getragen. Er arbeitete eine Karriere als indischer 
Kämpfer, Politiker und Grenzhumorist mit seiner Beherrschung von 
vernacular, Geschichten auf dem Kampagne Stumpf oder im Druck zu 
spinnen um. Crockett hatte viele angenommene Lebengeschichten, 
aber eine Darstellung der Lebensdauer von David Crockett des Zustandes
von Tennessee, veröffentlicht 1834, wird geglaubt, um Crocketts die 
tatsächliche Arbeit zu sein (bearbeitet von Thomas Chilton). 
Diese Excerpts über die Bär Jagd in Tennessee hoben Renommee 
Crocketts als großer Jäger hervor und trugen zu seinem legendären 
Status sogar vor seinem Tod beim Alamo 1836 bei.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Pendant le siècle de late-18th, beaucoup de 
habitants du sud dirigés occidental, laissant des zones plus anciennes 
telles que le Carolinas et la Géorgie ; par 1790 plus de 
100.000 était entré dans le Kentucky et le Tennessee. David 
Crockett a été soutenu en 1786 au Tennessee est. Il mode une 
carrière en tant qu'un combattant, un politicien, et humoriste 
indiens de frontière, en utilisant sa maîtrise du vernaculaire pour 
tourner des contes sur le tronçon de campagne ou dans la copie. 
Crockett a eu beaucoup d'histoires supposées de la vie, mais on
pense qu'un récit de la vie de David Crockett de l'état du 
Tennessee, édité en 1834, est le travail réel de Crockett (édité 
par Thomas Chilton). Ces extraits au sujet de la chasse d'ours 
au Tennessee ont souligné la réputation de Crockett en tant que 
grand chasseur et ont contribué à son mode légendaire même avant 
sa mort chez l'Alamo en 1836.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Durante o século de late-18th, muitos southerners
dirigidos ocidental, deixando áreas mais velhas tais como o Carolinas
e o Geórgia; por 1790 mais de 100.000 tinha-se movido em 
Kentucky e em Tennessee. David Crockett foi carregado em 1786 em
Tennessee do leste. Formou uma carreira como um lutador, um 
político, e um humorist indian da fronteira, usando seu mastery do 
vernacular girar tales no stump da campanha ou na cópia. 
Crockett teve muitas histórias supostas da vida, mas uma 
narrativa da vida de David Crockett do estado de Tennessee, publicado 
em 1834, é acreditada para ser trabalho real de Crockett (editado por
Thomas Chilton). Estes excerpts sobre a caça do urso em 
Tennessee emfatizaram a reputação de Crockett como um caçador 
grande e contribuíram-na a seu status legendário mesmo antes de sua 
morte no Alamo em 1836.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Durante il secolo di late-18th, i molti 
southerners diretti ad ovest, lasciando le più vecchie zone quali il 
Carolinas e la Georgia; da 1790 più di 100.000 aveva entrato 
nel Kentucky e nel Tennessee. David Crockett è stato sopportato
in 1786 nel Tennessee orientale. Moda una carriera come un 
combattente, un politico e humorist indiani di frontiera, usando la 
sua padronanza del vernacolare per filare i racconti sul ceppo di 
campagna o in stampa. Crockett ha avuto molte storia presunte di
vita, ma una descrizione della durata di David Crockett del 
Dichiarare del Tennessee, pubblicato in 1834, si crede per essere 
lavoro reale del Crockett (stampato da Thomas Chilton). Questi 
brani circa l'orso che cerca nel Tennessee hanno dato 
risalto alla reputazione del Crockett come cacciatore grande ed hanno 
contribuito alla sua condizione leggendaria anche prima della sua 
morte al Alamo in 1836.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατά τη διάρκεια του πρόσφατος-18$ου αιώνα, πολλοί 
νότιοι διεύθυναν τη δύση, αφήνοντας τις παλαιότερες περιοχές 
όπως το Carolinas και η Γεωργία  από 1790 περισσότερο 
από 100.000 είχε κινηθεί στο Κεντάκυ και το Tennessee. 
Ο Δαβίδ Crockett γεννήθηκε το 1786 στο ανατολικό 
Tennessee. Διαμόρφωσε μια σταδιοδρομία ως ινδικούς 
μαχητή, πολιτικό, και συνοριακό ευθυμογράφο, χρησιμοποιώντας την 
κυριότητά του του ιδιωματικού στις ιστορίες περιστροφής στο 
κολόβωμα εκστρατείας ή στην τυπωμένη ύλη. Το Crockett 
είχε πολλές υποτιθέμενες ιστορίες ζωής, αλλά ένα αφήγημα της 
ζωής του Δαβίδ Crockett του κράτους του Tennessee, που 
δημοσιεύεται το 1834, θεωρείται πραγματική εργασία Crockett 
(που επιμελείται από τον Thomas Chilton). Αυτά τα 
αποσπάσματα για το κυνήγι αρκούδων στο Tennessee υπογράμμισαν 
τη φήμη Crockett ως μεγάλο κυνηγό και συνέβαλαν στη θρυλική 
θέση του ακόμη και πριν από το θάνατό του alamo το 1836.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Durante el siglo de late-18th, muchos southerners 
dirigidos del oeste, dejando más viejas áreas tales como el 
Carolinas y la Georgia; por 1790 más de 100.000 se había 
movido en Kentucky y Tennessee. David Crockett fue llevado en 
1786 en Tennessee del este. Él formó una carrera como un 
combatiente, un político, y humorista indios de la frontera, usando 
su maestría del vernáculo para hacer girar cuentos en el tocón de 
la campaña o en la impresión. Crockett tenía muchas historias
supuestas de la vida, pero una narrativa de la vida de David Crockett 
del estado de Tennessee, publicado en 1834, se cree para ser trabajo 
real de Crockett (corregido por Thomas Chilton). Estos extractos
sobre la caza del oso en Tennessee acentuaron la reputación de 
Crockett como gran cazador y contribuyeron a su estatus legendario 
incluso antes de su muerte en el Alamo en 1836.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087421</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106294</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/bear-hunting-in-tennessee-davy-crockett-tells-tales-1834</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
