<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108048</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108048</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086925</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Crisis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Krise</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Crise</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Crise</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Crisi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η κρίση</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Crisis</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Crisis  was a monthly magazine put out by the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), an organization that advocated for African-American civil rights, and was edited by the black activist intellectual W. E. B. Du Bois. Heralding the style and substance of the Harlem Renaissance,  The Crisis  reached from 60,000 to nearly 100,000 readers monthly during the 1920s. The flowering of black culture known as the Harlem Renaissance took inspiration from the emergence of pan-Africanism as an intellectual and political movement, and a growing sense of racial pride. In an era when white publications largely ignored African Americans,  The Crisis  presented a mix of news of African-American accomplishment; exposes of southern and northern racism; reports on efforts to improve the political, economic, and social circumstances of African Americans; and incisive editorials penned by Du Bois himself. The magazine also promoted African-American artistic production by publishing the work of and sponsoring contests for writers, composers, and visual artists.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Krise war eine Monatszeitschrift, die heraus 
durch die nationale Verbindung für die Zuführung der Farbiger 
(NAACP) gesetzt wurde, der Organisation, die für 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanische Zivilrechte befürworteten, und wurde vom 
schwarzen Aktivisten intellektuelles W. E. B. Du Bois bearbeitet. 
Die Art und die Substanz der Harlem Renaissance ankündigend, 
erreichte die Krise von 60.000 zu fast 100.000 Lesern monatlich 
während der zwanziger Jahre. Das Blühen der schwarzen Kultur 
bekannt als die Harlem Renaissance nahm Inspiration vom Hervortreten 
der Wanne-Africanism als intellektuelle und politische Bewegung und 
eine wachsende Richtung des rassischen Stolzes. In einer Ära, 
als weiße Publikationen groß afrikanische Amerikaner ignorierten, 
stellte die Krise eine Mischung der Nachrichten der 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanischen Vollendung dar; stellt vom südlichen
und Nordrassismus heraus; Berichte über Bemühungen, die 
politischen, ökonomischen und Sozialumstände der afrikanischen 
Amerikaner zu verbessern; und incisive Leitartikel eingesperrt 
von Du Bois selbst. Die Zeitschrift förderte auch 
Afrikanisch-Amerikanische künstlerische Produktion, indem sie die 
Arbeit von veröffentlichte und Wettbewerbe für Verfasser, 
Komponisten und Sichtkünstler förderte.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La crise était un magasin mensuel eteint par 
l'association nationale pour l'avancement des personnes de couleur 
(NAACP), d'une organisation qui ont préconisé pour des droits 
civiques afro-américains, et a été éditée par l'activiste noir W. E. 
B. Du Bois intellectuel. Annonçant le modèle et la substance 
de la Renaissance de Harlem, la crise a atteint de 60.000 à 
presque 100.000 lecteurs mensuellement pendant les années 20. 
La fleuraison de la culture noire connue sous le nom de 
Renaissance de Harlem a pris l'inspiration de l'apparition de la 
casserole-Africanism comme mouvement intellectuel et politique, et un 
sens croissant de fierté raciale. Dans une ère quand les 
publications blanches ont en grande partie ignoré les Américains 
africains, la crise a présenté un mélange des nouvelles de 
l'accomplissement afro-américain ; expose du racisme méridional 
et nordique ; états sur des efforts d'améliorer les 
circonstances politiques, économiques, et sociales des Américains 
africains ; et éditoriaux incisifs parqués par du Bois 
lui-même. Le magasin a également favorisé la production 
artistique afro-américaine en éditant le travail de et en commanditant 
des concours pour des auteurs, des compositeurs, et des artistes 
visuels.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A crise era um compartimento mensal posto para 
fora pela associação nacional para o avanço dos povos coloridos 
(NAACP), de uma organização que advogaram para direitas civis 
Africano-Americanas, e foi editada pela activista preta W. intelectual
E. B. Du Bois. Heralding o estilo e a substância do 
renascimento de Harlem, a crise alcançou de 60.000 a quase 100.000 
leitores mensalmente durante os 1920s. Flowering da cultura 
preta sabido como o renascimento de Harlem fêz exame da inspiração 
do emergence da bandeja-Africanism como um movimento intelectual e 
político, e de um sentido crescente do orgulho racial. Em uma 
era quando as publicações brancas ignoraram pela maior parte 
americanos africanos, a crise apresentou uma mistura da notícia da 
realização Africano-Americana; expõe do racism do sul e do 
norte; relatórios em esforços melhorar as circunstâncias 
políticas, econômicas, e sociais de americanos africanos; e 
editorials incisive penned por Du Bois ele mesmo. O 
compartimento promoveu também a produção artística 
Africano-Americana publicando o trabalho de e patrocinando 
competições para escritores, compositores, e artistas visuais.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La crisi era uno scomparto mensile messo fuori 
dall'associazione nazionale per l'avanzamento della gente colorata 
(NAACP), di un'organizzazione che hanno sostenuto per i diritti civili
Africano-Americani ed è stata stampata dall'attivista nero W. E. B.
Du Bois intellettuale. Annunziando lo stile e la sostanza della 
rinascita di Harlem, la crisi ha raggiunto mensilmente da 60.000 a 
quasi 100.000 lettori durante gli anni 20. La fioritura della 
coltura nera conosciuta come la rinascita di Harlem ha preso 
l'ispirazione dall'emersione della vaschetta-Africanism come movimento
intellettuale e politico e un senso crescente di orgoglio razziale. 
In un'era quando le pubblicazioni bianche in gran parte hanno 
ignorato gli Americani africani, la crisi ha presentato una miscela 
delle notizie della realizzazione Africano-Americana; espone del
razzismo del sud e nordico; rapporti sugli sforzi migliorare le 
circostanze politiche, economiche e sociali degli Americani africani; 
ed editoriali incisive rinchiusi da Du Bois egli stesso. 
Lo scomparto egualmente ha promosso la produzione artistica 
Africano-Americana pubblicando il lavoro di e patrocinando i concorsi 
per i produttori, i compositori e gli artisti visivi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η κρίση ήταν ένα μηνιαίο περιοδικό που τέθηκε έξω 
από την εθνική ένωση για την πρόοδο των έγχρωμων ανθρώπων 
(NAACP), μιας οργάνωσης που υποστήριξαν για τα 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικά αστικά δικαιώματα, και επιμελήθηκε από 
το μαύρο ενεργό στέλεχος διανοητικό Θ*Ω. Ε. Β. du Bois. 
Ανακοινώνοντας το ύφος και την ουσία της αναγέννησης 
Harlem, η κρίση έφθασε από 60.000 σε σχεδόν 100.000 
αναγνώστες μηνιαία κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '20. 
Το άνθισμα του μαύρου πολιτισμού γνωστού ως αναγέννηση 
Harlem πήρε την έμπνευση από την εμφάνιση παν- africanism ως
διανοητική και πολιτική μετακίνηση, και μια αυξανόμενη αίσθηση 
της φυλετικής υπερηφάνειας. Σε μια εποχή όταν αγνόησαν 
κατά ένα μεγάλο μέρος οι άσπρες δημοσιεύσεις αφρικανικούς 
Αμερικανούς, η κρίση παρουσίασε ένα μίγμα των ειδήσεων της 
αφρικανικός-αμερικανικής ολοκλήρωσης  εκθέτει του νότιου 
και βόρειου ρατσισμού  εκθέσεις σχετικά με τις προσπάθειες 
να βελτιωθούν οι πολιτικές, οικονομικές, και κοινωνικές 
περιστάσεις αφρικανικών Αμερικανών  και κύρια άρθρα που 
περιφράζονται δηκτικά από du Bois ο ίδιος. Το 
περιοδικό προώθησε επίσης την αφρικανικός-αμερικανική 
καλλιτεχνική παραγωγή με την έκδοση της εργασίας και των 
διαγωνισμών υποστήριξης για τους συγγραφείς, τους συνθέτες, και 
τους εικαστηκούς καλλιτέχνες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La crisis era un compartimiento mensual puesto 
hacia fuera por la asociación nacional para el adelanto de la gente 
coloreada (NAACP), de una organización que abogaron para las derechas
civiles Africano-Americanas, y fue corregida por el activista negro W.
intelectual E. B. Du Bois. Anunciando el estilo y la sustancia 
del renacimiento de Harlem, la crisis alcanzó a partir del 60.000 a 
casi 100.000 programas de lectura mensualmente durante los años 20. 
El florecimiento de la cultura negra conocido como el 
renacimiento de Harlem tomó la inspiración de la aparición de la 
cacerola-Africanism como movimiento intelectual y político, y un 
sentido cada vez mayor del orgullo racial. En una era cuando las
publicaciones blancas no hicieron caso en gran parte de americanos 
africanos, la crisis presentó una mezcla de las noticias de la 
realización Africano-Americana; expone de racismo meridional y 
norteño; informes sobre esfuerzos de mejorar las circunstancias
políticas, económicas, y sociales de americanos africanos; y 
editoriales incisivos encerrados por Du Bois mismo. El 
compartimiento también promovió la producción artística 
Africano-Americana publicando el trabajo de y patrocinando las 
competencias para los programas de escritura, los compositores, y los 
artistas visuales.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086925</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108048</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-crisis</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
