<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106087</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106087</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086882</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"That Broke Down the Ethnic Barriers": A Steelworker Describes the Decline of Ethnic Hostility in the 1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"das hinunter die ethnischen Sperren" brach: 
Ein Steelworker beschreibt die Abnahme der ethnischen 
Feindseligkeit in den dreißiger Jahren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"qui a décomposé les barrières ethniques" : 
Un travailleur dans l'industrie sidérurgique décrit le déclin
de l'hostilité ethnique dans les années 30</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"que quebrou abaixo as barreiras étnicas": 
Um steelworker descreve o declínio da hostilidade étnica nos 
1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"che ha suddiviso le barriere etniche": Un 
addetto alla lavorazione dell'acciaio descrive il declino di ostilità
etnica nei 1930s</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Αυτός κατάργησε τα εθνικά εμπόδια": Ένας 
σιδηρουργός περιγράφει την πτώση της εθνικής εχθρότητας στη 
δεκαετία του '30</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"que analizó las barreras étnicas": Un 
trabajador siderúrgico describe la declinación de la hostilidad 
étnica en los años 30</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Tensions among industrial workers of different ethnic backgrounds often proved a barrier to unionization in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. It was, for example, a key factor in the defeat of the 1919 steel strike. In the 1930s, however, that began to change, particularly under the auspices of the CIO. In this 1974 interview done by historian Peter Gotlieb in 1974, Polish-American steelworker Joe Rudiak recalled how ethnic hostility declined in the "CIO days," particularly among the "young folks." This decrease in suspicion between people of different nationalities fostered unionization in the 1930s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spannkräfte unter industriellen Arbeitern der 
unterschiedlichen ethnischen Hintergründe prüften häufig eine 
Sperre zum Unionization in dem späten 19. und früh zu den 
zwanzigsten Jahrhunderten. Es war z.B. ein Schlüsselfaktor in 
der Niederlage des Stahlschlages 1919. In den dreißiger Jahren 
jedoch die anfingen zu ändern, besonders unter den Auspizienn des 
CIO. In diesem Interview 1974, das mit Historiker Peter Gotlieb 
1974 erfolgt war, rief Polieren-Amerikanischer Steelworker Joe Rudiak,
wie ethnische Feindseligkeit an den "CIO Tagen sank," besonders unter 
den "jungen Völkern." wieder auf Diese Abnahme am Misstrauen 
zwischen Leuten der unterschiedlichen Nationalitäten förderte 
Unionization in den dreißiger Jahren.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les tensions parmi les ouvriers industriels de 
différents milieux ethniques ont souvent prouvé une barrière à la 
syndicalisation vers la fin du dix-neuvième et tôt aux vingtième 
siècles. C'était, par exemple, un facteur principal dans la 
défaite de la grève 1919 en acier. Dans les années 30, 
cependant, qui ont commencé à changer, en particulier sous les 
auspices du CIO. Dans cette entrevue 1974 faite par l'historien 
Peter Gotlieb en 1974, le travailleur dans l'industrie 
sidérurgique Polir-Américain Joe Rudiak s'est rappelé comment 
l'hostilité ethnique a diminué en "jours de CIO," en particulier 
parmi les "jeunes gens." Cette diminution de soupçon entre les 
personnes de différentes nationalités a stimulé la syndicalisation 
dans les années 30.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">As tensões entre trabalhadores industriais de 
fundos étnicos diferentes provaram frequentemente uma barreira ao 
unionization no décimo nono atrasado e cedo aos vigésimos séculos. 
Era, para o exemplo, um fator chave na derrota da batida 1919 de
aço. Nos 1930s, entretanto, que começaram a mudar, 
particularmente sob os auspices do CIO. Nesta entrevista 1974 
feita pelo historian Peter Gotlieb em 1974, o steelworker 
Lustr-Americano Joe Rudiak recordou como a hostilidade étnica 
declinou de "nos dias CIO," particularmente entre "os povos novos." 
Esta diminuição na suspeita entre povos de nacionalidades 
diferentes promoveu o unionization nos 1930s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">I tensionamenti fra i lavoratori dell'industria 
degli ambiti di provenienza etnici differenti hanno dimostrato spesso 
una barriera a unionization verso la fine del diciannovesimi e presto 
ai ventesimi secoli. Era, per esempio, un fattore chiave nella 
sconfitta del colpo d'acciaio 1919. Nei 1930s, tuttavia, che 
hanno cominciato a cambiare, specialmente sotto gli auspici del CIO. 
In questa intervista 1974 fatta dallo storico Peter Gotlieb in 
1974, l'addetto alla lavorazione dell'acciaio Lucid-Americano Joe 
Rudiak ha ricordato come l'ostilità etnica ha declinato "nei giorni 
di CIO," specialmente fra "la gente giovane." Questa diminuzione
nel sospetto fra la gente delle nazionalità differenti ha promosso il
unionization nei 1930s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι εντάσεις μεταξύ των βιομηχανικών εργατών των 
διαφορετικών εθνικών υποβάθρων απέδειξαν συχνά ένα εμπόδιο στη 
συνδικαλικοποίηση προς το τέλος του δέκατου έννατου και τους 
εικοστούς νωρίς αιώνες. Ήταν, παραδείγματος χάριν, ένας 
βασικός παράγοντας στην ήττα της απεργίας χάλυβα του 1919. 
Στη δεκαετία του '30, εντούτοις, που άρχισε να αλλάζει, 
ιδιαίτερα υπό την αιγίδα του CIO. Σε αυτήν την 
συνέντευξη του 1974 που έγινε από τον ιστορικό Peter 
Gotlieb το 1974, ο πολωνικός-αμερικανικός σιδηρουργός Joe 
Rudiak υπενθύμισε πώς η εθνική εχθρότητα μειώθηκε στις 
"ημέρες CIO," ιδιαίτερα μεταξύ των "νέων λαών." Αυτή η 
μείωση στην υποψία μεταξύ των ανθρώπων των διαφορετικών 
υπηκοοτήτων ενθάρρυνε τη συνδικαλικοποίηση στη δεκαετία του '30.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las tensiones entre los trabajadores industriales 
de diversos fondos étnicos probaron a menudo una barrera a la 
sindicalización en la último diecinueveavo y temprano a los 
vigésimos siglos. Era, por ejemplo, un factor dominante en la 
derrota de la huelga de acero 1919. En los años 30, sin 
embargo, que comenzaron a cambiar, determinado bajo auspicios del CIO.
En esta entrevista 1974 hecha por el historiador Peter Gotlieb 
en 1974, el trabajador siderúrgico Pulir-Americano Joe Rudiak 
recordó cómo la hostilidad étnica declinó en los "días de CIO," 
determinado entre la "gente joven." Esta disminución de la 
suspicacia entre la gente de diversas nacionalidades fomentó la 
sindicalización en los años 30.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086882</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106087</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/that-broke-down-the-ethnic-barriers-a-steelworker-describes-the-decline-of-ethnic-hostility-in-the-1930s</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
