<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102864</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102864</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087147</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Two Bits for a Tragic Tale: Walter Fink's  The Ludlow Massacre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zwei Bits für eine tragische Geschichte: 
Das Blutbad Ludlow Des Walter Informanten</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Deux bits pour un conte tragique : Le 
Massacre de Ludlow du Mouchard de Walter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Dois bits para um tale trágico: O Massacre 
De Ludlow Do Fink De Walter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Due bit per un racconto tragico: Il Massacre
Di Ludlow Del Fink Di Walter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δύο μπιτ για μια τραγική ιστορία: Walter 
Fink's η σφαγή Ludlow</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Dos dígitos binarios para un cuento trágico: 
La Masacre De Ludlow Del Fink De Walter</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The often violent labor struggles of the early 20th century engendered deep concern at all levels of society and led to a series of governmental investigations, including the federal Commission on Industrial Relations, appointed in 1913. The commission was in the midst of taking testimony from owners, workers, and reformers in dozens of industrial communities around the country when a coal strike broke out in southern Colorado. On Easter night, 1914, three women and eleven children were killed at a mining encampment in Ludlow, Colorado.The United Mine Workers of America, the union that represented the striking Colorado miners, quickly printed and sold (for 25 cents) thousands of copies of a pamphlet (excerpted here) entitled  The Ludlow Massacre  by Walter Fink, director of publicity of UMWA District 15. In addition to providing a dramatic retelling of the events leading up to the tragedy, the title of the pamphlet became the commonly accepted term for the event.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die häufig heftigen Arbeitskämpfe des frühes 
20. Jahrhundert erzeugten tiefen Interesses auf allen Stufen der 
Gesellschaft und zu eine Reihe Regierungsuntersuchungen, 
einschließlich die Bundeskommission auf den industriellen Beziehungen
zwischen den Sozialpartnern geführt, ernannt 1913. Die 
Kommission war in der Mitte des Nehmens des Zeugnisses von den 
Inhabern, von den Arbeitern und von den Reformern in den 
Dutzenden der industriellen Gemeinschaften um das Land, als ein 
Kohleschlag in Südkolorado ausbrach. Auf Ostern Nacht wurden 
1914, drei Frauen und elf Kinder an einem gewinnenlager in Ludlow, an 
Colorado.The vereinigten Grube Arbeitern von Amerika, an den 
Anschluß- beendet, der die auffallenden Kolorado Bergmänner 
darstellte, schnell gedruckten und verkauften(für 25 Cents) Tausenden
der Exemplare einer Flugschrift (hier excerptiert) erlaubt das Ludlow 
Blutbad von Walter Fink, Direktor der Werbung UMWA Bezirkes 15. 
Zusätzlich zum Zur Verfügung stellen eines drastischen 
Wiederholens der Fälle, die bis zur Tragödie führen, wurde der 
Titel der Flugschrift die geläufig akzeptierte Bedingung für den 
Fall.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les luttes de travail souvent violentes du souci 
profond engendré début du 20ème par siècle de tous les niveaux de 
la société et menés à une série d'investigations 
gouvernementales, y compris la Commission fédérale sur des relations
industrielles, désignées en 1913. La commission était au 
milieu de prendre le témoignage des propriétaires, des ouvriers, et 
des réformateurs dans les douzaines des communautés industrielles dans
le pays quand une grève de charbon a éclaté dans le Colorado 
méridional. La nuit de Pâques, les 1914, trois femmes et les 
onze enfants ont été détruits à un campement d'extraction dans 
Ludlow, aux mineurs unis par Colorado.The de l'Amérique, aux milliers
des syndicats qui ont représenté les mineurs saisissants du 
Colorado, rapidement impression et vendue (pour 25 cents) de copies 
d'une brochure (extraite ici) autorisée le Massacre de Ludlow par 
Walter Fink, directeur de la publicité de la zone 15 d'UMWA. En
plus de fournir raconter de nouveau excessif des événements amenant à 
la tragédie, le titre de la brochure est devenu la limite 
généralement reçue pour l'événement.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os esforços labor frequentemente violentos 20o 
século adiantado do interesse profundo engendered em todos os níveis
da sociedade e conduzidos a uma série de investigações 
governamentais, including o commission federal nas relações 
industriais, apontadas em 1913. O commission estava no meio de 
fazer exame do testimony dos proprietários, dos trabalhadores, e dos 
reformers nas dúzias de comunidades industriais em torno do país 
quando uma batida de carvão quebrou para fora em Colorado do sul. 
Na noite de Easter, 1914, três mulheres e onze crianças foram 
matadas em um encampment minando em Ludlow, em trabalhadores de mina 
unidos Colorado.The de América, nos milhares da união que 
representou os mineiros impressionantes de Colorado, rapidamente 
imprimido e vendido (para 25 centavos) das cópias de um panfleto 
(excerpted aqui) intitulado o massacre de Ludlow por Walter Fink, 
diretor do publicity do distrito 15 de UMWA. Além a fornecer 
retelling dramático dos eventos que conduzem à tragédia, o título 
do panfleto transformou-se o termo geralmente aceitado para o evento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Le lotte di lavoro spesso violente della 
preoccupazione profonda generata inizio del 20esimo secolo a tutti i 
livelli della società e condotti ad una serie di indagini 
governative, compreso la Commissione federale sulle relazione 
industriali, nominate in 1913. La commissione in mezzo a stava 
prendendo la testimonianza dai proprietari, dagli operai e dai 
reformers nelle dozzine delle Comunità industriali intorno al paese 
quando un colpo del carbone ha scoppiato in Colorado del sud. 
Sulla notte di Pasqua, 1914, tre donne ed undici bambini sono 
stati uccisi ad un encampment estraente in Ludlow, ai minatori uniti 
Colorado.The dell'America, alle migliaia rapidamente stampata e 
venduto del sindacato che ha rappresentato i minatori notevoli del 
Colorado, (per 25 centesimi) delle copie di un opuscolo (stralciato 
qui) intitolato il massacre di Ludlow da Walter Fink, direttore di 
pubblicità del distretto 15 di UMWA. Oltre che fornire 
retelling drammatico degli eventi che portano alla tragedia, il titolo
dell'opuscolo si è transformato in nel termine comunemente accettato 
per l'evento.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι συχνά βίαιες προσπάθειες εργασίας του πρόωρου 
20ού αιώνα προκάλεσαν τη βαθιά ανησυχία σε όλα τα επίπεδα της 
κοινωνίας και οδήγησαν σε μια σειρά κυβερνητικών ερευνών, 
συμπεριλαμβανομένης της ομοσπονδιακής Επιτροπής στις εργασιακές 
σχέσεις, που διορίστηκαν το 1913. Η επιτροπή ήταν στη 
μέση της λήψης της κατάθεσης από τους ιδιοκτήτες, τους 
εργαζομένους, και τους μεταρρυθμιστές στις δωδεκάδες των 
βιομηχανικών κοινοτήτων γύρω από τη χώρα όταν ξέσπησε μια 
απεργία άνθρακα στο νότιο Κολοράντο. Στη νύχτα Πάσχας, 
1914, τρεις γυναίκες και ένδεκα παιδιά σκοτώθηκαν σε μια 
στρατοπέδευση μεταλλείας σε Ludlow, Κολοράντο Οι ενωμένοι
εργαζόμενοι ορυχείου της Αμερικής, τυπωμένη και πωλημένη (για 
25 σεντ) χιλιάδες ένωσης που αντιπροσώπευσαν τους εντυπωσιακούς
ανθρακωρύχους του Κολοράντο, γρήγορα αντίγραφα ενός τεύχους 
(εδώ) εξουσιοδότησαν τη σφαγή Ludlow από walter Fink, 
σκηνοθέτης της δημοσιότητας UMWA της περιοχής 15. 
Εκτός από την παροχή μιας δραματικής επανάληψης των 
γεγονότων που καταλήγουν στην τραγωδία, ο τίτλος του τεύχους 
έγινε ο συνήθως αποδεκτός όρος για το γεγονός.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Las luchas de trabajo a menudo violentas vigésimo
de la preocupación profunda engendrada siglo temprano en todos los 
niveles de la sociedad y conducidos a una serie de investigaciones 
gubernamentales, incluyendo la Comisión federal en las relaciones 
laborales, designadas en 1913. La comisión estaba en el medio 
de tomar testimonio de propietarios, de trabajadores, y de reformadores
en docenas de comunidades industriales alrededor del país cuando una 
huelga del carbón explotó en Colorado meridional. El la noche 
de Pascua, mataron a 1914, tres mujeres y a once niños en un 
campamento que minaba en Ludlow, los trabajadores de mina unidos 
Colorado.The de América, los millares de la unión que representó a 
mineros llamativos de Colorado, rápidamente impresa y vendida (para 
25 centavos) de copias de un folleto (extractado aquí) titulado la 
Masacre de Ludlow por Walter Fink, director de la publicidad del 
districto 15 de UMWA. Además de proporcionar a un retelling 
dramático de los acontecimientos que conducían a la tragedia, el 
título del folleto se convirtió en el término comúnmente validado 
para el acontecimiento.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087147</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102864</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/two-bits-for-a-tragic-tale-walter-finks-the-ludlow-massacre</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
