<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106160</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106160</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212913</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Understanding Algebra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Verstehende Algebra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Algèbre d'arrangement</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Álgebra Compreensiva</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Algebra Capente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κατανόηση της άλγεβρας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Álgebra Que entiende</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">A complete introductory algebra textbook, this site covers many concepts including arithmetic, word problems, graphing and lines, equations and expressions, exponents, and polynomials. Includes a graphing applet, a prime factorization machine, and a prime number list. Brennan uses inserts to answer common questions as the lesson goes on, helping the student master new ideas. A printable version is also available on the website. This resource is part of the Teaching Quantitative Skills in the Geosciences collection. http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein komplettes einleitendes Algebralehrbuch, diese
Site umfaßt viele Konzepte einschließlich Arithmetik, Wortprobleme, 
graphischee Darstellung und Zeilen, Gleichungen und Ausdrücke, 
Exponenten und Polynome. Schließt einen graphisch 
darstellenapplet, eine Hauptfaktorisierungmaschine und eine 
Hauptzahlliste ein. Brennan benutzt Einsätze, um die 
geläufigen Fragen zu beantworten, während die Lektion weitergeht und
hilft den Kursteilnehmerhauptneuen Ideen. Eine bedruckbare 
Version ist auch auf der Web site vorhanden. Dieses Hilfsmittel 
ist ein Teil der Unterricht quantitativen Fähigkeiten in der 
Geosciences Ansammlung http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un manuel préliminaire complet d'algèbre, ce 
site couvre beaucoup de concepts comprenant l'arithmétique, les 
problèmes de mot, graphique et les lignes, les équations et les 
expressions, les exposants, et les polynômes. Inclut un applet 
de graphique, une machine principale de factorisation, et une liste 
principale de nombre. Brennan emploie des insertions pour 
répondre à des questions communes pendant que la leçon continue, 
aidant idées de maître d'étudiant les nouvelles. Une version 
imprimable est également disponible sur le site Web. Cette 
ressource fait partie des qualifications quantitatives d'enseignement 
dans la collection http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de 
Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um textbook introdutório completo da álgebra, 
este local cobre muitos conceitos including a aritmética, os 
problemas da palavra, representar graficamente e as linhas, as 
equações e as expressões, os exponentes, e os polynomials. 
Inclui um applet representando graficamente, uma máquina 
principal do factorization, e uma lista principal do número. 
Brennan usa inserções responder às perguntas comuns enquanto 
a lição vai sobre, ajudando às idéias novas do mestre do 
estudante. Uma versão printable está também disponível no 
Web site. Este recurso é parte das habilidades quantitative do 
ensino na coleção http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de 
Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un manuale introduttivo completo di algebra, 
questo luogo riguarda molti concetti compresi aritmetica, problemi di 
parola, rappresentare graficamente e righe, equazioni ed espressioni, 
esponenti e polinomi. Include un applet rappresentante 
graficamente, una macchina principale di scomposizione in fattori e 
una lista principale di numero. Brennan usa gli inserti per 
rispondere alle domande comuni mentre la lezione accende, aiutanti 
idee del supervisore dell'allievo le nuove. Una versione 
stampabile è egualmente disponibile sul Web site. Questa 
risorsa fa parte delle abilità quantitative di insegnamento 
nell'accumulazione http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ di 
Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα πλήρες εισαγωγικό εγχειρίδιο άλγεβρας, αυτή η 
περιοχή καλύπτει πολλές έννοιες συμπεριλαμβανομένης της 
αριθμητικής, των προβλημάτων λέξης, να δώσει με γραφική 
παράσταση και των γραμμών, των εξισώσεων και των εκφράσεων, των 
εκθετών, και των πολυωνύμων. Περιλαμβάνει ένα να δώσει με 
γραφική παράσταση applet, μια πρωταρχική μηχανή 
παραγοντοποίησης, και έναν πρωταρχικό κατάλογο αριθμού. Το 
Brennan χρησιμοποιεί τα ένθετα για να απαντήσει στις κοινές 
ερωτήσεις καθώς το μάθημα συνεχίζεται, βοηθώντας τις κύριες 
νέες ιδέες σπουδαστών. Μια εκτυπώσιμη έκδοση είναι επίσης
διαθέσιμη στον ιστοχώρο. Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς 
είναι μέρος των ποσοτικών δεξιοτήτων διδασκαλίας στη 
Geosciences συλλογή 
http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un libro de textos introductorio completo de la 
álgebra, este sitio cubre muchos conceptos incluyendo aritmética, 
los problemas de la palabra, representación gráfica gra'ficamente y 
las líneas, las ecuaciones y las expresiones, los exponentes, y los 
polinomios. Incluye un applet de representación gráfico 
gra'ficamente, una máquina primera de la facturización, y una lista 
primera del número. Brennan utiliza los separadores de millares
para contestar a las preguntas comunes como continúa la lección, 
ayudando ideas del amo del estudiante a las nuevas. Una versión
imprimible está también disponible en el Web site. Este 
recurso es parte de las habilidades cuantitativas de la enseñanza en 
la colección http://serc.carleton.edu/quantskills/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:JAMES BRENNAN
FN:JAMES BRENNAN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212913</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106160</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/understanding-algebra</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
