<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106197</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106197</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207113</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Three Historic Nevada Cities: Carson City, Reno, Virginia City</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Drei Historische Nevada Städte: Carson 
City, Reno, Virginia Stadt</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Trois Villes Historiques du Nevada : Ville 
De Carson, Reno, Ville de la Virginie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Três Cidades Historic De Nevada: Cidade De 
Carson, Reno, Cidade De Virgínia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Tre Città Storiche Del Nevada: Città Di 
Carson, Reno, Città Della Virginia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τρεις ιστορικές πόλεις της Νεβάδας: Πόλη 
Carson, Reno, πόλη της Βιρτζίνια</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tres Ciudades Históricas De Nevada: Ciudad 
De Carson, Reno, Ciudad De Virginia</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells the stories of three cities established after the Comstock Lode discovery in 1859 brought a reverse migration from California. The stories, told by this travel itinerary of 57 places, feature the mining and agricultural city now known for gaming, the remarkable collection of 19th-century buildings created with wealth generated by the Comstock Lode, and the state capital.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt die Geschichten von drei Städte, die 
nach der Comstock Aderentdeckung in 1859 hergestellt werden, holte 
eine Rückmigration von Kalifornien. Die Geschichten, erklärt 
durch diesen Spielraumreiseweg von 57 Plätzen, von Merkmal der 
Bergbau und die landwirtschaftliche Stadt jetzt bekannt für Spiel, 
von bemerkenswerten Ansammlung der Gebäude 19th-century hergestellt 
mit der Fülle festgelegt durch die Comstock Ader und von 
Zustandkapital.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit les histoires de trois villes établies après
la découverte de filon de Comstock dans 1859 a apporté un transfert 
renversé de la Californie. Les histoires, indiquées par cet 
itinéraire de voyage de 57 endroits, de dispositif l'exploitation et 
la ville agricole maintenant connues pour le jeu, de la collection 
remarquable de bâtiments 19th-century créés avec la richesse 
produite par le filon de Comstock, et du capital d'état.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz as histórias de três cidades estabelecidas 
após a descoberta do lode de Comstock em 1859 trouxe uma migração 
reversa de Califórnia. As histórias, ditas por este itinerary 
do curso de 57 lugares, de característica a mineração e a cidade 
agricultural conhecidas agora para o gaming, da coleção notável dos
edifícios 19th-century criados com a riqueza gerada pelo lode de 
Comstock, e do capital de estado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice alle storia di tre città stabilite dopo la 
scoperta del lode di Comstock in 1859 ha portato un'espansione 
d'inversione dalla California. Le storia, dette a da questo 
itinerario di corsa di 57 posti, della caratteristica l'estrazione 
mineraria e la città agricola ora conosciute per gioco, 
dell'accumulazione notevole delle costruzioni 19th-century create con 
ricchezza generata dal lode di Comstock e del capitale di dichiarare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει τις ιστορίες τριών πόλεων που καθιερώνονται 
αφότου έφερε η ανακάλυψη κοιτασμάτων Comstock το 1859 μια 
αντίστροφη μετανάστευση από Καλιφόρνια. Οι ιστορίες, που 
λέονται από αυτήν την περιήγηση ταξιδιού 57 θέσεων, 
χαρακτηρίζουν τη μεταλλεία και τη γεωργική πόλη που είναι γνωστή
τώρα για το τυχερό παιχνίδι, την αξιοπρόσεκτη συλλογή των 
κτηρίων 19$ος-αιώνα που δημιουργούνται με τον πλούτο που 
παράγεται από το κοίτασμα Comstock, και το κρατικό κεφάλαιο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cuenta las historias de tres ciudades establecidas
después del descubrimiento de la veta de Comstock en 1859 trajo una 
migración reversa de California. Las historias, contadas por 
este itinerario del recorrido de 57 lugares, de la característica la 
explotación minera y la ciudad agrícola ahora conocidas para el 
juego, de la colección notable de los edificios 19th-century creados 
con la abundancia generada por la veta de Comstock, y de la Capital 
del Estado.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207113</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106197</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/three-historic-nevada-cities-carson-city-reno-virginia-city</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
