<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103852</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103852</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209812</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Area enclosed by a circle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bereich umgeben durch einen Kreis</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Zone entourée par un cercle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Área incluída por um círculo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Zona chiusa da un cerchio</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Περιοχή που εσωκλείεται από έναν κύκλο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Área incluida por un círculo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the area of a circle. A circle is shown with a point on the circumference that can be dragged to resize the circle. As the circle is resized, the radius and the area computation is shown changing in real time. The radius and formula can be hidden for class discussion. Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die den Bereich eines Kreises zeigen. Ein Kreis wird 
mit einem Punkt auf dem Umkreis gezeigt, der geschleppt werden kann, 
um den Kreis die Größe neu zu bestimmen. Während der Kreis 
die Größe neu bestimmt wird, wird der Radius und das Bereich 
Übertragen auf Lochkarten das Ändern in der Istzeit gezeigt. 
Der Radius und die Formel können für Kategorie Diskussion 
versteckt werden. Applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für 
Gebrauch mit einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. 
Nachgebrauch im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von 
jedem möglichem web browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den 
benötigten LOGON wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein 
Bestandteil des Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven 
Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent la zone d'un cercle. Un cercle est montré avec 
un point sur la circonférence qui peut être traînée pour remettre 
à la côte le cercle. Pendant que le cercle est remis à la 
côte, le rayon et le calcul de zone est montré changer en temps 
réel. Le rayon et la formule peuvent être cachés pour la 
discussion de classe. L'applet peut être agrandi à la taille 
de plein écran pour l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. 
Le après utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut 
lui accéder encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison 
ou dans la bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. 
Cette ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel 
de la géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem a área de um círculo. Um círculo é mostrado com 
um ponto na circunferência que pode ser arrastada para resize o 
círculo. Enquanto o círculo resized, o raio e a computação 
da área estão mostrados a mudança no tempo real. O raio e a 
fórmula podem ser escondidos para a discussão da classe. O 
applet pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de tela cheia para o uso com um 
projetor da sala de aula. O depois de uso na sala de aula, 
estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo o web browser na HOME ou
na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma sessão requerido. Este 
recurso é um componente do projeto interativo do textbook da 
geometria da referência aberta do math em http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano la zona di un cerchio. Un cerchio è indicato con un 
punto sulla circonferenza che può essere trascinata per 
ridimensionare il cerchio. Mentre il cerchio è ridimensionato, 
il raggio ed il calcolo di zona è indicato cambiare in tempo reale. 
Il raggio e la formula possono essere nascosti per la 
discussione del codice categoria. Il applet può essere 
ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore 
dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può 
accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria 
senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un 
componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τον τομέα ενός κύκλου. Ένας κύκλος 
εμφανίζεται με ένα σημείο στην περιφέρεια που μπορεί να σέρθεί 
για να επαναταξινομήσει τον κύκλο. Δεδομένου ότι ο κύκλος 
επαναταξινομείται, η ακτίνα και ο υπολογισμός περιοχής 
εμφανίζονται μεταβαλλόμενος στον πραγματικό χρόνο. Η ακτίνα
και ο τύπος μπορούν να κρυφτούν για τη συζήτηση κλάσης. Το 
Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη 
χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων. Μετά από τη χρήση στην 
τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από 
οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς 
την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. Αυτό το στοιχείο 
συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του ανοικτού προγράμματος 
εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math διαλογικού σε 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran el área de un círculo. Un círculo se muestra con 
una punta en la circunferencia que se puede arrastrar para volver a 
clasificar según el tamaño el círculo. Mientras que se vuelve
a clasificar según el tamaño el círculo, el radio y el cómputo del
área se muestra cambiar en tiempo real. El radio y el fórmula 
se pueden ocultar para la discusión de la clase. El applet se 
puede agrandar a la talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un 
proyector de la sala de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de 
clase, estudiante puede tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web 
browser en el país o en la biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. 
Este recurso es un componente del proyecto interactivo del libro
de textos de la geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas
en http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209812</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103852</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/area-enclosed-by-a-circle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
