<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103766</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103766</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086124</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Equal and Exact Justice to Both Races": Booker T. Washington on the Reaction to his Atlanta Compromise Speech</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"gleiche und genaue Gerechtigkeit zu beiden 
Rennen": Booker T. Washington auf der Reaktion auf seine Atlanta
Kompromiss-Rede</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"justice égale et exacte aux deux courses" : 
Booker T. Washington sur la réaction à son discours de 
compromis d'Atlanta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"justiça igual e exata a ambas as raças": 
Booker T. Washington na reação a seu discurso do acordo de 
Atlanta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"giustizia uguale ed esatta ad entrambe le corse":
Booker T. Washington sulla reazione al suo discorso di 
compromesso de Atlanta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Ίση και ακριβής δικαιοσύνη και στις δύο φυλέσ": 
Booker Τ. Ουάσιγκτον στην αντίδραση στην ομιλία 
συμβιβασμού της Ατλάντας του</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"justicia igual y exacta a ambas razas": 
Booker T. Washington en la reacción a su discurso del 
compromiso de Atlanta</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The Atlanta Compromise speech, which Booker T. Washington delivered before the Cotton States and International Exposition in 1895, established Washington as the leading black spokesman in America. He came to control enormous amounts of northern white philanthropy directed at African Americans as well as much of the federal patronage dispensed to them by the Republican party. In this excerpt from his autobiography  Up From Slavery , Washington described the reactions of both black and white Americans to his speech.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Atlanta Kompromißrede, die Booker T. 
Washington vor den Baumwollzuständen und der internationalen 
Ausstellung 1895 lieferte, stellte Washington als der führende 
schwarze Wortführer in Amerika her. Er kam, enorme Mengen der 
weißen Nordphilanthropie zu steuern, die an den afrikanischen 
Amerikanern sowie viel des Bundespatronats zugeführt auf sie von der 
republikanischen Partei verwiesen wurde. In diesem 
Excerpt von seiner Autobiographie oben von der Sklaverei, beschrieb 
Washington die Reaktionen Schwarzes und Weiß der Amerikaner zu seiner
Rede.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le discours de compromis d'Atlanta, que Booker T. 
Washington a fourni avant les états de coton et l'exposition 
internationale en 1895, a établi Washington en tant que principal 
porte-parole noir en Amérique. Il est venu pour contrôler 
d'énormes quantités de philanthropie blanche nordique dirigée aux 
Américains africains aussi bien qu'une grande partie du patronage 
fédéral distribués vers eux par la partie républicaine. Dans
cet extrait de son autobiographie vers le haut d'esclavage, Washington
a décrit les réactions des Américains de noir et de blanc à son 
discours.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O discurso do acordo de Atlanta, que Booker T. 
Washington entregou antes dos estados do algodão e da exposição 
internacional em 1895, estabeleceu Washington como o spokesman preto 
principal em América. Veio controlar quantidades enormes de 
philanthropy branco do norte dirigido nos americanos africanos 
as.well.as muito do patronage federal dispensados a eles pelo partido 
republicano. Neste excerpt de seu autobiography acima do 
slavery, Washington descreveu as reações  de americanos do preto e 
do branco a seu discurso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il discorso di compromesso de Atlanta, che Booker 
il T. Washington trasportata prima che il cotone Dichiari ed 
esposizione internazionale in 1895, ha stabilito Washington come il 
portavoce nero principale in America. È venuto gestire gli 
importi enormi della filantropia bianca nordica diretta agli Americani
africani così come gran parte del patronato federale erogati verso 
loro dal partito Repubblicano. In questo brano dal suo 
autobiography in su da slavery, Washington ha descritto le reazioni 
sia degli Americani di bianco che di nero al suo discorso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ομιλία συμβιβασμού της Ατλάντας, που Booker Τ. 
Ουάσιγκτον παρέδωσε πριν από τα κράτη βαμβακιού και τη διεθνή 
έκθεση το 1895, καθιέρωσε την Ουάσιγκτον ως κύριο μαύρο 
εκπρόσωπο στην Αμερική. Ήρθε να ελέγξει τα τεράστια ποσά 
βόρειας άσπρης φιλανθρωπίας που κατευθύνθηκε σε αφρικανικούς 
Αμερικανούς καθώς επίσης και ένα μεγάλο μέρος της ομοσπονδιακής
προστασίας που διένεμε σε τους από το δημοκρατικό κόμμα. Σε
αυτό το απόσπασμα από την αυτοβιογραφία του επάνω από τη 
σκλαβιά, η Ουάσιγκτον περιέγραψε τις αντιδράσεις και μαύρων και 
λευκών Αμερικανών στην ομιλία του.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El discurso del compromiso de Atlanta, que Booker 
T. Washington entregó antes de los estados del algodón y de la 
exposición internacional en 1895, estableció Washington como el 
portavoz negro principal en América. Él vino controlar 
cantidades enormes de filantropía blanca norteña dirigida en los 
americanos africanos así como mucho del patrocinio federal 
dispensados a ellos por el partido republicano. En este extracto
de su autobiografía para arriba de la esclavitud, Washington 
describió las reacciones de los americanos del negro y del blanco a 
su discurso.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086124</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103766</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/equal-and-exact-justice-to-both-races-booker-t-washington-on-the-reaction-to-his-atlanta-compromise-speech</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
