<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108196</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108196</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086786</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Right After That They Walked Out": Alice Wolfson Recalls the Origins of the CIO</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Recht Nachher, Dem Sie Aus" Gingen: Alice 
Wolfson erinnert an die Ursprung des CIO</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Droit Ensuite Hors Dont Ils Ont marché" : 
Alice Wolfson rappelle les origines du CIO</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Direito Em seguida De Que Andaram Para fora": 
Alice Wolfson recorda as origens do CIO</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Di destra Dopo Che Hanno camminato Verso 
l'esterno": Alice Wolfson ricorda le origini del CIO</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Σωστός μετά από αυτόν περπάτησαν έξω": 
Θ*Αληθε Wolfson Recalls η προέλευση του CIO</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Derecho Después Fuera De Que Recorrieron": 
Alicia Wolfson recuerda los orígenes del CIO</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">John L. Lewis' dramatic walkout from the October 1935 American Federation of Labor (AFL) convention and the creation of the Committee for Industrial Organization (later the Congress of Industrial Organizations) that soon followed marked a new stage in labor's drive to organize industrial unions in depression-era America. Here Alice Dodge Wolfson, who was working as a stenographer in 1935, recalled her own contribution to the Lewis walkout and the creation of the CIO. Attending the October 1935 AFL convention in Atlantic City as a delegate from her stenographers local of the United Office and Professional Workers Union (a left-wing New York union aligned with the supporters of industrial unionism around Lewis), Wolfson played a small but decisive role in helping launch the CIO when she rose to challenge an AFL official from the convention floor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">John L. Lewis' drastische Arbeitsniederlegung von der 
Oktober 1935 Amerikaner-Vereinigung der Arbeits Vereinbarung (AFL) und
von der Kreation des Ausschusses für Industrieverband (später der 
Kongreß von den Industrieverbänden) das bald folgte, kennzeichnete 
ein neues Stadium im Laufwerk der Arbeit, um Industriegewerkschaften 
in der Tiefstand-Ära Amerika zu organisieren. Hier erinnerte an
Alice rasches Ausweichen Wolfson, das als Stenograph 1935 arbeitete, 
ihren eigenen Beitrag zur Lewis Arbeitsniederlegung und die Kreation des 
CIO. Die Oktober 1935 AFL Versammlung in Atlantic City als 
Delegiertes von ihrem Stenographeinheimischen des vereinigten 
Büro-und Fachmann-Arbeiter-Anschlußes (ein left-wing New York 
Anschluß ausgerichtet mit den Verfechtern des industriellen unionism 
um Lewis) bedienend, spielte Wolfson eine kleine aber entscheidende 
Rolle in helfender Produkteinführung das CIO, als sie stieg, um einen
AFL Beamten vom Versammlungfußboden herauszufordern.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La grève surprise excessive de John L. Lewis'de la
fédération d'Américain d'octobre 1935 de la convention (AFL) de 
travail et de la création du Comité pour l'organisation industrielle
(plus tard le congrès des organismes industriels) qui a bientôt 
suivi a marqué une nouvelle étape dans le lecteur du travail pour 
organiser les syndicats ouvriers dans la dépression-ère Amérique. 
Ici le détour Wolfson de Alice, qui fonctionnait en tant que 
sténographe en 1935, a rappelé sa propre contribution à la grève 
surprise de Lewis et à la création du CIO. Servant la 
convention d'octobre 1935 AFL à Atlantic City en tant que délégué 
de ses gens du pays de sténographes du syndicat uni de bureau et de 
professionnel (une union de gauche de New York alignée avec les 
défenseurs du syndicalisme industriel autour de Lewis), Wolfson a joué
un petit mais décisif rôle dans le lancement aidant le CIO quand 
elle s'est levée pour défier un fonctionnaire d'AFL du plancher de 
convention.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O walkout dramático de John L. Lewis' do 
federation do americano de outubro 1935 da convenção (AFL) labor e 
da criação do comitê para a organização industrial (mais tarde 
congress de organizações industriais) que seguiu logo marcou um 
estágio novo na movimentação do trabalho para organizar uniões 
industriais na depression-era América. Aqui o rodeio Wolfson de
Alice, que estava trabalhando como um stenographer em 1935, recordou 
sua própria contribuição ao walkout de Lewis e à criação do CIO.
Atendendo à convenção de outubro 1935 AFL na cidade atlantic 
como um delegado de seu local dos stenographers da união de 
trabalhadores unida do escritório e do profissional (uma união 
left-wing de New York alinhada com os supporters do unionism 
industrial em torno de Lewis), Wolfson jogou um papel pequeno mas 
decisive no lançamento de ajuda o CIO quando se levantou para 
desafiar um oficial de AFL do assoalho da convenção.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il walkout drammatico del John L. Lewis dalla 
federazione dell'americano di ottobre 1935 della convenzione 
Di lavoro (AFL) e dalla creazione del comitato per l'organizzazione 
industriale (più successivamente il congresso delle organizzazioni 
industriali) che presto è seguito ha contrassegnato una nuova fase 
nell'azionamento di lavoro per organizzare i sindacati industriali 
nell'depressione-era America. Qui l'espediente Wolfson della 
Alice, che stava lavorando come stenografo in 1935, ha ricordato il 
suo proprio contributo al walkout di Lewis ed alla creazione del CIO. 
Assistendo alla convenzione ottobre 1935 di AFL a Atlantic City 
come delegato dal suo local degli stenografi dell'unione di operai 
unita del professionista e dell'ufficio (un'unione left-wing de New 
York stata allineata rispetto ai sostenitori del unionism industriale 
intorno a Lewis), Wolfson ha svolto un piccolo ma ruolo decisivo nel 
lancio d'assistenza il CIO quando è aumentato per sfidare un 
funzionario di AFL dal pavimento di convenzione.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Δραματική απεργία John L. Lewis' από την 
αμερικανική ομοσπονδία Οκτωβρίου 1935 της σύμβασης εργασίας 
(AFL) και τη δημιουργία της Επιτροπής για τη βιομηχανική 
οργάνωση (αργότερα το συνέδριο των βιομηχανικών οργανώσεων) που 
ακολούθησε σύντομα χαρακτήρισε ένα νέο στάδιο στην κίνηση της 
εργασίας για να οργανώσει τις βιομηχανικές ενώσεις στην 
κατάθλιψη-εποχή Αμερική. Εδώ η Alice Dodge Wolfson,
που εργαζόταν ως στενογράφος το 1935, υπενθύμισε τη συμβολή της
στην απεργία Lewis και τη δημιουργία του CIO. Στη 
σύμβαση AFL Οκτωβρίου 1935 στην Ατλάντικ Σίτυ ως εκπρόσωπο 
από τους στενογράφους της τοπικούς του ενωμένου γραφείου και της 
επαγγελματικής ένωσης εργαζομένων (μια αριστερή ένωση της Νέας 
Υόρκης που ευθυγραμμίζεται με τους υποστηρικτές του βιομηχανικού 
συνδικαλισμού γύρω από Lewis), Wolfson διαδραμάτισε έναν 
μικρό αλλά αποφασιστικό ρόλο στη βοήθεια να προωθηθεί το CIO 
όταν αυξήθηκε για να προκαλέσει έναν ανώτερο υπάλληλο AFL 
από το πάτωμα συμβάσεων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La huelga dramática de Juan L. Lewis de la 
federación del americano de octubre 1935 de la convención de trabajo
(AFL) y de la creación del comité para la organización industrial 
(más adelante el congreso de organizaciones industriales) que pronto 
siguió marcó una nueva etapa en el mecanismo impulsor del trabajo 
para ordenar uniones industriales en la depresio'n-era América. 
Aquí el regate Wolfson de Alicia, que trabajaba como 
taquígrafo en 1935, recordó su propia contribución a la huelga de 
Lewis y a la creación del CIO. Atendiendo a la convención de 
octubre 1935 AFL en Atlantic City como delegado de su local de los 
taquígrafos de la unión de trabajadores unida de la oficina y del 
profesional (una unión izquierdista de Nueva York alineada con los 
partidarios del unionism industrial alrededor de Lewis), Wolfson 
desempeñó un papel pequeño pero decisivo en lanzamiento que ayudaba
el CIO cuando ella se levantó para desafiar a un funcionario de AFL 
del suelo de la convención.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086786</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108196</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/right-after-that-they-walked-out-alice-wolfson-recalls-the-origins-of-the-cio</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
