<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107377</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107377</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086912</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The business of America is accommodation.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Geschäft von Amerika ist Anpassung.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les affaires de l'Amérique sont logement.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O negócio de América é acomodação.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il commercio dell'America è sistemazione.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η επιχείρηση της Αμερικής είναι στέγαση.</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El negocio de América es comodidad.</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">In this photograph, battle flags captured by northern troops during the Civil War are returned to aged Confederate veterans in a 1927 ceremony in front of the Capitol supervised by President Calvin Coolidge. Such rites of reconciliation between the Blue and the Gray represented a rapprochement between whites and ignored the central importance of slavery to the war, as well as the contribution of black troops. More damaging, this attitude of reconciliation obscured the repressive state of race relations in the South during the 1920s.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">In dieser Fotographie werden die 
Schlachtmarkierungsfahnen, die von den Nordtruppen während des 
Bürgerkrieges erfaßt werden, zu gealterten verbündeten Veteranen in
einer Zeremonie 1927 vor dem Kapitol zurückgebracht, das vom 
Präsidenten Calvin Coolidge überwacht wird. Solche rites der 
Versöhnung zwischen dem Blauen und dem Grau stellten eine 
Annäherung zwischen Weiß dar und ignorierten den zentralen Wert 
der Sklaverei zum Krieg, sowie den Beitrag der schwarzen Truppen. 
Zerstörender, machte diese Haltung der Versöhnung den 
repressiven Zustand der Rennenrelationen im Süden während der 
zwanziger Jahre undeutlich.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">En cette photographie, des indicateurs de bataille 
capturés par les troupes nordiques pendant la guerre civile sont 
retournés aux vétérans confédérés âgés dans une cérémonie 
1927 devant le capitol dirigé par le Président Calvin Coolidge. 
De tels rites de la réconciliation entre le bleu et le 
gris ont représenté un rapprochement entre les blancs et ont ignoré 
l'importance centrale de l'esclavage à la guerre, aussi bien que la 
contribution des troupes noires. Plus préjudiciable, cette 
attitude de la réconciliation a obscurci l'état répressif de 
relations inter-raciales dans les Sud pendant les années 20.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Nesta fotografia, as bandeiras de batalha capturadas por 
tropas do norte durante a guerra civil são retornadas aos veterans 
confederate envelhecidos em um ceremony 1927 na frente do capitol 
supervisionado pelo presidente Calvin Coolidge. Tais rites do 
reconciliation entre o azul e o cinza representaram um rapprochement 
entre brancos e ignoraram a importância central do slavery à guerra,
as.well.as a contribuição de tropas pretas. Mais prejudicial, 
esta atitude do reconciliation obscureceu o estado repressive de 
relações de raça no sul durante os 1920s.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">In questa fotografia, le bandierine di battaglia bloccate 
dalle truppe nordiche durante la guerra civile sono restituite ai 
veterani confederati invecchiati in una cerimonia 1927 davanti il 
capitol sorvegliato dal presidente Calvin Coolidge. Tali rites 
della riconciliazione fra il blu ed il gray hanno rappresentato un 
rapprochement fra i bianchi ed hanno ignorato l'importanza centrale di
slavery alla guerra, così come il contributo delle truppe nere. 
Più offensivo, questo atteggiamento della riconciliazione ha 
oscurato il repressivo dichiara dei rapporti di corsa nel sud 
durante gli anni 20.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Σε αυτήν την φωτογραφία, οι σημαίες μάχης που 
συλλαμβάνονται από τα βόρεια στρατεύματα κατά τη διάρκεια του 
εμφύλιου πολέμου επιστρέφονται στους ηλικίας ομόσπονδους 
παλαιμάχους σε μια τελετή του 1927 μπροστά από το Capitol 
που εποπτεύεται από τον Πρόεδρο Calvin Coolidge. 
Τέτοιες ιεροτελεστίες της συμφιλίωσης μεταξύ μπλε και του 
γκρίζου αντιπροσώπευσαν μια συνδιαλλαγή μεταξύ των λευκών και 
αγνόησαν την κεντρική σημασία της σκλαβιάς στον πόλεμο, καθώς 
επίσης και τη συμβολή των μαύρων στρατευμάτων. Πιό 
καταστρεπτική, αυτή η τοποθέτηση της συμφιλίωσης έκρυψε την 
κατασταλτική κατάσταση των φυλετικών σχέσεων στο νότο κατά τη 
διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '20.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En esta fotografía, los indicadores de batalla capturados
por las tropas norteñas durante la guerra civil se vuelven a los 
veteranos confederados envejecidos en una ceremonia 1927 delante del 
capitol supervisado por presidente Calvin Coolidge. Tales rites 
de la reconciliación entre el azul y el gris representaron un 
acercamiento entre los blancos y no hicieron caso de la importancia 
central de la esclavitud a la guerra, así como la contribución de 
tropas negras. Más perjudicial, esta actitud de la 
reconciliación obscureció el estado represivo de las relaciones de 
raza en el sur durante los años 20.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086912</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107377</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/the-business-of-america-is-accommodation</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
