<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102958</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102958</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202702</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Selecting Evidence to Support an Argument</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Auswählen des Beweises, um ein Argument zu 
unterstützen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Choix de l'évidence pour supporter un argument</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Selecionando a evidência para suportar um 
argumento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Selezione della prova per sostenere un argomento</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιλογή των στοιχείων για να υποστηριχθεί ένα όρισμα</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Seleccionar evidencia para utilizar un argumento</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is a strategy lesson to teach students how to select evidence from a text to support an argument for an essay. It was designed to take two class periods and is comprised of three mini-lessons; these lessons include teacher modeling strategy to large group, student practice with strategy in small groups, and student practice with strategy individually on what will ultimately be the essay that they write.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist eine Strategie Lektion, zum 
Kursteilnehmern beizubringen, wie man Beweis von einem Text auswählt,
um ein Argument für einen Versuch zu unterstützen. Es war 
konzipiert, um zwei Kategorie Perioden zu dauern und wird von drei 
Mini-Lektionen enthalten; diese Lektionen enthalten den Lehrer, 
der einzeln Strategie zur großen Gruppe, Kursteilnehmerpraxis mit 
Strategie in den kleinen Gruppen und Kursteilnehmerpraxis mit 
Strategie formt auf, was schließlich der Versuch ist, den sie 
schreiben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est une leçon de stratégie pour enseigner à 
des étudiants comment choisir l'évidence à partir d'un texte pour 
supporter un argument pour un essai. Elle a été conçue pour 
prendre deux périodes de classe et est composée de trois 
mini-leçons ; ces leçons incluent le professeur modelant la 
stratégie au grand groupe, la pratique en matière d'étudiant avec 
la stratégie dans de petits groupes, et la pratique en matière 
d'étudiant avec la stratégie individuellement sur ce qui sera 
finalement l'essai qu'elles écrivent.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Esta é uma lição da estratégia para ensinar a 
estudantes como selecionar a evidência de um texto para suportar um 
argumento para um essay. Foi projetada fazer exame de dois 
períodos da classe e é compreendida de três mini-lições; 
estas lições incluem o professor que modela a estratégia ao 
grupo grande, a prática do estudante com estratégia em grupos 
pequenos, e a prática do estudante com estratégia individualmente em
o que será finalmente o essay que escreve.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è una lezione di strategia per insegnare ad 
allievi come selezionare la prova a partire da un testo per sostenere 
un argomento per un saggio. È stata destinata per occorrere due
periodi del codice categoria ed è contenuta tre mini-lezioni; 
queste lezioni includono l'insegnante che modella 
individualmente la strategia al grande gruppo, la pratica dell'allievo
con strategia nei piccoli gruppi e la pratica dell'allievo con 
strategia su che cosa infine sarà il saggio che scrivono.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι ένα μάθημα στρατηγικής για να διδάξει 
τους σπουδαστές πώς να επιλέξει τα στοιχεία από ένα κείμενο για
να υποστηριχθεί ένα όρισμα για ένα δοκίμιο. Είχε ως σκοπό
να πάρει δύο περιόδους κλάσης και αποτελείται από τρία 
μίνι-μαθήματα  αυτά τα μαθήματα περιλαμβάνουν τη 
στρατηγική διαμόρφωσης δασκάλων στη μεγάλη ομάδα, την πρακτική 
σπουδαστών με τη στρατηγική στις μικρές ομάδες, και την πρακτική 
σπουδαστών με τη στρατηγική χωριστά σε αυτό που θα είναι τελικά 
το δοκίμιο που γράφουν.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esto es una lección de la estrategia para 
enseñar a estudiantes cómo seleccionar evidencia de un texto para 
utilizar un argumento para un ensayo. Fue diseñada para tomar 
dos períodos de la clase y se abarca de tres mini-lecciones; 
estas lecciones incluyen a profesor que modela estrategia al 
grupo grande, práctica del estudiante con estrategia en grupos 
pequeños, y práctica del estudiante con estrategia individualmente 
en cuál será en última instancia el ensayo que él escribe.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CAROLINE SAIN
FN:CAROLINE SAIN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770202702</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102958</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/selecting-evidence-to-support-an-argument</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
