<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/107587</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>107587</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201820</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Thematic Poetry Videos </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Thematische Poesie Videos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Poésie Thématique Videos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Poesia Thematic Videos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Poesia Tematica Videos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Θεματικά βίντεο ποίησης</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Poesía Temática Videos</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Overview: Youth literacy can be promoted by leveraging youth culture, such as rap/music videos. By merging sound and visual imagery with text, a poetry writing task can be transformed into a multi-media video assignment. English teachers with access to a computer lab equipped with video editing software (e.g. i-Movie) can carry this out with their classes. Alternatively, English and computer lab teachers can collaborate to have their students produce thematic poetry videos as the culminating activity of an English poetry unit. It assumes that students have been taught the basic forms of poetry. Furthermore, by having students discuss the process of producing their poetry videos with peers in face-to-face or on-line workgroups, they develop the literate and social skills necessary for functioning effectively in the project-based team culture of today's workplace. Students will use the resources of takingitglobal.org to become informed about a theme of their choice. They will then compose a poem that expresses their thoughts and feelings about that topic. This poem will then form the basis for a video.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Überblick: Jugendbildungsgrad kann 
gefördert werden, indem man Jugendkultur, wie rap/music videos 
wirksam einsetzt. Indem man die stichhaltigen und Sichtbilder 
mit Text mergt, kann eine Poesieschreiben Aufgabe in eine multi-media 
videoanweisung umgewandelt werden. Die englischen Lehrer mit 
Zugriff zu einem Computerlabor, das mit Bildschirm Software 
(ausgerüstet wird z.B. IchFilm) bearbeitend können dieses mit ihren 
Kategorien heraus tragen. Wechselweise können Englisch und 
Computerlaborlehrer zusammenarbeiten, um ihre thematischen videos 
Poesie des Kursteilnehmererzeugnisses als die kulminierende Aktivität
einer englischen Poesiemaßeinheit zu haben. Sie nimmt an, daß 
Kursteilnehmern die grundlegenden Formulare von Poesie unterrichtet 
worden sind. Ausserdem indem Sie Kursteilnehmer behandeln Sie 
den Prozeß des Produzierens ihrer Poesie videos mit Gleichen in 
vertraulichem haben, oder Onlineworkgroups, entwickeln sie die 
gebildeten und Sozialfähigkeiten, die für effektiv arbeiten in der 
Projekt-gegründeten Teamkultur des heutigen Arbeitsplatzes notwendig 
sind. Kursteilnehmer benutzen die Betriebsmittel von 
takingitglobal.org, um über ein Thema ihrer Wahl informiert zu 
werden. Sie bestehen dann ein Gedicht, das ihre Gedanken und 
Gefühle über dieses Thema ausdrückt. Dieses Gedicht bildet 
dann die Grundlage für einen Bildschirm.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Vue d'ensemble : L'instruction de la 
jeunesse peut être favorisée en accroissant la culture de la 
jeunesse, telle que des videos de rap/music. En fusionnant le 
langage figuré sain et visuel avec le texte, une écriture de poésie
chargent peut être transformée en affectation visuelle 
multimédia. Les professeurs anglais avec l'accès à un 
laboratoire d'ordinateur équipé du vidéo éditant le logiciel (par 
exemple je-Film) peuvent porter ceci dehors avec leurs classes. 
Alternativement, l'anglais et les professeurs de laboratoire 
d'ordinateur peuvent collaborer pour avoir leurs videos thématiques 
de poésie de produit d'étudiants comme activité culminante d'une 
unité anglaise de poésie. Elle suppose qu'on a enseigné des 
étudiants les formes de base de la poésie. En outre, en ayant 
des étudiants discutez le processus de produire leurs videos de 
poésie avec des pairs dans tête à tête ou des équipes de travail 
en ligne, ils développent les qualifications instruites et sociales 
nécessaires pour fonctionner pertinemment dans la culture 
projet-basée d'équipe du lieu de travail d'aujourd'hui. Les 
étudiants emploieront les ressources de takingitglobal.org pour 
devenir au courant au sujet d'un thème de leur choix. Ils 
composeront alors une poésie qui exprime leurs pensées et sentiments
au sujet de ce sujet. Cette poésie formera alors la base pour 
un vidéo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Vista geral: O literacy da juventude pode 
ser promovido leveraging a cultura da juventude, tal como videos de 
rap/music. Fundindo o imagery sadio e visual com o texto, uma 
tarefa da escrita da poesia pode ser transformada em uma atribuição 
video multi-media. Os professores ingleses com acesso a um 
laboratório do computador equipado com o vídeo que editam o software
(por exemplo eu-Filme) podem carregar este para fora com suas classes.
Alternativamente, o inglês e os professores do laboratório do 
computador podem collaborate para ter seus videos thematic da poesia 
do produto dos estudantes como a atividade culminando de uma unidade 
inglesa da poesia. Supõe que os estudantes estiveram ensinados 
os formulários básicos da poesia. Além disso, tendo 
estudantes discuta o processo de produzir seus videos da poesia com os
pares em face-to-face ou workgroups em linha, desenvolvem as 
habilidades literate e sociais necessárias para funcionar eficazmente
na cultura projeto-baseada da equipe do workplace de hoje. Os 
estudantes usarão os recursos de takingitglobal.org tornar-se 
informed sobre um tema de sua escolha. Comporã0 então um poema
que expresse seus pensamentos e sentimentos sobre esse tópico. 
Este poema dará forma então à base para um vídeo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Descrizione: Il literacy della gioventù 
può essere promosso leveraging la coltura della gioventù, quali i 
videos di rap/music. Fondendo il linguaggio figurato sano e 
visivo con il testo, un'operazione di scrittura di poesia può essere 
trasformata in una video assegnazione multimedia. Gli insegnanti
inglesi con accesso ad un laboratorio del calcolatore fornito del 
video che stampano il software (per esempio i-film) possono 
trasportare questo fuori con i loro codici categoria. 
Alternativamente, l'inglese e gli insegnanti del laboratorio del
calcolatore possono collaborare per avere loro videos tematici di 
poesia dei prodotti degli allievi come l'attività di culminazione di 
un'unità inglese di poesia. Suppone che gli allievi sono stati 
insegnati le forme di base della poesia. Ancora, avendo allievi 
discuta il processo di produrre i loro videos di poesia con i pari in 
faccia a faccia o workgroups in linea, sviluppano le abilità literate
e sociali necessarie per il funzionamento efficacemente nella coltura 
progetto-basata della squadra di odierno posto di lavoro. Gli 
allievi useranno le risorse di takingitglobal.org per essere informed 
circa un tema della loro scelta. Allora comporranno un poem che 
esprime i loro pensieri e sensibilità circa quel soggetto. 
Questo poem allora costituirà la base per un video.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επισκόπηση: Η βασική εκπαίδευση νεολαίας μπορεί
να προωθηθεί με ο πολιτισμός νεολαίας, όπως τα βίντεο 
κτυπήματος/μουσικής. Με τη συγχώνευση των υγιών και οπτικών
καλολογικών στοιχείων με το κείμενο, μια στοιχειώδης εργασία 
γραψίματος ποίησης μπορεί να μετασχηματιστεί σε μια τηλεοπτική 
ανάθεση πολυμέσων. Οι αγγλικοί δάσκαλοι με την πρόσβαση σε 
ένα εργαστήριο υπολογιστών που εξοπλίζεται με το τηλεοπτικό να 
επιμεληθούν λογισμικό (π.χ. ι-κινηματογράφος) μπορούν να φέρουν 
αυτό έξω με τις κλάσεις τους. Εναλλακτικά, τα αγγλικά και 
οι δάσκαλοι εργαστηρίων υπολογιστών μπορούν να συνεργαστούν να 
έχουν τους σπουδαστές τους να παραγάγουν τα θεματικά βίντεο 
ποίησης ως καταλήγοντας δραστηριότητα μιας αγγλικής μονάδας 
ποίησης. Υποθέτει ότι οι σπουδαστές έχουν διδαχθεί τις 
βασικές μορφές της ποίησης. Επιπλέον, από την κατοχή των 
σπουδαστών συζητήστε τη διαδικασία τα βίντεο ποίησής τους με 
τους συνομήληκους μέσα πρόσωπο με πρόσωπο ή σε απευθείας 
σύνδεση ομάδες εργασίας, αναπτύσσουν τις εγγράμματες και 
κοινωνικές δεξιότητες απαραίτητες για να λειτουργήσουν 
αποτελεσματικά στον πρόγραμμα-βασισμένο στον πολιτισμό ομάδων του
σημερινού εργασιακού χώρου. Οι σπουδαστές θα 
χρησιμοποιήσουν τα στοιχεία συμπεριφοράς takingitglobal.org για 
να γίνουν ενημερωμένοι για ένα θέμα της επιλογής τους. Θα 
συνθέσουν έπειτα ένα ποίημα που εκφράζει τις σκέψεις και τα 
συναισθήματά τους για εκείνο το θέμα. Αυτό το ποίημα θα 
αποτελέσει έπειτα τη βάση για ένα βίντεο.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Descripción: La instrucción de la juventud
puede ser promovida leveraging la cultura de la juventud, tal como 
videos de rap/music. Combinando imágenes sanas y visuales con 
el texto, una tarea de la escritura de la poesía se puede transformar
en una asignación video multi-media. Los profesores ingleses 
con el acceso a un laboratorio del ordenador equipado de vídeo que 
corrigen el software (e.g. yo-Peli'cula) pueden llevar esto hacia 
fuera con sus clases. Alternativomente, el inglés y los 
profesores del laboratorio del ordenador pueden colaborar para tener 
sus videos temáticos de la poesía del producto de los estudiantes 
como la actividad que culmina de una unidad inglesa de la poesía. 
Asume que han enseñado los estudiantes las formas básicas de 
poesía. Además, teniendo estudiantes discuta el proceso de 
producir sus videos de la poesía con los pares en cara a cara o los 
workgroups en línea, desarrollan las habilidades que sabe leer y 
escribir y sociales necesarias para funcionar con eficacia en la 
cultura proyecto-basada del equipo del lugar de trabajo de hoy. 
Los estudiantes utilizarán los recursos de takingitglobal.org 
para hacer informados sobre un tema de su opción. Entonces 
compondrán un poema que exprese sus pensamientos y sensaciones sobre 
ese asunto. Este poema entonces formará la base para un vídeo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201820</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-No Derivative Works 2.5</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>107587</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/thematic-poetry-videos</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
