<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103922</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103922</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085243</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Growing Ethnic Diversity</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wachsende Ethnische Verschiedenartigkeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Diversité Ethnique Croissante</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Diversidade Étnica Crescente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Diversità Etnica Crescente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυξανόμενη εθνική ποικιλομορφία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Diversidad Étnica Cada vez mayor</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">People from around the world continued to come to California in the early 1900s, many in search of work and a better life. Two photographs depict men in turbans in San Francisco in 1910. Southern California attracted numerous Japanese immigrants. Photographs in this group show Japanese workers standing in front of delivery trucks at the Nakamura Company and inside Japanese owned businesses such as the Kusumoto Barbershop in Anaheim. Mexicans and Filipinos also came to California during this period. As new farming technologies enabled the consolidation of smaller parcels of land into large farms up and down the state, the need for workers increased. In response, many Filipinos came to work in the fields and in related agricultural jobs. "Snapshot of Workers' Camp" shows some of these men. Mexican and Japanese immigrants also found agricultural work in California. Photographs in this group show Japanese workers in a field; and another image shows a young Mexican agricultural worker. The photograph of workers in the Tokay grape packing shed in Florin shows a diversity of workers, including an African American woman and Japanese and Filipino men. This mix of very different cultures gave rise to tensions and conflicts. Migrant workers were threatened and warned not to take jobs away from other groups. Images include two letters threatening a farmer with reprisals if he hires Filipinos; and a US Immigration sign in Spanish threatening non-citizens with deportation if they go on strike. Although the Chinese Exclusion Act of 1882 prevented new immigrants from coming to the United States, the Chinese who were already here continued to assimilate into Western culture. A photograph taken in 1910 shows an unidentified San Diego Chinese American family. Anti-Chinese discrimination continued, as evidenced by a letter from the Chinese Chamber of Commerce pointing out the unfair conditions inflicted by the Immigration Law of 1924. Nonetheless, many of these images show that Chinese people persevered, engaging in daily activities ? going to school, working, walking in a funeral procession.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Leute um von der Welt fuhren fort, zu Kalifornien 
in den frühen 1900s, zu vielen auf der Suche nach Arbeit zu kommen 
und zu einer besseren Lebensdauer. Zwei Fotographien stellen 
Männer in den turbans in San Francisco 1910 bildlich dar. 
Südkalifornien zog zahlreiche japanische Immigranten an. 
Fotographien in dieser Gruppe zeigen die japanischen Arbeiter, 
die vor Lieferwägen an Nakamura Company stehen und die japanischen 
besessenen Geschäfte des Inneres wie der Kusumoto Friseursalon in 
Anaheim. Mexikaner und Filipinos kamen auch zu Kalifornien 
während dieser Periode. Da neue bewirtschaftende Technologien 
die Verdichtung der kleineren Pakete des Landes in große Bauernhöfe 
auf und ab den Zustand aktivierten, erhöhte sich die Notwendigkeit an
den Arbeitern. In der Antwort kamen viele Filipinos, in zu 
arbeiten auffängt und in in Verbindung stehenden 
landwirtschaftlichen Jobs. "Snapshot des Lagers der Arbeiter" 
zeigt einige dieser Männer. Mexikanische und japanische 
Immigranten fanden auch Landarbeit in Kalifornien. Fotographien 
in dieser Gruppe zeigen japanische Arbeiter in auffangene; 
und ein anderes Bild zeigt einen jungen mexikanischen 
landwirtschaftlichen Arbeiter. Die Fotographie der Arbeiter im 
Tokay Traube-Packereigebäude im Florin zeigt eine 
Verschiedenartigkeit der Arbeiter, einschließlich eine afrikanische 
amerikanische Frau und japanischen und Filipino Männer. Diese 
Mischung der sehr unterschiedlichen Kulturen verursachte Spannkräfte 
und $überschneidungen. Gastarbeiter wurden, um bedroht und 
gewarnt Jobs weg von anderen Gruppen nicht zu nehmen. Bilder 
schließen zwei Zeichen ein, die einen Landwirt mit Repressalien 
bedrohen, wenn er Filipinos anstellt; und ein US 
Immigrationzeichen in den spanischen bedrohenden Nichtbürgern mit 
Zwangsverschickung, wenn sie streiken. Obgleich die chinesische 
Ausschluss-Tat von 1882 neue Immigranten am Kommen in die Vereinigten 
Staaten hinderte, die Chinesen, die bereits hier fortgesetzt wurden, 
um in westliche Kultur anzupassen. Eine Fotographie genommen in 
1910 Erscheinen eine nicht identifizierte San Diego chinesische 
amerikanische Familie. Anti-Chinesische Unterscheidung fuhr 
fort, wie durch ein Zeichen von der chinesischen Handelskammer 
bewiesen die unfairen Bedingungen unterstreichend, die durch das 
Immigration-Gesetz von 1924 zugefügt wurden. Nichtsdestoweniger
zeigen viele dieser Bilder, daß chinesische Leute ausharrten und in 
den täglichen Aktivitäten sich engagierten? zur Schule gehen, 
Funktion, gehend in eine Begräbnis- Prozession.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les gens de partout dans le monde ont continué à
venir à la Californie au début des années 1900, à beaucoup à la 
recherche du travail et à une meilleure vie. Deux photographies
dépeignent des hommes dans les turbans dans San Francisco en 1910. 
La Californie méridionale a attiré de nombreux immigrés 
japonais. Les photographies dans ce groupe montrent les ouvriers
japonais se tenant devant des camions de livraison à Nakamura Company
et les entreprises possédées japonaises d'intérieur telles que le 
raseur-coiffeur de Kusumoto dans Anaheim. Le Mexicain et les 
Philippins sont également venus à la Californie pendant cette 
période. Car les nouvelles technologies cultivatrices ont 
permis la fusion de plus petites parcelles terrain dans de grandes 
fermes à travers l'état, le besoin d'ouvriers a augmenté. 
Dans la réponse, beaucoup de Philippins sont venus pour 
travailler dans les domaines et dans les travaux agricoles relatifs. 
l'"instantané du camp des ouvriers" montre certains de ces 
hommes. Les immigrés mexicains et japonais ont également 
trouvé le travail agricole en Californie. Les photographies 
dans ce groupe montrent les ouvriers japonais dans un domaine ; 
et une autre image montre un jeune ouvrier agricole mexicain. 
La photographie des ouvriers dans l'atelier d'emballage de 
raisin de Tokay en florin montre une diversité des ouvriers, y 
compris une femme américaine africaine et des hommes japonais et 
philippins. Ce mélange des cultures très différentes a 
provoqué des tensions et des conflits. Des travailleurs 
migrants ont été menacés et avertis pour ne pas prendre les travaux
loin d'autres groupes. Les images incluent deux lettres 
menaçant un fermier par des représailles s'il loue des Philippins ; 
et un signe d'immigration des USA dans les non-citoyens 
menaçants espagnols avec la déportation si elles font la grève. 
Bien que l'acte chinois d'exclusion de 1882 ait empêché de 
nouveaux immigrés de venir aux Etats-Unis, les Chinois qui déjà 
suite ici pour assimiler dans la culture occidentale. Une 
photographie prise dans 1910 expositions une famille américaine 
chinoise non identifiée de San Diego. La discrimination 
Anti-Chinoise a continué, comme démontré par une lettre de la 
chambre de commerce chinoise précisant les conditions injustes 
infligées par la loi d'immigration de 1924. Néanmoins, 
plusieurs de ces images prouvent que les  chinois ont persévéré, 
s'engageant dans des activités quotidiennes ? allant à 
l'école, fonctionnement, marchant dans un cortège funèbre.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Os povos em torno do mundo continuaram a vir a 
Califórnia nos 1900s adiantados, a muitas na busca do trabalho e a 
uma vida melhor. Duas fotografias descrevem homens nos turbans 
em San Francisco em 1910. Califórnia do sul atraiu immigrants 
japoneses numerosos. As fotografias neste grupo mostram os 
trabalhadores japoneses que estão na frente dos caminhões de entrega
no Nakamura Companhia e negócios possuídos japoneses do interior 
tais como o barbershop de Kusumoto em Anaheim. O mexicano e os 
filipinos vieram também a Califórnia durante este período. 
Como novo as tecnologias cultivando permitiram a consolidação 
de pacotes menores da terra em fazendas grandes acima e tragam o 
estado, a necessidade para os trabalhadores aumentados. Na 
resposta, muitos filipinos vieram trabalhar nos campos e em trabalhos 
agriculturais relacionados. o "instantâneo do acampamento dos 
trabalhadores" mostra alguns destes homens. Os immigrants 
mexicanos e japoneses encontraram também o trabalho agricultural em 
Califórnia. As fotografias neste grupo mostram trabalhadores 
japoneses em um campo; e uma outra imagem mostra um trabalhador 
agricultural mexicano novo. A fotografia dos trabalhadores na 
vertente de embalagem da uva de Tokay no florin mostra uma diversidade
dos trabalhadores, including uma mulher americana africana e uns 
homens japoneses e filipino. Esta mistura de culturas muito 
diferentes deu a ascensão às tensões e aos conflitos. Os 
trabalhadores emigrantes foram ameaçados e advertidos não fazer 
exame de trabalhos away de outros grupos. As imagens incluem 
duas letras que ameaçam um fazendeiro com as represálias se empregar
filipinos; e um sinal do immigration dos E. U. em non-citizens 
ameaçando espanhóis com deporta16cao se forem na batida. 
Embora o ato chinês da exclusão de 1882 impedisse que os 
immigrants novos venham aos estados unidos, os chineses que já foram 
continuados aqui a assimilate na cultura ocidental. Uma 
fotografia feita exame em 1910 mostras uma família americana chinesa 
não identificada do San Diego. A discriminação Anti-Chinesa 
continuou, como evidenciado por uma letra da câmara de comércio 
chinesa que indica as circunstâncias unfair inflicted pela lei do 
immigration de 1924. Nonetheless, muitas destas imagens mostram 
que os povos chineses persevered, acoplando em atividades diárias? 
indo à escola, funcionamento, andando em uma procissão 
funeral.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La gente intorno al mondo ha continuato a venire 
alla California all'inizio degli anni 1900, molte alla ricerca di 
lavoro e ad una vita migliore. Due fotografie descrivono gli 
uomini nei turbans a San Francisco in 1910. La California del 
sud ha attratto gli immigranti giapponesi numerosi. Le 
fotografie in questo gruppo mostrano gli operai giapponesi che si 
levano in piedi davanti i camion di consegna al Nakamura Company ed i 
commerci posseduti giapponesi della parte interna quale il barbershop 
di Kusumoto in Anaheim. Il mexicans ed i filipinos egualmente 
sono venuto alla California durante questo periodo. Poichè le 
nuove tecnologie d'agricoltura hanno permesso il consolidamento di 
più piccoli pacchetti di terra nei grandi poderi su e giù il 
dichiarare, l'esigenza degli operai è aumentato. Nella 
risposta, molti filipinos sono venuto lavorare nei campi e nei lavori 
agricoli relativi. "la fotografia istantanea dell'accampamento 
degli operai" mostra alcuno di questi uomini messicani e del lavoro 
agricolo anche trovato giapponese degli immigranti nella California. 
Le fotografie in questo gruppo mostrano gli operai giapponesi in
un campo; e un'altra immagine mostra un operaio agricolo 
messicano giovane. La fotografia degli operai nel locale per 
l'imballaggio dell'uva di Tokay nel florin mostra una diversità degli
operai, compreso una donna americana africana e gli uomini giapponesi 
e filipino. Questa miscela delle colture molto differenti ha 
provocato i tensionamenti ed i conflitti. I lavoratori migranti 
sono stati minacciati ed avvertito stati per non prendere i lavori via
da altri gruppi. Le immagini includono due lettere che 
minacciano un coltivatore per i reprisals se assume i filipinos; 
e un segno di immigrazione degli Stati Uniti in non-citizens 
minacciosi spagnoli con la deportazione se vanno sul colpo. 
Anche se la Legge cinese di esclusione di 1882 ha impedito 
ai nuovi immigranti di venire ai uniti Dichiara, il cinese
che già qui sono stati continuati per assimilare in coltura 
occidentale. Una fotografia presa in 1910 esposizioni una 
famiglia americana cinese non identificata de San Diego. La
distinzione di Anti-cinese è continuato, come provato da una 
lettera dalla camera di commercio cinese che precisa le 
circostanze ingiuste inflitte dalla legge di immigrazione di 1924. 
Ciò nonostante, molte di queste immagini indicano che la gente 
cinese ha perseverato, agganciandosi nelle attività quotidiane? 
andando alla scuola, funzionamento, ambulante in un procession 
funereo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οι άνθρωποι από σε όλο τον κόσμο συνέχισαν να 
έρχονται σε Καλιφόρνια στις αρχές των δεκαετιών του 20ου αιώνα, 
πολλές σε αναζήτηση της εργασίας και μιας καλύτερης ζωής. 
Δύο φωτογραφίες απεικονίζουν τα άτομα στα τουρμπάνια στο 
Σαν Φρανσίσκο σε 1910, νότιους γοητευμένους Καλιφόρνια 
πολυάριθμους ιαπωνικούς μετανάστες. Οι φωτογραφίες σε αυτήν
την ομάδα εμφανίζουν ιαπωνικούς εργαζομένους που στέκονται 
μπροστά από τα truck παράδοσης στις ιαπωνικές κύριες 
επιχειρήσεις επιχείρησης Nakamura και εσωτερικών όπως το 
Kusumoto Barbershop στο Αναχάιμ. Μεξικανοί και 
Φιλιππίνοι ήρθαν επίσης σε Καλιφόρνια κατά τη διάρκεια αυτής 
της περιόδου. Δεδομένου ότι οι νέες τεχνολογίες 
καλλιέργειας επέτρεψαν τη σταθεροποίηση των μικρότερων δεμάτων 
του εδάφους στα μεγάλα αγροκτήματα πάνω-κάτω το κράτος, η 
ανάγκη για τους εργαζομένους αυξανόμενη. Στην απάντηση, 
πολλοί Φιλιππίνοι ήρθαν να εργαστούν στα πεδία και στις σχετικές
γεωργικές εργασίες. "Το στιγμιότυπο του στρατόπεδου των 
εργαζομένων" εμφανίζει μερικών από αυτά τα άτομα. Οι 
μεξικάνικοι και ιαπωνικοί μετανάστες βρήκαν επίσης τη γεωργική 
εργασία σε Καλιφόρνια. Οι φωτογραφίες σε αυτήν την ομάδα 
εμφανίζουν ιαπωνικούς εργαζομένους σε ένα πεδίο  και μια 
άλλη εικόνα εμφανίζει νέο μεξικάνικο γεωργικό εργαζόμενο. 
Η φωτογραφία των εργαζομένων στο υπόστεγο συσκευασίας 
σταφυλιών Tokay σε φλορίνι εμφανίζει μια ποικιλομορφία των 
εργαζομένων, συμπεριλαμβανομένης μιας αφρικανικής αμερικανικής 
γυναίκας και ιαπωνικών και των Φηληππίνων ανδρών. Αυτό το 
μίγμα των πολύ διαφορετικών πολιτισμών προκάλεσε τις εντάσεις 
και τις συγκρούσεις. Οι διακινούμενοι εργαζόμενοι 
απειλήθηκαν και προειδοποιήθηκαν για να μην αναλάβουν δουλειές 
μακρυά από άλλες ομάδες. Οι εικόνες περιλαμβάνουν δύο 
επιστολές απειλώντας έναν αγρότη με τα αντίποινα εάν μισθώνει 
Φιλιππίνους  και ένα σημάδι αμερικανικής μετανάστευσης στα 
ισπανικά που απειλούν τους μη-πολίτες με την εκτόπιση εάν 
πηγαίνουν στην απεργία. Αν και ο κινεζικός νόμος 
αποκλεισμού 1882 απέτρεψε τους νέους μετανάστες από τον 
ερχομό στις Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες, οι Κινέζοι που ήδη εδώ 
συνεχίστηκαν αφομοιώνω στο δυτικό πολιτισμό. Μια φωτογραφία
που λαμβάνεται οικογένεια το 1910 εμφανίζει σε ένα μη 
αναγνωρισμένο Σαν Ντιέγκο κινεζική αμερικανική. 
Αντι-κινεζικά η διάκριση συνεχίστηκε, όπως αποδειγμένος 
από μια επιστολή από το κινεζικό εμπορικό επιμελητήριο που 
επισημαίνει τους άδικους όρους που επιβάλλονται από το νόμο 
μετανάστευσης 1924, Εν τούτοις, πολλές από αυτές τις 
εικόνες δείχνουν ότι οι κινεζικοί λαοί ενέμειναν, συμμετέχοντας
στις καθημερινές δραστηριότητες; πηγαίνοντας στο σχολείο, 
εργασία, που περπατά σε μια νεκρική πομπή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La gente alrededor del mundo continuó viniendo a 
California en los 1900s tempranos, a muchas en la búsqueda del 
trabajo y a una vida mejor. Dos fotografías representan a 
hombres en turbans en San Francisco en 1910. California 
meridional atrajo a inmigrantes japoneses numerosos. Las 
fotografías en este grupo muestran los trabajadores japoneses que 
están parados delante de los carros de salida en el Nakamura Company 
y los negocios poseídos japoneses del interior tales como el 
barbershop de Kusumoto en Anaheim. El mexicano y los filipinos 
también vinieron a California durante este período. Pues las 
nuevas tecnologías que cultivaban permitieron la consolidación de 
paquetes más pequeños de la pista en granjas grandes arriba y abajo 
del estado, la necesidad de trabajadores aumentó. En respuesta,
muchos filipinos vinieron trabajar en los campos y en trabajos 
agrícolas relacionados. la "foto del campo de los trabajadores"
muestra a algunos de estos hombres. Los inmigrantes mexicanos y 
japoneses también encontraron el trabajo agrícola en California. 
Las fotografías en este grupo muestran a trabajadores japoneses
en un campo; y otra imagen muestra a trabajador agrícola 
mexicano joven. La fotografía de trabajadores en la vertiente 
de embalaje de la uva de Tokay en florín muestra una diversidad de 
trabajadores, incluyendo una mujer americana africana y hombres 
japoneses y filipinos. Esta mezcla de culturas muy diversas dio 
lugar a tensiones y a conflictos. Se advertidas a las 
trabajadores emigrantes fueron amenazadas y que no tomaran trabajos 
lejos de otros grupos. Las imágenes incluyen dos cartas que 
amenazan a un granjero con represalias si él emplea a filipinos; 
y una muestra de la inmigración de los E.E.U.U. en non-citizens
amenazadores españoles con la deportación si van en huelga. 
Aunque el acto chino de la exclusión de 1882 evitó que los 
nuevos inmigrantes vinieran a los Estados Unidos, los chinos que ya 
aquí fueron continuados para asimilar en cultura occidental. 
Una fotografía tomada en 1910 demostraciones una familia 
americana china no identificada de San Diego. La discriminación
Contra-China continuó, según lo evidenciado por una carta de la 
Cámara de Comercio china que precisaba las condiciones injustas 
infligidas por la ley de la inmigración de 1924. ¿No obstante, 
muchas de estas imágenes muestran que perseveró la gente china, 
enganchando a actividades diarias? yendo a la escuela, 
funcionamiento, recorriendo en una procesión fúnebre.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765085243</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103922</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/growing-ethnic-diversity</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
