<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104446</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104446</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213117</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">WebAIM: Web Accessibility in Mind</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">WebAIM: Web-Zugänglichkeit im Verstand</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">WebAIM : Accessibilité de Web à 
l'esprit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">WebAIM: Acessibilidade do Web na mente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">WebAIM: Accessibilità di Web in mente</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">WebAIM: Δυνατότητα πρόσβασης Ιστού στο μυαλό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">WebAIM: Accesibilidad del Web en 
mente</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This website presents a collection of materials and information that can be used to improve accessibility to web-based information for individuals with disabilities. The site provides web design techniques and useful guidelines, as well as descriptions and reviews of various products and tools related to web accessibility. Features of the site also include educational materials, software applications, a collection of web accessibility discussion groups, courses and curricula, training tips, consultants, books, and web sites. This resource is part of the Creating Web-based Resources in the Geosciences collection. http://serc.carleton.edu NAGTWorkshops/webresources03/</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Web site stellt eine Ansammlung Materialien 
und Informationen dar, die verwendet werden können, um 
Zugänglichkeit zu Web-gegründeten Informationen für Einzelpersonen 
mit Unfähigkeit zu verbessern. Die Site stellt 
Web-Entwurfstechniken und nützliche Korrekturlinien, sowie 
Beschreibungen und Zusammenfassungen der verschiedenen Produkte und 
der Hilfsmittel zur Verfügung, die auf Web-Zugänglichkeit in 
Verbindung gestanden werden. Merkmale der Sites schließen auch 
pädagogische Materialien, Software-Anwendungen, eine Ansammlung 
Web-Zugänglichkeit Diskussion Gruppen, Kurse und Lehrpläne, 
ausbildenspitzen, Berater, Bücher und Web-Sites ein. Dieses 
Hilfsmittel ist ein Teil der erstellenden Web-gegründeten 
Betriebsmittel in der Geosciences Ansammlung http://serc.carleton.edu 
NAGTWorkshops/webresources03/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site Web présente une collecte de matériaux 
et d'information qui peuvent être employés pour améliorer 
l'accessibilité à l'information Web-basée pour des individus avec 
des incapacités. Le site fournit des techniques de conception 
de Web et des directives utiles, aussi bien que des descriptions et 
des examens de divers produits et d'outils liés à l'accessibilité 
de Web. Les dispositifs du site incluent également les 
matériaux éducatifs, les applications de logiciel, une collection de
groupes de discussion d'accessibilité de Web, des cours et des 
programmes d'études, des extrémités s'exerçantes, des conseillers,
des livres, et des sites de Web. Cette ressource fait partie des
ressources créantes de Web-based dans la collection 
http://serc.carleton.edu NAGTWorkshops/webresources03/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este Web site apresenta uma coleção dos 
materiais e da informação que podem ser usados melhorar a 
acessibilidade à informação Web-baseada para indivíduos com 
inabilidades. O local fornece técnicas de projeto do Web e 
guidelines úteis, as.well.as descrições e revisões de vários 
produtos e das ferramentas relacionados à acessibilidade do Web. 
As características do local incluem também materiais 
educacionais, aplicações do software, uma coleção de grupos de 
discussão da acessibilidade do Web, cursos e curricula, pontas 
treinando, consultantes, livros, e locais do Web. Este recurso 
é parte dos recursos Web-baseados criadores na coleção 
http://serc.carleton.edu NAGTWorkshops/webresources03/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo Web site presenta una collezione di 
materiali e di informazioni che possono essere usati per migliorare 
l'accessibilità alle informazioni Web-basate per gli individui con le
inabilità. Il luogo fornisce le tecniche di disegno di Web e la
guida di riferimento utile, così come le descrizioni e le revisioni 
di vari prodotti e degli strumenti relativi ad accessibilità di Web. 
Le caratteristiche del luogo egualmente includono i materiali 
educativi, applicazioni del software, una collezione di gruppi di 
discussione di accessibilità di Web, corsi e programmi di studi, 
punte d'addestramento, consulenti, libri e luoghi di Web. Questa
risorsa fa parte delle risorse Web-basate di creazione 
nell'accumulazione http://serc.carleton.edu 
NAGTWorkshops/webresources03/ di Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος παρουσιάζει μια συλλογή των υλικών 
και των πληροφοριών που μπορεί να χρησιμοποιηθεί για να βελτιώσει 
τη δυνατότητα πρόσβασης στις βασισμένες στο WEB πληροφορίες για
τα άτομα με ειδικές ανάγκες. Η περιοχή παρέχει τις 
τεχνικές σχεδίου Ιστού και τις χρήσιμες οδηγίες, καθώς επίσης 
και τις περιγραφές και τις αναθεωρήσεις των διάφορων προϊόντων 
και των εργαλείων σχετικών με τη δυνατότητα πρόσβασης Ιστού. 
Τα χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα της περιοχής περιλαμβάνουν 
επίσης τα εκπαιδευτικά υλικά, εφαρμογές λογισμικού, μια συλλογή 
των ομάδων συζήτησης δυνατότητας πρόσβασης Ιστού, των σειρών 
μαθημάτων και των προγραμμάτων σπουδών, των ακρών κατάρτισης, των
συμβούλων, των βιβλίων, και των ιστοχώρων. Αυτό το στοιχείο
συμπεριφοράς είναι μέρος των δημιουργώντας βασισμένων στο WEB 
στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς στη Geosciences συλλογή 
http://serc.carleton.edu 
NAGTWorkshops/$l*webresources03/</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este Web site presenta una colección de los 
materiales y de la información que se pueden utilizar para mejorar 
accesibilidad a la información Web-basada para los individuos con 
inhabilidades. El sitio proporciona a técnicas de diseño del 
Web y a guías de consulta útiles, así como descripciones y 
revisiones de varios productos y de herramientas relacionados con la 
accesibilidad del Web. Las características del sitio también 
incluyen los materiales educativos, las aplicaciones del software, una
colección de grupos de discusión de la accesibilidad del Web, los 
cursos y los planes de estudios, las extremidades de entrenamiento, 
los consultores, los libros, y los sitios del Web. Este recurso 
es parte de los recursos de Web-based que crean en la colección 
http://serc.carleton.edu NAGTWorkshops/webresources03/ de Geosciences</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770213117</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104446</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/webaim-web-accessibility-in-mind</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
