<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106282</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106282</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973923</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Chemistry Games: PCR Method</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Chemie-Spiele: PCR Methode</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jeux de Chimie : Méthode de PCR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogos Do Chemistry: Método de PCR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Giochi Di Chimica: Metodo di PCR</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παιχνίδια χημείας: Pcr μέθοδος</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Juegos De la Química: Método de PCR</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Play a game and find out about a Nobel Prize awarded discovery or work! PCR is a method by which a few fragments of DNA can be duplicated into millions in a couple of hours. This makes PCR a very useful method in forensic science, as it means that very small amounts of DNA could be enough to identify a person. PCR was invented by Kary Mullis, one of two Nobel Laureates in Chemistry in 1993. If you play the game below, you will be able to learn more about PCR!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Spielen Sie ein Spiel und finden Sie über eine 
zugesprochene Entdeckung oder eine Arbeit des Nobelpreises heraus! 
PCR ist eine Methode, durch die einige Fragmente von DNA in 
Millionen in einem Paar von Stunden kopiert werden können. 
Dieses bildet PCR eine sehr nützliche Methode in der 
gerichtlichen Wissenschaft, da es bedeutet, daß sehr etwas DNA genug 
sein konnten, zum einer Person zu kennzeichnen. PCR wurde von 
Kary Mullis, einer von zwei Nobel Laureaten in der Chemie 1993 
erfunden. Wenn Sie das Spiel unten spielen, können Sie, mehr 
über PCR zu erlernen!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Jouez un jeu et découvrez au sujet d'une 
découverte ou d'un travail attribuée de prix Nobel ! PCR est 
une méthode par laquelle quelques fragments de l'ADN peuvent être 
reproduits dans des millions dans un couple des heures. Ceci 
fait à PCR une méthode très utile en science légale, car il 
signifie qu'un peu d'ADN très pourraient être assez pour identifier 
une personne. PCR a été inventé par Kary Mullis, un de deux 
lauréats Nobel en chimie en 1993. Si vous jouez le jeu 
ci-dessous, vous pourrez apprendre plus au sujet de PCR !</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Jogue um jogo e encontre-o para fora sobre uma 
descoberta ou um trabalho concedido do prêmio de nobel! PCR é 
um método por que alguns fragmentos do DNA podem ser duplicados em 
milhões em um par das horas. Isto faz a PCR um método muito 
útil na ciência forensic, porque significa que as quantidades muito 
pequenas de DNA poderiam ser bastantes para identificar uma pessoa. 
PCR foi inventado por Kary Mullis, um de dois laureates de Nobel
no chemistry em 1993. Se você jogar o jogo abaixo, você 
poderá  aprender mais sobre PCR!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Gioc un gioco e scopra circa una scoperta o un 
lavoro ricevuta del premio Nobel! PCR è un metodo da cui alcuni
frammenti di DNA possono essere duplicati in milioni in una coppia 
delle ore. Ciò rende a PCR un metodo molto utile nella scienza 
legale, poichè significa che gli importi di DNA molto piccoli 
potrebbero essere abbastanza per identificare una persona. PCR 
è stato inventato da Kary Mullis, uno di due laureates Nobel nella 
chimica in 1993. Se giocate il gioco qui sotto, potrete imparare
più circa PCR!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Παίξτε ένα παιχνίδι και ανακαλύψτε για μια 
απονεμημένη βραβείο ανακάλυψη ή μια εργασία Νόμπελ! Pcr είναι μια μέθοδος με την οποία μερικά τεμάχια του DNA 
μπορούν να αναπαραχθούν στα εκατομμύρια σε μερικές ώρες. 
Αυτό κάνει pcr μια πολύ χρήσιμη μέθοδο στη δικανική 
επιστήμη, δεδομένου ότι σημαίνει ότι τα πολύ μικρά ποσά του 
DNA θα μπορούσαν να είναι αρκετά να προσδιορίσουν ένα 
πρόσωπο. Pcr εφευρέθηκε από Kary Mullis, ένας από
δύο δαφνοστεφές Νόμπελ στη χημεία το 1993. Εάν παίξετε 
το παιχνίδι κατωτέρω, θα είστε σε θέση να μάθετε περισσότερους 
για pcr!</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¡Juegue un juego y descubra sobre un 
descubrimiento o un trabajo concedido del premio Nobel! PCR es 
un método por el cual algunos fragmentos de la DNA se pueden duplicar
en millones en un par de horas. Esto hace PCR un método muy 
útil en ciencia forense, pues significa que las cantidades muy 
pequeñas de DNA podrían ser bastantes para identificar a una 
persona. PCR fue inventado por Kary Mullis, uno de dos laureados
Nobel en química en 1993. ¡Si usted juega el juego abajo, usted
podrá aprender más sobre PCR!</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805973923</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106282</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/chemistry-games-pcr-method</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
