<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106804</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106804</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086772</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Race and Racism at the 1886 Knights of Labor Convention</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Rennen und Rassismus an den 1886 Rittern der 
Arbeitsversammlung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Course et racisme aux 1886 chevaliers de la 
convention de travail</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Raça e racism nos 1886 knights da convenção 
labor</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Corsa e razzismo ai 1886 cavalieri della 
convenzione Di lavoro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Φυλή και ρατσισμός στους 1886 ιππότες της Συνθήκης 
εργασίας</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Raza y racismo en los 1886 caballeros de la 
convención de trabajo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The annual convention of the Knights of Labor that convened in Richmond, Virginia, on October 4, 1886, took place in a region riven by racial and political conflict. The convention and the Knights, the most powerful labor organization in late 19th century America, were quickly plunged into conflict over the organization's attitudes toward the question of social equality between the races. A major controversy erupted over whether or not Frank J. Ferrell, a black representative of the Knights' powerful District Assembly #49 in New York City, should introduce the governor of Virginia at the opening session. This excerpt from Knights' leader General Master Workman Terence V. Powderly's 1890 autobiography detailed the tense moments leading up to Frank Ferrell's appearance at the podium, where he agreed to introduce Powderly and the Grand Master Workman in turn would introduce the governor.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die jährliche Versammlung der Ritter der Arbeit, 
die in Richmond, Virginia, an Oktober 4, 1886 zusammenkamen, fand in 
einer Region riven durch rassische und politische $überschneidung 
statt. Die Versammlung und die Ritter, die leistungsfähigste 
Gewerkschaft im des späten 19. jahrhunderts Jahrhundert Amerika, 
wurden schnell in $überschneidung über den einstellungen der 
Organisation gegenüber der Frage der Sozialgleichheit zwischen die 
Rennen getaucht. Eine Hauptkontroverse brach Überschuß aus, ob
oder nicht aufrichtiges J. Ferrell, ein schwarzer Repräsentant des 
leistungsfähigen Bezirkes #49 der Ritter in New York City, den Regler
von Virginia an der Eröffnungssitzung einführen sollte. Dieses
Excerpt von Terence V. Powderlys arbeiter Führer der Ritter 
allgemeines VorlagenAutobiographie 1890 schilderte die angespannten 
Momente genau, die bis zum Aussehen aufrichtigen Ferrells am Podium 
führen, in dem er damit einverstandenWAR, Powderly einzuführen und 
der großartige Vorlagenarbeiter der Reihe nach den Regler einführen 
würde.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La convention annuelle des chevaliers du travail 
qui se sont assemblés à Richmond, la Virginie, 4 octobre 1886, a eu
lieu dans une région riven par conflit racial et politique. La 
convention et les chevaliers, l'organisation de travail la plus 
puissante en fin du 19me siècle Amérique, ont été rapidement 
plongés dans le conflit au-dessus des attitudes de l'organisation 
envers la question de l'égalité sociale entre les courses. Une
polémique importante a éclaté l'excédent si J. Ferrell non franc, 
un représentant noir de l'Assemblée puissante #49 de la zone des 
chevaliers à New York City, devrait présenter le gouverneur de la 
Virginie à la session d'ouverture. Cet extrait de 
l'autobiographie 1890 de Terence V. Powderly's principal général 
d'ouvrier du Chef des chevaliers a détaillé les moments tendus 
menant vers le haut à contresigner l'aspect de Ferrell au podiume, 
où il a accepté de présenter Powderly et l'ouvrier principal grand 
au tour présenterait le gouverneur.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A convenção anual dos knights do trabalho que se
reuniram em Richmond, Virgínia, outubro em 4, 1886, ocorreu em uma 
região riven pelo conflito racial e político. A convenção e 
os knights, a organização labor a mais poderosa no 1ø século 
atrasado América, foram mergulhados rapidamente no conflito sobre as 
atitudes da organização para a pergunta da igualdade social entre as
raças. Uma controvérsia principal erupted o excesso se ou J. 
nao frank Ferrell, um representante preto do conjunto poderoso #49 do 
distrito dos knights' em New York City, deve introduzir o regulador de
Virgínia na sessão de abertura. Este excerpt do autobiography 
1890 de Terence V. Powderly mestre geral do trabalhador do líder dos 
knights' detalhou os momentos tensos que conduzem à aparência de 
Ferrell frank no podium, onde concordou introduzir Powderly e o 
trabalhador mestre grande por sua vez introduziria o regulador.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La convenzione annuale dei cavalieri del 
Lavoro che si sono riuniti a Richmond, la Virginia, il 4 ottobre 
1886, ha avvenuto in una regione riven dal conflitto razziale e 
politico. La convenzione ed i cavalieri, l'organizzazione 
di lavoro più potente nel fine del 19esimo secolo America, sono 
stati immersi rapidamente nel conflitto sopra gli atteggiamenti 
dell'organizzazione nei confronti della domanda di uguaglianza sociale
fra le corse. Una polemica importante ha scoppiato 
l'eccedenza se o J. Ferrell non franco, un rappresentante nero 
dell'Assemblea potente #49 del distretto dei cavalieri a New York 
City, dovrebbe introdurre il regolatore della Virginia alla sessione 
di apertura. Questo brano dal autobiography 1890 di Terence V. 
Powderly matrice generale dell'operaio del capo dei cavalieri 
ha dettagliato i momenti tesi che portano all'apparenza del Ferrell 
franco al podium, in cui ha accosentito per introdurre Powderly 
ed il grande operaio matrice a sua volta introdurrebbe il regolatore.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ετήσια σύμβαση των ιπποτών της εργασίας που 
συγκάλεσαν στο Ρίτσμοντ, Βιρτζίνια, στις 4 Οκτωβρίου ..1886, 
πραγματοποιήθηκε σε μια περιοχή διασπασμένη από τη φυλετική και 
πολιτική σύγκρουση. Η σύμβαση και οι ιππότες, η ισχυρότερη 
οργάνωση εργασίας στο 19$ο αργά αιώνα Αμερική, βυθίστηκαν 
γρήγορα στη σύγκρουση πέρα από τη στάση της οργάνωσης απέναντι 
στο θέμα της κοινωνικής ισότητας μεταξύ των φυλών. Μια 
σημαντική διαμάχη εξερράγη πέρα από εάν ο Frank J. 
Ferrell, ένας μαύρος αντιπρόσωπος της ισχυρής συμβολικής 
γλώσσας περιοχής των ιπποτών #49 στην πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης, 
πρέπει ή όχι να εισαγάγει τον κυβερνήτη της Βιρτζίνια στην 
εναρκτήρια συνεδρίαση. Αυτό το απόσπασμα από τη γενική 
κύρια Workman Terence Θ*Β. Powderly's 1890 αυτοβιογραφία
ηγετών των ιπποτών απαρίθμησε τις ανήσυχες στιγμές που 
καταλήγουν στην εμφάνιση του Frank Ferrell's στην εξέδρα, 
όπου συμφώνησε να εισαγάγει Powderly και ο μεγάλος κύριος 
εργάτης στη συνέχεια θα εισήγε τον κυβερνήτη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La convención anual de los caballeros del trabajo
que convocaron en Richmond, Virginia, 4 de octubre de 1886, 
ocurrió en una región riven por conflicto racial y político. 
Hundieron a la convención y a los caballeros, la organización 
de trabajo más de gran alcance de la a fines del siglo XIX América, 
rápidamente en conflicto sobre las actitudes de la organización 
hacia la cuestión de la igualdad social entre las razas. Una 
controversia importante entró en erupción el excedente si o J. no 
franco Ferrell, representante negro de la asamblea de gran alcance #49
del districto de los caballeros en New York City, debe introducir el 
gobernador de Virginia en la sesión de apertura. Este extracto 
de la autobiografía 1890 de Terence V. Powderly principal general del
trabajador del arranque de cinta de los caballeros detalló los 
momentos tensos que conducían al aspecto de Ferrell franco en el 
podium, donde él acordó introducir Powderly y el trabajador 
principal magnífico alternadamente introduciría el gobernador.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765086772</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106804</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/race-and-racism-at-the-1886-knights-of-labor-convention</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
