<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103797</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103797</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209940</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">45-45-90 triangle </string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">45-45-90 Dreieck</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">45-45-90 triangle</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">45-45-90 triângulo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">45-45-90 triangolo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τρίγωνο του 45-45-90</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">45-45-90 triángulo</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An interactive applet and associated web page that demonstrate the properties of a 45-45-90 isosceles right triangle. The applet shows a right triangle that can be resized by dragging any vertex. As it is dragged, the remaining vertices change so that the triangle's angles remain 45 degrees, 45 degrees and 90 degrees The text on the page points out that the sides of a 45-45-90 triangle are always in the ratio of 1 : 2 : root 2 Applet can be enlarged to full screen size for use with a classroom projector. After use in the classroom, student can access it again from any web browser at home or in the library with no login required. This resource is a component of the Math Open Reference Interactive Geometry textbook project at http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Mathematics and Statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktiver applet und eine verbundene 
Webseite, die die Eigenschaften eines isosceles rechten Dreiecks 
45-45-90 zeigen. Der applet zeigt ein rechtes Dreieck, das die 
Größe neu bestimmt werden kann, indem man jeden möglichen Gipfel 
schleppt. Während er geschleppt wird, ändern die restlichen 
Gipfel, damit die Winkel des Dreiecks 45 Grad bleiben, 45 Grad und 90 
Grad der Text auf der Seite unterstreicht, daß die Seiten eines 
Dreiecks 45-45-90 immer im Verhältnis von 1 sind: 2: 
Wurzel 2 applet kann zum vollen Bildumfang für Gebrauch mit 
einem Klassenzimmerprojektor vergrößert werden. Nachgebrauch 
im Klassenzimmer, Kursteilnehmer kann auf es von jedem möglichem web 
browser zu Hause oder in der Bibliothek ohne den benötigten LOGON 
wieder zugreifen. Dieses Hilfsmittel ist ein Bestandteil des 
Mathe-geöffnetes Bezugsinteraktiven Geometrielehrbuchprojektes an 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un applet interactif et une page Web associée 
qui démontrent les propriétés d'une bonne triangle 45-45-90 
isocèle. L'applet montre une bonne triangle qui peut être 
remise à la côte en traînant n'importe quel sommet. Pendant 
qu'il est traîné, les sommets restants changent de sorte que les 
angles de la triangle demeurent de 45 degrés, 45 degrés et 90 
degrés le texte à la page précise que les côtés d'une triangle 
45-45-90 sont toujours dans le taux de 1 : 2 : l'applet de
la racine 2 peut être agrandi à la taille de plein écran pour 
l'usage avec un projecteur de salle de classe. Le après 
utilisation dans la salle de classe, étudiant peut lui accéder 
encore de n'importe quel navigateur de Web à la maison ou dans la 
bibliothèque sans la procédure de connexion exigée. Cette 
ressource est un composant du projet interactif de manuel de la 
géométrie de référence ouverte de maths à 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um applet interativo e um Web page associado que 
demonstrem as propriedades de um triângulo 45-45-90 direito 
isosceles. O applet mostra um triângulo direito que possa 
resized arrastando todo o vertex. Enquanto é arrastado, os 
vertices restantes mudam de modo que os ângulos do triângulo 
remanesçam 45 graus, 45 graus e 90 graus o texto na página indicam 
que os lados de um triângulo 45-45-90 estão sempre na relação de 
1: 2: o applet da raiz 2 pode ser ampliado ao tamanho de 
tela cheia para o uso com um projetor da sala de aula. O depois 
de uso na sala de aula, estudante pode alcançá-la outra vez de todo 
o web browser na HOME ou na biblioteca com nenhum início de uma 
sessão requerido. Este recurso é um componente do projeto 
interativo do textbook da geometria da referência aberta do math em 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un applet interattivo e un Web page collegato che 
dimostrano le proprietà di giusto triangolo isosceles 45-45-90. 
Il applet mostra un giusto triangolo che può essere 
ridimensionato trascinando tutto il vertice. Mentre è 
trascinato, i vertici restanti cambiano in modo che gli angoli del 
triangolo rimangano di 45 gradi, 45 gradi e 90 gradi il testo alla 
pagina precisa che i lati di un triangolo 45-45-90 sono sempre nel 
rapporto di 1: 2: il applet della radice 2 può essere 
ingrandito al formato di schermo pieno per uso con un proiettore 
dell'aula. La post-utilizzazione nell'aula, allievo può 
accederle ancora da tutto il web browser nel paese o nella libreria 
senza l'inizio attività richiesto. Questa risorsa è un 
componente del progetto interattivo del manuale della geometria di 
riferimento aperto di per la matematica a http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό applet και σχετική ιστοσελίδας που 
καταδεικνύουν τις ιδιότητες ενός ισοσκελούς σωστού τριγώνου του 
45-45-90. Το applet εμφανίζει σωστό τρίγωνο που μπορεί
να επαναταξινομηθεί με το σύρσιμο οποιουδήποτε vertex. 
Δεδομένου ότι σέρνεται, υπόλοιπα vertices αλλάζουν έτσι
ώστε οι γωνίες του τριγώνου παραμένουν 45 βαθμοί, 45 
βαθμοί και 90 βαθμοί που το κείμενο στη σελίδα επισημαίνει 
ότι οι πλευρές ενός τριγώνου του 45-45-90 είναι πάντα σε 
αναλογία 1: 2: η ρίζα 2 Applet μπορεί να διευρυνθεί
στο πλήρες μέγεθος οθόνης για τη χρήση με έναν προβολέα τάξεων.
Μετά από τη χρήση στην τάξη, ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να έχει 
πρόσβαση σε τον πάλι από οποιοδήποτε ξεφυλλιστή Ιστού στο σπίτι
ή στη βιβλιοθήκη χωρίς την άδεια εισόδου που απαιτείται. 
Αυτό το στοιχείο συμπεριφοράς είναι ένα συστατικό του 
ανοικτού προγράμματος εγχειριδίων γεωμετρίας αναφοράς Math 
διαλογικού σε http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un applet interactivo y un Web page asociado que 
demuestran las características de un triángulo derecho isósceles 
45-45-90. El applet muestra un triángulo derecho que pueda ser 
vuelto a clasificar según el tamaño arrastrando cualquier cima. 
Mientras que se arrastra, las cimas restantes cambian de modo 
que los ángulos del triángulo sigan siendo 45 grados, 45 grados y 90
grados el texto en la paginación precisan que las caras de un 
triángulo 45-45-90 están siempre en la relación de transformación 
de 1: 2: el applet de la raíz 2 se puede agrandar a la 
talla de la pantalla completa para el uso con un proyector de la sala 
de clase. El uso posterior en la sala de clase, estudiante puede
tenerle acceso otra vez de cualquier web browser en el país o en la 
biblioteca sin la conexión requerida. Este recurso es un 
componente del proyecto interactivo del libro de textos de la 
geometría de la referencia abierta de la matemáticas en 
http://www.mathopenref.com.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Mathematik und Statistiken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Mathématiques et statistiques</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Matemática e statistics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Matematica e statistiche</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μαθηματικά και στατιστικές</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Matemáticas y estadística</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:PAGE,JOHN
FN:PAGE,JOHN
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770209940</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103797</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/45-45-90-triangle</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
