<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105723</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105723</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205688</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Helping Your Child with Homework</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Helfen Ihres Kindes mit Heimarbeit</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Aider votre enfant avec le travail</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ajudando a sua criança com homework</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Assistenza del vostro bambino con lavoro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βοήθεια του παιδιού σας με την εργασία</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ayudar a su niño con la preparación</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">tells how parents can make sure children succeed with homework and develop strong study skills. Among the topics: setting a regular time and place for homework, removing distractions, looking over completed assignments, discussing assignments to be sure they are clear, talking with teachers, and more. A brief checklist is included.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">erklärt, wie Eltern sicherstellen können Kinder,
mit Heimarbeit zu folgen und starke Studie Fähigkeiten zu entwickeln.
Unter den Themen: Einstellung eine regelmäßige Zeit und 
einen Platz für Heimarbeit, Ablenkungen löschend und schauen die 
Überschuß abgeschlossenen Anweisungen und behandeln Anweisungen, um 
sicher zu sein, daß sie klar sind und mehr mit Lehrern und sprechen. 
Eine kurze Checkliste ist enthalten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dit que les parents peuvent s'assurer des enfants 
réussir avec le travail et développer des qualifications fortes 
d'étude. Parmi les sujets : plaçant un temps et un 
endroit réguliers pour le travail, retirant des distractions, 
regardant des affectations réalisées par excédent, discutant des 
affectations pour être sûr qu'elles sont certaines, parlant avec des
professeurs, et davantage. Une brève liste de contrôle est 
incluse.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">diz como os pais podem se certificar crianças 
para suceder com homework e para desenvolver habilidades fortes do 
estudo. Entre os tópicos: ajustando uma estadia e um 
lugar regulares para o homework, removendo os distractions, olhando as
atribuições terminadas excesso, discutindo atribuições para ser 
certo que estão desobstruídas, falando com professores, e mais. 
Uma lista de verificação breve é incluída.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dice a come i genitori possono assicurarsi bambini
riuscire con lavoro e sviluppare le abilità forti di studio. 
Fra i soggetti: regolando una data e una località normali
per lavoro, rimuovendo le distrazioni, osservando le assegnazioni 
completate eccedenza, discutenti le assegnazioni per essere sicuro che
sono chiare, comunicando con gli insegnanti e più. Una breve 
lista di controllo è inclusa.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">λέει πώς οι γονείς μπορούν να σιγουρευτούν ότι τα 
παιδιά πετυχαίνουν με την εργασία και αναπτύσσουν τις ισχυρές 
δεξιότητες μελέτης. Μεταξύ των θεμάτων: θέτοντας 
έναν κανονικούς χρόνο και τόπο για την εργασία, αφαιρώντας τις 
αποσπάσεις της προσοχής, κοιτάζοντας πέρα από τις ολοκληρωμένες 
αναθέσεις, που συζητούν τις αναθέσεις για να είναι βέβαιος ότι 
είναι σαφείς, μιλώντας με τους δασκάλους, και περισσότερο. 
Ένας συνοπτικός πίνακας ελέγχου συμπεριλαμβάνεται.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">dice cómo los padres pueden cerciorarse de los 
niños tener éxito con la preparación y desarrollar habilidades 
fuertes del estudio. Entre los asuntos: fijando un rato y 
un lugar regulares para la preparación, quitando distracciones, 
mirando las asignaciones terminadas excedente, discutiendo 
asignaciones para ser seguro que están claras, hablando con los 
profesores, y más. Una lista de comprobación abreviada es 
incluida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Arti</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Artes</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770205688</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105723</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/helping-your-child-with-homework</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
