<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104573</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104573</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974017</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Garbage Glut</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Abfall-Sättigung</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Surabondance d'Ordures</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Glut Do Lixo</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sovrabbondanza Dell'Immondizia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πλεόνασμα απορριμάτων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Superabundancia De la Basura</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No one wants garbage. No one wants to think about it. No one wants to pay for it. But it isn't going away. Can you create a garbage plan for New York City? What do you do with your household garbage? How should the city handle it? Can you keep New York from drowning in our own refuse? Play the Garbage Game. Begin by sorting your own waste. What would you throw unsorted into the garbage can, recycle for curbside pickup -- or keep from going into the trash altogether?</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Niemand wünscht Abfall. Niemand möchte an 
es denken. Niemand möchte für es zahlen. Aber es geht 
nicht weg. Können Sie einen Abfalplan für New York City 
erstellen? Was tun Sie mit Ihrem Haushalt Abfall? Wie 
sollte die Stadt ihn handhaben? Können Sie New York vom 
Ertrinken in unserem eigenen Abfall halten? Spielen Sie das 
Abfall-Spiel. Fangen Sie an, indem Sie Ihre eigene Vergeudung 
sortieren. Was würden Sie unsortiertes in die Abfalldose 
werfen, für curbside Aufnahme -- aufbereiten oder halten von in den 
Abfall zusammen einsteigen?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Personne ne veut des ordures. Personne ne 
veut penser cela. Personne ne veut payer lui. Mais il ne 
part pas. Pouvez-vous créer un plan d'ordures pour New York 
City ? Que faites-vous avec vos ordures de ménage ? 
Comment la ville devrait-elle les manipuler ? Pouvez-vous 
garder New York de la noyade en nos propres ordures ? Jouez le 
jeu d'ordures. Commencez en triant votre propre perte. 
Queest-ce que vous jetteriez non trié dans le bidon d'ordures, 
le réutiliseriez pour la collecte de curbside -- ou garderiez de 
l'entrée dans le détritus tout à fait ?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ninguém quer o lixo. Ninguém quer pensar 
sobre ele. Ninguém quer pagar por ele. Mas não está 
partindo. Pode você criar uma planta do lixo para New York 
City? Que você faz com seu lixo da casa? Como deve a 
cidade o segurar? Pode você manter New York de afogar-se em 
nossa própria recusa? Jogue o jogo do lixo. Comece 
classificando seu próprio desperdício. Que você jogaria 
unsorted na lata do lixo, recycle para o coletor do curbside -- ou se 
manteria de entrar no lixo completamente?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nessuno desidera l'immondizia. Nessuno 
desidera pensare a questo proposito. Nessuno desidera pagare 
esso. Ma non sta andando via. Potete creare un programma 
dell'immondizia per New York City? Che cosa fate con la vostra 
immondizia della famiglia? Come dovrebbe la città maneggiarla? 
Potete mantenere New York dalla sommersione in nostri propri 
rifiuti? Gioc il gioco dell'immondizia. Cominci ordinando 
il vostro proprio spreco. Che cosa gettereste non selezionato 
nella latta dell'immondizia, riciclereste per la raccolta di curbside 
-- o manterreste dall'entrare nei rifiuti complessivamente?</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κανένας θέλει τα απορρίματα. Κανένας θέλει να 
σκεφτεί για το. Κανένας θέλει να πληρώσει για το. 
Αλλά δεν πηγαίνει μακριά. Μπορείτε να δημιουργήσετε 
ένα σχέδιο απορριμάτων για την πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης; Τι 
κάνετε με τα οικιακά απορρίματά σας; Πώς θα έπρεπε η πόλη
να τον χειριστεί; Μπορείτε να κρατήσετε τη Νέα Υόρκη από 
το πνίξιμο στα απορρίματά μας; Παίξτε το παιχνίδι 
απορριμάτων. Αρχίστε με την ταξινόμηση των αποβλήτων σας. 
Τι θα ρίχνατε unsorted στα απορρίματα μπορείτε, θα 
ανακυκλώνατε για την επανάλειψη curbside -- ή θα κρατούσατε 
από να πάτε στα απορρίμματα συνολικά;</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Nadie desea la basura. Nadie desea pensar de
él. Nadie desea pagar él. Pero no está saliendo. 
¿Puede usted crear un plan de la basura para New York City? 
¿Qué usted hace con su basura de la casa? ¿Cómo debe la 
ciudad dirigirla? ¿Puede usted guardar Nueva York de ahogarse en
nuestra propia basura? Juegue el juego de la basura. 
Comience clasificando su propia basura. ¿Qué usted 
lanzaría sin clasificar en la lata de la basura, lo reciclaría para 
la recolección del curbside -- o guardaría de entrar la basura en 
conjunto?</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:GAIL ROBINSON, EDITOR-IN-CHIEF
FN:GAIL ROBINSON, EDITOR-IN-CHIEF
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1805974017</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104573</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/garbage-glut</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
