<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/103269</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>103269</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087365</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Aint I A Woman": Reminiscences of Sojourner Truth Speaking</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Aint I Eine Frau": Erinnerungen Sojourner 
Wahrheit des Sprechens</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Aint I Une Femme" : Réminiscences de 
parler de vérité de Sojourner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Aint I Uma Mulher": Reminiscences do 
discurso da verdade de Sojourner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Aint I Una Donna": Reminiscenze di parlare 
di verità di Sojourner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Μεταξύ άλλων Γυναίκα Aint": Reminiscences
της ομιλίας αλήθειας Sojourner</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Aint I Una Mujer": Reminiscencias del 
discurso de la verdad de Sojourner</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Isabelle Van Wagenen was born enslaved in New York State and became a well-known abolitionist speaker under the name Sojourner Truth after gaining her freedom in 1827. She moved to New York City where she engaged in evangelical and other reform activities; at various points she also lived in several utopian communities. Truth supported herself by traveling and speaking on abolitionist and women's rights subjects, taking the name Sojourner Truth in 1843. She often faced opposition at her speaking engagements. Truth made this extemporaneous speech in Akron Ohio in 1851 at a women's rights meeting. No direct record of the speech exists, but Frances Gage, a white activist and author who was presiding over the meeting, recalled it over a decade later. While some historians have questioned Gage's accuracy in reconstructing the syntax and even the exact language of Truth's oration, the power and charismatic force of her argument about the equality of women remains evident.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <coverage>
            <string language="en">North America</string>
          </coverage>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Isabelle Van Wagenen war versklavt im Staat 
New-York geborenes und nach der Gewinnung ihrer Freiheit 1827 wurde 
ein weithin bekannter abolitionist Sprecher unter dem Namen Sojourner 
Wahrheit. Sie zog nach New York City um, in dem sie in 
evangelischem und in anderem Verbesserungaktivitäten sich engagierte;
an den verschiedenen Punkten lebte sie auch in einigen 
utopischen Gemeinschaften. Wahrheit unterstützte sich, indem 
sie über abolitionist und der Frauen die Rechtthemen reiste und 
sprach und die Namenssojourner Wahrheit 1843 nahm. Sie stellte 
häufig Opposition an ihr sprechende Verpflichtungen gegenüber. 
Wahrheit bildete diese extemporaneous Rede in Akron Ohio 1851 an
einem Rechttreffen der Frauen. Kein direkter Satz der Rede 
existiert, aber Frances Lehre, ein weißer Aktivist und Autor, der der
Sitzung vorsaß, später wieder aufgerufen ihm über einer Dekade. 
Während einige Historiker Genauigkeit der Lehre gefragt haben, 
wenn sie die Syntax und sogar die genaue Sprache der Rede der Wahrheit
wieder aufbauten, bleibt die Energie und die charismatische Kraft 
ihres Arguments über die Gleichheit der Frauen offensichtlich.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Isabelle Van Wagenen était né asservi dans 
l'état de New-York et est devenu un orateur bien connu d'abolitionniste 
sous le nom de la vérité de Sojourner après avoir gagné sa 
liberté en 1827. Elle s'est déplacée à New York City où 
elle s'est engagée dans évangélique et autre des activités de 
réforme ; à de divers points elle a également vécu dans 
plusieurs communautés utopiques. La vérité s'est supportée 
en voyageant et en parlant des sujets de droits d'abolitionniste et de 
femmes, prenant la vérité nommée de Sojourner en 1843. Elle a
souvent fait face à l'opposition à elle des engagements parlants. 
La vérité a fait ce discours impromptu à Akron Ohio en 1851 
à se réunir des droits des femmes. Aucun enregistrement direct
du discours n'existe, mais mesure de Frances, un activiste blanc et 
l'auteur qui présidait au-dessus de la réunion, rappelés lui 
au-dessus d'une décennie plus tard. Tandis que quelques 
historiens ont remis en cause l'exactitude de la mesure en 
reconstruisant la syntaxe et même le langage exact du discours 
solennel de la vérité, la puissance et la force charismatique de son
argument au sujet de l'égalité des femmes demeure évidente.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Isabelle Camionete Wagenen era nascido enslaved no
estado de New York e transformava-se um altofalante well-known do 
abolitionist sob a verdade conhecida de Sojourner após ter ganhado 
sua liberdade em 1827. Moveu-se para New York City onde acoplou 
em evangelical e em outro atividades da reforma; em vários 
pontos viveu também em diversas comunidades utópicas. A 
verdade suportou-se viajando e falando nos assuntos das direitas do 
abolitionist e das mulheres, fazendo exame da verdade conhecida de 
Sojourner em 1843. Enfrentou frequentemente a oposição nela 
acoplamentos faladores. A verdade fêz este discurso 
extemporaneous em Akron Ohio em 1851 em um encontro das direitas das 
mulheres. Nenhum registro direto do discurso existe, mas calibre
de Frances, uma activista branca e o autor que presiding sobre a 
reunião, recordados lhe sobre uma década mais tarde. Quando 
alguns historians questionarem a exatidão do calibre em 
reconstructing a sintaxe e mesmo a língua exata do oration da 
verdade, a potência e a força charismatic de seu argumento sobre a 
igualdade das mulheres remanescem evidentes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Isabelle Van Wagenen era nato asservito a New York
Dichiara e diventato un altoparlante ben noto di abolitionist 
sotto il nome della verità di Sojourner dopo avere guadagnato la sua 
libertà in 1827. Si è mossa verso New York City in cui si è 
agganciata in evangelical ed in altro attività di riforma; ai 
vari punti egualmente ha vissuto in parecchie Comunità utopian. 
La verità si è sostenuta viaggiando e parlando sugli oggetti 
di diritti delle donne e di abolitionist, prendenti la verità noma di
Sojourner in 1843. Ha affrontato spesso l'opposizione lei 
impegni parlanti. La verità ha fatto questo discorso 
extemporaneous a Akron Ohio in 1851 a venire a contatto di diritti 
delle donne. Nessun record diretto del discorso esiste, ma 
calibro di Frances, un attivista bianco ed autore che stava 
presiedendo la riunione, ricordati esso sopra una decade più 
successivamente. Mentre alcuni storici hanno messo in 
discussione l'esattezza del calibro nella ricostruzione la sintassi e 
perfino del linguaggio esatto del oration della verità, l'potenza e 
la forza charismatic del suo argomento sull'uguaglianza delle donne 
rimane evidenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η Isabelle Van Wagenen γεννήθηκε που 
υποδουλώθηκε στο κράτος της Νέας Υόρκης και έγινε γνωστός 
ομιλητής ρεφορμιστών με το όνομα η αλήθεια Sojourner μετά από
να κερδίσει την ελευθερία της το 1827. Κινήθηκε προς την 
πόλη της Νέας Υόρκης όπου συμμετείχε στις εβαγγελικές και άλλες
δραστηριότητες μεταρρύθμισης  στα διάφορα σημεία έζησε 
επίσης σε διάφορες ουτοπιστικές κοινότητες. Η αλήθεια 
υποστηρίχθηκε με το ταξίδι και την ομιλία στα θέματα δικαιωμάτων 
ρεφορμιστών και των γυναικών, που παίρνουν την αλήθεια 
Sojourner ονόματος το 1843. Αντιμετώπισε συχνά την 
αντίθεση στις δεσμεύσεις ομιλίας της. Η αλήθεια έκανε 
αυτήν την αυτοσχέδια ομιλία στο Ακρον Οχάιο το 1851 σε μια 
συνάντηση δικαιωμάτων των γυναικών. Κανένα άμεσο αρχείο 
της ομιλίας δεν υπάρχει, αλλά η Frances Gage, ένα λευκοί 
ενεργό στέλεχος και ένας συντάκτης που προήδρευε πέρα από τη 
συνεδρίαση, το υπενθύμισαν κατά τη διάρκεια μιας δεκαετίας 
αργότερα. Ενώ μερικοί ιστορικοί έχουν εξετάσει την 
ακρίβεια του διαμετρήματος στην αναδημιουργία της σύνταξης και 
ακόμη και της ακριβούς γλώσσας του oration της αλήθειας, η 
δύναμη και η χαρισματική δύναμη του ορίσματός της για την 
ισότητα των γυναικών παραμένουν εμφανείς.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Isabelle Van Wagenen era nato esclavizado en el 
estado de Nueva York e hizo un locutor bien conocido del abolitionist 
bajo el nombre de la verdad de Sojourner después de ganar su libertad
en 1827. Ella se trasladó a New York City en donde ella 
enganchó a evangélico y a otro las actividades de la reforma; 
en las varias puntas ella también vivió en varias comunidades 
utópicas. La verdad se apoyó viajando y hablando en los temas 
de las derechas del abolitionist y de las mujeres, tomando la verdad 
conocida de Sojourner en 1843. Ella hizo frente a menudo a la 
oposición en ella los contratos de discurso. La verdad hizo 
este discurso improvisado en Akron Ohio en 1851 en satisfacer de las 
derechas de las mujeres. Ningún expediente directo del discurso
existe, solamente galga de Frances, un activista blanco y el autor que
presidía la reunión, recordados le sobre una década más adelante. 
Mientras que algunos historiadores han preguntado la exactitud 
de la galga en la reconstrucción del sintaxis e incluso del lenguaje 
exacto de la oración de la verdad, la potencia y la fuerza 
carismática de su argumento sobre la igualdad de mujeres sigue siendo
evidentes.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087365</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">License Unknown</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>103269</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/aint-i-a-woman-reminiscences-of-sojourner-truth-speaking</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
