<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108650</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108650</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201367</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Earth Exploration Toolbook Chapter: Looking into Earth with GIS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse Erforschung Toolbook Kapitel: Schauen 
in Masse mit GIS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Chapitre de Toolbook d'Exploration de la Terre : 
Regarder dans la terre avec des GIs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Capítulo De Toolbook Da Exploração Da Terra: 
Olhar na terra com SOLDADOS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Capitolo Di Toolbook Di Esplorazione Della Terra: 
Esaminando la terra con i GIS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κεφάλαιο Toolbook γήινης εξερεύνησης: Να 
εξετάσει τη γη με το GIS</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Capítulo De Toolbook De la Exploración De la 
Tierra: El mirar en la tierra con SOLDADOS ENROLADOS EN EL 
EJÉRCITO</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Step-by-step instructions walk users through working with data from a seismic wave model in a freely available GIS (geographic information system) program, ESRI's ArcVoyager SE. Users generate and examine maps and produce graphs to explore variations in seismic wave velocities at depths of 28 and 100 km below Earth's surface. By examining and analyzing GIS-ready data, users visualize density changes and earthquake distributions near a spreading center and two subduction zones. Finally, users will infer the location (depth) of the upper mantle under ocean basins and under continents from their analyses.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schrittweisee Anweisungen Wegbenutzer durch das 
Arbeiten mit Daten von einem seismischen Welle Modell in einem frei 
vorhandenen Programm der GIS (geographisches Informationssystem), SE 
ArcVoyager ESRIs. Benutzer legen fest und überprüfen Karten 
und produzieren Diagramme, um Schwankungen der seismischen Welle 
Geschwindigkeiten an den Tiefen von 28 und 100 Kilometern unterhalb 
der Oberfläche der Masse zu erforschen. Indem sie 
GIS-betriebsbereite Daten überprüfen und analysieren, machen 
Benutzer Dichteänderungen und Erdbebenverteilungen nahe einer 
ausgebreiteten Mitte und zwei Subductionzonen sichtbar. 
Schließlich schließen Benutzer den Standort (Tiefe) des oberen
Umhangs unter Ozeanbassins und unter Kontinenten von ihren Analysen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Utilisateurs pas à pas de promenade 
d'instructions en travaillant avec des données d'un modèle 
séismique de vague dans un programme librement disponible de 
GIs (système d'information géographique), expert en logiciel
d'ArcVoyager d'ESRI. Les utilisateurs produisent et examinent 
des cartes et produisent des graphiques pour explorer des variations 
des vitesses séismiques de vague aux profondeurs de 28 et 100 
kilomètres au-dessous de la surface de la terre. En examinant 
et en analysant des données de GI-ready, les utilisateurs 
visualisent des changements de densité et des distributions de 
tremblement de terre près d'un centre de propagation et de deux zones
de subduction. En conclusion, les utilisateurs impliqueront 
l'emplacement (profondeur) du manteau supérieur sous des bassins 
d'océan et sous des continents de leurs analyses.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Usuários passo a passo da caminhada das 
instruções com trabalhar com dados de um modelo seismic em um 
programa livremente disponível dos SOLDADOS (sistema de informação 
geográfico), SE da onda de ArcVoyager de ESRI. Os usuários 
geram e examinam mapas e produzem gráficos para explorar variações 
em velocidades seismic da onda em profundidades de 28 e 100 
quilômetros abaixo da superfície da terra. Examinando e 
analisando dados Soldado-prontos, os usuários visualizam mudanças da
densidade e distribuições do terremoto perto de um centro espalhando
e de duas zonas do subduction. Finalmente, os usuários infer a 
posição (profundidade) do mantle superior sob bacias do oceano e sob
continentes de suas análises.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Utenti graduali della camminata di istruzioni con 
il funzionamento con i dati da un modello sismico in un programma 
liberamente disponibile di GIS (sistema d'informazione geografico), 
esperto in informatica dell'onda di ArcVoyager del ESRI. Gli 
utenti generano ed esaminano i programmi e producono i grafici per 
esplorare le variazioni nelle velocità sismiche dell'onda alle 
profondità di 28 e 100 chilometri sotto la superficie della terra. 
Esaminando ed analizzando i dati di GIS-aspettare, gli utenti 
prevedono i cambiamenti di densità e le distribuzioni di terremoto 
vicino ad un centro di diffusione ed a due zone di subduction. 
Per concludere, gli utenti arguiranno la posizione (profondità)
del manto superiore sotto i bacini dell'oceano e sotto i continenti 
dalle loro analisi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βαθμιαίοι χρήστες περιπάτων οδηγιών μέσω της 
εργασίας με τα στοιχεία από ένα σεισμικό μοντέλο κυμάτων σε 
ένα ελεύθερα διαθέσιμο πρόγραμμα GIS (γεωγραφικό σύστημα 
πληροφοριών), SE ArcVoyager ESRI. Οι χρήστες 
παράγουν και εξετάζουν τους χάρτες και παράγουν τις γραφικές 
παραστάσεις για να ερευνήσουν τις παραλλαγές στις σεισμικές 
ταχύτητες κυμάτων στα βάθη 28 και 100 χλμ κάτω από τη 
γήινη επιφάνεια. Με την εξέταση και την ανάλυση 
GIS-ΑΝΑΜΕΊΝΕΤΕ τα στοιχεία, οι χρήστες απεικονίζουν τις 
αλλαγές πυκνότητας και τις διανομές σεισμού κοντά σε διαδίδοντας
κέντρο και δύο subduction ζώνες. Τέλος, οι χρήστες θα 
συμπεράνουν τη θέση (βάθος) του ανώτερου μανδύα κάτω από τις 
ωκεάνιες λεκάνες και κάτω από τις ηπείρους από τις αναλύσεις 
τους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Utilizadores paso a paso de la caminata de las 
instrucciones con el trabajo con datos de un modelo sísmico en un 
programa libremente disponible de los SOLDADOS ENROLADOS EN EL 
EJÉRCITO (sistema de información geográfico), SE de la onda de 
ArcVoyager de ESRI. Los utilizadores generan y examinan 
correspondencias y producen gráficos para explorar variaciones en 
velocidades sísmicas de la onda en las profundidades de 28 y 100 
kilómetros debajo de la superficie de la tierra. Examinando y 
analizando datos Soldado-listos, los utilizadores visualizan cambios 
de la densidad y distribuciones del terremoto cerca de un centro que 
se separa y de dos zonas del subduction. Finalmente, los 
utilizadores deducirán la localización (profundidad) de la capa 
superior bajo los lavabos del océano y bajo continentes de sus 
análisis.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:DAVID SMITH
FN:DAVID SMITH
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770201367</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:OERCommons
FN:OERCommons
ORG:OERCommons
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108650</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/earth-exploration-toolbook-chapter-looking-into-earth-with-gis</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
