<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/106664</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>106664</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211334</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">NOAA Fisheries Shark Web Site</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">NOAA Fischerei-Haifisch-Web site</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Site de Web de Requin de Pêche de NOAA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Web site Do Tubarão Dos Fisheries de NOAA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Web site Dello Squalo Delle Industrie della pesca 
di NOAA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστοχώρος καρχαριών αλιείας NOAA</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sitio Del Web Del Tiburón De las 
Industrias pesqueras de NOAA</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This site, managed by NOAA Fisheries, provides a vast amount of information regarding sharks, their characteristics and behavior. Users can access information on a variety of shark species including white sharks, tiger sharks, blacktip sharks and bull sharks. Also included is information regarding shark management, shark sciences, reducing risks of shark attack and frequently asked shark questions. Users can also link to external information on shark research and science, tagging, attacks, domestic and international management, identification and general education. This site contains a wealth of information and reflects NOAA Fisheries' commitment to conserving shark populations.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Diese Site, gehandhabt durch NOAA Fischereien, 
liefert eine beträchtliche Menge Informationen betreffend sind 
Haifische, ihre Eigenschaften und Verhalten. Benutzer können 
auf Informationen über eine Vielzahl der Haifischsorte 
einschließlich weiße Haifische, Tigerhaifische, blacktip Haifische 
und Stierhaifische zugreifen. Auch worden geschlossen die 
Informationen betreffend sind Haifischmanagement, die 
Haifischwissenschaften ein und verringern Gefahren des 
Haifischangriffs und der häufig gestellten Haifischfragen. 
Benutzer können mit externen Informationen über 
Haifischforschung auch binden und -wissenschaft, Etikettieren, 
Angriffe, inländisches und internationales Management, Kennzeichen 
und allgemeine Ausbildung. Diese Site enthält eine Fülle der 
Informationen und teilt Verpflichtung der NOAA Fischereien an 
konservierende Haifischbevölkerungen mit.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ce site, contrôlé par la pêche de NOAA, fournit
une vaste quantité d'informations concernant des requins, leurs 
caractéristiques et comportement. Les utilisateurs peuvent 
accéder à l'information sur une variété d'espèces de requin 
comprenant les requins blancs, les requins de tigre, les requins de 
blacktip et les requins de taureau. En outre incluse est 
l'information concernant la gestion de requin, les sciences de requin,
réduisant des risques d'attaque de requin et de questions 
fréquemment posées de requin. Les utilisateurs peuvent 
également joindre à l'information externe sur la recherche et la 
science de requin, étiquetage, les attaques, la gestion domestique et
internationale, l'identification et l'éducation générale. Ce 
site contient une richesse d'information et reflète l'engagement de 
la pêche de NOAA aux populations d'économie de requin.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este local, controlado por fisheries de NOAA, 
fornece uma quantidade de informação vasta a respeito dos tubarões,
das suas características e do comportamento. Os usuários podem
alcançar a informação em uma variedade da espécie do tubarão 
including os tubarões brancos, os tubarões do tigre, os tubarões de
blacktip e os tubarões de touro. É incluída também a 
informação a respeito da gerência do tubarão, ciências do 
tubarão, reduzindo riscos do ataque do tubarão e de perguntas 
freqüentemente feitas do tubarão. Os usuários podem também 
ligar à informação externa na pesquisa e a ciência do tubarão, 
etiquetar, os ataques, gerência doméstica e internacional, 
identificação e instrução geral. Este local contem uma 
riqueza da informação e reflete o compromisso dos fisheries' de NOAA
às populações conservando do tubarão.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Questo luogo, gestito dalle industrie della pesca 
del NOAA, fornisce una grande quantità di informazioni per quanto 
riguarda gli squali, le loro caratteristiche ed il comportamento. 
Gli utenti possono accedere alle informazioni su una varietà di
specie dello squalo compreso gli squali bianchi, gli squali della 
tigre, gli squali di blacktip e gli squali di toro. Egualmente 
sono incluse le informazioni per quanto riguarda la gestione dello 
squalo, le scienze dello squalo, riducenti i rischi di attacco dello 
squalo e di domande frequentemente fatte dello squalo. Gli 
utenti possono anche collegarsi alle informazioni esterne su ricerca e
la scienza dello squalo, etichettare, attacchi, gestione nazionale ed 
internazionale, identificazione ed istruzione generale. Questo 
luogo contiene una ricchezza delle informazioni e riflette l'impegno 
delle industrie della pesca di NOAA alle popolazioni di conservazione 
dello squalo.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτή η περιοχή, διοικούμενη από NOAA την αλιεία, 
παρέχει ένα απέραντο ποσό πληροφοριών σχετικά με τους 
καρχαρίες, τα χαρακτηριστικά και τη συμπεριφορά τους. Οι 
χρήστες μπορούν να έχουν πρόσβαση στις πληροφορίες για ποικίλα 
είδη καρχαριών συμπεριλαμβανομένων των άσπρων καρχαριών, των 
καρχαριών τιγρών, blacktip των καρχαριών καρχαριών και ταύρων.
Επίσης περιλαμβάνονται οι πληροφορίες σχετικά με τη 
διαχείριση καρχαριών, επιστήμες καρχαριών, που μειώνουν τους 
κινδύνους της επίθεσης καρχαριών και συχνά ερωτήσεων καρχαριών. 
Οι χρήστες μπορούν επίσης να συνδέσουν με τις εξωτερικές 
πληροφορίες για την έρευνα και την επιστήμη καρχαριών, την 
επικόλληση, τις επιθέσεις, την εσωτερική και διεθνή διαχείριση, 
τον προσδιορισμό και τη γενική εκπαίδευση. Αυτή η περιοχή 
περιέχει έναν πλούτο των πληροφοριών και απεικονίζει τη δέσμευση
της αλιείας NOAA για τη συντήρηση των πληθυσμών καρχαριών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Este sitio, manejado por las industrias pesqueras 
de NOAA, proporciona a una cantidad de información extensa con 
respecto tiburones, sus características y al comportamiento. 
Los utilizadores pueden tener acceso a la información sobre una
variedad de especie del tiburón incluyendo los tiburones blancos, los
tiburones del tigre, los tiburones de blacktip y los tiburones de 
toro. También se incluye la información con respecto a la 
gerencia del tiburón, ciencias del tiburón, reduciendo riesgos del 
ataque del tiburón y de preguntas con frecuencia hechas del tiburón.
Los utilizadores pueden también conectar a la información 
externa sobre la investigación y ciencia del tiburón, el marcar con 
etiqueta, los ataques, gerencia doméstica e internacional, 
identificación y educación general. Este sitio contiene una 
abundancia de la información y refleja la consolidación de las 
industrias pesqueras de NOAA a las poblaciones conservadoras del 
tiburón.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770211334</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>106664</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/noaa-fisheries-shark-web-site</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
