<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/104811</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>104811</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207138</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">History of Medicine Homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Geschichte von Medizin-homepage</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Histoire de homepage de médecine</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">History do homepage da medicina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Storia del homepage della medicina</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ιστορία της αρχικής σελίδας ιατρικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Historia del homepage de la medicina</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features all book-length material in the National Library of Medicine (NLM) printed before 1914, thousands of later pamphlets and dissertations, and all pre-1871 journals. It includes Arabic, Persian, and early western manuscripts, reprints of more than 1,300 important Chinese medical works, prints and photographs, films, and videocassettes. The site also offers information on the Library's services and programs.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet alles Buch-Länge Material in der 
nationalen Bibliothek von Medizin (NLM) gedruckt vor 1914, Tausenden 
der neueren Flugschriften und der Abhandlungen und allen Journalen 
pre-1871. Es enthält die arabischen, persischen und frühen 
westlichen Manuskripte, die Neuauflagen von mehr als 1.300 wichtigen 
chinesischen medizinischen Arbeiten, die Drucke und die Fotographien, 
die Filme und die Videokassetten. Die Site bietet auch 
Informationen über der die Dienstleistungen und die Programme 
Bibliothek an.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte tout le matériel de livre-longueur dans 
la bibliothèque nationale de la médecine (NLM) imprimée avant 1914,
milliers de brochures et de dissertations postérieures, et tous les 
journaux pre-1871. Il inclut les manuscrits occidentaux arabes, 
persans, et tôt, les réimpressions de plus de 1.300 travaux 
médicaux chinois importants, les copies et les photographies, les 
films, et les vidéocassettes. Le site offre également 
l'information aux services et aux programmes de la bibliothèque.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza todo o material do livro-comprimento 
na biblioteca nacional da medicina (NLM) impressa antes de 1914, de 
milhares de uns panfletos e de uns dissertations mais atrasados, e de 
todos os jornais pre-1871. Inclui manuscritos ocidentais 
árabes, persas, e adiantados, reprints de mais de 1.300 trabalhos 
médicos chineses importantes, cópias e fotografias, películas, e 
videocassettes. O local oferece também a informação nos 
serviços e em programas da biblioteca.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza tutto il materiale di libro-lunghezza
nella libreria nazionale della medicina (NLM) stampata prima di 1914, 
delle migliaia degli opuscoli e delle dissertazioni successivi e di 
tutte le pubblicazioni pre-1871. Include i manoscritti 
occidentali arabi, persiani ed in anticipo, le ristampe di più di 
1.300 impianto medico cinese importante, le stampe e le 
fotografie, le pellicole e le video-cassette. Il luogo 
egualmente offre le informazioni sui servizi e sui programmi delle 
biblioteche.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει όλο το υλικό βιβλίο-μήκους στην εθνική 
βιβλιοθήκη της ιατρικής (NLM) που τυπώνεται και πριν από το 
1914, χιλιάδες πιό πρόσφατες τεύχη και διατριβές, και τα προ- 
1871 περιοδικά. Περιλαμβάνει τα αραβικά, περσικά, και 
πρόωρα δυτικά χειρόγραφα, τα ανάτυπα περισσότερων από 1.300 
σημαντικών κινεζικών ιατρικών εργασιών, τις τυπωμένες ύλες και 
τις φωτογραφίες, τις ταινίες, και τις βιντεοκασέτες. Η 
περιοχή προσφέρει επίσης τις πληροφορίες για τις υπηρεσίες της 
βιβλιοθήκης και τα προγράμματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece todo el material de la libro-longitud en la
biblioteca nacional de la medicina (NLM) impresa antes de 1914, de 
millares de folletos y de disertaciones más últimos, y de todos los 
diarios pre-1871. Incluye los manuscritos occidentales árabes, 
persas, y tempranos, las reimpresiones de más de 1.300 trabajos 
médicos chinos importantes, las impresiones y las fotografías, las 
películas, y las cintas video. El sitio también ofrece la 
información sobre los servicios y los programas de la biblioteca.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770207138</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>104811</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/history-of-medicine-homepage</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
