<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/108343</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>108343</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087117</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">"Thus This Poore People Populate This Howling Desart": Edward Johnson Describes the Founding of the Town of Concord in Massachusetts Bay, 1635</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">"Folglich Bevölkern Diese Poore Leute Dieses 
Heulen Desart": Edward Johnson beschreibt die Gründung der 
Stadt der Übereinstimmung in Massachusetts Bucht, 1635</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">"Ces Personnes de Poore Peuplent Ainsi Cet 
Hurlement Desart" : Edouard Johnson décrit la 
fondation de la ville de l'accord dans le compartiment du 
Massachusetts, 1635</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">"Assim Este Pessoa De Poore Povoa Este Howling 
Desart": Edward Johnson descreve fundar da cidade do concord na 
baía de Massachusetts, 1635</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">"Questa Gente Di Poore Popola Così Questo Urlo 
Desart": Edward Johnson descrive fondare della città di accordo
nella baia del Massachusetts, 1635</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">"Έτσι οι άνθρωποι αυτό το Poore εποικούν αυτό το 
ουρλιαχτό Desart": Θ*Εδωαρδ Johnson Describes η 
ίδρυση της πόλης της συμφωνίας στον κόλπο της Μασαχουσέτης, 
1635</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">"Esta Gente De Poore Puebla Así Este Grito 
Desart": Edward Johnson describe la fundación de la ciudad de 
la concordia en la bahía de Massachusetts, 1635</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">After their arrival, the Puritan migrants to Massachusetts Bay quickly dispersed into a series of settlements around Boston and then moved inland. Colonists formed clustered towns where they could secure land for their families and churches for their worship. One such community was Concord, Massachusetts, founded by Simon Willard, a fur trader with the local Indians. In his history of New England, entitled  The Wonder-Working Providence , woodworker and local historian Edward Johnson recorded an account "of the manner how they placed downe their dwellings in this Desart Wildernesse." Johnson emphasized the providential (God-given) nature of the Puritan mission, one that saw the eastern woodlands, a region that the English and Indians shared in the first decades of settlement, as a wilderness.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Nach ihrer Ankunft bellen die puritanischen 
Wanderer zu Massachusetts schnell zerstreut in eine Reihe Regelungen 
um Boston und dann verschobenes inländisches. Kolonisten 
bildeten gebündelte Städte, in denen sie Land für ihre Familien und
Kirchen für ihre Anbetung sichern konnten. Eine solche 
Gemeinschaft war Übereinstimmung, Massachusetts, gegründet von Simon
Willard, ein Pelzhändler mit den lokalen Indern. In seiner 
Geschichte von Neu-England, erlaubt die Wundern-Arbeitende Vorsehung, 
das woodworker und den lokalen Historiker Edward Johnson speicherte 
ein Konto "der Weise, wie sie legten downe ihre Wohnungen in dieses 
Desart Wildernesse." Johnson hob die providential 
(Gott-vorgegebene) Natur der puritanischen Mission, eine, die das 
östliche Waldland sah, eine Region, die Englisch und die Inder in den
ersten Dekaden der Regelung teilten, als Wildnis hervor.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Après leur arrivée, les migrants puritains vers 
le Massachusetts aboient rapidement dispersé dans une série de 
règlements autour de Boston et d'intérieur alors déplacé. 
Les colons ont formé les villes groupées où ils pourraient 
fixer la terre pour leurs familles et les églises pour leur culte. 
Une telle communauté était l'accord, le Massachusetts, fondé 
par Simon Willard, un commerçant de fourrure avec les Indiens locaux.
Dans son histoire de la Nouvelle Angleterre, autorisée la 
providence Demander-Travaillante, le travailleur du bois et l'historien local 
Edouard Johnson a enregistré un compte "de la façon comment
ils ont placé le downe leurs logements dans ce Desart Wildernesse." 
Johnson a souligné la nature (Dieu-donnée) providentielle de
la mission puritaine, une qui a vu les régfions boisées orientales, 
une région que l'anglais et les Indiens ont partagée dans les 
premières décennies du règlement, comme désert.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Após sua chegada, os emigrantes puritan a 
Massachusetts latem dispersado rapidamente em uma série dos 
estabelecimentos em torno de Boston e de inland então movido. 
Os colonos deram forma às cidades aglomeradas onde poderiam 
fixar a terra para suas famílias e as igrejas para sua adoração. 
Uma tal comunidade era o concord, Massachusetts, fundado por 
Simon Willard, um comerciante da pele com os indians locais. Em 
seu history de Nova Inglaterra, intitulado o providence Quer 
saber-Trabalhando, o woodworker e o historian local Edward Johnson 
gravou um cliente "da maneira como colocaram o downe suas moradias 
neste Desart Wildernesse." Johnson emfatizou a natureza 
(Deus-dada) providential da missão puritan, uma que viu as florestas 
orientais, uma região de que o inglês e os indians compartilhassem 
nas primeiras décadas do estabelecimento, como uma região selvagem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Dopo il loro arrivo, i migranti puritan a 
Massachusetts abbaiano a disperso rapidamente in una serie di 
stabilimenti intorno a Boston e ad interno allora spostato. I 
colonizzatori hanno formato le città ragruppate in cui potrebbero 
fissare la terra per le loro famiglie e le chiese per il loro culto. 
Una tale Comunità era accordo, Massachusetts, fondato da Simon 
Willard, un commerciante della pelliccia con gli indiani locali. 
Nella sua storia della Nuova Inghilterra, intitolata il 
providence diFunzionamento, il woodworker e lo storico locale Edward 
Johnson ha registrato un cliente "del modo come hanno disposto il 
downe le loro dimore in questo Desart Wildernesse." Johnson ha 
dato risalto (alla Dio-data) natura providential della missione 
puritan, una che ha visto i terreni boscosi orientali, una regione che
l'inglese e gli indiani hanno ripartito nelle prime decadi dello 
stabilimento, come selva.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μετά από την άφιξή τους, οι πουριτανοί μετανάστες 
στον κόλπο της Μασαχουσέτης διασκόρπισαν γρήγορα σε μια σειρά 
τακτοποιήσεων γύρω από τη Βοστώνη και κίνησαν έπειτα εσωτερικό.
Οι άποικοι που διαμορφώθηκαν συγκεντρώθηκαν τις πόλεις όπου
μπόρεσαν να εξασφαλίσουν το έδαφος για τις οικογένειές τους και 
τις εκκλησίες για τη λατρεία τους. Μια τέτοια κοινότητα 
ήταν συμφωνία, Μασαχουσέτη, που ιδρύθηκε από simon Willard,
ένας έμπορος γουνών με τους τοπικούς Ινδούς. Στην ιστορία 
Νέας Αγγλίας του, που τιτλοφορήθηκε την πρόνοια 
κατάπληξη-εργασίας, woodworker και τοπικός ιστορικός Edward 
Johnson κατέγραψε έναν απολογισμό "του τρόπου πώς τοποθέτησαν
downe τις κατοικίες τους σε αυτό το Desart Wildernesse." 
Το Johnson υπογράμμισε τη θεόσταλτη (Θεός-) φύση της 
πουριτανής αποστολής, μια που εβλέίδε τις ανατολικές 
δασώδεις περιοχές, μια περιοχή που οι Αγγλοι και οι Ινδοί 
μοιράστηκαν στις πρώτες δεκαετίες τακτοποίησης, ως αγριότητα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Después de su llegada, los nómadas puritan a 
Massachusetts ladran dispersado rápidamente en una serie de 
establecimientos alrededor de Boston y de interior entonces movida. 
Los colonos formaron las ciudades arracimadas en donde podrían 
asegurar la pista para sus familias y las iglesias para su adoración.
Una tal comunidad era la concordia, Massachusetts, fundado por 
Simon Willard, comerciante de la piel con los indios locales. En
su historia de Nueva Inglaterra, dada derecho el providence de 
Preguntar-Trabajo, el woodworker y el historiador local Edward Johnson
registró una cuenta "de la manera cómo pusieron el downe sus 
viviendas en este Desart Wildernesse." Johnson acentuó la 
naturaleza (Dios-dada) providential de la misión puritan, una que vio
los arbolados del este, una región que el inglés y los indios 
compartieron en las primeras décadas del establecimiento, como yermo.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Menschlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sciences humaines</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Humanities</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Studi umanistici</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ανθρωπότητες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Humanidad</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
FN:CENTER FOR HISTORY AND NEW MEDIA/AMERICAN SOCIAL HISTORY PROJECT
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1765087117</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">No License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>108343</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/libraries/thus-this-poore-people-populate-this-howling-desart-edward-johnson-describes-the-founding-of-the-town-of-concord-in-massachusetts-bay-1635</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
