<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105067</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105067</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206848</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Water In Africa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wasser In Afrika</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Eau En Afrique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Água Em África</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Acqua In Africa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ύδωρ στην Αφρική</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Agua En África</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">is designed to help students learn important knowledge and skills in geography, language arts, and other disciplines by studying the use of water in 24 African countries. This website features online lessons developed by teachers and built around 600 photos and 300 anecdotes from Peace Corps volunteers in Africa. Photos and anecdotes may also be browsed by country, with basic country information and maps provided.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">wird konzipiert, Kursteilnehmern zu helfen, 
wichtiges Wissen und Fähigkeiten in der Geographie, in den 
Sprachenkünsten und in anderen Disziplinen zu erlernen, indem man den
Gebrauch des Wassers in 24 afrikanischen Ländern studiert. 
Diese Web site kennzeichnet die Onlinelektionen, die von den 
Lehrern entwickelt werden und aufgebaut herum 600 Fotos und 300 
Anekdoten von den Friedenskorpsen erbietet sich in Afrika freiwillig. 
Fotos und Anekdoten können durch Land auch durchgestöbert 
werden, wenn grundlegenden Landinformationen und die Karten 
bereitgestellt sind.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">est conçu pour aider des étudiants à apprendre 
la connaissance et des qualifications importantes dans la géographie,
les arts de langage, et d'autres disciplines en étudiant 
l'utilisation de l'eau dans 24 pays africains. Ce site Web 
comporte des leçons en ligne développées par des professeurs et 
construit autour 600 photos et 300 anecdotes des corps de paix offre 
en Afrique. Des photos et les anecdotes peuvent également être
parcourues par pays, avec l'information de base de pays et des cartes 
fournies.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">é projetado ajudar a estudantes aprender o 
conhecimento e habilidades importantes na geografia, nas artes da 
língua, e nas outras disciplinas estudando o uso da água em 24 
países africanos. Este Web site caracteriza as lições em 
linha desenvolvidas por professores e construído ao redor 600 fotos e
300 anecdotes dos corpos de paz oferece-se em África. As fotos 
e os anecdotes podem também browsed pelo país, com informação 
básica do país e mapas fornecidos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">è destinato a aiutare gli allievi ad imparare la 
conoscenza e le abilità importanti nella geografia, nelle arti di 
linguaggio ed in altre discipline studiando l'uso di acqua in 24 paesi
africani. Questo Web site caratterizza le lezioni in linea 
sviluppate dagli insegnanti e costruito intorno 600 foto e 300 
anecdotes dal Corpo di pace si offre volontariamente in Africa. 
Le foto ed i anecdotes possono anche essere passati in rassegna 
per pæse, con le informazioni di base del paese ed i programmi 
forniti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σχεδιάζεται για να βοηθήσει τους σπουδαστές να μάθουν 
τη σημαντικές γνώση και τις δεξιότητες στη γεωγραφία, τις 
γλωσσικές τέχνες, και άλλες επιστήμες με τη μελέτη της χρήσης 
του ύδατος σε 24 της Αφρικής χώρες. Αυτός ο ιστοχώρος 
χαρακτηρίζει τα σε απευθείας σύνδεση μαθήματα που αναπτύσσονται 
από τους δασκάλους και χτισμένος περίπου 600 φωτογραφίες και 
300 ανέκδοτα από την ειρήνη προσφέρεται εθελοντικά Σώμα 
στην Αφρική. Οι φωτογραφίες και τα ανέκδοτα μπορούν επίσης 
να περιοδευθούν από τη χώρα, με τις βασικές πληροφορίες χωρών 
και τους χάρτες παρεχόμενους.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">es diseñado ayudar a estudiantes a aprender 
conocimiento y habilidades importantes en la geografía, artes del 
lenguaje, y otras disciplinas estudiando el uso del agua en 24 países
africanos. Este Web site ofrece las lecciones en línea 
desarrolladas por los profesores y construido alrededor 600 fotos y 
300 anecdotes de cuerpos de paz se ofrece voluntariamente en África. 
Las fotos y los anecdotes se pueden también hojear por el 
país, con la información básica del país y correspondencias 
proporcionadas.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206848</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105067</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/water-in-africa</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
