<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/105872</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>105872</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206846</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Price of Freedom: Americans at War</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Preis der Freiheit: Amerikaner am Krieg</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le prix de la liberté : Américains à la 
guerre</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O preço da liberdade: Americanos na guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il prezzo di libertà: Americani alla 
guerra</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η τιμή της ελευθερίας: Αμερικανοί στον πόλεμο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El precio de la libertad: Americanos en la 
guerra</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">features a timeline of America's wars, from the Revolution to Iraq. Watch an interactive presentation on each war -- slideshows and movies, text and photos, and dozens of artifacts (firearms, flags, uniforms). Read an overview of each conflict; learn about its causes, major events, and consequences. Gain a sense of how wars have shaped our history.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Social Sciences</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">kennzeichnet ein timeline von Kriegen Amerikas, 
von der Umdrehung nach den Irak. Überwachen Sie eine 
interaktive Darstellung auf jedem Krieg -- Slideshows und Filme, Text 
und Fotos und Dutzende Kunstprodukte (Feuerwaffen, Markierungsfahnen, 
Uniformen). Lesen Sie einen Überblick über jede 
$überschneidung; erlernen Sie über seine Ursachen, Hauptfälle
und Konsequenzen. Gewinnen Sie eine Richtung von, wie Kriege 
unsere Geschichte geformt haben.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">comporte une chronologie des guerres de 
l'Amérique, de la révolution en Irak. Observez une 
présentation interactive sur chaque guerre -- des présentations et 
des films, texte et des photos, et des douzaines d'objets façonnés 
(armes à feu, indicateurs, uniformes). Lisez une vue d'ensemble
de chaque conflit ; renseignez-vous sur ses causes, événements
principaux, et conséquences. Gagnez un sens de la façon dont 
les guerres ont formé notre histoire.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">caracteriza um timeline de guerras de América, da
volta a Iraq. Preste atenção a uma apresentação interativa 
em cada guerra -- slideshows e filmes, texto e fotos, e dúzias dos 
artifacts (firearms, bandeiras, uniformes). Leia uma vista geral
de cada conflito; aprenda sobre seus causas, eventos principais,
e conseqüências. Ganhe um sentido de como as guerras deram 
forma a nosso history.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">caratterizza un timeline delle guerre 
dell'America, dalla rivoluzione ad Irak. Guardi una 
presentazione interattiva su ogni guerra -- slideshows e film, 
testo e foto e dozzine dei manufatti (firearms, bandierine, 
uniformi). Legga una descrizione di ogni conflitto; 
impari circa le relativi cause, eventi importanti e conseguenze.
Guadagni un senso di come le guerre hanno modellato la nostra 
storia.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">χαρακτηρίζει μια υπόδειξη ως προς το χρόνο των πολέμων
της Αμερικής, από την επανάσταση στο Ιράκ. Προσέξτε μια 
διαλογική παρουσίαση για κάθε πόλεμο -- slideshows και τους 
κινηματογράφους, το κείμενο και τις φωτογραφίες, και τις δωδεκάδες
των χειροποίητων αντικειμένων (πυροβόλα, σημαίες, στολές). 
Διαβάστε μια επισκόπηση κάθε σύγκρουσης  μάθετε για 
τις αιτίες, τα σημαντικά γεγονότα, και τις συνέπειές του. 
Κερδίστε μια αίσθηση για το πώς οι πόλεμοι έχουν 
διαμορφώσει την ιστορία μας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ofrece un timeline de las guerras de América, de 
la revolución a Iraq. Mire una presentación interactiva en 
cada guerra -- los slideshows y las películas, texto y las fotos, y 
las docenas de artefactos (armas de fuego, indicadores, uniformes). 
Lea una descripción de cada conflicto; aprenda sobre sus 
causas, acontecimientos importantes, y consecuencias. Gane un 
sentido de cómo las guerras han formado nuestra historia.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sozialwissenschaften</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Les Sciences Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciências Sociais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienze Sociali</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κοινωνικές επιστήμες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencias Sociales</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770206846</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>105872</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-price-of-freedom-americans-at-war</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
