<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/102931</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>102931</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212582</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The Goldilocks Zone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Goldilocks Zone</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Zone de Goldilocks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A Zona De Goldilocks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">La Zona Di Goldilocks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ζώνη Goldilocks</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La Zona De Goldilocks</string>
          </title>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is an article from "Teachable Moments in the News," a newsletter that takes recent Earth and space science related news stories and places them in a context relevant to the science curriculum. This particular edition describes the Goldilocks Zone, a range of environmental conditions that can support life. Teachers are provided a brief introduction, relevant news links, and developed lesson plans. Some lessons are in PDF format. Activity themes include: exploration of environmental conditions necessary to sustain life, physical and behavioral adaptations of organisms, and identification of resources on Earth that are essential for life to thrive.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Science and Technology</string>
          </keyword>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist ein Artikel "von den lehrbaren Momenten
in den Nachrichten," ein Rundschreiben, das neue Masse und des Platzes
Wissenschaft in Verbindung gestandene Nachrichten Geschichten nimmt 
und sie in einen Kontext legt, der zum Wissenschaft Lehrplan relevant 
ist. Diese bestimmte Ausgabe beschreibt die Goldilocks Zone, 
eine Strecke der Klimabedingungen, die das Leben unterstützen 
können. Lehrern werden einer kurzen Einleitung, relevanten 
Nachrichten Links und entwickelte Lektionpläne zur Verfügung 
gestellt. Einige Lektionen sind im pdf Format. Aktivität 
Themen schließen ein: Erforschung der Klimabedingungen 
notwendig, das Leben, körperliche und Verhaltensanpassungen der 
organismen zu unterstützen und Kennzeichen der Betriebsmittel auf 
Masse, die wesentlich sind, damit das Leben vorwärtskommt.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est un article "des moments enseignables dans 
les nouvelles," un bulletin qui prend des histoires récentes de 
nouvelles associées par science de la terre et de l'espace et les 
place dans un contexte concernant le programme d'études de la 
science. Cette édition particulière décrit la zone de 
Goldilocks, un intervalle des conditions environnementales qui peuvent
supporter la vie. Des professeurs sont fournis une brève 
introduction, des liens appropriés de nouvelles, et des plans 
développés de leçon. Quelques leçons sont dans le format de 
pdf. Les thèmes d'activité incluent : exploration des 
conditions environnementales nécessaires pour soutenir la vie, 
adaptations physiques et comportementales des organizations, et 
identification des ressources sur terre il est essentielle pour que la
vie prospère que.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este é um artigo "dos momentos teachable na 
notícia," um boletim de notícias que faça exame de histórias 
relacionadas ciência recentes da notícia da terra e do espaço e as 
coloque em um contexto relevante ao curriculum da ciência. Esta
edição particular descreve a zona de Goldilocks, uma escala das 
circunstâncias ambientais que podem suportar a vida. Os 
professores são fornecidos uma introdução breve, umas ligações 
relevantes da notícia, e umas plantas desenvolvidas da lição. 
Algumas lições estão no formato do pdf. Os temas da 
atividade incluem: exploração das circunstâncias ambientais 
necessárias sustentar a vida, adaptações físicas e behavioral dos 
organismos, e identificação dos recursos na terra que são 
essenciais para que a vida prospere.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è un articolo "dai momenti insegnabili nelle
notizie," un bollettino che prende le storia recenti di notizie 
riferite la scienza dello spazio e della terra e le dispone in un 
contesto relativo al programma di studi di scienza. Questa 
edizione particolare descrive la zona di Goldilocks, una gamma di 
condizioni ambientali che possono sostenere la vita. Gli 
insegnanti sono forniti una breve introduzione, i collegamenti 
relativi di notizie ed i programmi sviluppati di lezione. Alcune
lezioni sono nel formato del pdf. I temi di attività includono:
esplorazione delle condizioni ambientali necessarie per 
sostenere durata, adattamenti fisici e del comportamento degli 
organismi ed identificazione delle risorse su terra che sono 
essenziali affinchè la vita prosperino.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι ένα άρθρο από τις "teachable στιγμές 
στις ειδήσεις," ένα ενημερωτικό δελτίο που παίρνει την πρόσφατη 
γη και τις διαστημικές σχετικές με την επιστήμη ιστορίες ειδήσεων
και τις τοποθετεί σε ένα πλαίσιο σχετικό με το πρόγραμμα σπουδών
επιστήμης. Αυτή η ιδιαίτερη έκδοση περιγράφει τη 
Goldilocks ζώνη, μια σειρά των περιβαλλοντικών συνθηκών που 
μπορούν να υποστηρίξουν τη ζωή. Οι δάσκαλοι παρέχονται μια 
συνοπτική εισαγωγή, σχετικές συνδέσεις ειδήσεων, και αναπτυγμένα
σχέδια μαθήματος. Μερικά μαθήματα είναι με τη μορφή 
PDF. Τα θέματα δραστηριότητας περιλαμβάνουν: 
εξερεύνηση των περιβαλλοντικών συνθηκών απαραίτητων να 
στηρίξουν τις φυσικών και συμπεριφοριστικών προσαρμογές ζωής, των
οργανισμών, και προσδιορισμός των στοιχείων συμπεριφοράς στη γη 
που είναι ουσιαστικά για τη ζωή να αναπτυχτεί.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Esto es un artículo a partir de "momentos 
enseñables en las noticias," un boletín de noticias que tome 
historias relacionadas ciencia recientes de las noticias de la tierra 
y del espacio y las ponga en un contexto relevante al plan de estudios
de la ciencia. Esta edición determinada describe la zona de 
Goldilocks, un rango de las condiciones ambientales que pueden 
utilizar vida. Proporcionan los profesores una introducción 
abreviada, conexiones relevantes de las noticias, y planes 
desarrollados de la lección. Algunas lecciones están en 
formato del pdf. Los temas de la actividad incluyen: 
exploración de las condiciones ambientales necesarias para 
sostener vida, adaptaciones físicas y del comportamiento de 
organismos, e identificación de los recursos en la tierra que son 
esenciales para que prospere la vida.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wissenschaft und Technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science et technologie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza e tecnologia</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Επιστήμη και τεχνολογία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia y tecnología</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:TEACHABLE MOMENTS IN THE NEWS
FN:TEACHABLE MOMENTS IN THE NEWS
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
N:CHALLENGER CENTER FOR SPACE SCIENCE EDUCATION, WWW.CHALLENGER.ORG
FN:CHALLENGER CENTER FOR SPACE SCIENCE EDUCATION, WWW.CHALLENGER.ORG
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oercommons.org</catalog>
            <entry>1770212582</entry>
          </identifier>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <language>en</language>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Custom License</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>102931</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oercommons.org/courses/the-goldilocks-zone-1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
