<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/29947</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>29947</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>Navet</catalog>
    <entry>skolverket_6157</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_6157</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>Navet</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_6157</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">4.104 Architecture Studio: Intentions, Spring 2005 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">4.104 Architektur-Studio: Absichten, 
Frühling 2005 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">4.104 Studio d'Architecture : 
Intentions, Le Printemps 2005 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">4.104 Estúdio Da Arquitetura: 
Intenções, Mola 2005 (Mit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">4.104 Studio Di Architettura: 
Intenzioni, Primavera 2005 (Mit)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">4.104 Στούντιο αρχιτεκτονικής: Προθέσεις, άνοιξη
του 2005 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">4.104 Estudio De la Configuración: 
Intenciones, Resorte 2005 (Mit)</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An online course from the MIT OpenCourseWare website (http://ocw.mit.edu) operated by Massachusetts Institute of Technology. This course material is free for anyone to use who accept the terms and conditions of use. The description of this course, published on the MIT OpenCourseWare website, is: "Second undergraduate design studio. Introduces a full range of architectural ideas and issues through drawing exercises, analysis of precedents, and explored design methods. Skills developed in conceptualizing, articulating, and representing architectural ideas and making aesthetic judgments about building design. Discussions regarding architecture s role in mediating culture, nature, and technology help develop architectural vocabulary. Special emphasis on both oral and written communication skills is intended to help students effectively convey design concepts. Open to sophomores, juniors, and seniors only. Required of Course IV majors."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">rendering</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">structure</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">tectonics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">light</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">artist habitation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">perspective</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">drawing</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">public</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">material</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">space</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Architecture (BArch  BA/BS  MArch  MA/MS  PhD)</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">MIT</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">intention creation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">private</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">visual arts</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">sketching</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Architecture</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">design</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">architecture</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">dynamism</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">introduction</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Onlinekurs von der MIT OpenCourseWare Web 
site (http://ocw.mit.edu) funktionierte durch Massachusetts Institute 
of Technology. Dieses Kursmaterial ist frei, damit jedermann 
verwendet, wem die Bedingungen des Gebrauches annehmen. Die 
Beschreibung dieses Kurses, veröffentlicht auf der MIT OpenCourseWare
Web site, ist: "zweites Nichtgraduiertdesignstudio. Stellt
eine volle Strecke der architektonischen Ideen und der Ausgaben durch 
zeichnende Übungen, Analyse von Präzedenzfällen und erforschte 
Designmethoden vor. Fähigkeiten entwickelten sich beim 
Auffassen und artikulierten, und architektonische Ideen darstellend 
und ästhetische Urteile über Gebäude bildend, konzipieren Sie. 
Die Diskussionen betreffend sind Rolle der Architektur s in der 
Vermittelnkultur, in der Natur und in der Technologiehilfe entwickeln 
architektonischen Wortschatz. Besondere Betonung auf den Mund- 
und schriftlichen Kommunikation Fähigkeiten soll Kursteilnehmern 
effektiv, helfen Konzepte des Entwurfes zu übermitteln. Öffnen
Sie sich nur zu den College-Studenten im 2. Jahr, zu den Jüngeren und zu den 
seniors. Benötigte selbstverständlich IV Majoren."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un cours en ligne du site Web de MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) actionné par 
massachusetts.institute.of.technology. Ce matériel de cours est
libre pour que n'importe qui utilise qui reçoivent les modalités et 
les conditions de l'utilisation. La description de ce cours, 
éditée sur le site Web de MIT OpenCourseWare, est : "deuxième
studio de conception d'étudiant préparant une licence. 
Présente une gamme complète des idées et des issues 
architecturales par des exercices de dessin, l'analyse des 
précédents, et les méthodes de conception explorées. Les 
qualifications développées en conceptualisant, en articulant, et en 
représentant des idées architecturales et en faisant des jugements 
esthétiques au sujet du bâtiment conçoivent. Les discussions 
concernant le rôle de l'architecture s dans la culture de médiation,
la nature, et l'aide de technologie développent le vocabulaire 
architectural. La considération particulière sur des 
qualifications orales et écrites de transmission est destinée pour 
aider des étudiants pertinemment à donner des concepts de 
construction. Ouvrez-vous aux étudiants en deuxième année, 
aux juniors, et aux seniors seulement. Naturellement commandants
priés d'IV."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um curso em linha do Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) operou-se por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material do curso está livre
para que qualquer um use-se quem aceitam os termos e as condições do
uso. A descrição deste curso, publicada no Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare, é: "segundo estúdio do projeto do 
undergraduate. Introduz uma escala cheia de idéias e de 
edições architectural com os exercícios desenhando, a análise dos 
precedents, e métodos de projeto explorados. As habilidades 
tornaram-se em conceptualizing, articulando, e representando idéias 
architectural e fazendo julgamentos aesthetic sobre o edifício 
projete. As discussões a respeito do papel da arquitetura s na 
cultura mediar, na natureza, e na ajuda da tecnologia desenvolvem o 
vocabulário architectural. A ênfase especial  em habilidades 
orais e escritas de uma comunicação é pretendida ajudar eficazmente
a estudantes fazer saber a conceitos de projeto. Abra aos 
estudantes de segundo ano de universidade, aos juniors, e aos seniors 
somente. Naturalmente majores requeridos do IV."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un corso in linea dal Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) ha funzionato da Massachusetts 
Institute of Technology. Questo materiale di corso è libero 
affinchè chiunque usi chi accettano i termini e le condizioni di uso.
La descrizione di questo corso, pubblicata sul Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare, è: "secondo studio di disegno dello studente 
non laureato. Introduce una gamma completa di idee e di edizioni
architettoniche con le esercitazioni dissipanti, l'analisi dei 
precedenti ed i metodi di progettazione esplorati. Le abilità 
si sono sviluppate nel concettualizzare, articolando e rappresentando 
le idee architettoniche e facendo i giudizi estetici circa costruzione
progetti. Le discussioni per quanto riguarda il ruolo di 
architettura s nella coltura di mediazione, nella natura e nell'aiuto 
di tecnologia sviluppano il vocabolario architettonico. 
L'importanza particolare sia sulle abilità orali che scritte di
comunicazione è intesa per aiutare efficacemente gli allievi a 
trasportare i concetti di progetto. Aprasi ai sophomores, ai 
junior ed ai seniors soltanto. Naturalmente maggiori richiesti 
del dispositivo di venipunzione."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρά μαθημάτων από τον 
ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) που 
χρησιμοποιείται από το ίδρυμα της Μασαχουσέτης τεχνολογίας. 
Αυτό το υλικό σειράς μαθημάτων είναι ελεύθερο για καθένα 
να χρησιμοποιήσει ποιοι αποδέχονται τους όρους και τους όρους 
χρησιμοποίησης. Η περιγραφή αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων, που
δημοσιεύεται στον ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare, είναι: 
"Δεύτερο στούντιο προπτυχιακού σχεδίου. Εισάγει μια 
πλήρη σειρά των αρχιτεκτονικών ιδεών και των ζητημάτων μέσω των 
ασκήσεων σχεδίων, ανάλυση των προηγουμένων, και των εξερευνημένων
μεθόδων σχεδίου. Οι δεξιότητες αναπτύχθηκαν να αντιληφθούν,
την άρθρωση, και την αντιπροσώπευση των αρχιτεκτονικών ιδεών και 
την κρίση αισθητικών την οικοδόμηση του σχεδίου. Οι 
συζητήσεις σχετικά με το ρόλο αρχιτεκτονικής s στη μεσολάβηση 
του πολιτισμού, της φύσης, και των οδηγιών τεχνολογίας 
αναπτύσσουν το αρχιτεκτονικό λεξιλόγιο. Ιδιαίτερη έμφαση 
και σε προφορικές και γραπτές δεξιότητες επικοινωνίας προορίζεται
να βοηθήσει τους σπουδαστές να μεταβιβάσουν αποτελεσματικά τις 
έννοιες σχεδίου. Ανοίξτε στους δευτεροετείς φοιτητές, τους 
νεώτερους, και τους πρεσβυτέρους μόνο. Απαιτημένος φυσικά 
IV ταγματάρχες."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un curso en línea del Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) funcionado por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material del curso está 
libre para que cualquier persona utilice quiénes validan los 
términos y las condiciones del uso. La descripción de este 
curso, publicada en el Web site del MIT OpenCourseWare, es: 
"segundo estudio del diseño del estudiante. Introduce una
gama completa de ideas y de ediciones arquitectónicas con ejercicios 
que trazan, el análisis de precedentes, y métodos de diseño 
explorados. Las habilidades desarrolladas en el 
conceptualización, la articulación, y la representación de ideas 
arquitectónicas y la fabricación de juicios estéticos sobre el 
edificio diseñan. Las discusiones con respecto a papel de la 
configuración s en cultura el mediar, naturaleza, y ayuda de la 
tecnología desarrollan vocabulario arquitectónico. El énfasis
especial en habilidades orales y escritas de la comunicación se 
piensa para ayudar a estudiantes con eficacia a transportar conceptos 
de diseño. Ábrase en los estudiantes de segundo año, los 
jóvenes, y los seniors solamente. Por supuesto comandantes 
requeridos del intravenoso."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Übertragung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Struktur</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tectonics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Licht</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Künstlerbehausung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Perspektive</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Zeichnung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Öffentlichkeit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Material</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Platz</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Architektur (BArch BA/BS März MA/MS PhD)</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">MIT</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Absicht Kreation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">privat</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sichtkünste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Skizzieren</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Architektur</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Design</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Architektur</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dynamismus</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Einleitung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">rendu</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">structure</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">tectonique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">lumière</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">habitation d'artiste</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">perspective</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">schéma</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">public</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">matériel</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'espace</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Architecture (BArch BA/BS Mars MA/MS PhD)</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">MIT</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">création d'intention</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">privé</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">arts visuels</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">esquisse</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Architecture</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">conception</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">architecture</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">dynamisme</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">introduction</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">render</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">estrutura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">tectonics</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">luz</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">habitation do artista</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">perspective</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">desenho</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">público</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">material</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">espaço</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Arquitetura (BArch BA/BS Março MA/MS PhD)</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Mit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">criação da intenção</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">confidencial</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">artes visuais</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">esboçar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Arquitetura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">projeto</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">arquitetura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">dinamismo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">introdução</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">rappresentazione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">struttura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">tettonica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">luce</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">habitation dell'artista</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">prospettiva</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">illustrazione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">pubblico</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">materiale</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">spazio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Architettura (BArch BA/BS Marzo MA/MS PhD)</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Mit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">creazione di intenzione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">riservato</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">arti visive</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">abbozzare</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Architettura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">disegno</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">architettura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">dinamismo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">introduzione</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">απόδοση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">δομή</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">τεκτονική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">φως</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">κατοικία καλλιτεχνών</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προοπτική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σχέδιο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">δημόσιος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">υλικό</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">διάστημα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχιτεκτονική (BA BArch/*BS MArch μΑ/κράτη μέλη 
PHD)</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">MIT</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">δημιουργία πρόθεσης</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ιδιωτικός</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εικαστηκές τέχνες</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σκιαγράφηση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αρχιτεκτονική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σχέδιο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αρχιτεκτονική</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">δυναμισμός</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">εισαγωγή</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">representación</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">estructura</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">tectónica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">luz</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">habitation del artista</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">perspectiva</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">gráfico</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">público</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">material</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">espacio</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Configuración (BArch BA/BS Marcha MA/MS PhD)</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">creación de la intención</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">privado</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">artes visuales</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el bosquejar</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Configuración</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">diseño</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">configuración</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">dinamismo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">introducción</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>85</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">architecture</string>
                <string language="sv">arkitektur</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_6157-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>Navet</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_6157-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-03-15T19:42:45.0Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
N:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
ORG:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T06:20:19.47Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>Navet</catalog>
      <entry>skolverket_6157</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://ocw.mit.edu/OcwWeb/Architecture/4-104Spring-2005/CourseHome/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
