<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/219039</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>219039</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>oai</catalog>
    <entry>oai:s01.klascement.net:18862</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lom.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:s01.klascement.net:18862</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>KC</catalog>
            <entry>18862</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="nl">TV link : Videoclips</string>
          </title>
          <language>nl</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Engelstalige videoclips m.b.t.: milieu, transport, energie, water, werkgelegenheid, sociale zaken, consumenten, gezondheid, EU in de wereld, archieven
TVLINK Europe: a video on-line distribution platform for TV professionals
The TVLINK Europe is a video on-line distribution platform designed to meet the needs of audiovisual journalists by helping them to provide better coverage of European issues.
The site enables journalists to illustrate European subjects through the distribution of video reports that can be obtained directly on-line. These video reports are also accompanied by a full description of the images used in each film, transcripts of the commentary and interviews.
The TVLink Europe site enables journalists to view (via video streaming) the various video features on offer. If the subject is of interest, TVLINK can facilitate an easy and efficient transfer of broadcast quality and webcast digital video files directly to newsrooms and journalists in the field.
Journalists can also request a copy in professional format (Betacam SP or DVCam). The videos are available to journalists and TV channels free of charge and copyrights. The TVLINK website is managed by Mostra, an agency based in Brussels and specialised in audio-visual production.
 </string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">EU in de wereld</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">gezondheid</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">consumenten</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">sociale zaken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">werkgelegenheid</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">water</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">energie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">transport</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">milieu</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">archieven</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">video</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Europa</string>
          </keyword>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <aggregationLevel>
            <source>aggregationLevelValues</source>
            <value>4</value>
          </aggregationLevel>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Engelstalige videoclips m.b.t.: Umgebung, Transport, energie,
Wasser, werkgelegenheid, sociale zaken, consumenten, gezondheid, EU in
de Wereld, archievenTVLINK Europa: eine video Onlineverteilung 
Plattform für Fernsehapparat professionalsThe TVLINK Europa ist eine 
video Onlineverteilung Plattform, die konzipiert ist, um die 
Bedürfnisse der audio-visuellen Journalisten zu erfüllen, indem sie 
ihnen hilft, bessere Dichte der europäischen issues.The Sites zur 
Verfügung zu stellen, aktiviert Journalisten, europäische Themen 
durch die Verteilung der videoreports zu veranschaulichen, die direkt 
online erhalten werden können. Diese videoreports werden auch von 
einer vollen Beschreibung der Bilder begleitet, die in jedem Film, 
Abschriften des Kommentars verwendet werden und interviews.The TVLink 
Europa Site aktiviert Journalisten, (über den strömenden Bildschirm)
die verschiedenen videomerkmale auf Angebot anzusehen. Wenn das Thema 
vom Interesse ist, kann TVLINK ein einfaches erleichtern und 
leistungsfähige Übertragung Sendung der Qualitäts- und webcast 
digitalen videodateien direkt auf Nachrichtenredaktionen und 
Journalisten im field.Journalists kann um ein Exemplar im 
professionellen Format auch bitten (Betacam SP oder DVCam). Die videos
sind für Journalisten und Gernsehkanäle kostenlos und copyright 
vorhanden. Die TVLINK Web site wird von Mostra, eine Agentur 
gehandhabt, die in Brüssel gegründet wird und auf audio-visuelle 
Produktion spezialisiert ist.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Videoclips m.b.t. d'Engelstalige : le milieu, transport, 
energie, l'eau, werkgelegenheid, sociale zaken, consumenten, le 
gezondheid, EU en de wereld, archievenTVLINK l'Europe : une plateforme
en ligne visuelle de distribution pour le professionalsThe TVLINK 
l'Europe de TV est une plateforme en ligne visuelle de distribution 
conçue pour satisfaire les besoins des journalistes audiovisuels en 
les aidant à fournir une meilleure assurance de site européen 
d'issues.The permet à des journalistes d'illustrer les sujets 
européens par la distribution des états visuels qui peuvent être 
obtenus directement en ligne. Ces états visuels sont également 
accompagnés d'une description complète des images utilisées en 
chaque film, transcriptions du commentaire et le site d'interviews.The
TVLink l'Europe permet à des journalistes de visualiser (par 
l'intermédiaire du vidéo coulant) les divers dispositifs visuels en 
vente. Si le sujet est d'intérêt, TVLINK peut faciliter un facile et
le transfert efficace des fichiers visuels digitaux de qualité et de 
webcast d'émission directement aux salles de presse et aux 
journalistes dans le field.Journalists peut également demander une 
copie dans le format professionnel (SP de Betacam ou DVCam). Les 
videos sont à la disposition des journalistes et des canaux de TV 
gratuitement et copyright. Le site Web de TVLINK est contrôlé par 
Mostra, une agence basée à Bruxelles et spécialisée dans la 
production audiovisuelle.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Videoclips m.b.t. de Engelstalige: o milieu, transporte, 
energie, água, werkgelegenheid, sociale zaken, consumenten, o 
gezondheid, EU em de wereld, archievenTVLINK Europa: uma plataforma em
linha video da distribuição para o professionalsThe TVLINK Europa da
tevê é uma plataforma em linha video da distribuição projetada 
encontrar-se com as necessidades de journalists audiovisual ajudando 
os fornecer a cobertura melhor do local europeu de issues.The permite 
journalists de ilustrar assuntos europeus com a distribuição dos 
relatórios video que podem ser obtidos diretamente em linha. Estes 
relatórios video são acompanhados também por uma descrição cheia 
das imagens usadas em cada película, transcripts do commentary e o 
local de interviews.The TVLink Europa permite journalists de ver 
(através do vídeo que flui) as várias características video na 
oferta. Se o assunto for do interesse, TVLINK pode facilitar um fácil
e transferência eficiente de limas video digitais da qualidade e do 
webcast da transmissão diretamente aos newsrooms e aos journalists no
field.Journalists pode também pedir uma cópia no formato 
profissional (SP de Betacam ou DVCam). Os videos estão disponíveis 
aos journalists e às canaletas de tevê livre da carga e do 
copyright. O Web site de TVLINK é controlado por Mostra, uma agência
baseada em Bruxelas e especializada na produção audio-visual.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Videoclips m.b.t. di Engelstalige: l'ambiente, trasporto, 
energie, acqua, werkgelegenheid, sociale zaken, consumenten, 
gezondheid, UE in de wereld, archievenTVLINK Europa: una video
piattaforma in linea di distribuzione per il professionalsThe TVLINK 
Europa della TV è una video piattaforma in linea di distribuzione 
destinata per soddisfare le esigenze dei giornalisti audiovisivi 
aiutandoli a fornire il riempimento migliore del luogo europeo di 
issues.The permette ai giornalisti di illustrare gli oggetti europei 
con la distribuzione di video rapporti che possono essere ottenuti 
direttamente in linea. Questi video rapporti egualmente sono 
accompagnati da una descrizione completa delle immagini usate in ogni 
pellicola, le trascrizioni del commento ed il luogo di interviews.The 
TVLink Europa permette ai giornalisti di osservare (via il video che 
effluisce) le varie video caratteristiche in vendita. Se l'oggetto è 
di interesse, TVLINK può facilitare un facile ed il trasferimento 
efficiente archivi digitali di qualità e del webcast di 
radiodiffusione di video direttamente nelle redazioni e nei 
giornalisti nel field.Journalists può anche chiedere una copia nel 
formato professionale (SP di Betacam o DVCam). I videos sono a 
disposizione di i giornalisti e scanalature di TV gratis e copyright. 
Il Web site di TVLINK è gestito da Mostra, un'agenzia basata a 
Bruxelles e specializzata nella produzione audiovisiva.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Engelstalige videoclips m.b.t.: το περιβάλλον, μεταφορά, 
energie, ύδωρ, werkgelegenheid, sociale, gezondheid, ΕΕ 
σε de ωερελδ, archievenTVLINK Ευρώπη: μια τηλεοπτική σε 
απευθείας σύνδεση πλατφόρμα διανομής για την TV 
professionalsThe TVLINK Ευρώπη είναι μια τηλεοπτική σε 
απευθείας σύνδεση πλατφόρμα διανομής με σκοπό να ικανοποιήσει 
τις ανάγκες των οπτικοακουστικών δημοσιογράφων με τη βοήθεια τους 
για να παρασχεθεί η καλύτερη κάλυψη των ευρωπαϊκών ζητημάτων Η 
περιοχή επιτρέπει στους δημοσιογράφους για να επεξηγήσει τους 
ευρωπαϊκούς υπηκόους μέσω της διανομής των τηλεοπτικών εκθέσεων
που μπορούν να ληφθούν άμεσα on-line. Αυτές οι τηλεοπτικές 
εκθέσεις συνοδεύονται επίσης από μια πλήρη περιγραφή των 
εικόνων που χρησιμοποιούνται σε κάθε ταινία, τα αντίγραφα των 
σχολίων και τις συνεντεύξεις Η περιοχή TVLink Ευρώπη επιτρέπει
στους δημοσιογράφους για να εμφανίσει (μέσω του βίντεο που ρέει) 
τα διάφορα τηλεοπτικά χαρακτηριστικά γνωρίσματα στην προσφορά. 
Εάν το θέμα είναι ενδιαφέρον ενδιαφέρον, TVLINK μπορεί να 
διευκολύνει μια εύκολη και αποδοτική μεταφορά της ποιότητας 
ραδιοφωνικής μετάδοσης και webcast τα ψηφιακά τηλεοπτικά 
αρχεία άμεσα στις αίθουσες τύπου και τους δημοσιογράφους στους 
δημοσιογράφους πεδίων μπορούν επίσης να ζητήσουν ένα αντίγραφο 
με την επαγγελματική μορφή (Betacam SP ή DVCam). Τα 
βίντεο είναι διαθέσιμα στους δημοσιογράφους και τα τηλεοπτικά 
κανάλια δωρεάν και τα πνευματικά δικαιώματα. Ο ιστοχώρος 
TVLINK ρυθμίζεται από Mostra, μια αντιπροσωπεία που εδρεύει 
στις Βρυξέλλες και που ειδικεύεται στην οπτικοακουστική παραγωγή.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Videoclips m.b.t. de Engelstalige: el entorno, transporte, 
energie, agua, werkgelegenheid, sociale zaken, consumenten, el 
gezondheid, EU en de wereld, archievenTVLINK Europa: una plataforma en
línea video de la distribución para el professionalsThe TVLINK 
Europa de la TV es una plataforma en línea video de la distribución 
diseñada para resolver las necesidades de periodistas audio-visuales 
ayudándoles a proporcionar a una cobertura mejor del sitio europeo de
issues.The permite a periodistas ilustrar temas europeos con la 
distribución de los informes video que se pueden obtener directamente
en línea. Estos informes video también son acompañados por una 
descripción completa de las imágenes usadas en cada película, 
transcripciones del comentario y el sitio de interviews.The TVLink 
Europa permite a periodistas visión (vía el vídeo que fluye) las 
varias características video en oferta. Si el tema está de interés,
TVLINK puede facilitar un fácil y la transferencia eficiente de los 
ficheros video digitales de la calidad y del webcast de la difusión 
directamente a las redacciones y a los periodistas en el 
field.Journalists puede también solicitar una copia en formato 
profesional (SP de Betacam o DVCam). Los videos están disponibles 
para los periodistas y los canales de TV gratuitamente y copyright. El
Web site de TVLINK es manejado por Mostra, una agencia basada en 
Bruselas y especializada en la producción audio-visual.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">EU in de Wereld</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">gezondheid</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">consumenten</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">sociale zaken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">werkgelegenheid</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Wasser</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">energie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Transport</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Umgebung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">archieven</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bildschirm</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Europa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">EU en de wereld</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">gezondheid</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">consumenten</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">le sociale zaken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">werkgelegenheid</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'eau</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">energie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">transport</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">milieu</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">archieven</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">vidéo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Europa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">EU em de wereld</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">gezondheid</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">consumenten</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">o sociale zaken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">werkgelegenheid</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">água</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">energie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">transporte</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">milieu</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">archieven</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">vídeo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Europa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">UE in de wereld</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">gezondheid</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">consumenten</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">il sociale zaken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">werkgelegenheid</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">acqua</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">energie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">trasporto</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">ambiente</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">archieven</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">video</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Europa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ΕΕ σε de ωερελδ</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">gezondheid</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el"></string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">sociale</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">werkgelegenheid</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">ύδωρ</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">energie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">μεταφορά</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιβάλλον</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el"></string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">βίντεο</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ευρώπη</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">EU en de wereld</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">gezondheid</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">consumenten</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">el sociale zaken</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">werkgelegenheid</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">agua</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">energie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">transporte</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">entorno</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">archieven</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">vídeo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Europa</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <status>
            <source>statusValues</source>
            <value>final</value>
          </status>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-03-10T23:31:46.00Z</dateTime>
            </date>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD 
VERSION:3.0 
N:KlasCement
FN:KlasCement 
EMAIL;TYPE=INTERNET:info@klascement.net 
ORG: KlasCement
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:s01.klascement.net:18862</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>KC</catalog>
            <entry>18862</entry>
          </identifier>
          <metadataSchema>MELTv1.0</metadataSchema>
          <language>nl</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Klascement
N:Klascement
ORG:Klascement
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-03-11T03:06:45.97Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>web page</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">14-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="nl">no description</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1291</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>oai</catalog>
      <entry>18862</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.klascement.net/18862/?ref=aspect</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
