<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/25944</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>25944</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
    <entry>skolverket_8008</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_8008</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_8008</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">17.951 Reading Seminar in Social Science: The Geopolitics and Geoeconomics of Global Energy, Spring 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">17.951 Leseseminar in der 
Sozialwissenschaft: Die Geopolitik und das Geoeconomics der 
globalen Energie, Frühling 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">17.951 Conférence de lecture en la Science
sociale : La géopolitique et le Geoeconomics de l'énergie 
globale, le printemps 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">17.951 Seminário da leitura na ciência 
social: O geopolitics e o Geoeconomics da energia global, mola 
2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">17.951 Seminario della lettura nella 
scienza sociale: Il geopolitics ed il Geoeconomics di energia 
globale, primavera 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">17.951 Ανάγνωση του σεμιναρίου στις κοινωνικές 
επιστήμες: Η γεωπολιτική και το Geoeconomics της σφαιρικής
ενέργειας, άνοιξη του 2007 (MIT)</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">17.951 Seminario de la lectura en ciencia 
social: El geopolitics y el Geoeconomics de la energía global, 
resorte 2007 (MIT)</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">An online course from the MIT OpenCourseWare website (http://ocw.mit.edu) operated by Massachusetts Institute of Technology. This course material is free for anyone to use who accept the terms and conditions of use. The description of this course, published on the MIT OpenCourseWare website, is: "This course focuses on strategic and political implications of ongoing trends in global energy markets, particularly markets for crude oil and natural gas. The course examines the world s major oil and natural gas producing regions: the Middle East, the Caspian Region, Russia, Venezuela, and the North Sea. Producer-consumer relationships are considered for China, India, Japan, and the United States. United States foreign policy implications, especially with respect to China, are discussed."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="en">Political Science</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein Onlinekurs von der MIT OpenCourseWare Web 
site (http://ocw.mit.edu) funktionierte durch Massachusetts Institute 
of Technology. Dieses Kursmaterial ist frei, damit jedermann 
verwendet, wem die Bedingungen des Gebrauches annehmen. Die 
Beschreibung dieses Kurses, veröffentlicht auf der MIT OpenCourseWare
Web site, ist: "dieser Kurs konzentriert auf die strategischen 
und politischen Implikationen der fortwährenden Tendenzen in den 
globalen Energiemärkten, die besonders Märkte für Rohöl und 
Erdgas. Der Kurs überprüft das Hauptöl der Welt s und das 
Erdgas, Regionen produzierend: der Mittlere Osten, die kaspische
Region, Rußland, Venezuela und die Nordsee Produzent-Verbraucher 
Verhältnisse werden für China, Indien, Japan und die Vereinigten 
Staaten betrachtet. Vereinigte Staaten Implikationen der fremden
Politik, besonders in Bezug auf China, werden behandelt."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un cours en ligne du site Web de MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) actionné par 
massachusetts.institute.of.technology. Ce matériel de cours est
libre pour que n'importe qui utilise qui reçoivent les modalités et 
les conditions de l'utilisation. La description de ce cours, 
éditée sur le site Web de MIT OpenCourseWare, est : "ce cours 
se concentre sur des implications stratégiques et politiques des 
tendances continues sur les marchés globaux de l'énergie, en 
particulier des marchés pour le pétrole brut et le gaz naturel. 
Le cours examine le pétrole principal du monde s et le gaz 
naturel produisant des régions : le Moyen-Orient, la région 
caspienne, la Russie, le Venezuela, et les rapports du nord de 
Producteur-consommateur de mer sont considérés pour la Chine, 
l'Inde, le Japon, et les Etats-Unis. Des implications de 
politique étrangère des Etats-Unis, particulièrement en ce qui 
concerne la Chine, sont discutées."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um curso em linha do Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) operou-se por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material do curso está livre
para que qualquer um use-se quem aceitam os termos e as condições do
uso. A descrição deste curso, publicada no Web site do MIT 
OpenCourseWare, é: "este curso focaliza em implicações 
estratégicas e políticas de tendências ongoing em mercados de 
energia globais, particularmente em mercados para o óleo cru e no 
gás natural. O curso examina o óleo principal do mundo s e o 
gás natural produzindo regiões: o Oriente Médio, a região 
caspian, Rússia, Venezuela, e os relacionamentos do 
Produtor-consumidor do mar norte são considerados para China, India, 
Japão, e os estados unidos. As implicações unidas da 
política extrangeira dos estados, especial com respeito a China, são
discutidas."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Un corso in linea dal Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) ha funzionato da Massachusetts 
Institute of Technology. Questo materiale di corso è libero 
affinchè chiunque usi chi accettano i termini e le condizioni di uso.
La descrizione di questo corso, pubblicata sul Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare, è: "questo corso mette a fuoco sulle 
implicazioni strategiche e politiche delle tendenze continue nei 
mercati dell'energia globali, specialmente sui mercati per petrolio 
greggio e sul gas naturale. Il corso esamina il petrolio 
principale del mondo s ed il gas naturale producendo le regioni: 
Medio Oriente, la regione caspica, la Russia, il Venezuela ed i 
rapporti del Produttore-consumatore del Mare del Nord sono considerati
per la Cina, India, Giappone ed unito Dichiara. Unito 
Dichiara le implicazioni di politica straniera, particolarmente
riguardo alla Cina, sono discussi."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Μια σε απευθείας σύνδεση σειρά μαθημάτων από τον 
ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) που 
χρησιμοποιείται από το ίδρυμα της Μασαχουσέτης τεχνολογίας. 
Αυτό το υλικό σειράς μαθημάτων είναι ελεύθερο για καθένα 
να χρησιμοποιήσει ποιοι αποδέχονται τους όρους και τους όρους 
χρησιμοποίησης. Η περιγραφή αυτής της σειράς μαθημάτων, που
δημοσιεύεται στον ιστοχώρο MIT OpenCourseWare, είναι: 
"Αυτή η σειρά μαθημάτων εστιάζει στις στρατηγικές και 
πολιτικές επιπτώσεις των τρεχουσών τάσεων στις παγκόσμιες αγορές
ενέργειας, ιδιαίτερα αγορές για το ακατέργαστο πετρέλαιο και 
φυσικός αέριο. Η σειρά μαθημάτων εξετάζει το παγκόσμιο
s σημαντικό πετρέλαιο και τις φυσικές αέριο παράγοντας 
περιοχές: η Μέση Ανατολή, η τισσα Κασπίας περιοχή, Ρωσία, 
Βενεζουέλα, και η Βόρεια Θάλασσα. Οι σχέσεις παραγωγών 
καταναλωτών εξετάζω για την Κίνα, την Ινδία, την Ιαπωνία, και τις
Ηνωμένες Πολιτείες. Οι επιπτώσεις Ηνωμένης εξωτερικής 
πολιτικής, ειδικά όσον αφορά την Κίνα, συζητούνται."</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un curso en línea del Web site del MIT 
OpenCourseWare (http://ocw.mit.edu) funcionado por Instituto de 
Tecnología de Massachusetts. Este material del curso está 
libre para que cualquier persona utilice quiénes validan los 
términos y las condiciones del uso. La descripción de este 
curso, publicada en el Web site del MIT OpenCourseWare, es: 
"este curso se centra en implicaciones estratégicas y 
políticas de tendencias en curso en mercados de la energía globales,
determinado los mercados para el petróleo crudo y el gas natural. 
El curso examina el aceite principal del mundo s y el gas 
natural produciendo regiones: el Oriente Medio, la región 
caspia, Rusia, Venezuela, y los lazos del Productor-consumidor de Mar 
del Norte se consideran para China, la India, Japón, y los Estados 
Unidos. Las implicaciones de la política no nativa de Estados 
Unidos, especialmente con respecto a China, se discuten."</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Politische Wissenschaft</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La Science Politique</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Ciência Política</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Scienza Politica</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Πολιτική επιστήμη</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ciencia Política</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>higher education</value>
          </context>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">18-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/</string>
            <string language="en">Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>998</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">political sciences</string>
                <string language="sv">-</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:spindeln.iml.umu.se:skolverket_8008-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
            <entry>skolverket_8008-M</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Taawo;Alma
FN:Alma Taawo
ORG:skolverket
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2009-03-15T19:57:31.0Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
N:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
ORG:Myndigheten för skolutveckling
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T06:31:54.65Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>IML-NOT</catalog>
      <entry>skolverket_8008</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://ocw.mit.edu/OcwWeb/Political-Science/17-906Spring-2007/CourseHome/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
