<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/223032</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>223032</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/lukiluukas</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/lukiluukas</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/lukiluukas</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Luki-Luukas</string>
            <string language="fi">Luki-Luukas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Luki-Luukas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Luki-Luukas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Luki-Luukas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Luki-Luukas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λuκη- Luukas</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Luki-Luukas</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Luki-Luukas is an interactive exercise website targeted at learners suffering from particular difficulties with reading and writing. The focus in the planning of the tasks has been on multichannel learning. Many of the tasks include a listening option in addition to the texts. The exercises work in Internet Explorer 6, Firefox 1, Mozilla/Netscape 7 and Opera 7 or newer versions. JavaScript must not be turned off. Audio files can only be listened to if the computer has audio properties and a player software that supports mp3 files (for example Windows Media Player). Free Adobe Reader software is required for opening the PDF file (work book).</string>
            <string language="fi">Luki-Luukas on peruskouluikäsille, lukemisen ja kirjoittamisen erityisvaikeuksista kärsiville oppijoille suunnattu interaktiivinen harjoitussivusto. Tehtävien suunnittelussa on kiinnitetty huomiota monikanavaiseen oppimiseen. Tekstien ohella monissa tehtävissä on kuuntelumahdollisuus.

Kahdeksan www-tehtäväsarjan lisäksi Luki-Luukkaaseen kuuluu kaksi tulostettavaa työkirjaa. Materiaalia saa tulostaa ja monistaa maksutta opetuskäyttöön.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Luki-Luukas ist eine interaktive Übung Web site,
die an den Anfängern gezielt wird, die unter bestimmten 
Schwierigkeiten mit Messwert und Schreiben leiden. Der Fokus in 
der Planung der Aufgaben ist auf dem Mehrkanallernen gewesen. 
Viele der Aufgaben schließen eine hörende Option zusätzlich 
zu den Texten ein. Die Übungen arbeiten in Internet Explorer 6,
Firefox 1, Mozilla/Netscape 7 und Oper 7 oder neuere Versionen. 
Javascript darf nicht abgestellt werden. Audiodateien 
können nur gehört werden, wenn der Computer Audioeigenschaften und 
eine Spielersoftware hat, die Dateien mp3 unterstützt (zum Beispiel 
Windows Media-Spieler). Freie Ziegelstein-Lesersoftware wird 
für das Öffnen der pdf Datei benoetigt (Übungsteil).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Luki-Luukas est un site Web interactif d'exercice
visé aux étudiants souffrant des difficultés particulières avec la
lecture et l'écriture. Le foyer dans la planification du 
charge a été sur l'étude multicanale. Beaucoup de 
charge incluent une option d'écoute en plus des textes. 
Les exercices fonctionnent dans l'Internet Explorer 6, le 
Firefox 1, le Mozilla/Netscape 7 et l'opéra 7 ou les plus nouvelles 
versions. Le Javascript ne doit pas être arrêté. Des 
fichiers sonores peuvent seulement être écoutés si l'ordinateur a 
des propriétés sonores et un logiciel de joueur qui supporte les 
fichiers mp3 (par exemple joueur de medias de Windows). Le 
logiciel libre de lecteur d'adobe est exigé pour ouvrir le fichier de
pdf (livre de travail).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Luki-Luukas é um Web site interativo do 
exercício alvejado nos learners que sofrem das dificuldades 
particulares com leitura e escrita. O foco no planeamento das 
tarefas estêve na aprendizagem multichannel. Muitas das tarefas
incluem uma opção escutando além aos textos. Os exercícios 
trabalham no Internet Explorer 6, o Firefox 1, o Mozilla/Netscape 7 e 
a ópera 7 ou umas versões mais novas. O Javascript não deve 
ser desligado. As limas audio podem somente ser escutadas se o 
computador tiver propriedades audio e um software do jogador que 
suporte as limas mp3 (para o jogador de media de Windows do exemplo). 
O software livre do leitor do adôbe é requerido abrindo a lima
do pdf (livro de trabalho).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Luki-Luukas è un Web site interattivo di 
esercitazione designato ai principianti che soffrono dalle difficoltà
particolari con lettura e scrittura. Il fuoco nella 
progettazione delle mansioni è stato sull'imparare multicanale. 
Molte delle mansioni includono un'opzione ascoltante oltre che i
testi. Le esercitazioni funzionano nel Internet Explorer 6, 
Firefox 1, Mozilla/Netscape 7 ed opera 7 o più nuove versioni. 
Il Javascript non deve essere spento. Gli archivi audio 
possono essere ascoltati soltanto se il calcolatore ha le proprietà 
audio e un software del giocatore che sostiene mp3 gli archivi (per 
esempio lettore multimediale di Windows). Il software libero del
lettore dell'adobe è richiesto per l'apertura dell'archivio del pdf 
(libro di lavoro).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Λuκη- Luukas είναι ένας διαλογικός ιστοχώρος 
άσκησης που στοχεύει στους αρχαρίους που πάσχουν από τις 
ιδιαίτερες δυσκολίες με την ανάγνωση και το γράψιμο. Η 
εστίαση στον προγραμματισμό των στοιχειωδών εργασιών ήταν στην 
πολυδιαυλική εκμάθηση. Πολλές από τις στοιχειώδεις 
εργασίες περιλαμβάνουν μια προαιρετική δυνατότητα ακούσματος 
εκτός από τα κείμενα. Οι ασκήσεις λειτουργούν στον 
εξερευνητή 6 Διαδικτύου, Firefox 1, Mozilla/$l*Netscape 7 και 
την όπερα 7 ή τις νεώτερες εκδόσεις. Τα JavaScript δεν 
πρέπει να κλειθούν. Τα ηχητικά αρχεία μπορούν μόνο να 
ακουστούν εάν ο υπολογιστής έχει τις ηχητικές ιδιότητες και ένα
λογισμικό φορέων που υποστηρίζει mp3 τα αρχεία (παραδείγματος 
χάριν παίκτης MEDIA Windows). Το ελεύθερο λογισμικό 
αναγνωστών πλίθας απαιτείται για το άνοιγμα του αρχείου PDF 
(βιβλίο εργασίας).</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Luki-Luukas es un Web site interactivo del 
ejercicio apuntado en los principiantes que sufren de dificultades 
determinadas con la lectura y la escritura. El foco en las hojas
de operación (planning) de las tareas ha estado en aprender de varios
canales. Muchas de las tareas incluyen una opción que escucha 
además de los textos. Los ejercicios trabajan en el Internet 
Explorer 6, Firefox 1, Mozilla/Netscape 7 y la ópera 7 o más nuevas 
versiones. El Javascript no se debe dar vuelta apagado. 
Los ficheros audio pueden ser escuchados solamente si el 
ordenador tiene características audio y un software del jugador que 
utilice los ficheros mp3 (por ejemplo jugador de media de Windows). 
El software libre del programa de lectura del adobe se requiere 
para abrir el fichero del pdf (libro de trabajo).</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Mirja Halonen
n:Halonen;Mirja
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Jouni Paakkinen
n:Paakkinen;Jouni
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Raija Suomi
n:Suomi;Raija
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Heikki Aro
n:Aro;Heikki
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/0F6BB7D4-97B0-311A-5BA8-4F459EA003C9</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/0F6BB7D4-97B0-311A-5BA8-4F459EA003C9</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Terhikki Rimmanen
n:Rimmanen;Terhikki 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-03-20T01:03:00.81Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>audio</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>special education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">7-16</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä-Epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1024</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1018</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>365</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1410</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1016</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1071</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>845</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1227</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/lukiluukas</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/lukiluukas</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
