<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222738</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222738</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/kursseja/englanti1</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/kursseja/englanti1</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/kursseja/englanti1</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Myself and others</string>
            <string language="fi">Minä ja muut</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Selbst und andere</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Moi-même et d'autres</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Eu mesmo e outro</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Io stesso ed altri</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο ίδιος και άλλοι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Mismo y otros</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The primary objective of the course is to boost the comprehension skills of heard and spoken English, so that students are able to cope with everyday conversations and situations of obtaining information. Particular attention is paid on pronunciation. The pronunciation practice focuses on learning the sounds, stress on words and phrases, and a natural speech rhythm. Understanding of the spoken word is practised by concentrating on extracting details from relatively easy contexts and finding the key points in more demanding ones. Comprehension of written text is practised mostly using open-ended questions. There are also vocabulary exercises linked to the texts. The vocabulary of the texts may be checked out immediately from the attached glossaries.</string>
            <string language="fi">Kurssin tavoitteena on ensisijaisesti kuullun- ja puheenymmärtämistaitojen vankentaminen siten, että suoriudutaan arkielämän keskustelu- ja tiedonhankintatilanteista. Erityistä huomiota kiinnitetään ääntämiseen. Ääntämisharjoittelussa korostetaan äänteiden, sana- ja lausepainon sekä luontevan puherytmin oppimista. Kuullun ymmärtämistä harjoitellaan keskittymällä yksityiskohtien poimimiseen helpohkoissa asiayhteyksissä ja ydinkohtien löytämiseen vaativimmissa. Tekstin ymmärtämistä harjoitellaan lähinnä avokysymysten avulla. Teksteihin liittyy myös sanastotehtäviä. Tekstien sanaston voi tarkistaa välittömästi niihin liittyvistä sanastoista.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">Opetushallitus</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Primärlernziel des Kurses ist, die 
Erfassenfähigkeiten gehörten und gesprochenen Englisch aufzuladen, 
damit Kursteilnehmer können, mit täglichen Gesprächen und 
Situationen des Einholens von von Informationen fertig zu werden. 
Bestimmte Aufmerksamkeit ist auf Aussprache zahlend. Die 
Aussprachepraxis konzentriert auf das Lernen der Töne, des Druckes 
auf Wörtern und der Phrasen, und ein natürliches Rederhythmus 
Verständnis des gesprochenen Wortes wird geübt, indem man auf das 
Extrahieren der Details von den verhältnismäßig einfachen Kontexten
und das Finden der Schlüsselpunkte in mehr fordernden sich 
konzentriert. Erfassen des schriftlichen Textes wird meistens 
mit offenen Fragen geübt. Es gibt auch die Wortschatzübungen, 
die mit den Texten gebunden werden. Der Wortschatz der Texte 
kann sofort von den angebrachten Glossaren heraus überprüft werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le premier objectif du cours est d'amplifier les 
qualifications de compréhension de l'anglais entendu et parlé, de 
sorte que les étudiants puissent faire face aux conversations et aux 
situations journalières d'obtenir l'information. Une attention 
particulière est payée sur la prononciation. La pratique en 
matière de prononciation se concentre sur apprendre les bruits, 
l'effort sur des mots et les expressions, et un Arrangement normal de 
rythme de la parole du mot parlé est pratiqué par la concentration 
sur extraire des détails à partir des contextes relativement faciles
et trouver les points clés dans plus de ceux exigeants. La 
compréhension du texte écrit est pratiquée la plupart du temps en 
utilisant des questions ouvertes. Il y a également des 
exercices de vocabulaire joints aux textes. Le vocabulaire des 
textes peut être vérifié immédiatement des glossaires joints.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objetivo preliminar do curso é impulsionar as 
habilidades da compreensão do inglês ouvido e falado, de modo que os
estudantes possam  lidar com as conversações e as situações 
diárias de obter a informação. A atenção particular é paga
na pronunciação. A prática da pronunciação focaliza em 
aprender os sons, o stress em palavras e as frases, e uma compreensão
natural do ritmo do discurso da palavra falada é praticada 
concentrando em extrair detalhes dos contextos relativamente fáceis e
em encontrar os pontos chaves em mais exijindo. A compreensão 
do texto escrito é praticada na maior parte usando perguntas 
open-ended. Há também uns exercícios do vocabulário ligados 
aos textos. O vocabulário dos textos pode ser verificado para 
fora imediatamente dos glossários unidos.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'obiettivo primario del corso è amplificare le 
abilità di comprensione dell'inglese sentito e parlato, di modo che 
gli allievi possono fare fronte alle conversazioni ed alle situazioni 
giornalieri di ottenere le informazioni. Particolare attenzione 
è paid sulla pronuncia. La pratica di pronuncia mette a fuoco 
sull'imparare i suoni, lo sforzo sulle parole e le frasi e una 
comprensione naturale di ritmo di discorso della parola si esercita in
concentrandosi sull'estrazione dei particolari dai contesti 
relativamente facili e sull'individuazione dei punti chiave in più 
esigenti. La comprensione di testo scritto si esercita in 
principalmente usando le domande espandibili. Ci sono egualmente
esercitazioni di vocabolario collegate ai testi. Il vocabolario 
dei testi può essere verificato immediatamente dai glossari fissati.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο αρχικός στόχος της σειράς μαθημάτων είναι να 
ωθηθούν οι δεξιότητες κατανόησης των ακουσμένων και προφορικών 
αγγλικών, έτσι ώστε οι σπουδαστές είναι σε θέση να 
αντιμετωπίσουν τις καθημερινές συνομιλίες και τις καταστάσεις της 
λήψης των πληροφοριών. Η ιδιαίτερη προσοχή δίνεται στην 
προφορά. Η εστίαση πρακτικής προφοράς στην εκμάθηση των 
ήχων, της πίεσης στις λέξεις και τις φράσεις, και μιας φυσικής 
κατανόησης λεκτικού ρυθμού της προφορικής λέξης ασκείται με να 
επικεντρωθεί στην εξαγωγή των λεπτομερειών από τα σχετικά εύκολα
συμφραζόμενα και την εύρεση των βασικών σημείων στην απαίτηση των
αυτών. Η κατανόηση του γραπτού κειμένου ασκείται συνήθως 
χρησιμοποιώντας τις ανοιχτές ερωτήσεις. Υπάρχουν επίσης 
ασκήσεις λεξιλογίου που συνδέονται με τα κείμενα. Το 
λεξιλόγιο των κειμένων μπορεί να ελεγχθεί έξω αμέσως από τα 
συνημμένα γλωσσάρια.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El objetivo primario del curso es alzar las 
habilidades de la comprensión del inglés oído y hablado, de modo 
que los estudiantes puedan hacer frente a conversaciones y a 
situaciones diarias de obtener la información. La atención 
determinada es pagada en la pronunciación. La práctica de la 
pronunciación se centra en aprender los sonidos, la tensión en 
palabras y frases, y una comprensión natural del ritmo del discurso 
de la palabra hablada es practicada concentrándose en extraer los 
detalles de contextos relativamente fáciles y encontrar las puntas 
dominantes en más exigentes. La comprensión del texto escrito 
se practica sobre todo usando preguntas ampliables. Hay también
ejercicios del vocabulario conectados a los textos. El 
vocabulario de los textos se puede controlar hacia fuera 
inmediatamente de los glosarios asociados.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Eeva Tuokko
n:Tuokko;Eeva
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Twinkle Oy
n:Twinkle Oy
org:Twinkle Oy
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Maija Ojutkangas
n:Ojutkangas;Maija
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Maini Knuuttila
n:Knuuttila;Maini
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/7AA9B89E-4974-6308-F060-5C11E9590E06</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/7AA9B89E-4974-6308-F060-5C11E9590E06</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:49:39.05Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>glossary</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/kayttoehdot/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1071</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>508</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1353</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>345</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>238</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>750</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/kursseja/englanti1</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www2.edu.fi/etalukio/kursseja/englanti1</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
