<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222653</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222653</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/sahkotekniikka</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/sahkotekniikka</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/sahkotekniikka</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The operation of an electrical engineering contracting company</string>
            <string language="fi">Sähkötekniikan urakointiyrityksen toiminta</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Operation einer Vertrages abschließendes 
Firma der Elektrotechnik</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'exécution d'une compagnie se contractante 
d'électrotechnique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A operação de uma companhia contraindo-se da 
engenharia elétrica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il funzionamento di un'azienda contraentesi di 
ingegneria elettrica</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η λειτουργία μιας συμβαλλόμενης επιχείρησης ηλεκτρικής
εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La operación de una compañía que contrae de la 
ingeniería eléctrica</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The material in The operation of an electrical engineering contracting company consists of independent learning objects which are linked by the same case company, Sähkömiehet Oy, which can be used as an example in the learning objects. The content advances from the first and simplest level to the fifth, i.e., most demanding level. The first level describes an individual work target of the electrical contracting company. At the fifth level, a business plan is drawn up for the company. The material is intended in particular for the technology and transport training sector, but it can also be used in other educational sectors and, during study, other case companies from the same sector and other sectors can be examined.
At the various levels of the material, there are next to a question mark tasks that introduce the student to the various learning objects. Contains examples of a company’s business correspondence in PDF format. The material also contains links relating to the topic</string>
            <string language="fi">Sähkötekniikan urakointiyrityksen toiminta -aineisto muodostuu toisistaan riippumattomista oppimisaihioista, joita yhdistää sama case -yritys, Sähkömiehet Oy, jota voidaan käyttää esimerkkinä  oppimisaihioissa. Sisältö etenee  ensimmäisestä ja yksinkertaisimmasta tasosta viidenteen eli vaativimpaan tasoon. Ensimmäisellä tasolla kuvataan sähköurakointiyrityksen yksittäistä työkohdetta. Viidennellä tasolla laaditaan yritykselle liiketoimintasuunnitelma. Aineisto on erityisesti tarkoitettu tekniikan ja liikenteen koulutusalalle, mutta sitä voidaan käyttää myös muilla koulutusaloilla ja opiskeltaessa voidaan tarkastella muitakin saman alan ja muiden alojen case-yrityksiä.
Aineiston eri tasoilla kysymysmerkin kohdalla on tehtäviä, jotka perehdyttävät eri oppimisaihioihin. Sisältää esimerkkejä yrityksen liikekirjeenvaihdosta pdf-muodossa. Aineisto sisältää myös aiheeseen liittyviä linkkejä.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Material in der Operation einer Vertrages 
abschließendes Firma der Elektrotechnik besteht aus unabhängigen 
erlernennachrichten, die von der gleichen Fallfirma gebunden werden, 
Sähkömiehet Oy, das als Beispiel in den erlernennachrichten 
verwendet werden kann. Der Inhalt rückt von der ersten und 
einfachsten Stufe zum Fünftel d.h. die meiste fordernde Stufe vor. 
Die erste Stufe beschreibt ein einzelnes Arbeit Ziel der 
elektrischen Vertrages abschließendes Firma. Auf der fünften 
Stufe wird ein Unternehmensplan für die Firma aufgestellt. Das 
Material ist insbesondere für den Technologie- und Transporttraining 
Sektor bestimmt, aber es kann in anderen pädagogischen Sektoren auch 
benutzt werden und, während der Studie, können andere Fallfirmen vom
gleichen Sektor und andere Sektoren examined.At sein die verschiedenen
Stufen des Materials, dort sind nahe bei Aufgaben eines Fragezeichens,
die den Kursteilnehmer zu den verschiedenen erlernennachrichten 
vorstellen. Enthält Beispiele einer company?s 
Geschäftskorrespondenz im pdf Format. Das Material enthält 
auch Links in bezug auf das Thema</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le matériel dans l'exécution d'une compagnie se 
contractante d'électrotechnique se compose des objets d'étude 
indépendants qui sont joints par la même compagnie de cas, 
Sähkömiehet Oy, qui peut être utilisé comme exemple dans les 
objets d'étude. Le contenu avance du premier et le plus simple 
niveau au cinquième, c.-à-d., la plupart de niveau exigeant. 
Le premier niveau décrit une cible individuelle de travail de 
la compagnie se contractante électrique. Au cinquième niveau, 
un plan d'affaires est élaboré pour la compagnie. Le matériel
est destiné en particulier pour le secteur de formation de 
technologie et de transport, mais il peut également être utilisé 
dans d'autres secteurs éducatifs et, pendant l'étude, d'autres 
compagnies de cas du même secteur et d'autres secteurs peuvent être 
examined.At les divers niveaux du matériel, là sont à côté d'un 
point d'interrogation charge qui présentent l'étudiant aux 
divers objets d'étude. Contient des exemples d'une 
correspondance d'affaires de company?s dans le format de pdf. Le
matériel contient également des liens concernant le sujet</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O material na operação de uma companhia 
contraindo-se da engenharia elétrica consiste nos objetos de 
aprendizagem independentes que são ligados pela mesma companhia do 
caso, Sähkömiehet Oy, que pode ser usado como um exemplo nos objetos
de aprendizagem. O índice avança do primeiro e nível o mais 
simples ao fifth, isto é, a maioria de nível exijindo. O 
primeiro nível descreve um alvo individual do trabalho da companhia 
contraindo-se elétrica. No quinto nível, uma planta de 
negócio é desenhada acima para a companhia. O material é 
pretendido no detalhe para o setor do treinamento da tecnologia e do 
transporte, mas pode também ser usado em outros setores educacionais 
e, durante o estudo, outras companhias do caso do mesmo setor e outros
setores podem ser examined.At os vários níveis do material, lá são
ao lado das tarefas de uma marca de pergunta que introduzem o 
estudante aos vários objetos de aprendizagem. Contem exemplos 
de uma correspondência de negócio dos company?s no formato do pdf. 
O material contem também as ligações que relacionam-se ao 
tópico</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il materiale nel funzionamento di un'azienda 
contraentesi di ingegneria elettrica consiste degli oggetti imparanti 
indipendenti che sono collegati dalla stessa azienda di caso, 
Sähkömiehet Oy, che può essere usato come esempio negli oggetti 
imparanti. Il soddisfare avanza dal primo e livello più 
semplice al fifth, cioè, la maggior parte del livello esigente. 
Il primo livello descrive un obiettivo specifico del lavoro 
dell'azienda contraentesi elettrica. Al quinto livello, un 
programma di affari è elaborato per l'azienda. Il materiale è 
inteso in particolare per il settore di addestramento di trasporto e 
di tecnologia, ma può anche essere usato in altri settori educativi 
e, durante lo studio, altre aziende di caso dallo stesso settore ed 
altri settori possono essere examined.At i vari livelli del materiale,
là sono vicino alle mansioni del punto interrogativo che introducono 
l'allievo ai vari oggetti imparanti. Contiene gli esempi di una 
corrispondenza di affari dei company?s nel formato del pdf. Il 
materiale egualmente contiene i collegamenti concernente il soggetto</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Το υλικό στη λειτουργία μιας συμβαλλόμενης επιχείρησης
ηλεκτρικής εφαρμοσμένης μηχανικής αποτελείται από τα ανεξάρτητα 
αντικείμενα εκμάθησης που συνδέονται από την ίδια επιχείρηση 
περίπτωσης, Sδhkφmiehet Oy, το οποίο μπορεί να 
χρησιμοποιηθεί για παράδειγμα στα αντικείμενα εκμάθησης. Το 
περιεχόμενο προωθεί από το πρώτο και απλούστερο επίπεδο στο 
πέμπτο, δηλ., το πιό απαιτητικό επίπεδο. Το πρώτο επίπεδο 
περιγράφει έναν μεμονωμένο στόχο εργασίας της ηλεκτρικής 
συμβαλλόμενης επιχείρησης. Στο πέμπτο επίπεδο, ένα 
επιχειρησιακό σχέδιο συντάσσεται για την επιχείρηση. Το 
υλικό προορίζεται ειδικότερα για τον τομέα της κατάρτισης 
τεχνολογίας και μεταφορών, αλλά μπορεί επίσης να χρησιμοποιηθεί 
σε άλλους εκπαιδευτικούς τομείς και, κατά τη διάρκεια της 
μελέτης, άλλες επιχειρήσεις περίπτωσης από τον ίδιο τομέα και 
άλλοι τομείς μπορούν να εξεταστούν Στα διάφορα επίπεδα του
υλικού, υπάρχει δίπλα στις στοιχειώδεις εργασίες ερώτησης 
σημαδιών που εισάγουν το σπουδαστή στα διάφορα αντικείμενα 
εκμάθησης. Περιέχει τα παραδείγματα μιας επιχειρησιακής 
αλληλογραφίας company?s με τη μορφή PDF. Το υλικό 
περιέχει επίσης τις συνδέσεις σχετικά με το θέμα</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El material en la operación de una compañía que
contrae de la ingeniería eléctrica consiste en los objetos que 
aprenden que son conectados por la misma compañía del caso, 
Sähkömiehet Oy de la independiente, que se puede utilizar como ejemplo 
en los objetos que aprenden. El contenido avanza del primer y 
más simple nivel al fifth, es decir, la mayoría del nivel exigente. 
El primer nivel describe una blanco individual del trabajo de la
compañía que contrae eléctrica. En el quinto nivel, un plan 
de negocio se elabora para la compañía. El material se piensa 
en el detalle para el sector del entrenamiento de la tecnología y del
transporte, pero puede también ser utilizado en otros sectores 
educativos y, durante estudio, otras compañías del caso del mismo 
sector y otros sectores pueden ser examined.At los varios niveles del 
material, allí están al lado de las tareas de un signo de 
interrogación que introducen a estudiante a los varios objetos que 
aprenden. Contiene ejemplos de una correspondencia de negocio de
los company?s en formato del pdf. El material también contiene 
conexiones referente al asunto</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/2DB8D0AF-C85A-370F-E74F-62923F89442B</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/2DB8D0AF-C85A-370F-E74F-62923F89442B</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pertti Siekkinen
n:Siekkinen;Pertti 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:54:56.18Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>presentation</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>open activity</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">16-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nd-nc/1.0/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>413</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>784</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>411</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1282</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>779</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>428</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/sahkotekniikka</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi//oppimateriaalit/sahkotekniikka</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
