<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222441</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222441</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/tee_samanlainen/index.html</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/tee_samanlainen/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/tee_samanlainen/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Do an identical one</string>
            <string language="fi">Tee samanlainen</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tun Sie ein identisches</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Faites identique</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Faça idêntico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Faccia identico</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κάνετε έναν ίδιο</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Haga idéntico</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Do an identical one is an object in the AbacoMath game intended for remedial mathematics teaching, a perception exercise in which a figure is completed to be the same as a model image by moving the requisite elements on top of the image. The aim of the task is to lead the learner through the aid of experiences and visualisation towards abstraction. The tasks of the AbacoMath game have been conceived and scripted on the basis of a rehabilitative method developed under Hendrik Radatz and Ursula Chaudhur. The application has been implemented with Flash technology, and so the program requires a browser with Flash support in order to work.</string>
            <string language="fi">Tee samanlainen on matematiikan erityisopetukseen tarkoitetun AbacoMath-pelin aihio, hahmotusharjoitus, jossa täydennetään kuvio samanlaiseksi kuin mallikuva siirtämällä tarvittavat elementit kuvan päälle. Tehtävän tavoite on johdattaa oppija kokemusten ja visualisoinnin avulla kohti abstraktiota. AbacoMath-pelin tehtävät on ideoitu ja käsikirjoitettu Hendrik Radatzin ja Ursula Chaudhurin johdolla kehitetyn kuntouttamismenetelmän pohjalta. Sovellus on toteutettu Flash-tekniikalla, joten ohjelma tarvitsee toimiakseen selaimen, jossa on Flash-tuki.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Tun Sie ein identisches ist eine Nachricht im 
AbacoMath Spiel, das für fehlerbehebenden Mathematikunterricht, eine 
Vorstellung Übung bestimmt ist, in der eine Abbildung durchgeführt 
wird, um dieselbe wie ein vorbildliches Bild zu sein, indem man die 
erforderlichen Elemente auf das Bild verschiebt. Das Ziel der 
Aufgabe ist, den Anfänger durch das Hilfsmittel von Erfahrungen und 
von Sichtbarmachung in Richtung zur Abstraktion zu führen. Die 
Aufgaben des AbacoMath Spiels sind begriffen worden und scripted auf 
der Grundlage von eine rehabilitierende Methode, die unter Hendrik 
Radatz und Ursula Chaudhur entwickelt wird. Die Anwendung ist 
mit greller Technologie eingeführt worden und also benötigt das 
Programm eine Datenbanksuchroutine mit grellem Support, um zu 
arbeiten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Faites identique est un objet dans le jeu 
d'AbacoMath destiné à l'enseignement réparateur de mathématiques, 
un exercice de perception dans lequel une figure est remplie pour 
être identique qu'une image modèle en déplaçant les éléments 
requis sur le dessus de l'image. Le but du charger est de 
mener l'étudiant par l'aide des expériences et de la visualisation 
vers l'abstraction. Charge du jeu d'AbacoMath ont 
été conçus et préétablirs sur la base d'une méthode 
réhabilitative développée sous Hendrik Radatz et Ursula Chaudhur. 
L'application a été mise en application avec la technologie 
instantanée, et ainsi le programme exige d'un navigateur avec le 
support instantané afin de travailler.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Faça idêntico é um objeto no jogo pretendido 
para o ensino corretivo da matemática, um exercício de AbacoMath da 
percepção em que uma figura é terminada para ser a mesma que uma 
imagem modelo movendo os elementos requisite no alto da imagem. 
O alvo da tarefa é conduzir ao learner através do dae 
(dispositivo automático de entrada) das experiências e do 
visualisation para o abstraction. As tarefas do jogo de 
AbacoMath conceived e scripted na base de um método rehabilitative 
desenvolvido sob Hendrik Radatz e Ursula Chaudhur. A aplicação
foi executada com tecnologia flash, e assim que o programa requer um 
browser com sustentação flash a fim trabalhar.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Faccia identico è un oggetto nel gioco destinato
ad insegnamento correttivo di matematica, un'esercitazione di 
AbacoMath di percezione in cui una figura è completata per essere la 
stessa come immagine di modello spostando gli elementi richiesti in 
cima all'immagine. Lo scopo dell'operazione è condurre il 
principiante attraverso il sussidio delle esperienze e della 
visualizzazione verso l'astrazione. Le mansioni del gioco di 
AbacoMath sono state concepite e scripted in base ad un metodo 
rieducativo messo a punto sotto Hendrik Radatz ed Ursula Chaudhur. 
L'applicazione è stata effettuata con tecnologia istantanea ed 
in modo da il programma richiede un browser con supporto istantaneo 
per funzionare.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Κάνετε έναν ίδιο είναι ένα αντικείμενο στο παιχνίδι
AbacoMath προοριζόμενο για τη θεραπευτική διδασκαλία 
μαθηματικών, μια άσκηση αντίληψης στην οποία ένας αριθμός 
ολοκληρώνεται για να είναι ο ίδιος με μια πρότυπη εικόνα με την 
κίνηση των απαραίτητων στοιχείων πάνω από την εικόνα. Ο 
στόχος της στοιχειώδους εργασίας είναι να οδηγηθεί ο αρχάριος 
μέσω της ενίσχυσης της εμπειρίας και της απεικόνισης προς την 
αφαίρεση. Οι στοιχειώδεις εργασίες του παιχνιδιού 
AbacoMath έχουν συλλήφθουν και προκαθορισμένος βάσει μιας 
αποκατάστασης μεθόδου που αναπτύσσεται κάτω από το Hendrik 
Radatz και την Ursula Chaudhur. Η εφαρμογή έχει 
εφαρμοστεί με την τεχνολογία λάμψης, και έτσι το πρόγραμμα 
απαιτεί έναν ξεφυλλιστή με την υποστήριξη λάμψης προκειμένου να 
λειτουργήσει.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Haga idéntico es un objeto en el juego previsto 
para la enseñanza remediadora de las matemáticas, un ejercicio de 
AbacoMath de la opinión en el cual una figura sea terminada para ser 
igual que una imagen modelo moviendo los elementos indispensables 
encima de la imagen. La puntería de la tarea es conducir al 
principiante a través de la ayuda de experiencias y de la 
visualización hacia la abstracción. Las tareas del juego de 
AbacoMath se han concebido y scripted en base de un método 
rehabilitativo desarrollado bajo Hendrik Radatz y Ursula Chaudhur. 
La aplicación se ha puesto en ejecucio'n con tecnología de 
destello, y así que el programa requiere un browser con la ayuda de 
destello para trabajar.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Jan Rosnell
n:Rosnell;Jan
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Anni Lampinen
n:Lampinen;Anni
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Marja Dräger
n:Dräger;Marja
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Janomedia
n:Janomedia
org:Janomedia
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/4EF1FFFA-369E-C11E-6D66-B3A033003738</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/4EF1FFFA-369E-C11E-6D66-B3A033003738</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:54:04.10Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>special education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">6-14</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Ei mainintaa</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>1227</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>790</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>632</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>544</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/tee_samanlainen/index.html</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/matematiikka/tee_samanlainen/index.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
