<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222712</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222712</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/maantiede/kurssi3/index.html</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/maantiede/kurssi3/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/maantiede/kurssi3/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">The world of risks</string>
            <string language="fi">Riskien maailma</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Welt von Gefahren</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le monde des risques</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O mundo dos riscos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Il mondo dei rischi</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο κόσμος των κινδύνων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El mundo de riesgos</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Examines the hazards of the globe from a geographical point of view. Hazards are classified into four main categories: natural hazards, hazards related to the interaction between man and nature, social hazards, and technological hazards. From each of these, at least two subjects are examined in further detail. It is important to aim to see connections between the reasons and regional occurrence of various hazard types. Hazards are also examined on the axis of developing countries – developed countries. The purpose of the material is to help outline the typical hazards for various regions. Contains exercises, many of which deal with information retrieval on the Internet. The use of a textbook is necessary in order to pass the course.</string>
            <string language="fi">Tarkastee maapallolla esiintyviä hasardeja maantieteellisestä näkökulmasta. Hasardit on luokiteltu neljään pääluokkaan: luonnonhasardeihin, ihmisen ja luonnon vuorovaikutukseen liittyviin, sosiaalisiin sekä teknologisiin hasardeihin, joista jokaisesta tarkastellaan lähemmin vähintään kahta aihetta. Tärkeää on pyrkiä näkemään yhteyksiä eri hasardityyppien syissä ja alueellisessa esiintymisessä. Hasardeja tarkastellaan myös akselilla kehitysmaat — teollisuusmaat. Aineiston tarkoituksena on auttaa hahmottamaan eri alueille tyypillisiä hasardeja. Sisältää tehtäviä, joista useat käsittelevät verkkotiedonhakua. Oppikirjan käyttö on kurssin suorittamiseksi välttämätöntä.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Überprüft die Gefahren der Kugel von einem 
geographischen Gesichtspunkt. Gefahren werden in vier 
Hauptkategorien eingestuft: natürliche Gefahren, Gefahren 
standen auf der Interaktion zwischen Mann und Natur, Sozialgefahren 
und technologische Gefahren in Verbindung. Von jedem von diesen,
mindestens werden zwei Themen ausführlich weiteres überprüft. 
Es ist wichtig darauf abzuzielen, Anschlüsse zwischen den 
Gründen und dem regionalen Auftreten der verschiedenen Gefahrtypen zu
sehen. Gefahren werden auch auf der Mittellinie der 
Entwicklungsländer überprüft? entwickelte Länder. Der 
Zweck des Materials ist zu helfen, die typischen Gefahren für 
verschiedene Regionen zu umreißen. Enthält Übungen, von denen
viele Information Retrieval auf dem Internet beschäftigen. Der 
Gebrauch eines Lehrbuchs ist notwendig, um den Kurs zu führen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Examine les risques du globe d'un point de vue 
géographique. Des risques sont classifiés dans quatre 
catégories principales : risques normaux, risques liés à 
l'interaction entre l'homme et la nature, risques sociaux, et risques 
technologiques. De chacune de ces derniers, au moins deux sujets
sont examinés dans davantage de détail. Il est important de 
viser à voir des connexions entre les raisons et l'occurrence 
régionale de divers types de risque. Des risques sont 
également examinés sur l'axe des pays en voie de développement ? 
pays développés. Le but du matériel est d'aider à 
tracer les grandes lignes des risques typiques pour différentes 
régions. Contient les exercices, dont beaucoup traitent la 
recherche documentaire sur l'Internet. L'utilisation d'un manuel
est nécessaire afin de passer le cours.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Examina os perigos do globo de um ponto 
geográfico da vista. Os perigos são classificados em quatro 
categorias principais: os perigos naturais, perigos 
relacionaram-se à interação entre o homem e a natureza, perigos 
sociais, e perigos technological. De cada uma destes, ao menos 
dois assuntos são examinados em um detalhe mais adicional. É 
importante apontar ver conexões entre as razões e a ocorrência 
regional de vários tipos do perigo. Os perigos são examinados 
também na linha central de países tornando-se? países 
desenvolvidos. A finalidade do material é ajudar esboçar os 
perigos típicos para várias regiões. Contem os exercícios, 
muitos de que tratam da recuperação de informação no Internet. 
O uso de um textbook é necessário a fim passar o curso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Esamina i rischi del globo da un punto di vista 
geografico. I rischi sono classificati in quattro categorie 
principali: i rischi naturali, rischi si sono riferiti 
all'interazione fra l'uomo e la natura, rischi sociali e rischi 
tecnologici. Da ciascuno di questi, almeno due oggetti sono 
esaminati in dettaglio ulteriore. È importante da mirare vedere
i collegamenti fra i motivi ed il caso regionale di vari tipi di 
rischio. I rischi egualmente sono esaminati sull'asse dei pæsi 
in via di sviluppo? paesi sviluppati. Lo scopo del 
materiale è contribuire a descrivere i rischi tipici per varie 
regioni. Contiene le esercitazioni, molti di cui si occupano di 
reperimento delle informazioni sul Internet. L'uso di un manuale
è necessario per passare il corso.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξετάζει τους κινδύνους της σφαίρας από γεωγραφική 
άποψη. Οι κίνδυνοι είναι ταξινομημένοι σε τέσσερις βασικές
κατηγορίες: οι φυσικοί κίνδυνοι, κίνδυνοι αφορούσαν την 
αλληλεπίδραση μεταξύ του ατόμου και της φύσης, των κοινωνικών 
κινδύνων, και των τεχνολογικών κινδύνων. Από κάθε έναν 
από αυτούς, τουλάχιστον δύο θέματα εξετάζονται με περαιτέρω 
λεπτομέρειες. Είναι σημαντικό να στοχεύσει να 
δει τις συνδέσεις μεταξύ των λόγων και του 
περιφερειακού περιστατικού των διάφορων τύπων κινδύνου. Οι 
κίνδυνοι εξετάζονται επίσης στον άξονα των αναπτυσσόμενων χωρών;
αναπτυγμένες χώρες. Ο σκοπός του υλικού είναι να 
βοηθήσει να περιγράψει τους χαρακτηριστικούς κινδύνους για τις 
διάφορες περιοχές. Περιέχει τις ασκήσεις, πολλές από τις 
οποίες εξετάζουν την ανάκτηση πληροφοριών στο διαδίκτυο. Η 
χρήση ενός εγχειριδίου είναι απαραίτητη προκειμένου να περαστεί
η σειρά μαθημάτων.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Examina los peligros del globo desde un punto de 
vista geográfico. Los peligros se clasifican en cuatro 
categorías principales: peligros naturales, peligros 
relacionados con la interacción entre el hombre y la naturaleza, 
peligros sociales, y peligros tecnológicos. De cada uno de 
éstos, por lo menos dos temas se examinan en detalle adicional. 
Es importante apuntar ver conexiones entre las razones y la 
ocurrencia regional de los varios tipos del peligro. ¿Los 
peligros también se examinan en el eje de países en vías de 
desarrollo? países desarrollados. El propósito del 
material es ayudar a contornear los peligros típicos para las varias 
regiones. Contiene los ejercicios, muchos de los cuales se 
ocupan de la recuperación de datos en el Internet. El uso de un
libro de textos es necesario para pasar el curso.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:ei mainita yksittäistä tekijää
n:ei mainita yksittäistä tekijää
org:ei mainita yksittäistä tekijää
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/D701E24A-B96C-FA94-3C3B-4F5E9533AED4</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/D701E24A-B96C-FA94-3C3B-4F5E9533AED4</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:50:24.63Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/kayttoehdot/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>345</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1141</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>540</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/maantiede/kurssi3/index.html</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www02.oph.fi/etalukio/maantiede/kurssi3/index.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
