<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/80017</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>80017</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa/k4/index.html</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa/k4/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa/k4/index.html</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">At home and abroad</string>
            <string language="fi">Meillä ja muualla</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Im In- und Ausland</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ici et ailleurs</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Na HOME e no exterior</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Nel paese ed all'estero</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Στο σπίτι και στο εξωτερικό</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">En el país y en el extranjero</string>
          </title>
          <language>de</language>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Deals with the people, geography, history, attractions and tourism of your own country and the focus countries. 
Emphasises listening comprehension and speech, and reinforces the management of basic structures. Writing skills are practised through communication exercises. The website contains texts on Germany, Austria and Switzerland, and in the section on Finland you learn what an overseas visitor appreciates in our country. There are study tips in connection with a few texts, telling how to practise text comprehension in various ways. The speech comprehension exercises in the course are related to situations a tourist may encounter. Therefore, speech comprehension exercises have been expanded into speech exercises providing practice in coping as a tourist in everyday situations where you need to get information.</string>
            <string language="fi">Käsittelee oman maan ja kohdekielisten maiden ihmisiä, maantiedettä, historiaa, nähtävyyksiä ja lomanviettomahdollisuuksia. 
Painottaa puheen ymmärtämistä ja puhumista ja vahvistaa perusrakenteiden hallintaa. Kirjoittamistaitoa harjoitellaan viestinnällisten tehtävien avulla. Sivustolla on Saksaa, Itävaltaa ja Sveitsiä käsitteleviä tekstejä, ja lisäksi Suomi-osuudessa tutustutaan siihen, mitä asioita ulkomaalainen kotimaassamme arvostaa. Muutamien tekstien yhteydessä on  opiskeluvihjeitä, joissa kerrotaan, miten eri tavoin tekstinymmärtämistä voi harjoitella. Kurssin puheenymmärtämisharjoitukset liittyvät tilanteisiin, joihin turistina voi joutua. Puheenymmärtämistehtäviä onkin laajennettu myös puheharjoituksiksi, joissa voi harjoitella matkailijan asemassa selviytymistä tavallisissa tiedonhakutilanteissa.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="fi">Opetushallitus</string>
            <string language="en">Sveitsi</string>
            <string language="en">Suomi</string>
            <string language="en">Itävalta</string>
            <string language="en">Saksa</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Abkommen mit den Leuten, der Geographie, der 
Geschichte, den Anziehungen und dem Tourismus Ihres eigenen Landes und
der Fokusländer. Hebt hörendes Erfassen und Rede hervor und 
verstärkt das Management der grundlegenden Strukturen. 
Schreiben Fähigkeiten werden durch Kommunikation Übungen 
geübt. Die Web site enthält Texte auf Deutschland, Österreich
und der Schweiz, und im Kapitel auf Finnland erlernen Sie, was ein 
Überseebesucher in unserem Land schätzt. Es gibt Studie 
Spitzen in Zusammenhang mit einigen Texten und erklärt, wie man 
Textverständnis in den verschiedenen Methoden übt. Die 
Redeerfassenübungen im Kurs hängen mit Situationen zusammen, die ein
Tourist antreffen kann. Folglich sind Redeerfassenübungen in 
die Redeübungen erweitert worden, die Praxis beim Fertig werden als 
Tourist in den täglichen Situationen bereitstellen, in denen Sie 
Informationen erhalten müssen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Affaires avec les personnes, la géographie, 
l'histoire, les attractions et le tourisme de votre propre pays et des
pays de foyer. Souligne la compréhension et le discours 
d'écoute, et renforce la gestion des structures de base. Des 
qualifications d'écriture sont pratiquées par des exercices de 
transmission. Le site Web contient des textes sur l'Allemagne, 
l'Autriche et la Suisse, et dans la section sur la Finlande vous 
apprenez ce qu'un visiteur d'outre-mer apprécie dans notre pays. 
Il y a des extrémités d'étude en liaison avec quelques 
textes, indiquant comment pratiquer la compréhension des textes dans 
diverses voies. Les exercices de compréhension de la parole 
dans le cours sont liés aux situations que un touriste peut 
rencontrer. Par conséquent, des exercices de compréhension de 
la parole ont été augmentés dans des exercices de la parole 
fournissant la pratique dans faire face en tant que touriste dans des 
situations journalières où vous devez obtenir l'information.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Negócios com os povos, a geografia, o history, as
atrações e o tourism de seu próprio país e dos países do foco. 
Emfatiza a compreensão e o discurso escutando, e reforça a 
gerência de estruturas básicas. As habilidades da escrita são
praticadas com os exercícios de uma comunicação. O Web site 
contem textos em Germany, em Áustria e em Switzerland, e na seção 
em Finland você aprende o que um visitante ultramarino aprecia em 
nosso país. Há umas pontas do estudo em relação a alguns 
textos, dizendo como praticar a compreensão de texto em várias 
maneiras. Os exercícios da compreensão do discurso no curso 
são relacionados às situações que um turista pode encontrar. 
Conseqüentemente, os exercícios da compreensão do discurso 
foram expandidos nos exercícios do discurso que fornecem a prática 
em lidar como um turista nas situações diárias onde você necessita
começar a informação.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Affari con la gente, la geografia, la storia, le 
attrazioni ed il turismo del vostro proprio paese e dei paesi del 
fuoco. Dà risalto alla comprensione ed al discorso ascoltanti e
rinforza la gestione delle strutture di base. Le abilità di 
scrittura si esercitano in con le esercitazioni di comunicazione. 
Il Web site contiene i testi sulla Germania, sull'Austria e 
sulla Svizzera e nella sezione sulla Finlandia imparate che cosa un 
ospite d'oltremare apprezza nel nostro paese. Ci sono punte di 
studio in relazione ad alcuni testi, dicenti a come esercitarsi nella 
comprensione del testo in vari modi. Le esercitazioni di 
comprensione di discorso nel corso sono collegate con le situazioni 
che un turista può incontrare. Di conseguenza, le esercitazioni
di comprensione di discorso sono state espanse nelle esercitazioni di 
discorso che forniscono la pratica nel fare fronte come turista nelle 
situazioni giornalieri dove dovete ottenere le informazioni.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Εξετάζει τους ανθρώπους, τη γεωγραφία, την ιστορία, 
την έλξη και τον τουρισμό της χώρας σας και των χωρών εστίασης. 
Υπογραμμίζει την κατανόηση και την ομιλία ακούσματος, και 
ενισχύει τη διαχείριση των βασικών δομών. Οι δεξιότητες 
σύνταξης εγγράφου ασκούνται μέσω των ασκήσεων επικοινωνίας. 
Ο ιστοχώρος περιέχει τα κείμενα στη Γερμανία, την Αυστρία 
και την Ελβετία, και στο τμήμα Φινλανδίας μαθαίνετε τι ένας 
υπερπόντιος επισκέπτης εκτιμά στη χώρα μας. Υπάρχουν άκρες
μελέτης σχετικά με μερικά κείμενα, λέγοντας πώς να ασκήσουν την
κατανόηση κειμένων με τους διάφορους τρόπους. Οι ασκήσεις 
λεκτικής κατανόησης στη σειρά μαθημάτων συσχετίζονται με τις 
καταστάσεις που ένας τουρίστας μπορεί να αντιμετωπίσει. 
Επομένως, οι ασκήσεις λεκτικής κατανόησης έχουν επεκταθεί 
στις λεκτικές ασκήσεις που παρέχουν την πρακτική στην 
αντιμετώπιση ως τουρίστα στις καθημερινές καταστάσεις όπου 
πρέπει να πάρετε τις πληροφορίες.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Repartos con la gente, la geografía, la historia,
las atracciones y el turismo de su propio país y de los países del 
foco. Acentúa la comprensión y el discurso que escuchan, y 
refuerza la gerencia de estructuras básicas. Las habilidades de
la escritura se practican con ejercicios de la comunicación. El
Web site contiene los textos en Alemania, Austria y Suiza, y en la 
sección en Finlandia usted aprende lo que aprecia un visitante de 
ultramar en nuestro país. Hay extremidades del estudio en la 
conexión con algunos textos, diciendo cómo practicar la comprensión
de texto de varias maneras. Los ejercicios de la comprensión 
del discurso en el curso se relacionan con las situaciones que un 
turista puede encontrar. Por lo tanto, los ejercicios de la 
comprensión del discurso se han ampliado en los ejercicios del 
discurso que proporcionaban a práctica en hacer frente como turista 
en las situaciones diarias donde usted necesita conseguir la 
información.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sveitsi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Suomi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Itävalta</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Saksa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Sveitsi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Suomi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Itävalta</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Saksa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Sveitsi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Suomi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Itävalta</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Saksa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sveitsi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Suomi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Itävalta</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Saksa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Sveitsi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Suomi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Itδvalta</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Saksa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Sveitsi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Suomi</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Itävalta</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Saksa</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Katri Oldendorff
n:Oldendorff;Katri
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>unknown</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Lingonet
n:Lingonet
org:Lingonet
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/0D4D9EAB-CF13-3167-5AC0-8F4C8173E426</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/0D4D9EAB-CF13-3167-5AC0-8F4C8173E426</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-04-26T11:49:39.51Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>course</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>glossary</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">15-19</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc-url">http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/kayttoehdot/</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1240</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>540</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>345</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>548</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>121</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1353</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1265</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>549</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>926</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>590</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1411</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>248</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa/k4/index.html</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.oph.fi/etalukio/saksa/k4/index.html</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
