<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/222872</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>222872</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
    <entry>http://www.edu.fi/SubPage.asp?path=498,3293,56804,14614</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.edu.fi/SubPage.asp?path=498,3293,56804,14614</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.edu.fi/SubPage.asp?path=498,3293,56804,14614</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Safe use of the Internet</string>
            <string language="fi">Internetin turvallinen käyttö</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sicherer Gebrauch des Internets</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Utilisation sûre de l'Internet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uso seguro do Internet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sicurezza di utilizzo del Internet</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ασφαλής χρήση του Διαδικτύου</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Uso seguro del Internet</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Safe use of the Internet’ is support material guiding and advising in safe use of the Internet in schools. 

The enclosed material provides information, practical help and ready templates for the safe use of the Internet in schools. The material also includes links related to the subject. The material contains slide shows for teachers and parents. The slide shows require PowerPoint software, which can be downloaded in connection with the slide shows. 

Safe use of the Internet consists of five sections dealing with the safety of Internet use, appropriate use of the Internet, instructions for using the Internet, versatile utilisation of the Internet, and web etiquette.

The material has been compiled, tested and developed as part of the DotSafe project funded by the European Commission in 2000–2002. The online material can be revised according to need and printed out.</string>
            <string language="fi">Internetin turvallinen käyttö -aineisto on tukimateriaali, joka ohjaa ja neuvoo Internetin turvalliseen käyttöön koulussa. 

Oheinen materiaali tarjoaa tietoa, käytännön apua ja valmiita mallipohjia Internetin turvalliseen käyttöön kouluissa. Aineisto sisältää myös aiheeseen liittyviä linkkejä. Materiaali sisältää diaesityksiä opettajille ja vanhemmille. Diaesitysten käyttöön tarvitaan Powerpoint -ohjelma, jonka voi ladata diaesitysten yhteydessä. 

Internetin turvallinen käyttö koostuu viidestä osiosta, jotka käsittelevät Internetin käytön turvallisuutta, Internetin asianmukaista käyttöä, toimintaohjeita, Internetin monipuolista hyödyntämistä ja nettikettia.

Aineisto on laadittu, testattu ja kehitetty osana Euroopan komission rahoittamaa DotSafe-hanketta vuosina 2000–2002. Verkkomateriaali on muokattavissa tarpeiden mukaiseksi ja tulostettavissa paperiversioksi.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Sicherer Gebrauch des Internets? ist das 
Hilfsmaterial, das im sicheren Gebrauch des Internets in den Schulen 
führt und rät. Das beiliegende Material stellt Informationen, 
praktische Hilfe und betriebsbereite Schablonen für den sicheren 
Gebrauch des Internets in den Schulen zur Verfügung. Das 
Material schließt auch die Links ein, die auf dem Thema in Verbindung
gestanden werden. Das Material enthält Diavorführungen für 
Lehrer und Eltern. Die Diavorführungen benötigen PowerPoint 
Software, die in Zusammenhang mit den Diavorführungen downloadet 
werden kann. Sicherer Gebrauch des Internets besteht aus fünf 
Kapiteln, die die Sicherheit des Internet-Gebrauches beschäftigen, 
verwendet Gebrauch des Internets, Anwendungsvorschriften das Internet,
vielseitige begabt Anwendung des Internets, und Material des Webs 
etiquette.The ist als Teil des DotSafe Projektes kompiliert worden, 
geprüft worden und entwickelt worden, das von der Europäischen 
Kommission in 2000?2002 finanziert wird. Das Onlinematerial kann
entsprechend Notwendigkeit verbessert werden und ausgedruckt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Utilisation sûre de l'Internet ? est le 
matériel de support guidant et informant dans l'utilisation sûre de 
l'Internet dans les écoles. Le matériel inclus fournit 
l'information, l'aide pratique et les descripteurs prêts pour l'usage
sûr de l'Internet dans les écoles. Le matériel inclut 
également des liens liés au sujet. Le matériel contient des 
projections de diapositives pour des professeurs et des parents. 
Les projections de diapositives exigent le logiciel de 
PowerPoint, qui peut être téléchargé en liaison avec les 
projections de diapositives. L'utilisation sûre de l'Internet 
se compose de cinq sections traitant la sûreté de l'utilisation 
d'Internet, s'approprient l'utilisation de l'Internet, instructions 
pour l'usage de l'Internet, utilisation souple de l'Internet, et le 
matériel du Web etiquette.The a été compilé, testé et développé
en tant qu'élément du projet de DotSafe financé par le Commission 
européen dans 2000?2002. Le matériel en ligne peut être mis 
à jour selon le besoin et être imprimé.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Uso seguro do Internet? é o material de 
sustentação que guia e que recomenda no uso seguro do Internet nas 
escolas. O material incluido fornece a informação, a ajuda 
prática e moldes prontos para o uso seguro do Internet nas escolas. 
O material inclui também as ligações relacionadas ao assunto.
O material contem mostras de corrediça para professores e pais.
As mostras de corrediça requerem o software de PowerPoint, que 
pode downloaded em relação às mostras de corrediça. O uso 
seguro do Internet consiste em cinco seções que tratam da segurança
do uso do Internet, apropria o uso do Internet, instruções para usar
o Internet, utilização versátil do Internet, e o material do Web 
etiquette.The foi compilado, testado e desenvolvido como a parte do 
projeto de DotSafe financiado pelo commission europeu em 2000?2002. 
O material em linha pode ser revisado de acordo com a 
necessidade e printed-out.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Sicurezza di utilizzo del Internet? è il 
materiale di sostegno che guida e che raccomanda nella sicurezza di 
utilizzo del Internet in scuole. Il materiale incluso fornisce 
le informazioni, aiuto pratico e aspetta le mascherine per la 
sicurezza di utilizzo del Internet in scuole. Il materiale 
egualmente include i collegamenti relativi all'oggetto. Il 
materiale contiene le proiezioni di diapositive per gli insegnanti ed 
i genitori. Le proiezioni di diapositive richiedono il software 
del PowerPoint, che può essere trasferito in relazione alle 
proiezioni di diapositive. La sicurezza di utilizzo del Internet
consiste di cinque sezioni che si occupano della sicurezza di uso del 
Internet, appropria l'uso del Internet, istruzioni per usando il 
Internet, utilizzazione versatile del Internet ed il materiale di Web 
etiquette.The è stato compilato, sperimentato stato e messo a punto 
come componente del progetto DotSafe costituito un fondo per dalla 
Commissione Europea in 2000?2002. Il materiale in linea può 
essere modificato secondo bisogno ed essere stampato.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ασφαλής χρήση του Διαδικτύου; είναι υλικό 
υποστήριξης που καθοδηγεί και που συμβουλεύει σε ασφαλή χρήση του
Διαδικτύου στα σχολεία. Το εσωκλειόμενο υλικό παρέχει τις 
πληροφορίες, πρακτικές οδηγίες και αναμένει τα πρότυπα για 
την ασφαλή χρήση του Διαδικτύου στα σχολεία. Το υλικό 
περιλαμβάνει επίσης τις συνδέσεις σχετικές με το θέμα. Το 
υλικό περιέχει τις επιδείξεις φωτογραφικών διαφανειών για τους 
δασκάλους και τους γονείς. Οι επιδείξεις φωτογραφικών 
διαφανειών απαιτούν το λογισμικό PowerPoint, το οποίο μπορεί 
να μεταφορτωθεί σχετικά με τις επιδείξεις φωτογραφικών 
διαφανειών. Η ασφαλής χρήση του Διαδικτύου αποτελείται από
πέντε τμήματα που εξετάζουν την ασφάλεια της χρήσης Διαδικτύου, 
κατάλληλη χρήση του Διαδικτύου, οδηγίες για τη χρησιμοποίηση του 
Διαδικτύου, της ευπροσάρμοστης χρησιμοποίησης του Διαδικτύου, και 
της εθιμοτυπίας Ιστού Το υλικό έχει μεταγλωττιστεί, έχει 
εξεταστεί και έχει αναπτυχθεί ως τμήμα του προγράμματος 
DotSafe που χρηματοδοτείται από την Ευρωπαϊκή Επιτροπή σε 
2000?2002. Το σε απευθείας σύνδεση υλικό μπορεί να 
αναθεωρηθεί σύμφωνα με τις ανάγκες και να εκτυπωθεί.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">¿Uso seguro del Internet? es el material de 
ayuda que dirige y que aconseja en el uso seguro del Internet en 
escuelas. El material incluido proporciona a la información, a 
la ayuda práctica y a los modelos listos para el uso seguro del 
Internet en escuelas. El material también incluye las 
conexiones relacionadas con el tema. El material contiene las 
demostraciones de diapositiva para los profesores y los padres. 
Las demostraciones de diapositiva requieren el software de 
PowerPoint, que se puede descargar en la conexión con las 
demostraciones de diapositiva. El uso seguro del Internet 
consiste en cinco secciones que se ocupan de la seguridad del uso del 
Internet, se apropia del uso del Internet, instrucciones para usar el 
Internet, utilización versátil del Internet, y el material del Web 
etiquette.The se ha compilado, se ha probado y se ha desarrollado como
parte del proyecto de DotSafe financiado por la Comisión de las 
Comunidades Europeas en 2000?2002. El material en línea puede 
ser revisado según necesidad y ser impreso.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Opetushallitus
n:Opetushallitus
org:Opetushallitus
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>oai</catalog>
            <entry>oai:fnbe.profium.com:http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/EA1CC986-370B-773A-8B9E-901527BB4CE9</entry>
          </identifier>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>profium</catalog>
            <entry>http://www.oph.fi/profium/2008/01/material/EA1CC986-370B-773A-8B9E-901527BB4CE9</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>begin:vcard
version:3.0
fn:Pekka Pirhonen
n:Pirhonen;Pekka 
org:Humap
end:vcard</entity>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
          <contribute>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
FN:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
N:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
ORG:National Centre for Technology in Education (NCTE0
VERSION:3.0
END:VCARD</entity>
            <role>
              <value>provider</value>
              <source>ASPECTv1.0</source>
            </role>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2010-03-14T00:43:38.92Z</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>teacher</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>parent</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>vocational education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">7-U</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Creative Commons Nimeä-Epäkaupallinen-Ei muutettuja teoksia 1.0</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>653</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>655</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>657</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>238</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>1116</id>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>673</id>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>fnbe</catalog>
      <entry>http://www.edu.fi/SubPage.asp?path=498,3293,56804,14614</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/html</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/SubPage.asp?path=498,3293,56804,14614</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
