<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82539</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82539</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>3992</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Street interview</string>
            <string language="sv">Gatuintervju</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Straße Interview</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Entrevue de rue</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Entrevista da rua</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Intervista della via</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Συνέντευξη οδών</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Entrevista de la calle</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The student will, with the aid of model interviews and instructions, make a questionnaire. As a model for an interview, he tells here five persons about his internet habits. On the screen there are instructions, video clips of those being interviewed for practice and links to clues on how to put together questions. There is also instructions to the "Comprehension check" - exercise. In this exercise the student will combine a correct reply with a correct question by moving the interviewer next to the right person. The student can then suggest interview questions of his own to the teacher and interview his classmates about different subjects.

</string>
            <string language="sv">Eleven ska, med hjälp av modellintervjuer och instruktioner, göra ett frågeformulär. Som modell för en intervju berättar här fem personer om sina internetvanor. I rutan finns instruktioner, videoklipp av de som provintervjuas samt länkar till tips på hur man kan göra upp frågor och till ”Comprehension check”-uppgiften. I uppgiften ska eleven kombinera rätt svar med rätt fråga genom att flytta intervjuarna bredvid rätt person. Eleven kan sedan föreslå egna intervjufrågor för läraren och intervjua sina klasskamrater om olika ämnen.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Der Kursteilnehmer wird, mit dem Hilfsmittel der 
vorbildlichen Interviews und der Anweisungen, einen Fragebogen zu 
bilden. Als Modell für ein Interview, erklärt er hier fünf 
Personen über seine Internet-Gewohnheiten. Auf dem Bildschirm 
gibt es Anweisungen, die videoclips von denen, die für Praxis 
interviewt werden und Links zu den Anhaltspunkten auf, wie man die 
Fragen zusammenfügt. Es gibt auch Anweisungen zur 
"Erfassenüberprüfung" - Übung. In dieser Übung kombiniert 
der Kursteilnehmer eine korrekte Antwort mit einer korrekten Frage, 
indem er den Interviewer nahe bei der rechten Person verschiebt. 
Der Kursteilnehmer kann Interviewfragen von seinen Selbst zum 
Lehrer dann vorschlagen und seine Mitschüler über unterschiedliche 
Themen interviewen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'étudiant , à l'aide des entrevues et des 
instructions modèles, faire un questionnaire. Comme modèle 
pour une entrevue, il dit ici cinq personnes au sujet de ses habitudes
d'Internet. Sur l'écran il y a des instructions, des clips 
visuels de ceux étant interviewés pour la pratique et des liens aux 
indices sur la façon dont remonter des questions. Il y a 
également des instructions à l'exercice "de contrôle de 
compréhension" -. Dans cet exercice l'étudiant combinera une 
réponse correcte avec une question correcte en déplaçant 
l'interviewer à côté de la bonne personne. L'étudiant peut 
alors suggérer des questions d'entrevue de ses propres au professeur 
et interviewer ses camarades de classe au sujet de différents sujets.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O estudante , com o dae (dispositivo automático 
de entrada) das entrevistas e das instruções modelo, para fazer um 
questionário. Como um modelo para uma entrevista, diz aqui 
cinco pessoas sobre seus hábitos do Internet. Na tela há umas 
instruções, grampos video daqueles que estão sendo entrevistados 
para a prática e ligações aos indícios em como unir as perguntas. 
Há também umas instruções da "ao exercício da verificação
compreensão" -. Neste exercício o estudante combinará uma 
resposta correta com uma pergunta correta movendo o interviewer ao 
lado da pessoa direita. O estudante pode então sugerir 
perguntas da entrevista do seus próprios ao professor e entrevistar 
seus classmates sobre assuntos diferentes.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'allievo, con l'aiuto delle interviste e delle 
istruzioni di modello, fare un questionario. Come modello per 
un'intervista, dice qui a cinque persone circa le sue abitudini del 
Internet. Sullo schermo ci sono istruzioni, video clip di quelle
che sono intervistati per la pratica e collegamenti agli indizii su 
come unire le domande. Ci sono egualmente istruzioni 
"all'esercitazione del controllo di comprensione" -. In questa 
esercitazione l'allievo unirà una risposta corretta con una domanda 
corretta spostando l'intervistatore vicino alla persona giusta. 
L'allievo può allora suggerire le domande di intervista dei 
suoi propri all'insegnante ed intervistare i suoi classmates circa gli
oggetti differenti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο σπουδαστής, με την ενίσχυση των πρότυπων 
συνεντεύξεων και των οδηγιών, θα κάνει ένα ερωτηματολόγιο. 
Σαν μοντέλο για μια συνέντευξη, λέει εδώ σε πέντε άτομα 
για τις συνήθειες Διαδικτύου του. Στην οθόνη υπάρχουν 
οδηγίες, τηλεοπτικοί συνδετήρες εκείνοι που περνούν από 
συνέντευξη για την πρακτική και συνδέσεις με τις ενδείξεις στο 
πώς να θέσουν μαζί τα ερωτήματα. Υπάρχουν επίσης οδηγίες 
στο "έλεγχο κατανόησησ" - άσκηση. Σε αυτήν την άσκηση ο 
σπουδαστής θα συνδυάσει μια σωστή απάντηση με μια σωστή ερώτηση 
με την κίνηση του ερευνητή δίπλα στο σωστό πρόσωπο. Ο 
σπουδαστής μπορεί έπειτα να προτείνει τα θέματα συνέντευξης 
δικών δικοί του στο δάσκαλο και να πάρει συνέντευξη από τους 
συμμαθητές του για τα διαφορετικά θέματα.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">El estudiante , con la ayuda de las entrevistas y
de las instrucciones modelo, hacer un cuestionario. Como modelo 
para una entrevista, él dice aquí a cinco personas sobre sus 
hábitos del Internet. En la pantalla hay instrucciones, clips 
video de ésos que son entrevistados con para la práctica y 
conexiones a las pistas en cómo poner juntas preguntas. Hay 
también instrucciones "al ejercicio del cheque de la comprensión" -.
En este ejercicio el estudiante combinará una contestación 
correcta con una pregunta correcta moviendo al entrevistador al lado 
de la persona adecuada. El estudiante puede después sugerir 
cuestiones de la entrevista sus el propios al profesor y entrevistarse
con a sus classmates sobre diversos temas.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>3992</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>open activity</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">13-15</string>
            <string language="sv">13-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Listening comprehension, practical application of the language knowledge Working two and two</string>
            <string language="sv">Hörförståelse, praktisk tillämpning av språkkunskaperna
Pararbete</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82539</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>image/bmp</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/gatuintervju_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
