<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82786</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82786</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1554</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="fi">Katuhaastattelu</string>
            <string language="en">Street Interwiews</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Straße Interwiews</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Rue Interwiews</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Rua Interwiews</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Via Interwiews</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Οδός Interwiews</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Calle Interwiews</string>
          </title>
          <language>fi</language>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Oppilaan tehtävänä on mallihaastattelujen ja ohjeiden avulla laatia englanninkielinen kyselylomake. Mallina tarjotuissa videoleikkeissä haastateltavat kertovat Internetin käyttötavoistaan. Perusruudulla on tehtävätoimeksianto, koehaastateltavien videoleikkeet sekä linkit kysymystenlaadintavinkkeihin ja ”Comprehension check” –tehtävään. Tehtävässä oppilaan tulee yhdistää oikea vastaus oikeaan kysymykseen siirtämällä haastattelijahahmot oikeiden henkilöiden viereen. Mallikysymysten lisäksi oppilaat voivat ehdottaa opettajalle omia haastattelukysymyksiä ja haastatella sitten opiskelijatovereitaan eri aiheista.
Aihio havainnollistaa digitaalisen oppimateriaalin merkitystä tehtäväperusteisen opetuksen (TBL) tukemisessa.</string>
            <string language="en">It is the student’s task to create a questionnaire with the help of model interviews and instructions. The persons in interviewed in the model video clips will tell about their ways of using the internet. On the screen the student will find the instructions for the task, the model video clips and the links to the hints for making the questionnaire and to the Comprehension check exercise. In the task the student has to match the correct answer with the correct question by moving the interviewers next to the right persons. In addition to model questions the student can give suggestions on his/her own questions and the interview the fellow students on different subjects. This task illustrates the significance of the use of digital learning material in task-based leaning.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Es ist die student?s Aufgabe, einen Fragebogen mit 
Hilfe der vorbildlichen Interviews und der Anweisungen herzustellen. 
Die Personen, die innen in den vorbildlichen videoclips 
interviewt werden, erklären über ihre Methoden des Verwendens des 
Internets. Auf dem Bildschirm findet der Kursteilnehmer die 
Anweisungen für die Aufgabe, die videoclips des Modells und die Links
zu den Tips für das Bilden des Fragebogens und zum Erfassen 
überprüfen Übung. In der Aufgabe muß der Kursteilnehmer die 
korrekte Antwort mit der korrekten Frage zusammenbringen, indem er die
Interviewer nahe bei den rechten Personen verschiebt. 
Zusätzlich zu den Modellfragen kann der Kursteilnehmer 
Vorschläge auf seinen/ihr eigenen Fragen und dem Interview geben die 
Mitkursteilnehmer auf unterschiedlichen Themen. Diese Aufgabe 
veranschaulicht die Stichhaltigkeit des Gebrauches von digitalem 
erlernenmaterial im Aufgabe-gegründeten Lehnen.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est les student?s chargent de créer un 
questionnaire avec l'aide des entrevues et des instructions modèles. 
Les personnes dedans interviewées dans les clips visuels 
modèles diront au sujet de leurs voies d'utiliser l'Internet. 
Sur l'écran l'étudiant trouvera les instructions pour le 
charger, les clips visuels de modèle et les liens aux conseils 
pour faire le questionnaire et à la compréhension contrôlent 
l'exercice. Dans le charger l'étudiant doit apparier la 
réponse correcte avec la question correcte en déplaçant les 
interviewers à côté des bonnes personnes. En plus des 
questions de modèle l'étudiant peut donner des suggestions sur ses 
propres questions et l'entrevue les étudiants de camarade sur 
différents sujets. Ceci chargent illustre la 
signification de l'utilisation du matériel d'étude digital dans le 
penchement de charger-based.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">É a tarefa dos student?s criar um questionário 
com a ajuda das entrevistas e das instruções modelo. As 
pessoas entrevistadas dentro nos grampos video modelo dirão sobre 
suas maneiras de usar o Internet. Na tela o estudante 
encontrará as instruções para a tarefa, os grampos video do modelo 
e as ligações às sugestões para fazer o questionário e à 
compreensão verificam o exercício. Na tarefa o estudante tem 
que combinar a resposta correta com a pergunta correta movendo os 
interviewers ao lado das pessoas direitas. Além para modelar 
perguntas o estudante pode dar sugestões em his/her próprias 
perguntas e na entrevista os estudantes do companheiro em assuntos 
diferentes. Esta tarefa ilustra o significado do uso do material
de aprendizagem digital em inclinar-se tarefa-baseado.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">È l'operazione degli student?s creare un 
questionario con l'aiuto delle interviste e delle istruzioni di 
modello. Le persone dentro intervistate nelle video clip di 
modello diranno a circa i loro modi di usando il Internet. Sullo
schermo l'allievo troverà le istruzioni per l'operazione, le video 
clip del modello ed i collegamenti ai suggerimenti per fare il 
questionario ed alla comprensione controllano l'esercitazione. 
Nell'operazione l'allievo deve abbinare la risposta corretta con
la domanda corretta spostando gli intervistatori vicino alle persone 
giuste. Oltre che le domande del modello l'allievo può dare i 
suggerimenti sulle sue proprie domande e sull'intervista gli allievi 
del collega sugli oggetti differenti. Questa operazione illustra
l'importanza dell'uso di materiale imparante digitale nell'inclinzione
operazione-basata.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Είναι η στοιχειώδης εργασία student?s να 
δημιουργηθεί ένα ερωτηματολόγιο με τη βοήθεια των πρότυπων 
συνεντεύξεων και των οδηγιών. Τα πρόσωπα παρμένος 
συνέντευξη από στους πρότυπους τηλεοπτικούς συνδετήρες θα πουν 
για τους τρόπους τους το Διαδίκτυο. Στην οθόνη ο σπουδαστής 
θα βρεί τις οδηγίες για τη στοιχειώδη εργασία, τους πρότυπους 
τηλεοπτικούς συνδετήρες και τις συνδέσεις με τους υπαινιγμούς για 
την παραγωγή του ερωτηματολογίου και στην άσκηση ελέγχου 
κατανόησης. Στη στοιχειώδη εργασία ο σπουδαστής πρέπει να 
ταιριάξει με τη σωστή απάντηση τη σωστή ερώτηση με την κίνηση 
των ερευνητών δίπλα στα σωστά πρόσωπα. Εκτός από τις 
πρότυπες ερωτήσεις ο σπουδαστής μπορεί να δώσει στις προτάσεις 
σχετικά με τις ερωτήσεις του/της και τη συνέντευξη τους 
συμφοιτητές στα διαφορετικά θέματα. Αυτή η στοιχειώδης 
εργασία επεξηγεί τη σημασία της χρήσης του ψηφιακού υλικού 
εκμάθησης στην εργασία-βασισμένη κλίση.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Es la tarea de los student?s crear un cuestionario
con la ayuda de las entrevistas y de las instrucciones modelo. 
Las personas adentro entrevistadas con en los clips video modelo
hablarán de sus maneras de usar el Internet. En la pantalla el 
estudiante encontrará las instrucciones para la tarea, los clips 
video del modelo y las conexiones a las indirectas para hacer el 
cuestionario y a la comprensión controlan ejercicio. En la 
tarea el estudiante tiene que corresponder con la respuesta correcta 
con la pregunta correcta moviendo a los entrevistadores al lado de las
personas adecuadas. Además de preguntas del modelo el 
estudiante puede dar sugerencias en su propias preguntas y la 
entrevista los estudiantes del compañero en diversos temas. 
Esta tarea ilustra la significación del uso del material que 
aprende digital en inclinarse tarea-basado.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1554</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-12</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-13</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Byholm;Tea;;;
FN:Tea Byholm
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-13</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>fi</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>open activity</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">13-15</string>
            <string language="fi">13-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="fi">Kuullunymmärtäminen, kielitaidon soveltaminen käytäntöön</string>
            <string language="en">Listening comprehension, practical use of English</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">englannin kieli</string>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielet</string>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>710</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="fi">kielten opetus</string>
                <string language="en">language teaching</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82786</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://www.edu.fi/oppimateriaalit/aihiot/fi/englannin_kieli/katuhaastattelu/co1_10.exe</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
