<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82488</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82488</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>1754</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">BurgerWriter</string>
            <string language="en">BurgerWriter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">BurgerWriter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">BurgerWriter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">BurgerWriter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">BurgerWriter</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">BurgerWriter</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">L'idea di questo oggetto di apprendimento è trasformare le esercitazioni di grammatica in un gioco. Nell'insegnare i principi fondamentali in inglese, ci sono molte strutture semplici che devono essere imparate. Queste strutture devono essere esercitate in modo che lo studente possa formularle automaticamente. Quindi, questi oggetti educativi di apprendimento sono particolarmente adatti quando le si impara. Il compito dell'allievo è di formare frasi grammaticalmente corrette scegliendo una parole o delle frasi da ognuno dei tre strati dell' hamburger. Le frasi  devono anche descrivere la piccola immagine sullo schermo, che cambia con ogni esercitazione. Se le frasi sono unite correttamente, l'allievo le sentirà leggere ad alta voce. Per ogni frase corretta, lo studente riceverà un piccolo hamburger nell'area di riscontro. L'allievo capisce quanti punti ha dal numero di hamburger sullo schermo.</string>
            <string language="en">The idea of this learning object is to make grammar exercises into a game.  When teaching the basics in English, there are many simple structures that need to be learned.  These structures need to be practiced so that the learner can form them automatically.  Thus, these edutainment learning objects are especially appropriate when learning them.
The learner’s task is to put together grammatically correct sentences by choosing a word or phrase from each of the three layers of the hamburger.  The sentences also have to describe the small picture on the screen, which changes with each exercise.  If the sentences are put together correctly, the learner will hear it read aloud.  For each correct sentence, the learner will receive a small hamburger in the feedback area.  The learner knows how many points he/she has from the number of hamburgers on the screen.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Die Idee dieser erlernennachricht ist, 
Grammatikübungen in ein Spiel zu bilden. Wenn man die 
Grundlagen auf englisch unterrichtet, gibt es viele einfache 
Strukturen, die erlernt werden müssen. Diese Strukturen müssen
geübt werden, damit der Anfänger sie automatisch bilden kann. 
So sind diese edutainment erlernennachrichten besonders 
angebracht, wenn erlernenthem.The learner?s Aufgabe, zusammenzufügen 
die grammatisch korrekten Programmsätze ist, indem sie ein Wort oder 
eine Phrase von jeder der drei Schichten des Hamburgers wählt. 
Die Programmsätze müssen die kleine Abbildung auf dem 
Bildschirm auch beschreiben, der mit jeder Übung ändert. Wenn 
die Programmsätze richtig zusammengefügt werden, hört der Anfänger
ihn, laut zu lesen. Für jeden korrekten Programmsatz empfängt 
der Anfänger einen kleinen Hamburger im Feedbackbereich. Der 
Anfänger weiß, zeigt daß wieviele, hat he/she von der Zahl 
Hamburgern auf dem Bildschirm.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">L'idée de cet objet d'étude est de transformer 
des exercices de grammaire en un jeu. En enseignant les 
fondations en anglais, il y a beaucoup de structures simples qui 
doivent être apprises. Ces structures doivent être pratiquées
de sorte que l'étudiant puisse les former automatiquement. 
Ainsi, ces objets d'étude d'edutainment sont particulièrement 
appropriés quand les learner?s d'étude de them.The chargent 
doit remonter des phrases grammaticalement correctes en choisissant un
mot ou une expression de chacune des trois couches de l'hamburger. 
Les phrases doivent également décrire la petite image sur 
l'écran, qui change avec chaque exercice. Si les phrases sont 
remontées correctement, l'étudiant l'entendra lire à haute voix. 
Pour chaque phrase correcte, l'étudiant recevra un petit 
hamburger dans la zone de feedback. L'étudiant sait que combien
se dirige he/she a du nombre d'hamburgers sur l'écran.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">A idéia deste objeto de aprendizagem é fazer 
exercícios da gramática em um jogo. Ao ensinar os princípios 
em inglês, há muitas estruturas simples que necessitam ser 
aprendidas. Estas estruturas necessitam ser praticadas de modo 
que o learner possa lhes dar forma automaticamente. Assim, estes
objetos de aprendizagem do edutainment são especial apropriados 
quando a tarefa de aprendizagem dos learner?s de them.The é unir as 
sentenças gramaticalmente corretas escolhendo uma palavra ou uma 
frase de cada uma das três camadas do hamburger. As sentenças 
também têm que descrever o retrato pequeno na tela, que muda com 
cada exercício. Se as sentenças forem unidas corretamente, o 
learner ouvi-la-á ler alto. Para cada sentença correta, o 
learner receberá um hamburger pequeno na área do feedback. O 
learner sabe que quanto apontam he/she tem do número dos hamburgers 
na tela.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Η ιδέα αυτού του αντικειμένου εκμάθησης είναι να 
γίνουν οι ασκήσεις γραμματικής σε ένα παιχνίδι. Κατά 
διδασκαλία των βασικών στα αγγλικά, υπάρχουν την πολλές απλές 
δομές που πρέπει να μαθευτούν. Αυτές οι δομές πρέπει να 
ασκηθούν έτσι ώστε ο αρχάριος μπορεί να τις διαμορφώσει 
αυτόματα. Κατά συνέπεια, αυτά τα αντικείμενα εκμάθησης 
edutainment είναι ιδιαίτερα κατάλληλα κατά τον εκμάθηση τα 
Η στοιχειώδης εργασία learner?s είναι να τεθούν μαζί 
γραμματικά οι σωστές προτάσεις με την επιλογή μιας λέξης ή μιας 
φράσης από κάθε ένα από τα τρία στρώματα του χάμπουργκερ. 
Οι προτάσεις πρέπει επίσης να περιγράψουν τη μικρή εικόνα 
στην οθόνη, η οποία αλλάζει με κάθε άσκηση. Εάν οι 
προτάσεις τίθενται μαζί σωστά, ο αρχάριος θα ακούσει ότι 
διάβασε μεγαλοφώνως. Για κάθε σωστή πρόταση, ο αρχάριος θα
λάβει ένα μικρό χάμπουργκερ στην περιοχή ανατροφοδότησης. 
Ο αρχάριος ξέρει πόσα σημεία έχει από τον αριθμό 
χάμπουργκερ στην οθόνη.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La idea de este objeto que aprende es hacer 
ejercicios de la gramática en un juego. Al enseñar los 
fundamentos en inglés, hay muchas estructuras simples que necesitan 
ser aprendidas. Estas estructuras necesitan ser practicadas de 
modo que el principiante pueda formarlas automáticamente. Así,
estos objetos que aprenden del edutainment son especialmente 
apropiados cuando la tarea de los learner?s de them.The que aprende es
poner juntas sentencias gramatical correctas eligiendo una palabra o 
una frase de cada uno de las tres capas de la hamburguesa. Las 
sentencias también tienen que describir el cuadro pequeño en la 
pantalla, que cambia con cada ejercicio. Si las sentencias se 
ponen juntas correctamente, el principiante la oirá leer en voz alta.
Para cada sentencia correcta, el principiante recibirá una 
hamburguesa pequeña en el área del feedback. El principiante 
sabe que cuántos señalan he/she tiene del número de hamburguesas en
la pantalla.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>1754</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-01-26</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-21</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">9-13</string>
            <string language="en">9-13</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Esercitazione pratica  in inglese di strutture grammaticali di base </string>
            <string language="en">Practicing basic grammatical structures in English</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82488</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>application/binary</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/burger_writer_eng.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
