<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/311157949</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>311157949</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>15518</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="it">La Protezione della Natura in Europa</string>
            <string language="en">Nature Protection in Europe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Naturschutz in Europa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Protection de nature en Europe</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Proteção de natureza em Europa</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Προστασία φύσης στην Ευρώπη</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Protección de naturaleza en Europa</string>
          </title>
          <language>en</language>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Un insieme interattivo di vari tipi di esercizi, argomenti, immagini e siti web sulla protezione della natura in Europa. È progettata per incoraggiare gli allievi a rischiare.  Questi possono usare le immagini ed i collegamenti per stabilire il contesto. Progredendo nel lavoro attraverso tutti gli esercizi, gli allievi gradatamente costruiscono una figura completa. Tale oggetto di apprendimento aspira ad accrescere la loro consapevolezza sulla ampia varietà degli habitat naturali e sulla grande diversità di fauna e flora selvatica in Europa, la loro estinzione e la minaccia al loro habitat naturale, le azioni europee per la loro protezione, la consapevolezza dell'esistenza di personaggi famosi passati e dei loro pensieri sulla natura, miranti particolarmente al rispetto della natura. Stimolerà la motivazione del principiante e migliorerà il processo di apprendimento. Può essere collegato a diversi argomenti nel programma di studi. Gli allievi possono lavorare individualmente, a coppia o a gruppi di tre.</string>
            <string language="en">An interactive set of various exercise types, topics, images and websites about nature protection in Europe. It is designed to encourage pupils to take risks. They can use images and links to establish the context. As they work through all exercises pupils gradually build up a complete picture.
This learning object aims at raising awareness of a vast range of natural habitats and a great diversity of wild flora and fauna in Europe, their extinction and threaten to their natural habitat, European actions on their protection, awareness of the famous persons of the past and their thoughts about nature, aiming especially at the respect of nature. It will stimulate the motivation of the learner and increase the learning process. It can be linked to many subjects in the curriculum. 
Pupils can work out for themselves individually, in pairs or groups of three.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">Europa</string>
            <string language="en">Europe</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">natura</string>
            <string language="en">nature</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">rispetto</string>
            <string language="en">respect</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">biodiversità</string>
            <string language="en">biodiversity</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">specie in pericolo</string>
            <string language="en">endangered species</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">la convenzione di Berna</string>
            <string language="en">the Bern Convention</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">Berna</string>
            <string language="en">Bern</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">ambiente</string>
            <string language="en">environment</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">Terra</string>
            <string language="en">Earth</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">accordo</string>
            <string language="en">agreement</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">protezione</string>
            <string language="en">protection</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">conservazione</string>
            <string language="en">conservation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">persone famose del passato</string>
            <string language="en">famous persons of the past</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="it">citazioni sulla natura</string>
            <string language="en">quotes on nature</string>
          </keyword>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Ein interaktives Set verschiedene Übung Typen, 
Themen, Bilder und Web site über Naturschutz in Europa. Es ist 
konzipiert, um Schüler anzuregen, Gefahren zu nehmen. Sie 
können Bilder und Links verwenden, um den Kontext herzustellen. 
Während sie durch alle Übungen arbeiten, die Schüler 
stufenweise ein komplettes picture.This erlernend aufbauen, daß 
Nachricht anstrebt, Bewußtsein einer beträchtlichen Strecke der 
natürlichen Lebensräume und einer großen Verschiedenartigkeit der 
wilden Flora und der Fauna in Europa aufzuwerfen, bedrohen ihre 
Löschung und zu ihrem natürlichen Lebensraum, zu europäischen 
Tätigkeiten auf ihrem Schutz, zu Bewußtsein der berühmten Personen 
der Vergangenheit und zu ihren Gedanken über Natur und zielen 
besonders auf den Respekt der Natur ab. Sie regt den Beweggrund 
des Anfängers an und erhöht den Lernprozeß. Sie kann mit 
vielen Themen im Lehrplan gebunden werden. Schüler können für
selbst, in den Paaren oder in den Gruppen von drei einzeln 
ausarbeiten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Un ensemble interactif de divers types, sujets, 
images et sites Web d'exercice au sujet de la protection de nature en 
Europe. Elle est conçue pour encourager des élèves à prendre
des risques. Ils peuvent employer des images et des liens pour 
établir le contexte. Pendant qu'ils travaillent par tous les 
exercices que les élèves accumulent graduellement un picture.This 
complet apprenant que l'objet vise à soulever la conscience d'un 
vaste intervalle des habitats normaux et d'une grande diversité de 
flore sauvage et de la faune en Europe, leur extinction et menacent à
leur habitat normal, actions européennes sur leur protection, 
conscience des personnes célèbres du passé et à leurs pensées au 
sujet de nature, visant particulièrement le respect de la nature. 
Elle stimulera la motivation de l'étudiant et augmentera 
l'apprentissage. Elle peut être jointe à beaucoup de sujets 
dans le programme d'études. Les élèves peuvent établir pour 
eux-mêmes individuellement, dans les paires ou les groupes de trois.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Um jogo interativo de vários tipos, tópicos, 
imagens e Web site do exercício sobre a proteção de natureza em 
Europa. É projetada incentivar os alunos fazer exame de riscos.
Podem usar imagens e ligações estabelecer o contexto. 
Enquanto trabalham com todos os exercícios que as pupilas 
constroem gradualmente acima de um picture.This completo que aprendem 
que o objeto visa levantar a consciência de uma escala vasta de 
habitats naturais e de uma diversidade grande do flora selvagem e do 
fauna em Europa, sua extinção e ameaça a sua habitat natural, 
ações européias em sua proteção, consciência das pessoas famosas
do passado e a seus pensamentos sobre a natureza, apontando especial 
no respeito da natureza. Estimulará o motivation do learner e 
aumentará o processo de aprendizagem. Pode ser ligada a muitos 
assuntos no curriculum. As pupilas podem trabalhar para fora 
para se individualmente, em pares ou grupos de três.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ένα διαλογικό σύνολο διάφορων τύπων, θεμάτων, 
εικόνων και ιστοχώρων άσκησης για την προστασία φύσης στην 
Ευρώπη. Έχει ως σκοπό να ενθαρρύνει τους μαθητές για να 
διατρέξει τους κινδύνους. Μπορούν να χρησιμοποιήσουν τις 
εικόνες και τις συνδέσεις για να καθιερώσουν το πλαίσιο. 
Δεδομένου ότι λειτουργούν μέσω όλων των μαθητών ασκήσεων 
ενισχύστε βαθμιαία μια πλήρη εικόνα Αυτό το αντικείμενο 
εκμάθησης στοχεύει να βελτιώσει την πληροφόρηση μιας απέραντης 
σειράς των φυσικών βιότοπων και μιας μεγάλης ποικιλομορφίας της 
άγριας χλωρίδας και της πανίδας στην Ευρώπη, η εξάλειψή τους και
απειλεί στο φυσικό βιότοπό τους, ευρωπαϊκές ενέργειες στην 
προστασία τους, τη συνειδητοποίηση των διάσημων προσώπων του 
παρελθόντος και τις σκέψεις τους για τη φύση, που στοχεύουν 
ειδικά στο σεβασμό της φύσης. Θα υποκινήσει το κίνητρο του 
αρχαρίου και θα αυξήσει τη διαδικασία εκμάθησης. Μπορεί να 
συνδεθεί με πολλά θέματα στο πρόγραμμα σπουδών. Οι μαθητές
μπορούν να επιλύσουν για τους χωριστά, ανά τα ζευγάρια ή τις 
ομάδες τριών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Un conjunto interactivo de varios tipos, asuntos, 
imágenes y Web site del ejercicio sobre la protección de naturaleza 
en Europa. Se diseña para animar a pupilas que tomen riesgos. 
Pueden utilizar imágenes y conexiones para establecer el 
contexto. Mientras que trabajan con todos los ejercicios que las
pupilas acumulan gradualmente un picture.This completo que aprenden 
que el objeto tiene como objetivo el levantar de conocimiento de un 
rango extenso de habitat naturales y de una gran diversidad de la 
flora salvaje y de la fauna en Europa, su extinción y amenaza a su 
habitat natural, acciones europeas en su protección, conocimiento de 
las personas famosas del pasado y a sus pensamientos sobre la 
naturaleza, apuntando especialmente al respecto de la naturaleza. 
Estimulará la motivación del principiante y aumentará el 
proceso de aprendizaje. Puede ser conectada a muchos temas en el
plan de estudios. Las pupilas pueden resolverse para sí mismos 
individualmente, en pares o grupos de tres.</string>
          </description>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Europa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Natur</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Respekt</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Biodiversity</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">gefährdete Sorte</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">die Bern Versammlung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Bern</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Umgebung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Masse</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Vereinbarung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Schutz</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Erhaltung</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">berühmte Personen der Vergangenheit</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Anführungsstriche auf Natur</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">l'Europe</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">nature</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">respect</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">biodiversité</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">espèces mises en danger</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">la convention de Berne</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Berne</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">environnement</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">La terre</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">accord</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">protection</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">économie</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">personnes célèbres du passé</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">guillemet sur la nature</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Europa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">natureza</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">respeito</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">biodiversity</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">espécie posta em perigo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">a convenção de Berna</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Berna</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">ambiente</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Terra</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">acordo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">proteção</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">conservation</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">pessoas famosas do passado</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">citações na natureza</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ευρώπη</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">φύση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">σεβασμός</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">βιοποικιλότητα</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">απειλούμενα υπό εξαφάνιση είδη</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">η Συνθήκη της Βέρνης</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Βέρνη</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">περιβάλλον</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Γη</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">συμφωνία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">προστασία</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">συντήρηση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">διάσημα πρόσωπα του παρελθόντος</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-el">αποσπάσματα στη φύση</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Europa</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">naturaleza</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">respecto</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">biodiversidad</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">especie puesta en peligro</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">la convención de Berna</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Berna</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">ambiente</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Tierra</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">acuerdo</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">protección</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">conservación</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">personas famosas del pasado</string>
          </keyword>
          <keyword>
            <string language="x-mt-es">cotizaciones en la naturaleza</string>
          </keyword>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Dusparic;Biserka;;;
FN:Biserka Dusparic
ORG:Osnovna skola 
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>15518</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Dusparic;Biserka;;;
FN:Biserka Dusparic
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2006-06-04</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-19</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-19</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-19</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Lattanzi;Giuseppina;;;
FN:Giuseppina Lattanzi
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-19</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>en</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>web page</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">12-15</string>
            <string language="en">12-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="it">Leggi l'articolo "Ama e proteggi la natura: Sii un europeo "verde""
http://myeurope.eun.org/ww/en/pub/myeurope/home/schools/teacher_s_corner/nature.htm 
Quindi verifica la tua conoscenza e apprendi di più utilizzando informazioni autentiche dai siti selezionati.</string>
            <string language="en">Read the article “Love and protect nature: Be a “green” European!”http://myeurope.eun.org/ww/en/pub/myeurope/home/schools/teacher_s_corner/nature.htm  Then test your knowledge and learn more using authentic information from the selected websites.</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/DerivativeWorks" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>432</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">environmental protection</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>431</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">environmental education</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>430</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">environment</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>311157949</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>text/plain</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://myeurope.eun.org/shared/data/myeurope/2005/los/01/bd/myweb/index.htm</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
