<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82919</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82919</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>3990</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Hobbies</string>
            <string language="sv">Hobbies</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Liebhabereien</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Passe-temps</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Passatempos</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Hobby</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Χόμπι</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Manías</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">The goal of this learning object is to practice vocabulary in a context rich multimedia environment and with the aid of authentic sounding speech. The student is to recognize the most central parts in a description of a hobby and link this to a picture that represents that hobby. The student sees pictures that represent various hobbies plus different speech bubbles. By clicking on a speech bubble the student hears a description of a hobby, without that the actual name of the hobby being mentioned. The student is to move the speech bubbles on top of the picture of the hobby that is being described. If the placement is correct, the bubble disappears and the student receives a comment confirming the action. After each correct reply a so-called gapfill-square will pop up, displaying the sentence just heard. The student will fill in the words - or the word - missing in the gaps. This means that the student is forced to listen more carefully to his response and it also strengthens the memorisation of the words that link to the hobbies. The bubbles that are not placed correctly slide, after a comment, back to their original places. In the next phase, the words familiar from the previous exercise are practised. Instead of bubbles, there are now talking bars on the screen. By clicking one of them, the student hears the name of a hobby. The student will move the sections on a correct hobby picture. When the student is done, he or she can check the exercise by clicking the button "Control". The sections that have been placed correctly disappear and the student hears the word and sees it written. The sections that have not been placed correctly slide back to their places and the student is urged to try again. By seeing the word the student gets help to memorise it and it makes the vocabulary studies meaningful. Hearing the words also means added value; the student experiences the word with many senses and in this way the learning object supports several kinds of learning styles.


</string>
            <string language="sv">Målet med detta lärobjekt är att öva ordförrådet i en kontextrik multimediamiljö och med hjälp av tal som låter autentiskt. Eleven ska känna igen det centrala i en beskrivning av en hobby och koppla det till en bild som föreställer hobbyn.

Eleven ser bilder som föreställer olika hobbyer samt olika pratbubblor. Genom att klicka på pratbubblan hör eleven en beskrivning av en hobby, utan att själva namnet på hobbyn nämns. Eleven ska flytta pratbubblorna ovanpå bilden av den hobby som beskrivs. Om placeringen är korrekt försvinner bubblan och eleven får en bekräftande kommentar. Efter varje korrekt svar dyker det också upp en s.k. gapfill-ruta, där den mening som just hörts finns nedskriven. Eleven ska fylla i de/t ord som fattas i luckorna. Detta gör att eleven tvingas lyssna noggrannare på sin respons och det förstärker också inlärningen av orden som anknyter till hobbyerna. De bubblor som placeras fel glider, efter en kommentar, tillbaka till sina ursprungliga platser.
I nästa moment övas de ord som blev bekanta i den förra övningen. I stället för bubblor finns det nu talande balkar i rutan. Genom att klicka på dem hör eleven namnet på hobbyer. Eleven ska flytta balkarna på rätt hobbybild. När eleven är klar kan han eller hon kontrollera uppgiften genom att klicka på knappen ’Kontrollera’. De balkar som placerats korrekt försvinner och eleven hör ordet och ser det skrivet. De felplacerade balkarna glider tillbaka till sina platser och eleven uppmanas att försöka på nytt.
Genom att se ordet får eleven hjälp med att komma ihåg det och det gör ordförrådsstudierna meningsfulla. Också att höra orden ger mervärde; eleven upplever ordet med många sinnen och på så sätt stödjer lärobjektet många slags inlärningsstilar.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Das Ziel dieser erlernennachricht ist, Wortschatz 
in einer reichen Multimediaumgebung des Kontextes und mit dem 
Hilfsmittel der authentischen klingenden Rede zu üben. Der 
Kursteilnehmer soll die zentralsten Teile in einer Beschreibung einer 
Liebhaberei erkennen und dieses mit einer Abbildung binden, die diese 
Liebhaberei darstellt. Der Kursteilnehmer sieht Abbildungen, die
verschiedene Liebhabereien plus unterschiedliche Redeluftblasen 
darstellen. Indem er auf einer Redeluftblase klickt, hört der 
Kursteilnehmer eine Beschreibung einer Liebhaberei, ohne die der 
tatsächliche Name der Liebhaberei, die erwähnt wird. Der 
Kursteilnehmer soll die Redeluftblasen auf die Abbildung der 
Liebhaberei verschieben, die beschrieben wird. Wenn die 
Plazierung korrekt ist, verschwindet die Luftblase und der 
Kursteilnehmer empfängt einen Kommentar, der die Tätigkeit 
bestätigt. Nachdem jede korrekte Antwort, die ein sogenanntes 
Gapfillquadrat oben knallt, den Programmsatz anzeigend hörte gerade. 
Der Kursteilnehmer füllt die Wörter - oder das Wort - 
vermissend in den Abständen aus. Dies heißt, daß der 
Kursteilnehmer erzwungen wird, zu seiner Antwort sorgfältig zu hören
und sie auch das Memorieren der Wörter verstärkt, die mit den 
Liebhabereien binden. Die Luftblasen, die nicht richtig plaziert
werden, schieben, nachdem ein Kommentar, zurück zu ihren 
ursprünglichen Plätzen. In der folgenden Phase werden die 
Wörter, die von der vorhergehenden Übung vertraut sind, geübt. 
Anstelle von den Luftblasen dort sprechen jetzt Stäbe auf dem 
Bildschirm. Indem er einen von ihnen anklickt, hört der 
Kursteilnehmer den Namen einer Liebhaberei. Der Kursteilnehmer 
verschiebt die Kapitel auf einer korrekten Liebhabereiabbildung. 
Wenn der Kursteilnehmer getan wird, können er oder sie die 
Übung überprüfen, indem er die Taste "Steuerung" anklickt. 
Die Kapitel, die richtig verschwinden plaziert worden sind und 
der Kursteilnehmer hört das Wort und sieht es geschrieben. Die 
Kapitel, die nicht richtig plaziert worden sind, schieben zurück zu 
ihren Plätzen und dem Kursteilnehmer wird gedrängt, um noch einmal 
zu versuchen. Indem er das Wort sieht, erhält der 
Kursteilnehmer Hilfe, um sie zu memorieren und sie Marken der 
Wortschatz studiert aussagefähiges. Die Wörter zu hören 
bedeutet auch hinzugefügten Wert; der Kursteilnehmer erfährt 
das Wort mit vielen Richtungen und auf diese Art unterstützt die 
erlernennachricht einige Arten erlernenarten.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Le but de cet objet d'étude est de pratiquer le 
vocabulaire dans un environnement riche de multimédia de contexte et 
à l'aide du discours retentissant authentique. L'étudiant doit
identifier les parties les plus centrales dans une description d'un 
passe-temps et joindre ceci à une image qui représente ce 
passe-temps. L'étudiant voit les images qui représentent de 
divers passe-temps plus différentes bulles de la parole. En 
cliquant sur une bulle de la parole l'étudiant entend une 
description d'un passe-temps, sans cela le nom réel du passe-temps 
étant mentionné. L'étudiant doit déplacer les bulles de la 
parole sur l'image du passe-temps qui est décrit. Si le 
placement est correct, la bulle disparaît et l'étudiant reçoit un 
commentaire confirmant l'action. Après que chaque réponse 
correcte que une prétendue gapfill-place sautera vers le haut, 
affichant la phrase juste entendue. L'étudiant complétera les 
mots - ou le mot - manquant dans les lacunes. Ceci signifie que 
l'étudiant est forcé d'écouter plus soigneusement sa réponse et 
elle renforce également la mémorisation des mots qui joignent aux 
passe-temps. Les bulles qui ne sont pas placées correctement 
glissent, après qu'un commentaire, de nouveau à leurs endroits 
initiaux. Dans la phase suivante, les mots familiers de 
l'exercice précédent sont pratiqués. Au lieu des bulles, là 
parlent maintenant des barres sur l'écran. En cliquant
l'une d'entre elles, l'étudiant entend le nom d'un passe-temps. 
L'étudiant déplacera les sections sur une image correcte de 
passe-temps. Quand l'étudiant est fait, lui ou elle peut 
contrôler l'exercice en cliquant le bouton "commande". 
Les sections qui ont été placées correctement disparaissent 
et l'étudiant entend le mot et le voit écrit. Les sections que
le démuni placé correctement glissent de nouveau à leurs 
endroits et à l'étudiant est invitées pour essayer encore. En
voyant le mot l'étudiant obtient l'aide pour la mémoriser et elle 
des marques le vocabulaire étudie signicatif. Entendre les mots
signifie également la valeur ajoutée ; l'étudiant éprouve le
mot avec beaucoup de sens et de cette façon l'objet d'étude supporte
plusieurs genres de modèles d'étude.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">O objetivo deste objeto de aprendizagem é 
praticar o vocabulário em um ambiente rico dos multimedia do contexto
e com o dae (dispositivo automático de entrada) do discurso soando 
authentic. O estudante deve reconhecer as partes as mais 
centrais em uma descrição de um passatempo e ligar isto a um retrato
que represente esse passatempo. O estudante vê os retratos que 
representam vários passatempos mais bolhas diferentes do discurso. 
Estalando em uma bolha do discurso o estudante ouve uma 
descrição de um passatempo, sem aquela o nome real do passatempo que
está sendo mencionado. O estudante deve mover as bolhas do 
discurso no alto do retrato do passatempo que está sendo descrito. 
Se a colocação estiver correta, a bolha desaparece e o 
estudante recebe um comentário que confirma a ação. Depois 
que cada resposta que correta um gapfill-quadrado so-called estalará 
acima, indicando a sentença ouvida apenas. O estudante 
preencherá as palavras - ou a palavra - que faltam nas aberturas. 
Isto significa que o estudante está forçado a escutar mais com
cuidado sua resposta e strengthens também o memorisation das palavras
que ligam aos passatempos. As bolhas que não são colocadas 
corretamente deslizam, depois que um comentário, traseiro a seus 
lugares originais. Na fase seguinte, as palavras familiares do 
exercício precedente são praticadas. Em vez das bolhas, lá 
estão falando agora barras na tela. Estalando um delas, o 
estudante ouve o nome de um passatempo. O estudante moverá as 
seções em um retrato correto do passatempo. Quando o estudante
é feito, ou podem verificar o exercício estalando a tecla 
"controle". As seções que foram colocadas corretamente 
desaparecem e o estudante ouvem a palavra e vêem-na escrita. As
seções que não foram colocadas corretamente deslizam para trás a 
seus lugares e ao estudante são incitadas para tentar outra vez. 
Vendo a palavra o estudante começa a ajuda memorise a e makes o
vocabulário estuda significativo. Ouvir as palavras significa 
também o valor adicionado; o estudante experimenta a palavra 
com muitos sentidos e nesta maneira o objeto de aprendizagem suporta 
diversos tipos de estilos de aprendizagem.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">L'obiettivo di questo oggetto imparante è di 
esercitarsi nel vocabolario in un ambiente ricco di multimedia di 
contesto e con l'aiuto di discorso suonante autentico. L'allievo
deve riconoscere le parti più centrali in una descrizione di un hobby
e collegare questo ad un'immagine che rappresenta quell'hobby. 
L'allievo vede le immagini che rappresentano i vari hobby più 
le bolle differenti di discorso. Scattandosi su una bolla di 
discorso l'allievo sente una descrizione di un hobby, senza quella il 
nome reale dell'hobby che è accennato. L'allievo deve spostare 
le bolle di discorso in cima all'immagine dell'hobby che sta 
descrivendo. Se la disposizione è corretta, la bolla sparisce e
l'allievo riceve un commento che conferma l'azione. Dopo che 
ogni risposta che corretta un cosiddetto gapfill-quadrato schioccherà
in su, visualizzando la frase sentita appena. L'allievo 
riempirà le parole - o la parola - che mancano nelle lacune. 
Ciò significa che l'allievo è costretto a ascoltare più con 
attenzione la sua risposta ed egualmente rinforza la memorizzazione 
delle parole che collegano agli hobby. Le bolle che non sono 
disposte correttamente fanno scorrere, dopo che un commento, di nuovo 
ai loro posti originali. Nella fase prossima, le parole esperte 
dall'esercitazione precedente si esercitano in. Anziché le 
bolle, là ora stanno comunicando le barre sullo schermo. 
Scattando loro una, l'allievo sente il nome di un hobby. 
L'allievo sposterà le sezioni su un'immagine corretta di hobby.
Quando l'allievo è fatto, lui o lei può controllare 
l'esercitazione scattando il tasto "controllo". Le sezioni che 
sono state disposte correttamente spariscono e l'allievo sente la 
parola e la vede scritta. Le sezioni che non sono state disposte
correttamente fanno scorrere di nuovo ai loro posti ed all'allievo è 
invitata per provare ancora. Vedendo la parola l'allievo 
convince l'aiuto per memorizzarlo e marche il vocabolario studia 
espressivo. Sentire le parole egualmente significa il valore 
aggiunto; l'allievo avverte la parola con molti sensi ed in 
questo modo l'oggetto imparante sostiene parecchi generi di stili 
imparanti.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Ο στόχος αυτού του αντικειμένου εκμάθησης είναι στο 
λεξιλόγιο πρακτικής σε ένα πλούσιο περιβάλλον πολυμέσων 
πλαισίου και με την ενίσχυση της αυθεντικής ηχώντας ομιλίας. 
Ο σπουδαστής πρόκειται να αναγνωρίσει τα κεντρικότερα μέρη 
σε μια περιγραφή ενός χόμπι και να συνδέσει αυτό με μια εικόνα 
που αντιπροσωπεύει εκείνο το χόμπι. Ο σπουδαστής 
βλέπει τις εικόνες που αντιπροσωπεύουν τα διάφορα χόμπι 
συν τις διαφορετικές λεκτικές φυσαλίδες. Με τον κρότο σε μια
λεκτική φυσαλίδα ο σπουδαστής ακούει μια περιγραφή ενός χόμπι, 
χωρίς αυτό το πραγματικό όνομα του αναφοράς του χόμπι. Ο 
σπουδαστής πρόκειται να κινήσει τις λεκτικές φυσαλίδες πάνω από
την εικόνα του χόμπι που περιγράφεται. Εάν η τοποθέτηση 
είναι σωστή, η φυσαλίδα εξαφανίζεται και ο σπουδαστής λαμβάνει 
ένα σχόλιο που επιβεβαιώνει την ενέργεια. Μετά από κάθε 
σωστή απάντηση ένα αποκαλούμενο γαπφηλλ-τετράγωνο θα σκάσει 
επάνω, παρουσιάζοντας την πρόταση που ακούστηκε ακριβώς. Ο 
σπουδαστής θα συμπληρώσει τις λέξεις η - ή λέξη - ελλείπων στα 
χάσματα. Αυτό σημαίνει ότι ο σπουδαστής αναγκάζεται να 
ακούσει προσεκτικότερα την απάντησή του και ενισχύει επίσης την 
αποστήθιση των λέξεων που συνδέουν με τα χόμπι. Οι 
φυσαλίδες που δεν είναι τοποθετημένη σωστά φωτογραφική 
διαφάνεια, μετά από ένα σχόλιο, πίσω στις αρχικές θέσεις τους.
Στην επόμενη φάση, οι λέξεις γνωστές από την προηγούμενη 
άσκηση ασκούνται. Αντί των φυσαλίδων, υπάρχουν τώρα 
ομιλούσες ράβδοι στην οθόνη. Με τον κρότο ενός από τους, ο
σπουδαστής ακούει το όνομα ενός χόμπι. Ο σπουδαστής θα 
κινήσει τα τμήματα σωστής εικόνας χόμπι. Όταν ο 
σπουδαστής γίνεται, μπορεί να ελέγξει την άσκηση με τον κρότο 
του κουμπιού "έλεγχοσ". Τα τμήματα που έχουν τοποθετηθεί 
σωστά εξαφανίζονται και ο σπουδαστής ακούει τη λέξη και την 
βλέπει γραπτή. Τα τμήματα που δεν είναι 
τοποθετημένη σωστά φωτογραφική διαφάνεια πίσω στις θέσεις τους 
και ο σπουδαστής ωθούνται για να προσπαθήσουν πάλι. Με να 
δει τη λέξη ο σπουδαστής παίρνει τις οδηγίες για να 
τις απομνημονεύσει και καθιστούν τις μελέτες λεξιλογίου 
σημαντικές. Η ακοή των λέξεων σημαίνει επίσης την 
προστιθέμενη αξία  ο σπουδαστής δοκιμάζει τη λέξη με 
πολλές αισθήσεις και κατ' αυτό τον τρόπο το αντικείμενο 
εκμάθησης υποστηρίζει διάφορα είδη εκμάθησης των μορφών.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">La meta de este objeto que aprende es practicar 
vocabulario en un ambiente rico de las multimedias del contexto y con 
la ayuda del discurso que suena auténtico. El estudiante debe 
reconocer las partes más centrales de una descripción de una manía 
y conectar esto a un cuadro que represente esa manía. El 
estudiante ve los cuadros que representan varias manías más diversas
burbujas del discurso. Haciendo clic en una burbuja del discurso
el estudiante oye una descripción de una manía, sin eso el nombre 
real de la manía que es mencionada. El estudiante debe mover 
las burbujas del discurso encima del cuadro de la manía se está 
describiendo que. Si la colocación está correcta, la burbuja 
desaparece y el estudiante recibe un comentario que confirma la 
acción. Después de que cada contestación correcta que un 
gapfill-cuadrado supuesto hará estallar para arriba, visualizando la 
sentencia oír. El estudiante completará las palabras - o la 
palabra - que faltan en los boquetes. Esto significa que fuerzan
al estudiante escuchar más cuidadosamente su respuesta y también 
consolida la memorización de las palabras que conectan a las manías.
Las burbujas que no se ponen correctamente resbalan, después de
que un comentario, de nuevo a sus lugares originales. En la fase
próxima, las palabras familiares del ejercicio anterior se practican.
En vez de burbujas, allí ahora están hablando barras en la 
pantalla. Haciendo clic una de ellas, el estudiante oye el 
nombre de una manía. El estudiante moverá las secciones en un 
cuadro correcto de la manía. Cuando hacen al estudiante, él o 
ella puede controlar el ejercicio haciendo clic el botón "control". 
Las secciones que se han colocado correctamente desaparecen y el
estudiante oye la palabra y la considera escrita. Las secciones 
que no se han puesto correctamente resbalan de nuevo a sus lugares y 
al estudiante se impulsan para intentar otra vez. Viendo la 
palabra el estudiante consigue ayuda para memorizarla y las marcas el 
vocabulario estudia significativo. Oír las palabras también 
significa valor agregado; el estudiante experimenta la palabra 
con muchos sentidos y de esta manera el objeto que aprende utiliza 
varias clases de estilos que aprenden.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>3990</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>special education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-U</string>
            <string language="sv">&gt; 10</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Exercise of listening comprehension and the Finnish language vocabulary</string>
            <string language="sv">Övning av hörförståelse och av finskans ordförråd</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82919</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>image/bmp</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/hobbies_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
