<expression xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0 http://fire.eun.org/lode/imslorsltitm_v1p0.xsd" xmlns="http://www.imsglobal.org/xsd/imslorsltitm_v1p0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <identifier>
    <catalog>hdl</catalog>
    <entry>10494/82803</entry>
  </identifier>
  <identifier>
    <catalog>expression-cmr-id</catalog>
    <entry>82803</entry>
  </identifier>
  <description>
    <facet>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.expressionDescriptionFacetValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>main</value>
    </facet>
    <metadata>
      <schema>http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM</schema>
      <lom xsi:schemaLocation="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/lomv1.0/lomLoose.xsd" xmlns="http://ltsc.ieee.org/xsd/LOM">
        <general>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eln:demoportal</catalog>
            <entry>3997</entry>
          </identifier>
          <title>
            <string language="en">Kitchen computer - news report</string>
            <string language="sv">Kitchen computer - nyhetsrapport</string>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Küchecomputer - Nachrichtenreport</string>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">Ordinateur de cuisine - état de nouvelles</string>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Computador da cozinha - relatório de notícia</string>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Calcolatore della cucina - rapporto di notizie</string>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Υπολογιστής κουζινών - έκθεση ειδήσεων</string>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Ordenador de la cocina - informe de noticias</string>
          </title>
          <language>sv</language>
          <description>
            <string language="en">This is an example of how to process a news material in linguistic manner with the aid of a permanent innovation (in this case the invention of the kitchen computer). The material includes four different exercises. First the student listens to the news about the invention of a kitchen computer and the reasons to why this - during the 60s - subversive idea never broke through. Then, the student moves on to the exercises based on that news item. The so called True or False - exercise is a listening comprehension exercise where you are to choose which statements from the news report are correct. The student chooses either” True” or” False” and can check his replies using the ”check” button. 
In the Lexitaire-excercise the student practices the central vocabulary of the news report, in the form of a so called vocabulary solitaire (lexitaire). To the left, there are English words that the student is to place/drag on top of the Swedish equivalents to the right. The words that are combined correctly disappear while the English mistakenly combined words return to their original places. In the Synonym Sweeper-exercise both vocabulary and text comprehension are practised. The student sees the news report as text. In the lower part of the screen there are squares where the student will drag the synonyms in the text to. The word that is placed on the correct synonym in the text disappears and the points in the point counter are increased. The sentence structure is practised through the Begin&amp;amp;End-exercise. On the screen there are five sentences whose beginning and end have been jumbled. The student's task is to form whole senses by arranging them so that beginning to the left and the end to the right fit together. The replies are checked using the Check-button and the score is shown on the screen. This many-faceted exercise illustrates how news can be used in a natural way when the different areas of a language are being practised.



</string>
            <string language="sv">Detta är ett exempel på hur man språkligt kan bearbeta ett nyhetsmaterial med hjälp av en bestående  nyhet (i detta fall uppfinningen av köksdatorn). Till materialet hör fyra olika övningar.
Först lyssnar eleven på en nyhet om uppfinningen av en köksdator och orsakerna till varför denna på 1960-talet omstörtande idé aldrig slog igenom. Därefter går eleven vidare till de övningsuppgifter som gjorts på basis av nyheten.
-	Den så kallade True or False- uppgiften är en hörföretåelseuppgift där man ska välja vilka påståenden från nyhetsrapporten som stämmer. Eleven väljer antingen ”True” eller ”False” och kan kontrollera sina svar med knappen ”Check”.
-	I Lexitaire-uppgiften övas nyhetsrapportens centala ordförråd, i form av så kallad ordförrådspassians (lexitaire). Till vänster finns engelska ord som eleven ska placera/dra ovanpå de svenska motsvarigheterna till höger. De ord som kombinerats korrekt försvinner medan det engelska felkombinerade ordet återvänder till sin ursprungliga plats.
-	I Synonym Sweeper-uppgiften övas både ordförråd och textförståelse. Eleven ser nyhetsrapporten som text. Nere i rutan finns ord som eleven ska dra in i synonymerna i texten Det ord som placerats på korrekt synonym i texten försvinner och poängen i poängräknaren höjs.
-	I Begin&amp;amp;End-uppgiften övas satsbyggnaden. I rutan finns fem meningar vars början och slut har blandats ihop. Elevens uppgift är att bilda hela meningar genom att arrangera dem så att början till vänster och slutet till höger passar ihop. Svaren kontrolleras med Check-knappen och poängställningen visas i rutan.
Denna mångsidiga uppgift åskådliggör hur man på ett naturligt sätt kan använda nyheter när man övar språkets olika delområden.</string>
          </description>
          <structure>
            <source>structureValues</source>
            <value>atomic</value>
          </structure>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-de">Dieses ist ein Beispiel von, wie man ein 
Nachrichten Material in der linguistischen Weise mit dem Hilfsmittel 
einer permanenten Innovation verarbeitet (in diesem Fall die Erfindung
vom Küchecomputer). Das Material schließt vier 
unterschiedliche Übungen ein. Zuerst hört der Kursteilnehmer 
zu den Nachrichten über die Erfindung eines Küchecomputers und zu 
den Gründen zu, warum dieses - während des 60s - subversivee Idee 
nie durch brach. Dann zieht der Kursteilnehmer an auf die 
Übungen um, die auf der Nachricht basieren. Das sogenannte 
zutreffende oder das falsch - Übung ist eine hörende Erfassenübung,
in der Sie wählen sollen, welche Anweisungen vom Nachrichtenreport 
korrekt sind. Der Kursteilnehmer wählt irgendein? 
Zutreffend? oder? Falsch? und kann seine 
Antworten mit dem?check überprüfen? Taste. Im 
Lexitaire-excercise übt der Kursteilnehmer den zentralen Wortschatz 
des Nachrichtenreports, in Form eines sogenannten Wortschatz solitaire
(lexitaire). Nach links gibt es englische Wörter, daß der 
Kursteilnehmer zu place/drag auf die schwedischen Äquivalente rechts 
ist. Die Wörter, die richtig kombiniert werden, verschwinden, 
während Englisch irrtümlich Wörter kombinierte, zurückgehen zu 
ihren ursprünglichen Plätzen. Im Synonym Kehrmaschine-exercise 
werden der Wortschatz und das Textverständnis geübt. Der 
Kursteilnehmer sieht den Nachrichtenreport als Text. Zu im 
unteren Teil des Bildschirms gibt es Quadrate, denen der 
Kursteilnehmer die Synonyme im Text schleppt. Das Wort, das auf 
das korrekte Synonym in den Text verschwindet gelegt wird und die 
Punkte im Punktkostenzähler werden erhöht. Die 
Programmsatzstruktur wird durch die Begin&amp;End-Übung geübt. 
Auf dem Bildschirm gibt es fünf Programmsätze deren der Beginn
und das Ende durcheinandergebracht worden sind. Die Aufgabe des 
Kursteilnehmers ist, vollständige Richtungen zu bilden, indem sie sie
ordnet, damit, zusammen anfangend zum links und zum Ende zum rechten 
Sitz. Die Antworten werden mit der Überprüfen-Taste 
überprüft und die Kerbe wird auf dem Bildschirm gezeigt. Diese
facettenreiche Übung veranschaulicht, wie Nachrichten in einer 
natürlichen Methode verwendet werden können, wenn die 
unterschiedlichen Bereiche einer Sprache geübt werden.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-fr">C'est un exemple de la façon traiter un matériel
de nouvelles de la façon linguistique à l'aide d'une innovation 
permanente (dans ce cas-ci l'invention de l'ordinateur de cuisine). 
Le matériel inclut quatre exercices différents. D'abord 
l'étudiant écoute les nouvelles au sujet de l'invention d'un 
ordinateur de cuisine et les raisons pourquoi ceci - pendant le 60s - 
idée subversive n'a jamais traversé. Puis, l'étudiant passe 
aux exercices basés sur celui nouvelle. Le prétendu vrai ou 
faux - l'exercice est un exercice d'écoute de compréhension où vous
devez choisir quels rapports de l'état de nouvelles sont corrects. 
L'étudiant choisit l'un ou l'autre ? Vrai ? ou ? 
Faux ? et peut contrôler ses réponses en utilisant le 
?check ? bouton. Dans le Lexitaire-excercise l'étudiant 
pratique le vocabulaire central de l'état de nouvelles, sous forme de
prétendu solitaire de vocabulaire (lexitaire). Vers la gauche,
il y a des mots anglais que l'étudiant est à place/drag sur les 
équivalents suédois vers la droite. Les mots qui sont 
combinés correctement disparaissent tandis que l'anglais combinait de
manière erronée des mots reviennent à leurs endroits initiaux. 
Dans le Balayeuse-exercice de synonyme le vocabulaire et la 
compréhension des textes sont pratiqués. L'étudiant voit 
l'état de nouvelles comme texte. Dans la partie plus 
inférieure de l'écran il y a à angle droit à où l'étudiant 
traînera les synonymes dans le texte. Le mot qui est placé sur
le synonyme correct dans le texte disparaît et les points dans le 
compteur de point sont augmentés. La structure de la phrase est
pratiquée par le Begin&amp;End-exercice. Sur l'écran il y a 
cinq phrases dont commencer et extrémité ont été brouillés. 
L'étudiant chargent doit former des sens entiers en les 
arrangeant de sorte que commençant à la gauche et à l'extrémité 
au bon ajustement ensemble. Les réponses sont contrôlées à 
l'aide du Contrôler-bouton et les points sont montrés sur l'écran. 
Cet exercice diversifié illustre comment des nouvelles peuvent 
être utilisées dans une voie normale quand les différentes zones 
d'un langage sont pratiquées.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-pt">Este é um exemplo de como processar um material 
da notícia na maneira lingüística com o dae (dispositivo 
automático de entrada) de uma inovação permanente (neste caso a 
invenção do computador da cozinha). O material inclui quatro 
exercícios diferentes. Primeiramente o estudante escuta a 
notícia sobre a invenção de um computador da cozinha e as razões 
porque este - durante o 60s - idéia subversiva nunca quebrou 
completamente. Então, o estudante move-se sobre para os 
exercícios baseados naquele artigo de notícia. A Verdadeiro 
assim chamada ou falso - o exercício é um exercício escutando da 
compreensão onde você deva escolher que indicações do relatório 
de notícia estão corretas. O estudante escolhe qualquer um? 
Verdadeiro? ou? Falso? e pode verificar suas 
respostas usando o?check? tecla. No Lexitaire-excercise o 
estudante pratica o vocabulário central do relatório de notícia, no
formulário do assim que do solitaire chamado do vocabulário 
(lexitaire). À esquerda, há umas palavras inglesas que o 
estudante é a place/drag no alto dos equivalentes suecos à direita. 
As palavras que são combinadas corretamente desaparecem quando 
o inglês combinou equivocadamente palavras retornam a seus lugares 
originais. No Sweeper-exercício do synonym  o vocabulário e a 
compreensão de texto são praticados. O estudante vê o 
relatório de notícia como o texto. Na parte mais inferior da 
tela há os quadrados a onde o estudante arrastará os synonyms no 
texto. A palavra que é colocada no synonym correto no texto 
desaparece e os pontos no contador do ponto são aumentados. A 
estrutura de sentença é praticada com o Begin&amp;End-exercício. 
Na tela há cinco sentenças cujo o começo e a extremidade 
jumbled. A tarefa do estudante é dar forma a sentidos inteiros 
arranjando os de modo que começando à esquerda e à extremidade ao 
ajuste direito junto. As respostas são verificadas usando a 
Verific-tecla e a contagem é mostrada na tela. Este exercício 
many-faceted ilustra como a notícia pode ser usada em uma maneira 
natural quando as áreas diferentes de uma língua estão sendo 
praticadas.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-it">Ciò è un esempio di come elaborare un materiale
di notizie nel modo linguistico con l'aiuto di un'innovazione 
permanente (in questo caso l'invenzione del calcolatore della cucina).
Il materiale include quattro esercitazioni differenti. In 
primo luogo l'allievo ascolta le notizie circa l'invenzione di un 
calcolatore della cucina ed i motivi perchè questo - durante il 60s -
idea sovversiva non ha attraversato mai. Allora, l'allievo passa
verso le esercitazioni basate su quella notizia. Il cosiddetto 
allineare o falso - l'esercitazione è un'esercitazione ascoltante di 
comprensione dove dovete scegliere quali istruzione dal rapporto di 
notizie sono corrette. L'allievo sceglie uno? Allineare? 
o? Falso? e può controllare le sue risposte usando 
il?check? tasto. Nel Lexitaire-excercise l'allievo si 
esercita nel vocabolario centrale del rapporto di notizie, sotto forma
d'un cosiddetto solitaire di vocabolario (lexitaire). Il a 
sinistra, ci sono parole inglesi che l'allievo è a place/drag in cima
agli equivalenti svedesi alla destra. Le parole che sono unite 
correttamente spariscono mentre l'inglese ha unito erroneamente le 
parole ritornano ai loro posti originali. 
Nell'Spazzatrice-esercitazione di sinonimo sia il vocabolario 
che la comprensione del testo si esercitano in. L'allievo vede 
il rapporto di notizie come testo. Nella parte più inferiore 
dello schermo ci sono quadrato a dove l'allievo trascinerà i sinonimi
nel testo. La parola che è disposta sul sinonimo corretto nel 
testo sparisce ed i punti nel contatore del punto sono aumentati. 
La struttura di frase si esercita in con 
l'Begin&amp;End-esercitazione. Sullo schermo ci sono cinque 
frasi di cui cominciare e l'estremità jumbled. L'operazione 
dell'allievo è di formare i sensi interi organizzandoli in modo che 
cominciando il a sinistra e l'estremità alla giusta misura insieme. 
Le risposte sono controllate per mezzo del Controll-tasto ed il 
segno è indicato sullo schermo. Questa esercitazione multiforme
illustra come le notizie possono essere usate in un modo naturale 
quando le zone differenti di un linguaggio stanno esercitandosi in.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-el">Αυτό είναι ένα παράδειγμα για το πώς να επεξεργαστεί
ένα υλικό ειδήσεων με το γλωσσικό τρόπο με την ενίσχυση μιας 
μόνιμης καινοτομίας (σε αυτήν την περίπτωση η εφεύρεση του 
υπολογιστή κουζινών). Το υλικό περιλαμβάνει τέσσερις 
διαφορετικές ασκήσεις. Πρώτα ο σπουδαστής ακούει τις 
ειδήσεις για την εφεύρεση ενός υπολογιστή κουζινών και τους 
λόγους γιατί αυτή η - κατά τη διάρκεια της δεκαετίας του '60 - 
ανατρεπτική ιδέα δεν έσπασε ποτέ κατευθείαν. Κατόπιν, ο 
σπουδαστής κινείται προς τις ασκήσεις βασισμένες σε εκείνο το 
αντικείμενο ειδήσεων. Αποκαλούμενος ο αληθινός ή ψεύτικος 
- η άσκηση είναι μια άσκηση κατανόησης ακούσματος όπου 
πρόκειται να επιλέξετε ποιες δηλώσεις από την έκθεση ειδήσεων 
είναι σωστές. Ο σπουδαστής επιλέγει καθενός; 
Αληθινός; ή; Ψεύτικος; και μπορεί να 
ελέγξει τις απαντήσεις του χρησιμοποιώντας το ?check; 
κουμπί. Λεξηταηρε- οι πρακτικές σπουδαστών που το 
κεντρικό λεξιλόγιο των ειδήσεων υποβάλλει έκθεση, υπό μορφή 
αποκαλούμενου μοναχικού λεξιλογίου (lexitaire). Στο 
αριστερό, υπάρχουν αγγλικές λέξεις ότι ο σπουδαστής πρόκειται 
να τοποθετήσει/έλξη πάνω από τα σουηδικά αντίτιμα στο δικαίωμα.
Οι λέξεις που συνδυάζονται σωστά εξαφανίζονται ενώ οι 
Αγγλοι συνδύασαν εσφαλμένα τις λέξεις επιστρέφουν στις αρχικές 
θέσεις τους. Στην όχημα αποκομιδής απορριμμάτων-άσκηση 
συνωνύμου και το λεξιλόγιο και η κατανόηση κειμένων ασκούνται. 
Ο σπουδαστής βλέπει την έκθεση ειδήσεων ως κείμενο.
Στο χαμηλότερο μέρος της οθόνης υπάρχουν τετράγωνα όπου ο 
σπουδαστής θα σέρει τα συνώνυμα στο κείμενο. Η λέξη που 
τοποθετείται στο σωστό συνώνυμο στο κείμενο εξαφανίζεται και τα 
σημεία στο μετρητή σημείου αυξάνονται. Η δομή πρότασης 
ασκείται μέσω της ψεγην&amp;αμπ;Ενδ-άσκησης. Στην οθόνη 
υπάρχουν πέντε προτάσεις η των οποίων αρχή και το τέλος έχει 
αναστατωθεί. Η στοιχειώδης εργασία του σπουδαστή είναι να 
διαμορφώσει ολόκληρες τις αισθήσεις με να τακτοποιήσει τις έτσι 
ώστε αρχή στο αριστερό και το τέλος στη σωστή τακτοποίηση από 
κοινού. Οι απαντήσεις ελέγχονται χρησιμοποιώντας το 
έλεγχος-κουμπί και το αποτέλεσμα εμφανίζεται στην οθόνη. 
Αυτή η many-faceted άσκηση επεξηγεί πώς οι ειδήσεις 
μπορούν να χρησιμοποιηθούν με έναν φυσικό τρόπο όταν ασκούνται 
οι διαφορετικοί τομείς μιας γλώσσας.</string>
          </description>
          <description>
            <string language="x-mt-es">Éste es un ejemplo de cómo procesar un material 
de las noticias de la manera lingüística con la ayuda de una 
innovación permanente (en este caso la invención del ordenador de la
cocina). El material incluye cuatro diversos ejercicios. 
Primero el estudiante escucha las noticias sobre la invención 
de un ordenador de la cocina y las razones porqué esto - durante el 
60s - idea subversiva nunca se rompió a través. Entonces, el 
estudiante se traslada encendido a los ejercicios basados en ése 
noticia. El el verdad supuesto o falso - el ejercicio es un 
ejercicio de la comprensión que escucha donde usted está elegir qué
declaraciones del informe de noticias están correctas. ¿El 
estudiante elige cualquiera? ¿Verdad? ¿o? ¿Falso? 
¿y puede controlar sus contestaciones usando el?check? 
botón. En el Lexitaire-excercise el estudiante practica 
el vocabulario central del informe de noticias, en la forma de un 
solitaire supuesto del vocabulario (lexitaire). A la izquierda, 
hay palabras inglesas que el estudiante está a place/drag encima de 
los equivalentes suecos a la derecha. Las palabras que se 
combinan correctamente desaparecen mientras que el inglés combinó 
equivocadamente palabras vuelven a sus lugares originales. En 
Barrendero-ejercicio del sinónimo se practican el vocabulario y la 
comprensión de texto. El estudiante ve el informe de noticias 
como texto. En la parte más inferior de la pantalla hay los 
cuadrados a donde el estudiante arrastrará los sinónimos en el 
texto. Se aumentan la palabra que se pone en el sinónimo 
correcto en el texto desaparece y las puntas en el contador de la 
punta. La estructura de sentencia se practica con el 
Begin&amp;End-ejercicio. En la pantalla hay cinco sentencias que
el comenzar y el extremo jumbled. La tarea del estudiante es 
formar sentidos enteros arreglándolos de modo que comenzando a la 
izquierda y al extremo al ajuste derecho junta. Se controlan las
contestaciones usando el Controlar-boto'n y la cuenta se muestra en la
pantalla. Este ejercicio diversificado ilustra cómo las 
noticias se pueden utilizar en una manera natural cuando las diversas 
áreas de un lenguaje se están practicando.</string>
          </description>
        </general>
        <lifeCycle>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>author</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>roleValues</source>
              <value>publisher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;National Board of Education, Finland
FN:National Board of Education, Finland
ORG:National Board of Education, Finland
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
        </lifeCycle>
        <metaMetadata>
          <metadataSchema>LREv4.0</metadataSchema>
          <identifier>
            <catalog>eun</catalog>
            <entry>3997</entry>
          </identifier>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>creator</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Juho;Helminen;;;
FN:Helminen Juho
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2004-02-16</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>provider</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:;European Schoolnet
FN:European Schoolnet
ORG:European Schoolnet
END:VCARD</entity>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <contribute>
            <role>
              <source>LRE.roleMetaValues</source>
              <value>enricher</value>
            </role>
            <entity>BEGIN:VCARD
VERSION:3.0
N:Alhovaara;Nilo;;;
FN:Nilo Alhovaara
ORG:
END:VCARD</entity>
            <date>
              <dateTime>2007-10-30</dateTime>
            </date>
          </contribute>
          <language>sv</language>
        </metaMetadata>
        <educational>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>drill and practice</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>reference</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <learningResourceType>
            <source>LRE.learningResourceTypeValues</source>
            <value>application</value>
          </learningResourceType>
          <intendedEndUserRole>
            <source>LRE.intendedEndUserRoleValues</source>
            <value>learner</value>
          </intendedEndUserRole>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>continuing education</value>
          </context>
          <context>
            <source>LRE.contextValues</source>
            <value>compulsory education</value>
          </context>
          <typicalAgeRange>
            <string language="x-t-lre">10-15</string>
            <string language="sv">10-15</string>
          </typicalAgeRange>
          <description>
            <string language="en">Young and adult students that have the basic command of English. An all-round, complete exercise in English listening comprehension and in vocabulary studies.</string>
            <string language="sv">Unga och vuxenstudenter som behärskar baskunskaperna i engelska. En mångsidig helhet i engelsk hörförståelse och i ordförrådsstudier.</string>
          </description>
        </educational>
        <rights>
          <cost>
            <source>costValues</source>
            <value>no</value>
          </cost>
          <copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
            <source>copyrightAndOtherRestrictionsValues</source>
            <value>yes</value>
          </copyrightAndOtherRestrictions>
          <description>
            <string language="x-t-cc">&lt;rdf:RDF xmlns="http://web.resource.org/cc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"&gt;&lt;Work rdf:about=""&gt;&lt;license rdf:resource="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/" /&gt;&lt;/Work&gt;&lt;License rdf:about="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.5/"&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Attribution" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Reproduction" /&gt;&lt;permits rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Distribution" /&gt;&lt;requires rdf:resource="http://web.resource.org/cc/Notice" /&gt;&lt;/License&gt;&lt;/rdf:RDF&gt;</string>
          </description>
        </rights>
        <classification>
          <purpose>
            <source>purposeValues</source>
            <value>discipline</value>
          </purpose>
          <taxonPath>
            <source>
              <string language="x-none">LRE-0001</string>
            </source>
            <taxon>
              <id>711</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">languages</string>
                <string language="sv">språkområden</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
            <taxon>
              <id>427</id>
              <entry>
                <string language="en">English language</string>
                <string language="sv">engelska språket</string>
              </entry>
            </taxon>
          </taxonPath>
        </classification>
      </lom>
    </metadata>
  </description>
  <manifestation>
    <identifier>
      <catalog>manifestation-cmr-id</catalog>
      <entry>82803</entry>
    </identifier>
    <name>
      <vocabularyID>LRE.manifestationNameValues</vocabularyID>
      <value>experience</value>
    </name>
    <parameter>
      <vocabularyID>MIME</vocabularyID>
      <value>image/bmp</value>
    </parameter>
    <item>
      <location>
        <uri>http://resources.eun.org/demoportal/kitchen_computer_sve.zip</uri>
      </location>
    </item>
  </manifestation>
</expression>
